This situation, we will start to discussing the lost topic in the ALBE hierarchy and concepts, the
operator overloading starting with the binary operator overloading operator overloading isn't a good
or B.
For example, some language doesn't have even operator ability, but it is something that would make
the good looks look more look more nicer and more useful.
So that's all about it.
So starting from this quarter, we're doing things like CNN X setout X and we're using such Lizelle
as that and to to make reading.
So now we know the CNNSI are just two objects.
But what how these two things are implemented in a similar way.
If you define the string across like Mustafah, any string is just your own is just an object.
We can do something like a star of one equals Z, but this is more like an array.
How is that happening?
And also we can say estab.
Lassard Ibrahim.
So we are doing some concatenation.
So like there are here Operators' how these operators are playing with the struct.
We know how to implement a struct.
We have to add variables and how to make functions, but how to make such things.
This is called operator overloading.
So remember from our discussion, the operators are of different types.
Some of them are unity.
So are binary, some are ternary.
We can also classify them like arithmetic, relational, logical, bitwise and so on.
So we already have played with this kind of apparatus.
And if I have two variables, X and Y, I can say integrate X equals Y or I can say plus plus X.
But what if I have a struct operator?
Overloading is all about that.
Some of these operators can be available to be applied with an object itself.
So we are doing the overloading here by the meaning that the object itself can't allow that.
This way you see something like the string class, it has the Bloss function, for example.
So instead of coming to numbers, the scene is a sense here now is we are concatenating two strings
to visit.
We we start here with the simple math class, which will be like our friend during the discussion,
most of the cases to highlight the what how can overexaggerating be implemented and how can make our
coding more beautiful.
So the middle class has two numbers, first and second, and has a constructor for that.
And then we have here some printing and getters and setters.
Now, interestingly, we have a function named Ed, so we add another function to us.
So the logic goes as following.
We get the pointer of our this class and return a new object of my first plus his first and my second.
The second.
That's it.
OK, so now if I created my idea of one and two and my bit of 10 and 20 and I started to say X and Y
and Z, if I try to print it, that would give me that eleven and twenty two.
So one plus 10, 11 tubeless two is twenty two.
So far so good.
Nothing without the could but thinking from a more convenient code.
What if you can do the following.
Z equals exodus Y instead of X and Y.
This is all about operator overloading the whole idea here.
The plus makes sense a lot in this city.
We know that two plus three is five.
But what if I want to add I can add these two objects.
This is operator overloading.
You start to overload this plus operator so that the class support plus operation.
OK, so we now want to get rid of this add function and add a new thing named Operators'.
So the logic and the syntax of the operator goes as far when you write the same syntax exactly.
Here, but you know you're right, operator plus operator.
Plus here is the function name literally the new function name is Operator Plus.
So we removed the word add and we added the the word operator plus now this is the function code.
So here is the it's a member function noticia.
Its function is defined inside the plus.
The word agreed to by the way is a reserved keyword.
So here the compiler, here we are writing X plus Y when the compiler x it say that O X is an object.
So now it says plus this is an operator, it goes and double check.
If there is a function in your class named Obreht or Bloss, when it finds it, it just send for you
here the second parameter, which is why doing this and returning the result for you.
So practically speaking on the compiler, see the plus here, it just replace it with dot operator plus
y.
So as.
He said a brutal brasier is actually a functioning notice here.
The plus is a vulnerability, so it takes two items.
Where are the two items?
The second item?
It is clear visibility, the parameter, but with the first parameter.
The first parameter is that this is said.
So the flaw in the compiler is X is an object.
Does it have an operator?
Yes.
Then call the operator plus function and give it the device.
OK, so what we did, we call it the member function operator.
Plus I can also define it outside the class.
But now if you decided outside the class, you need to give the two parameters explicitly for the for
the plus operator.
So you see here we are one and two again.
When the compiler see the first object of type operator plus one is try to identify a function that
matches its style and then it can call it if it wants, then we just use it.
So this we call it normal function or no function of global function.
The word no member function is the way we always describe the external operator.
This way, somewhere in the in the end of the section, we will highlight the differences between the
member and member functions.
OK, so in a very similar way to the front function, if you if you if you view highlighted this function
with a friend, you can just access the variables here in an easy way.
So I would like you to think all the time in the word operator plus as just the function name.
That's it.
So we have here like say add was two objects, just the compiler is doing more or more magic to to resolve
with the greater blast and provide the same function with the two variable names that you would like.
As usual, when you provide something as a friend, you are you are violating some of the object oriented
programming, but it might just make your code more efficient that it.