Another interesting thing in the world of looting is the convergence.
So let's first remember the something about the constructor, if we're defining here, Meyerbeer, into
your X, which is just defining the first and second was X..
This is fair enough, constructor.
Now, let's look here.
If we define X with one and two is going to use the second constructor, if we define Y equals three
here, Y three is going to use the first constructor.
Surprisingly, if you use here equals five is going also to use this constructor.
Think about it for a minute.
In C++, there is a rule if a constructor can be code with a single parameter, it can be used to convert
Edita type and there is a need.
So this conversion happened.
So and here we have only a single argument constructor, OK?
It can be it can be into X and something that has a temporary default value.
So here we are in C++ C that this five a double check if there is a single Aragón constructor that can
take this value or not.
If so, the C++ is going to do conversion.
So this what we call a conversion constructor, it is going to convert something to our database.
Now, this has an application over the operator overloading.
Let's say you are defining a non-member function operator, plus the text two objects.
If I wanted to do something like X plus five point three, the problem here, five point three, the
function is going to search.
Is there something of Dibia and double?
The answer is no, there is nothing.
But five point three is convertible to X, so double is convertible to integrate.
So this constructor will be used internally to convert this five point three to a beer that have two
values, five and five, and then use it directly and in a very similar way.
We can do three plus X and replace X plus five.
So the moral of that is.
C++ with that can do conversions.
Remember, we once did like overeaten plus for my beer and intriguer and for Integral my beer, but
now with this conversion constructor, we actually do need them.
However, this isn't the same for the member function conversion operator, which is still need something
that isn't just a temporary value here.
So these three can be converted to a minor object, but it would be temporary and C++ prevent it for
and for a member function.
So this is only available to another function.
Now what if I would like to prevent this implicit conversions from the some integer to my class or whatever
I can say here?
Explicit.
If I did the explicit, I'm saying I allow constructor like that, but please do not do a conversion
here, OK?
By the way, the conversion doesn't need to be primitive.
If you have a class rectangle and you have my bit of rectangle and you say the equals of rectangle,
it's going to convert it in an implicit way.
So if you would like to disable this kind of conversion, you just put the word explicit, then this
could be constructed.
This construction will not be allowed and this one will be allowed either member the functions in a
similar way, like the conversion constructor who can provide the conversion or the conversion constructor
converted something to our class, like integral to across the square, to across the rectangle, across
the conversion operator is the reverse it convert our class to something.
So here is how we define it.
If I say operator integer, you open the function and close it and return an integer.
This is going to convert your Berglas to a number.
Or you say I would like to provide a return over into your entier, then you return it.
Then again, it can be used here.
So you see you are converting the class, our class to another data type.
Now these two types of conversions happens in an implicit way most of the time, and we don't notice
them.
So they are in practice very problematic.
So I would suggest for you to use all those explicit to prevent this conversion and to not support this
kind of operators, if you would like to submit to them, make a function explicitly like, say, function
to say to bear function to end when someone is using it in in an explicit way, that's it.