Remember the assignment operator, if I have a class A and A Class B and I said it equal be, then there
is a member by member Cobbe that happened from the first class to the second class.
We said before that this is very risky if we have a pointer, because it's going to be a pointer from
the second quarter to the first pointer.
And now two objects are looking to the pointer and they are going to destroy it.
We learned the cubicle structure and we learned how the copy constructor can help us to protect us from
that.
So we define the before here, like, here's some class that has some value and we are deleting the
value in that structure.
And then we are providing constructor.
If you want to copy it, then we are copying by ourself with the value not taking the pointer.
Now we also say that you provide the structure for this case.
The missing case here is that we also have to provide assignment operator, because if someone say equal
B is again going to take his own copy of the pointer to our own copy to the pointer.
That's why we have to provide an assignment.
Operator The logic of the assignment operator is following.
You provide operator equal and then you provide an object to make an assignment for me.
And then you have here a return on time of your b, b, b, b difference.
Now implementing the assignment operator is tricky.
There are three steps that you have to keep in mind.
Remember, the first step is do not assign the variable to itself.
Do not assign a variable to.
So if someone did equal a you don't.
You don't.
You don't have to go and do all of the member values could be best.
This can be very problematic.
So the way is we first double check if this another object is the same as our class, if say we just
return, we do not have to do anything else.
The second tricky thing is ability class, if the middle class has already some logic, has some assignment
operator, then it's much better to even just call the operator equal function of the base class.
Once you're done with that, then go ahead with your step by step.
Member function could be based on values and just switch them to your internal class.
This way you are simply overloading the operator in case you would like to prevent the operator equal.
Like you can also prevent the constructor you do in the following.
You say here operator equal, equal, delete, equal delete prevented someone from assigning it.
Remember this is a B to equal B one.
Here is a copy constructor because we are creating an object, but here we are assigning.
So again, if you have a pointer inside your class that you have created, you have to do three things.
You have to destroy it.
You have to constructor, you have to operator assignment.
You have to do this three steps in order.
That said.