The third set for for operator overloading, the first is to read this program and the guess the output
of it.
There is something tricky here about the about this operator in terms of precedence.
So double check for this.
What was the precedence in C++ of this operator?
The second program is as following the first software engineer who wanted to operator overloading the
reading and writing.
He did it as far as he did as a member function inside his class.
So the first idea with the first question is how to use this ability of reading to really read and write.
So add two lines here to read and write your X Y and write them and give it up for the guy who did this
kind of design.
Fractured glass, fractured glasses, like three over a three or four and so on.
So this is a fraction.
We have a no hitter and numerator.
You are to implement a fraction that support this functionality, read it and understand it.
To simplify a fraction, you should do something with the greater the greater common deviser.
There is a built in function, underscore, underscore GCT.
If you try to use it and it doesn't work for a reason or another combination error, then you can use
this implementation.
If you want to skip the simplification, that's OK.
If you have two numbers and would like to simplify them as they did between A and B, and then divide
ABC and BBC.
Everyone, this is a close race that we would like to implement, it has internally appointer and size,
wherever you are, to add a bunch of methods here to support the following it allow creating the array.
You can access it with subscript operator to sit and get.
You can read and write.
You can do the plus plus prefix and postfix to increment every cell in the array with one you can compare
with equally Cuarón, but you can assign a rate to another.
So this is some sembler function to the class here.
So we are defining an array of six numbers.
So initially six is we are sending them from zero to six, we are incrementing and so on.
I would like you to read this mean and double check with the output in a similar way.
I would like you to extend the current array to add to the array.
So the extra thing here, Belarusan column, you are to try to to me to make use of the available things
in their function as much as you could with one extra functionality.
I would like you to allow us to exit using the function collaboratively with the I n g.
So it is again and again for the class.
Read it, double check it and make sure you can implement it.
Finally going back to the above the the company payroll homework that we had before.
Inboden, what is the one that has problems like being comparable, printable and cleanable were to
make two changes here.
The first one is we are going to submit to the insertion the extraction operator.
So I can now say instead of some able to print, I can say also see with this, that is then some people
or whatever five times.
The second thing is a comparable biocompatible has a function to make Kabeer, but more to provide me
with a greater list then to compare function.
So I also provide that the TYT.