And this video I'd like to highlight on more possibilities for the operator plus one, we are using
it as a nonmember function.
So now we have this operator.
Plus here, if you look to the first three function, they are all named operator Bloss.
But like any operator, like any function overloading you can have, you have to have different parameters.
So here we have the previous to my bare objects.
Now we have here Meyerbeer objects an integer and we have an integer and Meyerbeer function.
So it seems as if we're trying to provide some integer to interact with the operator overloading itself.
So the logic here, if we want to add an X, we are adding it to the first and to the second.
Now we have X and the number.
You can write it in the same way, but be smart and do not just duplicate your code.
You can just switch the you want to see one plus X to be the same call as here.
As you see, you can also have the same like operator multiplication or subtraction and so on.
So now this again the same for function, but we know just in a more visible way.
So let's see the main function to get a sense of what is happening here.
I have defined the beer one beer to like, be sorry.
Here is a normal beer.
Oh, by the way, the operator minus here is taking my beer class and taking normal beer, beer, beer
variable from.
So now here we say that Z one is defined as X plus five.
Now wait, it isn't like X Y and both of them are De beers, they are X which is the object and five
which is an integer.
When you see here you find here the object and you find here the, the, the X.
So what's happening is that this function X plus five is calling this guy to, to use it.
Now on the on the other side here, looking to.
Who looking to three times X, OK, three times X.
Let's go back one step to here.
If I try to do five plus X within these cases, you notice that it needs an integer plus my beer.
But there is nothing here like integer and my beer.
So this will be a competition.
Now the other side we have here something to say three times X, so it needs an operator overloading
the ticket and integer in the beginning and an object of three.
So we see here here is operator multiplication.
It is X as an integer and here is the object.
If I try to say six times the three, this would make a comparison error because it can search for an
X object times and then times integer but doesn't exist.
We say here also X minus be so this need a minus operator that has an X in the left side and has B in
the right side.
So we have here we have minus and the left side is integer and the right side is.
It's actually a bit like like this is a what could difference why we cannot make it.
Let's say I would like to support something like three times X using the member function.
We cannot do that Y because the member function needs on the left side an object.
What I say X plus five X here is an object calling function, that operator Bloss.
But if I say three times X, what is code and times A here with no, we cannot say it's the same.
That extends three.
This is different to different operator version.
So the compiler would not be able to find some object representing three.
We will know in the future how this might happen.
But for now, what's more important here is if you would like to submit to something that is more flexible
in terms of the appearance of the operators, then they num number function is the way to go.