Similar to the Dubina binary operator overloading, we can also override the owner operators.
Remember, there were many generators we can have the single minus, we can have the not.
We can have the plus, plus and minus minus and so on.
And many of them in next, which somewhere will explain the plus, plus and minus minus because it has
some electrics.
So let's add to the mix here.
And let's say that our logic is if you use the operator not we are multiplying each number with the
minus one.
So I can I can inside the class and find a new operator.
Not and then notice here, this is unary greater so you don't take a second parameter.
So we got the Meyerbeer here and just multiply created the new one with the minus one would definitely
make it more easier.
Just, just first equals minus first and so on in a very similar way.
We do find it inside the class.
We can also define it outside the class.
But if we defined it out of the class, it would have a single parameter only.
So inside the class, what parameters?
Outside the class, the first parameter, which will act like the lift operator.
So here we say X equals X is going to find additional objects are going to find, if not can be applied
to the operator or not.