One of the interesting things are the subscript operator.
So remember, we're using a string we used to exit with something like a race type.
So what would like to do that you simply override the operator on your code.
So you would like now to to override this operator overloading.
So what do you expect as a parameter?
You expect a position.
So if you would like now to provide some operator overloading for all my berglas such that if I said
X of zero it gives you a first number and X of one, it gives a second number.
It is how you define it.
So first, this is operator overloading for the subscript you say here, operator of operator overloading
the subscript and then you expect the parameter to be some position.
So you see, hear the integral position.
And as my work is to integrate, you are returning interior.
So this is dependent more on the function, on the object.
And then I have some logic.
I said if position equals zero, return of the first value or otherwise return the second value.
So now we can bring to the two values in a very normal way.
Very good so far.
Now, let's say that I would like to say X of zero equals seven.
So now if we have an array, we can print it, but we can say the value for the component here is going
to complain about that.
Why?
What is X zero zero?
Just like some value.
Imagine if you did integer X and then you say five equals X.
You know, the compiler will definitely complain because five isn't some memory in there isn't some
pointer address isn't some areas that you can just add something in it.
So actually zero here is just some integer value.
You cannot say five equals seven.
This would complete in a more formal terms.
This is good nifty value.
So if the value in a very informal way is some is some like points to address, there are some areas
that you can use it, but.
Right.
But it doesn't let the value and write value in like C++ 20 is is much more complicated.
That's a simplification.
But for now, this is just the left of does it have some address.
So if it if it isn't addressed, I could just put the value.
So now the question is, how can I provide something that allows me to put a value?
If I would like to put a value, I need some address referring to the first or the second event.
And this is where the second version of it comes to the C.
It's the same logic.
Exactly.
But you use here into your reference.
Now, if this function is returning, a value is returning value that has a reference to the first or
second is a specific reference in the in the class values.
So now if I say X zero X1, I can do that, but I can also write X zero, equal 10, x1 equal 20, because
this time it's in just like five or seven is actually a variable that we are looking to the memory for.
So this integral difference is it's what we call the value and the value and we can put some value inside
it.
Now there is an interesting thing here.
If you look to these two functions, they are very similar.
Remember, operator is just there is just a functioning.
So they are the same function name that we know that genotype doesn't matter.
So integrate into reference, they are different, but it doesn't matter.
How is it possible that we shouldn't have to function with the same name in a class there could differentiate
it is a contest if two function are the same.
Exactly.
But one of them was conscious.
This also is okay.
What will happen is if you have a if you if you, if you if the objects is going to call this going
to function, something that doesn't change the internal values and codes are going to be to call this
one and C++, the the, the, the ones that involve just the printing it is going to call this one,
which is the case, the one that involves changing.
It's going to be this one.
So this is relevant to the list, the privilege of principle specifically.
Are you printing then we call this function for you because you cannot you don't need to change your
variables.
Are you assigning this function for you?
So, OK, what if I just supervise the dysfunction here, this one in forty six and provided the kids
going to work well, but now even imprinting you are giving him an X's.
So this is improver from an obi perspective.
So although this function can work by itself, it is better to always provide the two Gourgeon one Kristofor
printing and one with our decongest.
OK, and interesting question here.
Can I define the subscript overeater outside the class?
The answer is no.
There are some operators in C++ that can only be defined inside the class and there are some operators
that cannot be overloaded either inside or outside the class.
That's it.