Let's define the regional operators, which might help us to sort the objects in a class in a very intuitive
way if we have an employee class here and we would like to make a certain let's say we'd like to it
sorted based on ID salary and not see it over here less than we'd need another object.
So we're comparing our variables with the other object.
Variables used to make a simple comparison to yourself with logic.
Order them in the way that you would like.
So we would like to compare first and then on Saturday the so on.
Once we define that, we now can actually compare every number.
One is this then and number two.
What's interesting here is if you have if you have a set of employees and would like to sort of them
the operator overloading would be working directly over them.
Remember before the operator overloading list, then you cannot do that.
You have to give some function here to be able to compare two things together.
But if you overloaded this operator, they are now like numbers, they can be compared together.
So far, so good.
But there is one one one issue here.
What if I would like to be more flexible on overloading, let's say, once on Saturday?
Once again, I'd want to know in different ways because no, I have only one default way.
There are two ways.
One way we did before you just defined some function that can compare two things together.
The other way is very similar to it.
You defined something we call the function collaborator.
So it is a clause that's going to compare by salary and it takes this operator like a function function
call and it takes this first quarter of this second.
When you are competing in whatever way and in practice you create one of these comparators.
One of these we call it conductor class and we give it the competitor.
The sort of function is going to use a competitor by sending it to different objects together with the
function call and make the comparison.
Remember, also, as we said, you can just do the function like we will compare and give it Embley.
Warren Beatty, this is just another way based on this function.
Corroborators.
That's it.