The second set of homework, which might be a little harder, the first one, it's a tracing program.
This is the end, the end ability to remember it if you have some through and through to falsify through
fossil fuels, the oil would be like a true false unless both of them are true.
So we have some boolean cross that Rabson true value and we have the operator and then taking another
boolean and just ending them together.
Now we would like to try something here.
This is a function through false.
Just returning.
True or false.
Very normal.
So we have here some elbit just that this is a normal one.
The second one, every one of them is returning some object of type boolean and then doing some.
And then I would like you to trace this program out.
In the second program, we are going to create our map, the remember the C++ map where you can access
with a string using the subscript operator.
This was really magic like you are.
You are dealing with an array.
But the index, the key was with the string was in the value today to implement our own mind map.
The map internally have two things.
It have a victor for strings and it have victor of integrase.
So they use it should be as follows.
You can say Mustafah 20, then you can say Mustafah 40, then you can say Saied 20.
If you try to bring to the value of Mostapha, it would be just the 40 the last one so far.
The behavior is like they are very normal C++ map.
On the other side you can also exit with into it.
If you exit with entier, it will find all the variables, all the strings with this value.
For example, if I was 20, then you notice here that say that they are the values of the also the class
would support us.
The Iterator has an X next to bring to the whole string content.
I would like you to provide a data structure functionality that allow such a papier.
The Doublecross, remember, we once talked about the double, if you did these two double values,
surprisingly, they will not be equal in most of the cases.
That's because the double representation isn't accurate.
Now, we would like to still like a let's say I would like to make a C++ map of Dublin something.
It will not work because the values aren't equal as you expect them.
So what we want to say that never compare W directly to compare them, that you need for us to compare
with some epsilon or use the word class would I would like you to create a double class that allow us
to use double Frehley so now we can have a C++ map of our class and some values.
This way if you if you noticed here, if you, if you define here to doubles of even these two values,
they are going to give you.
True, you can use them with a map.
So define a double class that acceptable value.
But allow us to compare the values together with the resident operator.
You can define a map of this variable mathematically if you have two double values and they are very
close in the representation, how to how to compare them the right way is using absolute function.
Subtracted is two values from each other.
Do one and two.
If the difference is very, very, very small, like one E to minus ten for example, then we know they
are equal.
Otherwise we can normally compare them for less than and greater that.
So the idea is about the difference between the two numbers to make sure.
Is it really very, very, very small?
If yes, they are equal.
Otherwise you can compare with this and agree to that.
Try to make use of this I.
Gispert, we have some classic chess board with some 2000 columns.
Think of it as a theory.
We would like to be able to exit this board with sitting and getting into ways.
We would like to be accessing it with function call collaborator and would like to be accessing it within
subscript operator.
Remember that C++ only allowed one subscript operator.
So how can you do this trick?
Think about it.
That's it.