Let's learn about overloading the prefix and postfix operators, remember, in the in the prefix operator,
we wanted to increment our ability, our our value, then return it.
If I say it's with X plus plus X. We need the exit to be incremented then to be presented.
So we'd like to present to some here the the the prefix operator.
We are going to do the similar logic.
We are providing the plus plus here.
So we are doing the plus plus for the first plus plus the second and then we are returning the this.
We are also returning it by reference so that someone can start to do further operation with it.
So far so good.
But what I would like now to provide the boost to fix it also should be plus plus.
So how to differentiate that.
C++ asks you to add for the boost to fix the Virgin attempt to integrate.
It will not be used just to differentiate the two syntax because as you know, we cannot have two functions
of the same name.
So this is just a temporary extra variable that we are going to use.
Now, the Mr. Fix is also more tricky when it comes to implementation.
Remember, we need to have the we need first to have the object to be returned, then increment it.
If I have S X plus plus we need to present the X, then we need to incremented to do that here in our
class.
We are going to take a copy first from the object, OK, and then we are going to return to this data
and in between we are going to increment it.
So this incrementing is having to the internal internal cost, but the return of that is going to be
presented is the one that is covid Noticia.
Do not return.
It is by reference because Cober here is a temporary variable, so this would be wrong.
So looking here to the query, we do find X1 with one or two and then we incremented it first, presenting
two and three.
But the other side here of x2 plus plus and we try to bring to it is going to bring to the original
values after it.
If we try to print X is going to be two and the three.
So the moral of that is the prefix operator need reference.
The was the fixed operator does a new reference.
That was the fix we need also to to create an extra parameter.
And the logic should be you make a copy, then you can amend, then you return.
The flow should be very similar to what we are doing here.
If you have probably a lot of logic defined in your plus, you might come here and just the original
vibrator so that you don't have to duplicate code here.
That's it.