And this video will learn how to do operator overloading for the input and output stream things.
Remember the stream insertion, for example?
Operator, we can define integrated.
This is very OK.
But surprisingly, we notice also that we can read the C++ history, the class.
So how did the C++ string class did that?
They are also bruta overruling that insertion operator.
This should be greater than greater than less than that.
Now what?
What about us?
We would like to define our own insertion operator here to read into what you know so far is enough
for you to do this by yourself.
Try to see an X if you managed to do it, try to send X Y and try to do it if you can.
Let's think together here in the next slide.
Let's think about it.
We would like to to use C an X now thinking about that, there are two ways to implement things either
at the member function or as a non-member function.
This is not to the member function.
If you thought about it.
We have two objects here sitting on the left X on the right.
Now, if we would like to implement this on the on the as a member function, we need to go to the class
of C in which is the stream and inside it defined this operator, the taking X parameter.
Now this is weird.
We will now.
Now this is weird because the the C in the class I stay stream class excludes the class.
We cannot adjust it this way.
So you cannot do this logic because C++ will not allow you.
OK, let's do more practical.
Let's define it as a member function, non-member function.
Now we can define it just as the first object, the extreme and the second object in the X.
This is fair enough.
So here is how we are going to do it.
You are defining an operator greater than greater than for reading.
You give it the object from type C in which is I remembered, and the object of type beer.
Then you do the normal reading for m b as to variable and set them together.
Now we have here Meyerbeer X and Y, we are in X and then we are renting.
Get one concern here.
What if I would like to read X and why this would not work.
Give yourself a minute to think about it.
The reason that this will not work is C an X is by itself a function call.
It's going to be replaced by the return of the greater the return is here void.
So it's now become void greater than greater than y it will not work.
What if I would like to read another number?
We would like this thing greater than greater than X to be replaced with again C and so we are going
to we need to return it this way.
When you take the extreme, you return it again.
Now saying X is resolved here within the return with the ice cream again, which is the end.
So now it becomes in Y, so an X in Y is now C in what if you have X, Y, Z it would be X, Y, Z,
then why is it Vincey in that.
So the return of the object is what helped us.
If you would like to avoid this ugly that said first, the second you can just define it as a friend
function.
So if I needed a friend to function and you just use it.
So now everything is perfect in reading, you see how we managed to use that to the extensibility using
the non-member function?
We cannot do that.
We cannot read this way using a member function site in a similar way.
We can define also the S function here.
So the S is it's a very similar logic.
But notice here we will here in the C out.
This is optional but is good.
If you are renting, you have no need to change the variable.
Yeah, that's it.