In this section, we will introduce the template, which is one of the functionalities in C++, it has
two types function templates and class templates .
So let's introduce the problem that encouraged the idea of the templates,
if you are looking to this function here, Max of A and B, it's just normal function that is .... A
and B, now
if I tried to call this function with only double values, I'm going to load the precision so the
standard way to handle this way is to duplicate this code as it is here and  just replace the two types
with Max and use it.
Now, let's say you would like to use more data types, let's say would like to get the max between
two characters and so on.
You have to keep making duplicates and duplicates duplicates of code,
but observe that they are exactly the same logic, regard data type here, regardless of its
double or integer or character or whatever, it is just exactly the same logic,
imagine for a while that we discovered a bug in this function, or that we found that there is a faster
implementation than it, we have to go for every one of our duplicate functions and just take it and
make a modification for it.
When it comes to duplication in the code, in the software engineering, we .... a lot that something
is wrong.
Now templates come to help us to solve this problem as following, the compiler would read
something like that,
I'm defining here some function that I'm naming here "MyMax",
imagine for a while that we have some structure that of name "Type" and we have type A and type B,
now when the C++ see this word "template type name type" it means that this function will be
called with some types
it could be integer, it could be double, it could be whatever,
and they all actually share the same logic, they share the same logic,
So instead of the user making the copy-paste by himself, the compiler will do the copy-paste by
himself.
For example, let's see here, MayMax of two and five,
so Memex is a function that is expect a generic data type from the word template,
you can you can think of it like a general guidelining,
it isn't something specific,
it will not exist in our final code,
it's just a way to help a generic code,
when we say a generic code, we mean it is it's a good that works like in general, regardless
of the of the internal details.
So here the combiner see my max of two and five and know that this is template function, so now I'm
telling here, hey, you know what we can call this function with two and five.
So now we type in reality in runtime would be resolved to integer and integer,
now, you can imagine this function exactly in runtime like this function with two integrate and returning
for an integer.
OK, so what if I would like to force other kind of cases?
The C++ allow you to use this notation,
if you did here , you are telling the compiler, hey, I want you
prepare for me this function, but using int,
so it's going to replace this type with int and this type with int and this type with int and this type with int,
now we are sending the max between two and five,
here it is again, five.
So what was the difference between line nine 15 and line 16? in line 15 you are using two integers,
so the compiler guess that you probably won't....
a copy of this function with type is integral in line 17,
we say, hey, I wanna this function to be with type double,
so when we hit, the compiler is going to generate a copy for you with the word,
type is replaced with a double, double and double,
so the moral of that is as following,
instead of you are doing the copy-paste by yourself and keeping integer, integer, integer, double
double, double, character, character, character, the compiler will do the copy-paste for you,
so it's actually in the competition time,
this is happening for you here in line 18 who are defining Memex or between character E and character
X..
So in reality, character type would be replaced with a character, character and character.
OK, let's keep going more.
What if I say here and to any memex of two and five point four, this would give a compilation error
y because the compiler now see an integer here and double it would be confused should they generate
for you function with type as integer or type as double.
This is confusing so it will not work when the other side I can generate function with integer.
I'm here more specific.
Now think about that.
Imagine that we have a function with integer integrity or if you are sending two to eight, it will
be two.
If you are sending five point four to B, which is no integer, it would be five.
So the Mexia between two and five point four would be five.
That's five point four on the other side.
If I tell him, hey, you generate a copy for me was the word, the type is replaced with that I double
it would be two point five, four is going to be five for one more trickier.
What if I have a structure that's named E and B and I said my maxcy between A and B of type Embley,
this would generate a composition error.
We don't know how to compare to Embley is using the greater that.
So it will tell you, hey, I don't know how to do this operation if I try to make a copy of this function.
So to understand it, imagine that we took this function could be built and replaced every time with
the word complete.
Can the compiler combine this could.
No, it cannot.
So the generation different types of the function memex are going to be generated by time.
OK, so on the use cases that the used, for example, if you could use the in our previous case we
have an integer and we have a double and we have a character.
So there were three use cases here.
This function was going to be replaced with three functions.
One that is intent n maximum, double, double, double my character, character, character.
Another another observation here.
I didn't use the function name as Max.
I use it as my Max.
Why?
Because the C++ already defined the max function as a template.
So I'm now defining something exactly as it's doing.
So this is what is going to give a competition.
Please try to replace the function with Max and see what's going to happen in practice.
It sometimes is really very hard and really complicated, but the worst is the error.
Messages of of templates are typically very hard and ugly to understand.
Try to generate mistakes and see some of these messages.
Let's go one more step.
We have the function so that we expect for the first parameter to be of a type and of the second parameter
to be of another type and is going to return to something of the type of the first function, for example,
of this function.
Take an integer here and double here is going to do so mission and return as a result in R, which will
be type of integer.
Let's see the examples here.
The model of this example.
You can define more than a variable.
We say here template that.
One came across that two with the second with the finitude as type name and now as a class, what is
different?
Nothing.
I'm just showing you more Sirtex.
You can use the the class and you can use the word to type name.
I'm here saying that this template function might well receive two different types.
So here I'm saying some one in 10.
And this is going to be guess that the compiler will know that type one is integer and type 10 a type
two is just what some of them to 11.
On the other side, I'm sending here one and then Tenebrae five.
So type one would be integer, type two will build will be double.
Now, when you add one last ten point five, it's going to be eleven point five.
But wait, the return here is of type one, which is integer.
So we are returning eleven point five as an integer.
The result would be integer on the other side.
If I book both of them as double, they would be some return as.
Now here if I, I said that the first one as double and the second as integer.
So now the submission would be eleven point two and we return as double.
So to return it as a different way to it for the same function call I said, hey, you know what, I
will know you for the first time.
First, the type to be integer and the second one to be integer.
Now one point to do is costly.
To integrate.
To be one one blastin is 11.
Aldy It is more fun.
Syntex If you say if you send a and the one eight is going to be type one character and B will be one.
So the submission of them is sixty six.
If you are returning here from this one it would be costly to character.
So it would return to the variable, the character B but if you did one and eight then that one would
be integer and E will be, you will be a character.
You sum them, it would be sixty six but you return as integer so it's going to be sixty six.
OK, this function is Bloss and remember that the string giclas we can concatenate strings if I have
string Mustafa and strings out and I can connect them, I can concatenate them so it doesn't have to
work on all integers.
So aligned to any.
I'm seeing some string of ayam space with the string stuff.
The question here, can the function, can the compiler take a copy of this function and create it of
two strings.
The answer is yes.
So it's going to add them in print.
I am spaceball.
Stuff like 19 is going to come by there.
The difference between line nineteen aligned to any line nineteen here is used is using a character
pointer, but this one is using a clause.
The question here is it a plus defined character array?
The answer is no is defined only on a string the clause.
We'll know more about that in the future.
The the static variable.
One interesting thing here, if you define a static variable inside the template function, every Turnblad
function is going to be have it's a static variable y because it if we have your increment to me was
integer and incremental, we was to for I would like you to understand in reality the compiler would
take this function, make two copies out of it, one of them for integer, one of them for a double.
So in reality there is one I would integrate religion and another set integral I with the double version.
So if you tried here to make a static goals and this is a global variable, the static ones would be
one, two, three and again, one, two, three.
But the global is going to be incremented.
OK, one more thing.
What we call function Turnblad specialisation.
The question here is what if I would like the function to be working the same for every type except
the specific data type?
Let's let's let's take an example here.
Let's think about the ADD function.
If I'm adding here, it must be like the sum that we just were doing.
It works well for integers.
It works well for some.
Everyone is happy.
Now let's think about multiply function I have here multiply function that multiply.
The first one was an integer.
So we are sending where we want one type only class D and we have a factor.
This is going to equal was integer is going to was double was collected everything.
But it will fail four characters for Estrich.
Let's say I have interest to apply for Estrich in a specific way and we know that this good will combine
if it just is a string.
So the way to that is to say, hey, you know what, I would like this multiply to be for every little
type except specifically to type.
So the syntax to specify something is as follows.
You write the word the template, but you do write at a time here and then you write your will function
as you would write it in the normal case, which is a function that would multiply a string.
Yes, there was some factor and return to string.
This is the same as that.
But we just thought everything was a string.
I'm sitting here, you know what, for the case of string, I'm going to handle it in a different way,
which is urologic.
And my guess here, I iterated the number of factors and concatenated there is so.
Give the word Mustafa three, it will concubinage Mustafa three times, this is my version logic, one
might say.
You know what?
I want a specific logic for David also.
Then he was going to double multiply, double something and factor.
So the moral of that is if in case you would like to have a specific handballing for a specific data
type, you are going to use the template specialization in mean we can hear.
Normally you just keep calling the add and multiply in a normal way here in the add, in the interior
and the string.
This one would be good here in the interior, this one would be cool.
But this one here in string, this one would be good.
That's it.