In a similar way to the functions, Templates are almost the same logic. Llet's say we have a struct
like the hospital queue. Remember, we needed a queue of integers and another queue of strings
and so on, Thinking about the code of the struct: its code is just copy-paste.
What happened?
You just replace integer with string,
Replace string with double to get a queue of double.
That's it, The same everywhere. The class templates come again so that the compiler in the compilation time is
going to generates several copies of your struct, Just as much as you used it.
If I used a template class of integer and another with double, it is going to generate two versions.
one of integer and one of double for you.
So here is how the
queue class is going to be implemented in
the class templates. You first like the function, you come here and find the template type name T
...
This  means this class is going to be a template, is going to be copy-paste versions
for it and the compliation time
and the type is T. Nowhere, Instead you define  integer array of hundred, we define it as T array of
hundred.
The function here is expecting for example in the parameter here an array to copy from it.
which type is going to be an integer.
You cannot put just integer, it is going to be of type T,
So the compiler will know that this is T. Also when you add an element, you wil know it of type T, Ok!. What if i have
a function that might need different data types, you can still have functions of different types.
So deal with the types as just you are giving more types as much as you need.
So this is a global class.
We are going to use T, we can define more than one here and this one is specific for the function.
Now here I'm defining a queue of type string.
Remember the less than and greater than. (should be rare) This is important here
as difference in syntax.
When you say my queue of type string, it means please make a copy from this class but use it as string
and here I'm saying my queue of type Integer so I'm using it. When I come here to add front add front you
can add only strings and you can print them.
You can also add here integer and integer.
Now I wanted to call the function double here at the sum and add.
and I can use the type, it has to be one element only and just applied here.
So the same logic
exactly.
Nothing new.
There is something also extra when it comes to the classes, what we call the non type parameters for templates.
when you look to the array size here in the previous one, it was const, fixed.
What if I would like to instantiate the different, not instantiate, to generate in compliation time different versions
but with different sizes for a reason and another?
You can come here and add here in the template, coma, integer size, and then use the size inside it.
Now in the code here, you say my queue, integer, coma 12.
It means that the queue of type integer and the size variable is going to be a size.
Notice that this variable has to be constant.
Why?
Because the compiler is going to generate array here of type size, which have to be generated
on the completion time.
So if the variable would be known in the runtime, the compiler is going to generate code
before the runtime.
So it have to be a const value.
The typical usage for such an addition is when you are defining some constants and arrays sizes.
That's it.
Remember, we talked about the function specialization. In class
There is also something very similar. I don't want to dig behind its details, but in class, if you
if you also have some generic, say, a class game that has a specific behavior and then another class,
another case for only string, you come here and define here the less than greater than
and then you add here the type here you added after the struct name and this
way for the generic case, this one would be used as a generic solution for this specific case,
This one is going to be used as a specific version.
So remember two things, you do here directly the less than the greater than and here you put the specific
data type.
It worth mentioning about the difference between overloading and templates.
Remember here in templates, we have an identical syntax that we keep copy paste for different data types.
That's it.
In function overloading, the function name is identical.
It has different parameters and it has different behavior.
So while the complier see different function names,
It just see different parameters and different like behaviors. In any case you needed to think about that.
That's it.