The variadic template is one of the very nice features of C++. Let's motivate that. So far in our functions,
We typically used a fixed number of parameters.
For example, If you have a function like sum, it's receiving, It has two parameters A and B, So it's
just maximum receiving two arguments, One value for A and one value for B.
Now, What if I would like to go something like 2, 5, 6, 7, 9, Which is passing five arguments.
This would not work. In modern C++,
We can use at least two mechanisms to allow a variable number of arguments and we can use the initializer
list in C++,
but our two cases are more about today, The C++11 variadic template, Which typically needs a couple of functions to be
implemented. In C++ 17, There is a simpler mechanism named fold expression, Which is simpler
for a specific 32 binary operators as we will you know in the next sessions. Let's motivate this more.
The word variadic is common in several programming languages.
It mainly when we say the parameter is a variadic parameter, It means it accepts zero or more values.
So typically, If the function has one of these parameters, It typically has at most one of the parameters
that are variadic and typically its the right most parameter.
You will always note as using these three periods (...), Which is the ellipsis syntax to indicate that this
is a variadic parameter and again a variadic parameter this time is expecting a single value like with it.
It's accepting zero or more values. Before C++ 11, There was also what's named in C++ as variadic
functions
and they are functions that take a variable number of arguments.
The printf function,
If you tried to open its syntax, You will notice these three dots.
It's a old style and it is unsafe.
Now, the variadic template is a new thing in C++ 11,  modern and safe way to do that.
Let's get a little about the basics of it.
So here is we are defining a function named hello.
It has here something called some args, some name for us and have also a name here args and it has
three dots.
If you try to inspect some args, You will notice it's a template type but it also has here this prefix
of three dots. This some args we call it a template parameter pack.
I think of it like a bunch of things together and this is not a data type, It is a template parameter
pack, Pack of a bunch of values, And the args itself is what we call a function parameter
pack. Now, When you try to call, let's go here to the main.
If you tried to call the function hello with four arguments, 1, 2, 3, 4 am, I'm here using
the size of operator size of also dot, dot, dot.
args, it is going to show you that the size is four.
It means that this variadic argument received four different values.
If you pass hello, Mustafa, 5, 2.5, Which are three arguments and of different
data types, You will notice that this size is three.
If you passed the c character single character, It will be the size of one.
If you passed something that is very empty, it will be zero.
I'm using here something called pretty function which is printing a fine name for this function.
I do not think this is redundant.
It is more of the GCC.
If you are using the Microsoft visual compiler, It will not probably work.
So you see here, In this case, It's showing you that the arguments that we received are four integers
here
arguments that we received are character pointer, an integer
and double. So again going back to this new syntax style that we call the parameter pack, This guy
is expecting zero like here or more arguments and they are all stored in this args thing and throw its size
If you can know about the number of arguments that we received.
Please make sure that your eyes are very familiar with this new syntax and this use of three
dots.
So one more time, The sum args here is a template parameter pack, It's an indicator that we are
going to receive a bunch of items together and in a very flexible way.
Let's go one more step to indicate something, I am here having a function, It has two normal parameters
integer A and a string name.
And you see it has here the template parameter pack on the most right parameter.
OK!, Then when you call here,
Hello, one,
and belal, the value one is matching A so A is one.
The value belal is matching the name and then there is nothing to send it to args.
So the size of args here is zero.
In another case, If you are sending one, belal, 2.5, 1 is with A, belal is with name and the
args is 2.5 only,
So the size is one, Here the size would be two.
That's why you typically have at most one parameter Pack and you typically have it in the most right
parameter.
Now, let's send this.
We have a function
that takes a single integer and the remaining of the args, If you sent from 1 to 5, A is 1 and the
remaining of 2, 3, 4, 5 is with args.
If you sent 2, 3, 4, 5, A is 2,
and the remaining 3, 4, 5, if you sent 3, 4, 5, A is 3 and the args is 4,
5. If you understood this logic, You can think for a while about how we could really make use of this
args because we cannot print it directly.
How can we make use of it?
It seems like we need to use some, some recursive style to be able to use the args, This is something like we
pass 1 to here and then the args are from 2 to 5, Then we pass args again to the function, then 2
is A and so on.
Let's try to review something about recursion before we proceed more.
We did this exercise before.
If you have an array of 5 numbers and you would like to sum its values in a recursive way.
So one way here I'm sending the sum array and sending the array and the current length, Which is 5.
I'm saying if the length is zero, Which is a base case, We are returning zero.
Otherwise, I'm taking the last element of the array plus the array
but with a length value minus 1. Thinking about that, I hope you understand it.
I remember refreshing from the recursion. The array here has a very close relationship with the args, It is
very dynamic but we have explicitly the length. We would like to do something like that with the variadic
template to be able to use it to do operations for us.
So here we would like to define a function sum that take a variable number of arguments and return
to the sum.
So sum 1, 2, 3, 4 is returning
3, 4, 7, 9, 10.
So here what's going to happen.
We are calling sum from 1 to 4.
The function is going to take A with 1 and the args is going to be the remaining, which is 2,
3, 4.
Now, I would like to make a bigger sum, so I'm going to recursively call the function sum with the
remaining args, which are now 2, 3, 4.
So we are calling sum 2, 3, 4. Again, 2 would be assigned to the value of A and args
would have the value of 3 and 4. we are adding the value of 2 plus the return from sending these
two values only 3, 4.
So again, 3 would be A and the answer would be 4, Recursively call with 4.
So 4 is going to be A and args is going to be empty.
Now, When you call sum with empty, This function is expecting a single integer at least.
So this would be a compilation error.
That's why we have a base case function
for us that has nothing.
If you tried to inspect the values, It's kind of generated like 1 plus 2 plus the return from here
3, 4. As if we are expanding from the right to the one in the right.
This recursion here is more of the left side, But here we are expanding more in the right direction.
The variadic template is typically two functions.
One of them, The your function with an args parameter and another without the args parameter to be
able to use it recursively,
and we typically code the variadic template in a recursive way.
Now let's try to make our function more generic.
So we are going to use a another kind of templates here.
We are going to template the variable a.
So A will be of type T now and this function now  need to call this sum function here but we will
at some point, we are going to call the base class here,
So we need to cast the function here using the template parameter, We need to instantiate something using based
on the used T. That's why you are adding T here.
So this sum is taking variable type a and then some of T is recursively calling this guy, this
guy, Then calling the base case with some of T.
Now let's use it here.
It's small generic now.
1, 2, 3, 4,
give us 10,  Bunch of double numbers
give 2.6. Notice here,
I removed this 0.2 , and shifted it here to the 4.
So the submission should be again 10.6 but it is just 10.
Stop the video for one minute and think while.
The reason is when we send the function sum with this bunch of numbers, The first number is an integer.
So the template T here will be an integer.
The consecutive calls here would be of type integer.
That's why it's going to be an integer
but if we would like to force it to be all of double, We just instantiated from the beginning of double, So
it doesn't have to deduce the type of the first parameter.
This how we made it more generic.
Let's see how variadic can be very powerful when you not only have a variable number of arguments,
You can even have them of different types.
So here I am defining a function to print 1, 2, 3, 4, four integers would be printed with
comma separated.
Here I have another list but with a bunch of different data types.
So the idea here, again, I'm defining two functions.
One of them is empty and the second one has here the first element to much of the first element and
adds to much of the remaining list.
Now would like to print it, comma-separated but we don't want to print a comma after the
last number.
So I'm taking the size of the current list, Which initially would be 3, then 2, then 1
and say if this isn't the last element, Print a comma here and then recursively print values.
So we are printing the current and then printing the remaining one on the right side.
As with any printing function, It doesn't make sense to allow the parameters to be changed.
So I'm adding here also const and I'm adding here also
const.
So far so good
end C++11. Now C++ 14 allows even you to get rid of the template parameter pack here, dot, dot, dot args  and you can
make it more similar and just use the auto parameter here.
That's all about the variadic template, The coding of variadic template
is very standard
as you see a couple of functions.
You typically take the first parameter, then the remaining with recursion, and that's on, Nothing
more.
Like any template-something, Remember, The templates are generated in the completion time, So the code
has some mechanism behind the scene to read your template and then instantiate all the needed examples
before you even run.
And sadly, You are going to face a bunch of ugly compilation errors,
If you have some mistakes, that's it.