In C++ 17, The fold expression cames to make the variadic template easier for specific binary operators
As you remember, We were doing the sum function in the variadic template, Remember
the binary operator class is a binary operator so needs two operands.
So for a specific 32 operators, The fold expression comes to make our life much simpler.
Similar to the variadic template.
The coding of the fold expression is very systematic.
The language recognizes for different cases what we call unary fold and binary fold
and every one of them is like right and left.
We will see that it's very systematic.
Remember if you wrote 1, 2, 3 + 2 + 3: In C++, that's OK
but if you have something like plus 1, 2, 3 or 1, 2, 3 plus here, it's going to
fail to compile
and this is the reason why we have the left and right folding, as we will see right now.
So let's go directly to what we call the right unary fold. The function
now to sum a bunch of numbers becomes as simple as this weird syntax that you see. Args plus dot, dot, dot and
that's it, The ellipses.
The function eventually is done, The code is done.
So now we would like to see really like what kind of magic is happening here and what what is this fold
word means.
So remember, This is a template parameter pack and this is its function argument and we can use the
size of it to get 4. What's happening in the fold expression is we are going to again as a template,
The template is going to take your template function and generate its answer.
This function is going to be expanded as eventually 1 plus 2, plus 3 plus 4.
...
But how to do this expansion?
Think as following: this args,
Think of it as the first element of the numbers that you received,
So we received 1, 2, 3, 4 from here then args now correspond only to 1 and the three
dots correspond to the remaining.
So now initially we will have that as a compile-time generation.
We have here the one plus dot, dot dot.
Now go and take this dot, dot, dot and replace it with again the expression args plus dot, dot, dot.
So when you replace it again, The args will be the first element of the new parameter, which is 2 plus dot, dot, dot.
Take the dot, the dot, and replace it again with the same expression that we have here.
It will be again, args is going to match the first element here, 3 plus dot, dot, dot.
Now, We have only one element remaining, Which will be configured out as 4.
So eventually this expression, which you have to write parameters and then args plus something,
Plus here as we would like to do a submission function later, It can be an asterisk, It can be division
but your expression has to be together with the args and the dot, dot, dot with some operator in the middle.
You cannot use args directly.
You cannot say here: Hey, cout args and that's it.
You have to use both of them together because the compiler see them and go to expand them as exactly
I did with you. This expression mathematically would eventually be one parameter,
Then 1 plus another parameter, 2 plus another parameter, 3 plus, Then 4
and that's it.
Now for the case of sending one variable and no variable, it's a bit tricky to know how the compiler
is exactly generating that.
But I would like you to know if you submitted only a single value for this case, The compiler
is going to resolve this only to 1 and just to drop the dot, dot, dot because there are no more parameters.
However, If you sent an empty value here, The compiler will not be able to guess the first value
and then it would be like something plus like it would be like a weird expression.
So it's going to generate the compilation error.
The moral of that is if in this case, You sent an empty parameter, It will compile an error.
If you sent to one value only, It would be only the args value.
If you sent more than one value, It's going to be expended this way.
And again, If you would like to trace how this expansion is going to happen? assign this value to
the first value, Assign args to the first value and expand recursively these three dots with the same expression
over and over again.
Now, This takes us to what we call instead of unary
right, Its called
binary right. The whole difference between binary right ( and unary right ), Go to the right of the dot, dot, dot, and put now
here plus some added value that makes your semantic correct.
If I would like to add a bunch of numbers, I can always add plus so that the whole submission
doesn't change.
So if we added here the plus zero, The only thing that we got is if we are passing an empty list,
It will be like plus zero here and
It will make the compilation in generation time works.
If you are confused about that, Like how really the generation behind the scene works.
This isn't our business
like we don't like to annoy ourselves exactly how the algorithm behind the scene is generating the expression?
What I would like you to know is if you are using an empty case, You need to add an extra element
here so that the submission doesn't end like 1 plus 2 plus 3 plus with nothing else, It might
end up with like plus nothing.
So with a plus zero here is going to end up with just zero, With one item is going to be like one plus zero.
This is the 1 plus 0.
This is the only new update that's going to happen here.
Now, You can call the function with empty list and it works.
The more of what I'm saying that the difference between the unary right fold and binary right fold is the binary
right fold allows you to have a case of empty list.
This is the reason why we have this binary right fold and it's more due to the the way that the compile
is generating the syntax and generating the code behind the scene. In a very similar way
There is what we call the left fold.
So the left has now the dot, dot, dot on the left side.
So that generation is going to be expanding from the left side and the left side, If you try to do the expansion
step by step as I was doing, You will notice that the 1, 2, 3, 4 is expanded like a brace
1 plus 2 plus a brace plus 4 and in a very similar way,
The binary left fold is going to has the zero from the right, The dot, dot, dot here and again expanding
from the right to the left this way.
So we have here now two things:
We have here left and right
and we have unary and binary.
The reason behind unary and binary is all about allowing an empty list, That's it.
But left and right is more about the direction you are expanding the list.
So the C++ 17 is giving us a more choices that fit with our domain.
So these are the four cases that we were referring to it.
Make sure that you understand how the expansion of every one of them is going to expand your list.
In a very similar way,
If you would like to support the multiplication, You now would replace the
plus with multiplication.
Now, Thinking about the multiplication, What could be initial good value for multiplication to
allow a list of a single element?  You know that you need times 1 because any number of
times one is just it's self.
...
So this is a good value.
As you see the initial value that you are going to provide to the binary case depend on more the nature
of the operator that you are going to use it.
Also similar to the variadic template, We can remove the variadic parameter pack here and just use
the auto for simpler.
code.
Over all these are the four cases that we have
and I would like you to you read this expression
expansions like to know if we are using this expression, This is how it's going to be expanded it and
so on. Op here is the operator.
So read it and make sure that you at least understand my my code expansion ways or at least understand
this ones or matching them together.
These are the thirty two operators that allowed
With the fold expression and a binary fold when it comes to using the extra folding here, You
have to have it in both operators, You cannot be here  asterisk
and then here plus. It have to be the same type.
As your turn, I would like you to do that division function and check out if the left fold is
same as right fold or not. That's it.