Let's continue the fold expression. So here is the division that I asked you to develop it.
It could wise let's develop just here the right case and the left the case.
If you tried to print the output of that, You will notice the answer isn't in the same way.
And the reason behind that is the order of the operation in the division would matter a lot comparing
in contrast to the multiplication and addition.
So if we send here 1, 2, 3, 4, The expression is going to be generated with
parameters in this order, Which mathematically is like 1 over 2 over 3 or 4.
So this the value.
Now, If you are doing the right expansion, The expression is like 1 over all of that term and to over
all of that term and so on.
So this is going to be this value.
And now here is the risk of using integer operators.
If you used the integer operator with the division left, It is going to end up with zero because the 3
over 4 is going to be ...
The left expansion is going to be starting with 1 over 2, which is zero
So the whole term would end up with zero
but if you did the right expression, It eventually would divide over 3 by 4, Which is zero
So you would end up with a runtime error.
So you have to be careful about the left and right and you have to think about the semantics of your
operator.
Another interesting thing is you can so far we're using the args in a very direct way
and we always say think of on args as the first element.
So given that is just practically speaking will be generated as the first element, We can even pass
some function here or functor or even later lambda function and just apply it so you
don't need even to use just args,
You can use some functions over args.
You can use some more complicated sometimes expression over args but put some parameters around it.
So here I have some functions to square and I am passing the square function,
So the square function is going to be the first element here and then it's going to be applied to the
first element and then the second element then the third element and so on.
So we can also pass a function to use it.
And this is typically how we can make complicated things with the fold expression.
There is one remaining concern is we said that there is a need for the binary folding to allow to handle
the case of the one of empty list, Right?
There are three operators that doesn't need the asterisk.
As a result, there is no binary folding for them, Which are the AND-AND, and OR-OR, and the comma.
OK!. So you can use the AND-AND this way and you can even send an empty list for all of them.
Remember, For an expression to be all of it true, You need everything to be true.
That's why by default it will be ended with a one.
So the default value for an empty expression would be one. On the other side, The OR's the default expression
is going to be zero.
Otherwise, it's just ANDING
or ORING for what exists and you'd need to care about the initial value.
The remaining one, Which is more tricker is the comma. Recall
the comma operator evaluates from left to right and also as you know it returns the value...
of the last expression.
We don't care about that for now.
So generally speaking, If you have to do a bunch of things to be evaluated from left to right or in
a sequential way, You need then the comma operator.
Let's here refresh
the comma operator with a vector here. I have a vector of integer V, I normally push 1 and push 2.
That's OK.
I can also push 3, 4, 5 with 3 comma.
This is totally OK.
Now, We know with the fold expression, There are a lot of parameters around things.
So what about parameters here?
Very normally, Simply going from left to right, These parameters don't affect our overall expression in a left
to right
ordering
for going to do it this way for example.
Now, I would like you to think about how can we develop a fold expression that allows pushing numbers
in a variable way like I'm doing here, So think about how to use the comma operator to do that.
Give yourself like a five minutes.
It is how we can do that. As simple as we are going to use the co mma operator, not the plus, not the
minus, not multiplication.
We're going to use the comma, Which is going to evaluate the first element, then the second element.
And here: In the first element, We can use args, We can use a function of args.
We can use an expression like V-dot-push-back-args. Remember, In the generation time args is actually
just the first number.
So practically speaking, How is that generated in the first number?
It would be like V-dot-push-back 10, then comma,
three dots. Three dots would be expanded again to open brace, V-dot-push-back 20, comma, three dots
close the braces and three dots would be expanded again to V-dot-push-back 30.
So eventually this is like V-dot-push-back 10, 20, 30, That's all.
I would like also to take the chance and tell you that you can pass the arguments that got the
parameter pack.
So I'm here having a function that says pass-pack, It is taking the vector and the parameter pack, I'm passing
it to another function so you can take the args and pass it to another function.
but notice the syntax here is a bit weird.
The three dots are after the args parameter, OK?
And in a similar way, You can say you would like to print a bunch of numbers using the fold
expression.
You can print them in a very similar logic using the comma operator.
That's it.