In this video, we will learn about the debugger, which is a very strong tool that helps us figuring
out the problems that happen in our code. a software bug is an error or failure or fault or whatever that
happened in your program.
It happens for a lot of reasons if you tried to access an invalid index of an array, that's a bug. If you divided
by the zero, if you used the variable that was uninitialized, maybe memory leaks, infinite loops and,
so on.
A lot of reasons.
And even sometimes the logic of your idea itself is wrong.
Let's say someone would like to check if the number is odd or not, and he said if N mod 2 equal-equal
1, looks so good code,
but what if the N is a negative number?
If N is negative number in the mod 2 will be negative one not
just one.
So you need a better condition than that.
Sometimes we do implementation
bug like that.
Sometimes the logic of the idea itself is buggy.
So there are a lot of bugs that we introduce in our code, and it really would take a lot of time from
you to minimize the bugs in your code.
You need to follow the coding guidelines that your team is using, like I remember referring to, for example,
Google style in coding guidelines.
You need to validate the input that you are using.
You need to have a good habit of initializing things.
You need to write your code in a modular way where your small functions or classes are handling things.
You need to do a lot of testing for your code.
One of the very common mistakes that guys do a lot of copy-paste for their code or maybe from stack overflow website
or whatever, and they don't read the code, they just do copy-paste, and then they end up with a lot of
bugs.
Give you a read for that.
Sometimes when the operating system has something wrong with the task, it's going to force some
, maybe some stopping for it, and send what we call signals.
This is a very minor topic.
I don't want to go into the details, but I would like you to read it for a future reading just
to be familiar with that. So the operating system can stop a task and send some signals,
and C++ allows you to register some actions for this signal.
So, for example, you define here whatever function, and you register this signal, if it
happened from the operating system, called this function. It acts as a logger for you,
for example, you can log that your program received a specific signal, anyway,
skip it for now.
Just wanted you to know that there are signals that come from the operating system and we can have
some final handling for them in the program.
Let's back to our topic,
the debugging. Debugging means to find a bug.
There are two approaches that we use to find bugs.
The first one is what you were doing through the course, what we call the printing approach,
and this is as simple as you print statements where you suspect something is wrong,
and although it seems like a naive way of debugging, however, it's still a very strong one,
and even in big companies like Google and Facebook, the project might be very, very, very big,
and probably printing is the only way to to find a bug.
So sometimes it is useful.
There's also a relevant topic, what we call loggers.
The loggers is something that just log several kinds of information like information, mistakes,
and so on.
It helps us because in reality, when the system fails, the first thing we do is to go to the logging
documents and see what kind of logging statements happened in the program during running
to find the bug.
Anyway, this is a printing approach and you already did a lot of that.
The other approach is the debugger approach, and this one is a tool called Debugger that helps you to
trace your code line by line.
You probably also did this tracing by yourself, looking at the code and guessing what is in this
variable and so on.
So the debugger does that for you, which is very powerful and very useful in small and medium projects.
There is something that we call the debug symbols. We learned that the compiler generates two
simple tables,
remember, for the linker later. A debug symbols is another extra kind of symbols that we embed in these
tables.
The purpose of that is the debugger will use this information so that it gives you a line by line tracing
for your code. So the whole purpose of this debug symbols is: just to be able to see the code line by line during
tracing.
And this takes us to something interesting that the debug mode and the release mode.
Remember, when we're installing our program,
we had something called debug option and release option in code blocks
and in eclipse. The major difference between both of them is: the debug mode is storing the debug
symbols, but the release mode doesn't store them.
The release mode is, in this case, cannot be used with the debugger,
and usually, this is what we use in the production itself.
The debug mode is compiled with the debug symbols, and we use it with the debugger.
There are a few things to know about it.
The generated files is usually bigger than the release files.
So, for example, if you have an executable from the release and an executable from the debug, the executable
from the debug would be much bigger than the executable from the release, and the execution time from the
debugger is bigger than the execution time of the release.
That's why the debug mode files are for the development and bugs inspection,
but the release mode is for the production,
but here is what is much more important than that.
Sometimes the behavior of the debug mode isn't the same as the behavior of the release mode,
and this is very tricky.
And you will find a lot of guys, especially in programming competitions, who complain that
the program is working on their machine but doesn't work on the server or doesn't work in reality or
production in the same way.
This is because there is some difference between them,
for example, sometimes the illegal memory access may work in the debug mode, but fails in the release
mode,
and as you see, the program is working well.
You think
that everything is OK, but you have some plus one extra access or minus one extra access that will
fail in the release mode.
Another very tricky case, especially for financing guys, the debugging when we have double values,
there is intermediate is storing for the double values that will cause some position loss, which will
make your numbers in the debugging a bit different from your numbers in the real release.
So anyway, I wanted you to know there is a difference in the behaviour and the release mode is what we use
really in the production,
by the way, the word production means that we use it with the actual customers.
This is what we give to the customers to use, and we need to make our testing in the release mode, not
in the debug mood.
The debugger is eventually a program, so there will be several ones with different capabilities.
The GNU debugger which I'm going to use in the course is a gdb one.
There is also the Microsoft visual debugger, which is a very nice one, at least comparing with
the old gdb version.
The Microsoft visual debugger is very strong. In a similar way, we can debug from the IDE, or we can debug also from
the terminal normally, and also even in the future,
you know, you can debug locally and even debug remotely.
That's it.
In the next sessions, we will see how to use the IDE to do some debugging.