In this video, you will learn how to use eclipse's debugger to debug, we have here a simple code, two functions,
one of them sum_square, which is just iterate on an array, summing every element, squaring every
element, then sum all of them together. We have also another factorial function and some main here.
Let's first see where are the items in the IDE that are relevant to the debugger.
First, go to the project itself, properties, you can find here in the setting,
Yeah, this debugging is one menu for some options,
but what we care more here is the configuration.
If you notice here, there are two configurations, one for the debug and another for the release.
If you would like to switch off from one to another, you come here and you must click it and you must
set it active.
Just switching it from here to there will not work.
Let's try it. If you put here this as set active, you clicked OK then ok,
you will notice here a new directory named release.
Also there is a compilation error here.
Why? this is a modern C++ syntax.
If you go to the configuration here of miscellaneous, you notice there's no C++ 17 here, but it's
here in the debug one.
So remember, if you configured the debugger, then moved to the release, it will not inherit
the configuration.
You have to write them again by yourself or fix everything to the old configuration from the beginning.
Remember, the debugging only happened in the debug mode, so you need to use the debug mode. If it didn't work
Well, one major reason is that you aren't in the debug mode.
So now let's go back to the debugging mode.
This is mainly the configuration.
I wanted you to check it out here.
Yeah, let's click OK.
So now the code is compiling. The second place of the debugging, which typically we will not
need, is to go to the window preferences here.
There is a debugging menu with a lot of options like - stop on the start-up, which will
stop your program in the first line. You notice here with the GDP program.
If it happens that you change it, then you might need to change it here.
The difference between the window menu and the project menu, the window menu is like for all of the
projects,
but the window menu is more specific for the project. You will typically not need to play with
this one, but in case for advanced changes.
The third position is the configuration of the running.
We used to click this button to run, but we can now click on this bug
symbol to run, or if you have several for configuration, you click it here,
but let's first go to the debug configuration from here.
This is the third place.
You notice the program that we run
is the debug
ztemp
debug is a folder name,
and you notice here is that the debugger also options coming from the global options.
But again, you still don't need them anyway.
Yeah, that's all.
So let's start debugging.
Let's click this guy.
OK, you see here, it didn't work if it happened that this happens with you, I would like you to come
and create what we call a break point.
You come here and double-Click twice.
It will be a blue small point here, now, let's try again.
Now, the debugger started, the first thing you noticed is we went to a different style for the IDE. It's called
a perspective. If you come here to the window, open perspective, you notice there are several kind of perspectives
that we have here,
and this is called the debug perspective.
Yeah, anyway, let's focus now on the debugging itself.
There are a few buttons that are very important for you to know.
The first one is this one, which is resuming to a breakpoint.
A breakpoint is a point in the code where you would like your code to stop at it.
When we put this one,
you see the compiler come to this line.
It means the compiler is here, and this guy can stop the process.
Now, there are other three buttons that are very important for us.
The first one is this guy, which is named Step into, it is F5,
and the other guy is a step over, F6, and there is also step return F7.
What is the difference?
The step over doesn't go in the details of the line.
For example, if the line is for a function, it doesn't go inside the function, it just gives you the
final output of it.
Step_into lets you get inside the function or the class's details. Step_return just gets you out of it.
Let's see how to use that in details.
Let's, for now, go with just step_over, which is F6,
and we will use it a lot.
We have an array, now we are in line 28.
If you go and stopover this arrow, you will start to notice that you can see the content of the
array itself.
You can also come here to the variables to see the current variable, which is an array, you will find
that it has now these three values.
Notice,
this is a function.
If you step into, you go inside the function,
but if we step over like here, we get only directly the result, which is now 29. You notice here 29.
...
One of the things is you can change values on the fly.
So for example, I can here come and say, oh, this was a wrong value.
Let's for now,
fix it to 5.
So now if you come to the result, you will find it now becomes 5.
So the debugger lets you make changes during the execution itself.
Let's change the value of the array.
Again, step over here,
you notice the array value changed. We have here a vector.
If we did step vector v, oh, I did step into.
OK, it's a good
....
lesson, also. If you did step_into, you notice it get you inside
the things of the C++ std itself.
Now, this is a good time to do std step return to get you out of it.
Now, we get back here. Let's again do step_over. Now, there is vector V here, which has also these
three elements, we can push back
another element, you see here, it's now updated.
You can update the factorial's output. Still didn't crash.
, if you click this guy, it just resume and finish the program.
Let's start this process again.
Now, you learned about F6, which is just getting you to step by step.
You can see the values during the execution.
You can change them on the fly.
Now, let's try to get step_into something here.
In this function, we will step inside it.
So step_into, now we jumped inside the square function.
We have the array, we have the length.
Now, here is one of very interesting things. Looking at this,
this is called the stack.
Remember, we learned that there is a stack of function calls. This is the stack of function calls.
If you click here, it shows you that you were in the main function.
So this is the stack of it,
and now we called now another function here.
So the stack now has the sum_square function and it has these variables, once this
function is done, these would be all destroyed.
Now, we are here at line 16.
We can step over this guy, get in the variable.
So now i is zero, the array of i is the array of zero, which will be 2, 2 times 2 will be 4. We can
double-check that X-X now has a value of 4. We keep summing, we can keep going.
What if I would like to just jump directly out of this small code. Let's say
I would like to jump to line 22.
You can come here double click, then this is a big point, and you can click this resume which you will
get you.
What happened?
I'm not sure.
...
Let's put it just here.
Let's start this program again.
Debugger still can give you a hard time. You know, the program started here. If I press this button,
it will jump directly to this line here. You see. So we use breakpoints to make big jumps in the code.
If you know there is a very deep function that has a very specific error in your code, you can directly
put a break point and run your code there.
Let's also see the expressions.
The expression is you can build expression like - let's say here I putt the expression of two times
sum. Sum now stills garbage.
Now it will be zero.
Let's increment it.
You see, the expression is changing,
this isn't a variable in your program,
you are just want to monitor some expressions.
Now, let's say I am done with this function,
I would like to get outside it.
You can come here to step return and just click it,
you get out of the function.
So now we learned about the configuration, about the five options, and you now can see changes
that we were doing in the code.
Let's get a little more further tricks.
Let's say I'm going to make this change.
I'm going to come here and say minus one two zero zero zero zero zero zero zero.
Let's run this program. If we run it,
It's going to crash because we have such an invalid index. One of the best things in the debugger,
It could sometimes get you directly where is the problem.
I'm going to remove this break point.
I'm going to run debug here,
and I'm going to tell it, just go. You see what happened, it jumped directly to where is the problem.
So now,
instead of you keep thinking about where is the problem, I'm writing a lot of printing statement, you can
directly jump to where is the problem in your code.
So this is one of the very nice things about the debugger. It could sometimes cut a lot of your time.
I think we are done with all of the major features,
but I would like to show you one more advanced feature.
You double click on the break point here.
Let's put it here and you right
click, get the break point,
What properties?
Yes, go to
common. This is called conditional break point.
A conditional break point is a break point that has a condition.
So you only go to it if there is a specific condition.
Let's say that you would like to go when sum, let's write that, sum equal-equal 4. You would like to
make a breakpoint, and you want the code to only jump there once the sum is four.
So let's try it.
Let's go.
So now what is the value of sum? 4
This is one of the very nice tricks.
If you know there is a specific condition where the code fails,
you just go to it in a very direct way. I think that's all about the debugger.
Remember that you cannot in the release mode.
You have to have a debugger mode which would typically give you such a directory with such executable.
In some of your cases, when guys try to run the debugger, it might not work eventually.
Sometimes it happens, but keep trying.
Yeah, that's all.