In this session, I would like to show you how debugging with a debugger can help you to understand
the recursive function, give you a better chance of understanding them.
So let's put here a breakpoint in this..., maybe starting from here and this factorial function and let's
run the debugger. So the debugger would go and jump for the factorial in here.
Now, I have called here with a factorial five, so looking to the stack, we have a function at the main
calling the factorial here and the value of N is 5.
The return is still garbage.
Now let's trace it.
We take one step here and it is going to call the factorial function with N with value 4. Now,
What's going to happen is..., try to guess it.
The stack here is going to get another function.
So let's resume. Now,
we are in the factorial function with N equal 4,
and here we have two positions.
We have a factorial at line 10, which is calling now factorial, which is at line 7,
and you notice the stack here N is 5, here
the N is 4. Let's proceed
little more steps. Again, another call.
Let's go to it. Now,
we have a third factorial function.
You can think of every one of them as a separate function.
So now looking here to the value of three,
we can go again,
value of two, again value of one.
Now, so far we have one, two, three, four, five functions. All of them on the stack here about
the factorial.
Now, when you get to this line, you will notice that the function with factorial N equal one is about
to return.
So this function will be getting out of the stack of calls, and the local variable will be
destroyed.
Now, let's get back here. Now,
we returned to the function where the factorial N with value 2, and we are done with this line of
code, and the ret here is value one.
Now, we multiply one with two.
Now, ret is 2. We return ret. We are returning ret, which one?
The one who called us.
So we return back here to the function when the factorial has N equal three. We multiplied it with
with N equal two, 3 times 2 which is six,
and now we returned back.
So you see here one more stack has like one more item is extracted from the stack. We have now
the ret with value 6, and N with value 4. 6 times
4 is 24.
Now, we returned back to the caller which is N with 5. Now, ret is 24 and N is 5.
We multiply both of them together, it will be 120, and this is the last factorial function.
Once we are done with it, we return back to the main function here and it's gone here.
This way, you see the factorial function can be traced with the debugger in an easy way.
That's it.