In this video, we'll learn how to use the code blocks IDE for debugging. Let's first learn about
the places where you can configure something about the debugger.
The first is from the settings menu,
click compiler. Remember here we are in the toolchain executable where we have our some modifications,
say, for C++ 17.
Now, you see here there is a default debugger configuration.
You typically don't need to do that.
So this is one place where there is something relevant to the debugger.
Another thing is here, also in the setting debugger, this is what you just say,
This is the default profile of the current debugger.
Let's say that you installed a different JDB or some other debugger, something recent.
This is the path that you need to change to see the new debugger.
Again, this is a menu that you don't need to play with it, just some default options that are good.
So these are the overall global settings. Now for the project itself, if you came here and get the
settings of the project itself.
From the build options now, this is now what is really more important. The first thing to keep in
mind here and to notice is this word debugger and this word release.
Remember, when we were trying to create a new project from here, we used to select something, let's
say console, go, C++, next, blah, blah, blah,
next.
Yeah, here I used to tell you that to create in the debug and create in the release and file in the
debug and the release.
What are these two terms now? now you should be familiar with that. The debug is where the debug symbols
are added.
The release is one without debug symbols and more ready for configuration.
So now, when you come to the project here from the build options, you can see that we have two profiles,
and these profiles every one of them will have different settings,
and one of the issues sometimes that we work a lot in the debug, we put all of our settings, but
when we start to run the release, we find things don't go well.
You need to make sure that your configuration is in both of them or in the profile that you would like
to use. All the time,
we were using the debug profile.,
and also, you can find it from here, debug and release.
Now, I would like you to remember that if you tried to debug in the release mode, it would not work.
OK, so now we are in the debug mode, we are going to debug.
The last two things here to notice is this debug's menu which has several debug's options, and they are corresponding
to this case
here, you see this button, it says debug continue, this one run to cursor,
then next line, we care about that, step into, we care about that, and step out,
we care about that,
and there is also some button here.
Let's start debugging.
We have a code here.
It has a sum_square function which takes an array, and some length, iterate on the array,
sum every element, return the sum.
We have also a recursive function for the factorial. our code here starts defining sum array,
calling sum_function over it, then calling array1 and this vector here, the vector we will learnt
about it in the STL and printing some side.
So just some basic code.
How to debug? you started debugging by clicking this button.
Let's click it.
OK, something appeared and then disappeared.
There is nothing more than that. If this happened, this means that there were no breakpoints
in your code, you need to put here
Something called break point. A breakpoint, as the name says, is something where the code stops.
So I am putting here a break point.
Let's click the button again here.
You see now the code showing this triangle thing here, it means that the code is active at this point.
I would like you to do three things.
The first is to get this console.
This console will be updated line by line.
So let's make it here always on to,p so we can see it.
I would like you to add other two important things here.
First, come to this menu, the debugging windows, and select watches.
The second menu comes from here and say..., or it is here,  call stack.
Yeah.
So these two menus we need them.
They are very, very useful menus.
I would like you to start to see what are going to do.
When we say debugger, we mean we can trace the code line by line.
Now, see the active line here, line 26.
If we go to the menu options here, we find something called  next line, OK.
The next line can allow us to move to the next line.
So we click here.
You see the active line now here.
Now the first thing to observe here is in the watches.
The watches here have variables that are available at the moment.
So, for example, it's telling you that there is an array of three elements of values 2, 3, 4.
There are other variables also that don't have values at the moment.
There is also another option called step_into. Step_into is good if you would like to jump inside
function's details.
So you see line 28 is stopping at this function call.
You have two choices
now. You either step next
so you go directly to line 30 and see the result of this line, or you jump inside the function itself.
let's for now,
focus on the step next line, that's all.
So we click here next line, which is, by the way, from the debug menu,
next line is button F7.
Now, look at the variable result,
the variable result here,
the value now changed to 29.
If you tried to double click, you cannot change it, but in something like eclipse or visual studio,
you can even change the value on the fly during the run.
But anyway, the debugger now is at line 30, and we have these variables.
Now, look to the array here.
values is 2, 3, 4.
It seemed line 30 is changing the value of the array of one, to 100.
So let's let's go next line.
Here you see what happened.
So as you see that debugger gives you the ability to see things like step by step, this lets you catch
the errors in a very easy way.
Now, we are going to declare and define a vector.
So let's see here, you see now the vector 2, 3, 4.
You also have a function that is pushing back. For educational purposes, let's now try to jump inside the
function.
So we will go to step_into and jump inside it.
You notice what happened?
We jumped into the implementation of the C++ itself, which typically is out of interest.
So now we don't want to jump here more in the file.
So let's get back from this function.
Now, here is the step out.
...
Step out means go back one step.
So we go back to our file.
Now, you notice the vector pushed in it a new value of 7.
Another thing here is
the cout line. Once we proceed it.
OK, so we notice here something when you proceed it, it didn't print the factorial five, which
is 120, why? Let's stop the processing.
Yes, if asking you to see the configuration. In the moral fundamentals unit, you will
know that sometimes cout doesn't see the output of something so we can right here flush,
which will force the output of our processing.
The second thing that I would like to make use here is I'm going to put here another breakpoint and
show you something else.
Now, let's debug again.
The code stopped here. If you clicked on continue here, debug continues, it will jump directly to this
point.
OK, let's get the output here.
Yeah, you see now the console screen has 120.
It's now printed.
So if you see cout not printed here or in a file, then flush it directly.
The second thing is you can put more breakpoints, and the code will jump directly to it.
So you don't need to trace line by line.
You can jump to another breakpoint.
Now, let's stop that again.
Let's play one more time, but before playing, I would like to show you what would happen if we tried
to switch to the release mode.
So I will come here and say release, and then I will try to rebuild the project.
Let's run it.
OK, good, so now let's try to debug that. If you tried to debug that what will happen?
It says here, no debug symbols are found. So when you see this message, you know that you are in
the release mode.
So please go back to the debug mode, rebuild, and make sure that you are in the debug mode.
Good.
Let's go back here.
Let's debug again.
Again, disappeared, but there are no error messages here exit normally, so please remember that
you need to put a breakpoint here.
Let's put breakpoint
at this line here, and let's start it again.
Now, we are at line 28 but instead of the next line, I would like to try to jump inside the function
itself.
So where is the step into? step into. Now, the step into jumped
you the line at line 16, the triangle.
It means we are inside this function.
Now, observe here the call stack. Remember, we explain what is a call stack is in the pointers.
So we see here we have the main function that called sum square function.
So our call stack currently has 2 function.
You can even double click the main,
and you notice it is giving you the values in the main or go back to the sumsquare function as
the values of the sum square function.
So, again, we can trace it line by line here.
So sum is zero. Now, array of i. Let's say,
I would like to know what is in the value of array of i.
You can definitely see it from here, but I would like to do something here.
Come and double click right array of i, and enter. You see it now giving you two.
This is what we call expressions.
You can add expressions, you can say here print for me, sum plus 6, for example, it's up to
you.
You can add more expressions to watches here.
Sometimes
as you see, the array here, for example, isn't accessible in an easy way.
Debugger sometimes have limitations, but you can add more variables, you can add the i, n and so on
In eclipse,
when you stop over a variable, you can see its values which is more powerful.
Now, the moral of that is let's try to do some tracing.
Next line, next line, you see the sum variable is changing and also our sum plus 6 is changing.
Now, let's say you're done with the function, and you don't need to trace anymore.
You can just come here and step out of the function, and just go outside of it.
Now, we jumped completely outside of the function in an easy way.
What else? So we know about the different options, about the variables, and the watches.
..., Let's finish the processing here.
I'm going to do something here.
Let's say that I'm going to put here minus one zero zero zero zero zero zero zero,
and I'm going to run this program now.
You see what happened, the debugger jumped directly to line 19 to tell you that something wrong happened
here. In a single second, you managed to know where is the problem in your code.
This doesn't happen all the time.
Sometimes yes.
Sometimes no.
But the moral of that, the debugger sometimes, can catch for you the error in a very short time.
So you can find it in a very simple way.
Again, you can put a breakpoint here and just click jump and the whole code will jump to this point.
Very normally here.
So what is the value of sum?
The value of some currently is zero.
But there is a very interesting and powerful feature which we call conditional breakpoint.
Come here to this point.
Right click, edit break point and come to break
when expression is true.
Let's put her sum
equal-equal 4. This is a conditional breakpoint. this breakpoint will be activated only when the sum
is 4.
Now let's run here.
You see, what's the value of the sum. So even sometimes if you knew that you would like to go to a very,
very specific point, you can put the value of the breakpoint, and just run and go for it.
So this is how we can use the debugger to debug step by step.
In the next video will learn how to debug recursive functions like factorial. That's it.