In this video, we will learn how the debugger can help us to understand factorial and understand some of
complicated cases about it.
So let's use the factorial as a simple example.
Now, let's run.
The first thing to notice here, as we said before, we have a stack of functions. Here is the main stack
and the factorial five stack. Let's trace step by step.
You go next line and then next line, which jumped to another breakpoint. Looking to the stack here,
we have a stack of factorial N five, and a stack of factorial N four. Our current call stack has three functions.
Let's continue tracing.
Now, another function in the stack. The good about the debugger, you can see all of the functions,
and you can know what's happening. If you double click here,
you know that N equal 4 is calling us, ret
is uninitialized. Now N equal here
3. Again also ret is uninitialized.
Let's keep going, next,
It jumps here, next,
It jumps here.
Now, at the N equal 1, we notice that the function is about to return.
So once it returned, this factorial N = 1 should be removed from the stack.
So let's see what's going to happen here, next,
you see now what happened, it removed from the stack, and we get back to the function of N equal 2, and
we have here our ret with value 1. Now, we will multiply the ret with 2,
and returning the result to the factorial of N equals 3, which will have the ret now with
2, and will be multiplied with 3, so now, it going to be six.
Returning six to whom?
To factorial N power of 4 that called us.
So now we have here 4 times 6
24, returned to factorial N five, which was the first call to the factorial here,
multiplied it, it will be 120 and then return it. Once you return here we see it's going
back to the main.
Once the main is done, the whole program is done.
So the moral of that, if you got confused about a recursive function, put a break point and just
find the the answer to your problem.
That's it.