So this is our first project in the course, as I promised, there will be many projects in the course
I think on average they are like 2 mini projects and 2 medium to large scale projects and 2 large
projects.
So this is our first smallest system, a hospital system.
In this system, Assume that there are 20 different specializations like children,
surgery, and things like that.
For each specialization, there are only five available spots.
So you can think of patients like they are making a queue of maximum five spots, per a specialization
in the system, we can add a patient;
So we need some specialization.
From one to 20, we get a status.
Is it regular or urgent?
If five patients exist,
we apologize and we cannot accept this patient.
If the user is regular, we add him at the end of the queue like what happens in a hospital.
But if he is urgent, we add him to the beginning of the queue, the very top beginning so we can print
patients for the specializations that have waiting patients.
We..., some doctor might come and pick a patient.
Then we check what is the specialization of the doctor if no patients at the moment we inform the doctor.
Otherwise, we ask the patient to go to the doctor and then remove this patient from the
queue.
We typicaly give him the top one in the queue now.
So let's see some some simulation for that.
Here is what we call a user interface.
an interface is something that the user is seeing.
When you hold your mobile, you are watching a user interface.
When you're accessing a website, you are seeing an interface.
So this is what we call a console interface, just text.
So the user here has a menu of four choices.
So he chose number 1, which is adding a new patient for each patient,
we add the specialization, the name, the status for the 'i'.
So this is like 15 mostafa 0.
This is 0 for regular, 1 for urgent.
15 is a specialization number and so on. We added another user.
And we added a third user. Notice, the first two were regular, but that one is urgent.
Now we are asked for 2, which is printing all the patients.
So we printed the following: Belal, Mostafa, Asmaa, but notice Belal here,
this guy came here in the top.
We again added another child, another person who is again urgent when we printed "Ziad" came at the top.
Remember that we if someone is urgent, we definitely add him in the top of everyone else.
Let's continue, we are adding one more person at specialization 15, and then we added one more person, but we now
have 5 persons in the specialization 15.
So it says: "sorry, we can't add more patients for this specialization".
Now, if we try to print, we have these five, three urgent and three, two urgent and three regular
Let's enter 3, which is getting a patient so we ask which specialization?
We say 10, but there are no patients at the moment.
OK, what about Specialization 15?
We asked "Ziad", which is the top person to go with the doctor.
If we print it again, we get the list.
Without "Ziad", let's add one more person.
But now for the specialization 7, and then let's print if we printed we see here, this is specialization
7 and "Soha", and this special 15 and the people here.
Let's add another person to specialization 15, let's get a patient from 7, so 7 goes
If we printed again, it go back to just specialization 15.
That's it.