In this video, we will explain the hospital project, first of all, let's focus on the big picture of
the project.
Thinking here about..., like to understand the way I am codding it, first of all, my program here start
with a hospital system function, which is just here, a function here.
This function has a very basic entry.
It has a while loop and it takes a choice from the user.
And based on choice, it starts call a specific function.
And I advise you, when you start your program, develop this function first where you are putting all
of your choices, choice by choice, for the different functionalities, then you start one
by one to implement the function and test it.
That is what we call front end; the word
front end refers to what the user is facing when you are using mobile or we are using web interface.
These are called interfaces or front ends.
And this is the front end also for our application.
But this is a console front end.
So this is a bunch of functionalities here.
Now, in terms of what kind of data structures we need in our code here, we definitely need some arrays.
We need an array to maintain the name of the current employee, the current patient.
And we have also different specialization.
So we need also to count over that. We have 20 specializations and we have five max_queue.
So one makes sense
the choice is to have something that is to restructure.
So we have 20 specializations.
And for every specialization we have here a max_queue of the needed items.
I doubt that we really need this plus one anyway.
And so this is a 2D structure to represent the names and the corresponding one for the status.
And this is a current queue length for the current items here, because like we need to know
that we have four items in the specialization 10, five items in specialization seven and so on.
The more we go during the course, we will learn things that will make our life in development much
better than that.
We'll learn about struct which will regroup
all of that in a nice way.
We learn about STL, which will make this code more dynamic.
We'll learn about OOP, which can have a different perspective.
So more is coming when it comes to structuring your code.
So this is a data structure of the project.
Before proceeding in the code, I would like you to make sure that you understand the purpose of these
three items.
Now, let's think about the first functionality here.
The add_patient, the add_patient will like only to add an element to our array.
But as we know, we have some requirements anyway.
We started in the function with reading the input from the user and we should be careful to not add
an element to the array if we have enough patients.
So the first thing here is I get the queue length of the current specialization.
Let's say the specialization is seven.
So what is the current queue of the specialization?
Let's say five elements.
So I'm confirming here that if the position is greater than our limit, we return false and
we give an error message.
Otherwise, we have some spaces for the people.
Now we have two cases.
The easy case is to add just the element in the end of the current queue if the status is zero, which
is a regular case.
So this is very straightforward.
We are going to add the position here for this guy.
We are going to add it for the status and it's very important to increment to the current queue length.
So we go to the target specialization and increment its size.
The tricky case is when you have to add the element in the beginning of the array here.
But the problem is we already have people in the array.
So the idea that I come with is to make a shift for the current content
one step to the right.
For example, if we have three elements in position zero one two, I would like to shift them to the
position
one, two, three.
After that, I'm going to put in the first element, the element here.
The shift is a straightforward function.
You would like to iterate on the array, but in a very careful way.
And start to shift. To do the shifting properly, you need to start from the end so that you don't
override the data wrongly.
So I start at 'i' of length minus one, and in every step, 'i' of len-1 is my last item.
So in every step I take the current item and put it in the next item, take the current item and put
it in next item and so on.
Going back from back to front, I would like you if you are confused why that we have to start from
the end,
try
three numbers or like zero one, two, four, let's say five, seven, eight, and try to do the
right shift in a different way to observe that we are overriding the data in a wrong way.
I'm also here incrementing the array with one item, because now the length is like it is a bit bigger.
Once we did this shifting, we are ready to remove the item from the queue.
So this is the add_patient function.
Please make sure to understand it very well before proceeding more.
In the second case, we had the print function, which is very straightforward.
You will iterate over the current specialization one by one and call the print patient function,
which just access the queue and just get the information.
Sorry, this one is iterating to print specialization by specialization and this one is printing a specific
specialization.
So this one is going to get a special specialization.
If there are no items, just return. Otherwise, iterate on them one by one and start to print the
content of the array.
The next function is the get next patient here, which would like to get the top element, first of all,
we need to make sure there are some elements in the queue.
If there are no elements, you just go back.
Otherwise, the first person would go to the queue.
Now, one issue here, we would like to remove the first element in the array, but we don't have the
remove operation.
So one way here is to just make a left shift for this array from left to right; the opposite direction
of what we did.
So let's go to this function starting from one.
I'm going to take the current element and move it one step back, current element moving step back.
Again, if you are confused about that, try to take three numbers in an array and do a simulation.
The shift left and shift right idea are very common in programming.
So you have to be very comfortable with these two functions. Once you are done here,
again, going to decrease by one element the length of the queue.
Yeah, that's all.
These are the three functionalities I would like you to be like more patient when we are trying to learn
and develop our own projects.
I know that some of the projects might be hard.
This is like it depends.
Sometimes guys find it easy.
Others find it hard, take it easy.
If you develop your own code in a different way, this is totally OK, but please also read my code to
learn from it.
If you could not develop mine, please listen to me.
Read the code line by line, try to understand.
And after that, remove the whole code, and start it from scratch, to not just proceed to the next project
or the next video.
The more you go during this project, I'm going to challenge you a lot.
And this is actually the whole purpose of this course.
I'm not going to like, give you easy exercises and then you are happy; you will be challenged.
So you have to make sure that step by step you can do the project.
Generally speaking, if you cannot do a project, you will not be able to do the next project.
The next project will typically be harder and would be much more codes.
That's all.