So far, we have been learning about the programming basics and learning about structs and how structs
helped us a lot to refine things, and we hear already before the word object.
From now, we are going to talk about one of the most important paradigms in programming, the object
oriented programming.
Let's remember something, at some point in the course, we really need to represent an employee
system,
and we had to create like a bunch of arrays to employee, reading function here, printing function
here and start thinking about adding one more feature for employee,
then you are changing, adding one more row here, changing a lot of variables here and there. That
was is very impractical,
and then we introduced the struct,
and remember, we created the struct of an employee, which is a struct of a struct of type a full name,
and then this guy has his own function, and this guy has his own function.
What happened here is that the struct helped us to group all relevant attributes in one unit.
In addition to that, we allowed composition.
We allowed the employee to be composed of full name objects, and also we attached internal operations
of this data together.
Now, you would have definitely less parameters if we would like to read or print as all parameters
are defined inside struct.
You even don't have all of these parameters that you see in the previous code.
What happened here is struct did binding for us, for the variables, and for the operations.
We can now create objects of the class employee, create an array of objects of class employee or rechange later to vector.
The number of changes that happen is much less than the normal case.
This takes us to the concept of encapsulation, which is one of the first mandatory concepts
in OOP. Encapsulation just means to encapsulate together the data members and the member functions.
From now,
we are going to refer to the variables inside a struct or a class as data members, and refer to
the functions inside it as a member function.
So note the word member is relevant to a struct or a class.
OK, so the encapsulation at this nice view here, it has methods or variable. The word method is coming
from something like Java. In Java,
we call it method, here
we call it member function.
The whole object-oriented programming, as a name reveals, is all about objects and supposed
due to the project that we did so far,
you can get a very good sense of the object and object perspective.
Looking at this very tall building.
You have 40 floors here.
You can describe it as an object.
You can think of what are other objects it contains and what these other objects contain and contain.
We can build a great hierarchy of compositions.
The word compose means something includes another thing.
We have elevators, we have floors,
we have an apartment, apartment consist of rooms and washrooms.
Each room has some details, there are electrical outlets in the home,
there are locations, there are garage details and parking information.
So you can think of the building as elevators and floors, floor as apartments, apartment as rooms
and washrooms.
You can think of this hierarchy of objects and hierarchy of relationships. In a similar way,
let's say that we have a Google calendar.
You can start to describe it in terms of years, and each year has months and each month has weeks and
days,
and there are events which has date and time,
guests to attend and so on.
So thinking about these member functions, a member variable is what encapsulation
gives us. That's it for today.