In this video, we'll discuss more about the big picture of object-oriented programming.
There is a nice diagram that we might call it the OO diagram.
It consists of, as you see, four levels, something called the OO paradigm,
and this is explaining what OO is about,
and then OO concepts, and this is typically the core of any OO programming concepts.
There are six fundamental concepts in programming. There are also the object-oriented principles,
some principles that are very important to make your code much better.
They are typically not explained in OO courses, but I'm going to highlight them in a specific way.
There are also design patterns that also like part of the big OO picture.
So the whole OOP paradigm is about making the objects as a very centralized concept in the whole project.
Suppose at this moment of time with the projects that we did them using the struct, you already created
a lot of objects, object of a hospital, object for a library, object for a user, object for a question,
and answer, and so on.
OOP is all about making these objects in a very centralized way to the projects,
but OOP involves a lot of things that would make the design mush fit with the
real life needs. OOP is a paradigm,
The word paradigm or programming paradigm means a way of thinking, view and structuring your software.
So it is like a philosophy of something.
OOP is just one of them.
Before that, there are many other paradigms like declarative, functional.
One of the very popular ways is the procedural programming.
This is what we actually were doing early in C++, introducing functions and so on.
So this is one of the old paradigms.
So why OOP? why is it important? if you tried to talk about the classes that we were doing (structs specifically),
we noticed some correspondence between real-world objects and OOP classes.
So the way that you interpret your own project, like, say, I'm doing a project to implement an ATM
machine, you notice there are some correspondence between what we have in reality and what we have
in our classes or our structs.
Every time I mentioned class, I just mean struct
if the word class is still not familiar for you. OOP helps us a lot to handle the complexity of software
products.
There is what we call software crisis.
A lot of softwares might be over
budget, might be overtime, delivered with a lot of buggy functionalities, or even functionality that doesn't
meet requirements, or even never delivered.
So this is what we call software crisis,
and OOP helps us to some extent to handle these issues.
OOP is just one paradigm.
..., OOP is the mandatory way of programming so far in the
market,
but still some people hate it and criticize it a lot.
Some people think that the current designs are a bit relative  like doesn't match with the old intention
OOP,
and so on.  This is a future link to to read it.
OK, so why did we stop the procedure?
Because of these advantages of
OOP, and because procedural lack a lot of issues, like, for example, no owner of data, a lot
of issues about comes to integrity of data.
If there is a bug, it might be very hard to identify where is the bug and to debug your code.
So I mentioned before the OOP concepts, we already know what is an object, what is a class, and we highlighted
what is encapsulation.
In the next videos, we will first dig more,
we will know about what is abstraction,
then we will go into one background to know what is a class like more of the class features in C++, for
example.
Then we will know what is this inheritance and what is this polymorphism?
This is what typically an OOP course will do, we will explain these
Programming concepts.
The principles, which is something that typically not taught in OOP concepts, is actually the
most important thing in designing good software. These principles make your code like a much better
one.
An example of the principles like solid principles, a single responsibility principle,
for example, tip you something like your class should have one single reason for a change,
It should be responsible for only one reason, one concern.
This makes us when we are developing classes, we do not make like a mega class containing every functionality
and every variable.
No, it will be very specific like this class for a user, this class for a question, and so on.
The open-closed principal:
Your classes shouldn't be modifiable but should allow people to extend them to add more
functionality and so on.
There are further concepts like dry,
don't repeat yourself.
Some people will do a lot of copy-paste in sizer code.
This is wrong. Kiss,
Keep it simple.
A lot of people will complicate things, how to make things easier.
YAGNI, sometimes people will add a lot of functionalities, and they claim that in the far future we
are going to use them, but they never used them.
OK, so one of the unique features of this course is the following:
In a lot of homework, I embed in an implicit way
these principles. So I actually solving homework that is actually a practice on one of these principles,
and this is how I am going in an implicit way, teaches you some of these principles.
Design patterns are also one of the important things in software engineering.
The idea, as simple as there are a lot of repetitive design sub-tasks that we all face in reality.
Remember the queue, the queue is something that we all meet,
It doesn't make sense that we ask people to implement it all the time. In a similar way,
the design of some functionality might be repetitive task.
So some people will gather together and tell us, you know what, this is one of the best ways to solve
this problem.
OK, I would like you to warn here from something. In a lot of CS curriculum, they
might be stressing design patterns in a way that students think that it's a way of life.
It is a skill to know when to use design patterns and how to use them.
It isn't about, let's suppose looks like let's create like tons of design patterns in a project.
It's actually the project decides what it needs.
Sometimes some of the patterns are very common, like single and factory design patterns,
also other are less important. From domain to another,
some patterns might be used much more than others.
Also, again, one of the unique things in this course, I embed some of these design patterns in the homework.
The homework of the OOP is very critical
so don't skip any of it.
OK, after that, when it comes to studying design principles and design patterns, you will find them
very intuitive because you already
know about them and non-contiguous.
There are three relevant terms, object-oriented analysis, object-oriented design, object-oriented
programming. Object-oriented analysis is a step that happened in industry when we would like to analyze
some requirements that we take from the customers
and then we start to think on things in terms of objects,
and these typically involve a lot of things and they are usually technology independent, just more
of thought levels.
Then there is something called object-oriented design, and this is where in reality we started to take
care of a lot of important issues, like what kind of hardware and software we have.
There's something called the availability of the system.
When you are using your Facebook, you find it available all the time, right ?.
The scalability, Facebook, for example, and Google, handle millions or millions of users.
How to what degree your software is going to be scalable?
What kind of budget is our target?
Designing a software design is an important skill that you take time to learn how to design good
systems.
One of the very important things in this course is design skills. Again, through the homework,
a lot of homework will stress a lot of design notes in a very useful way for you.
If we are done with the object-oriented analysis and the object-oriented design, the next step is the
object-oriented programming.
This is actually what you usually are taught in programming courses, the syntax of a specific language
so that you convert a design to an implementation.
We are going definitely to make,
this is our focus here, the object oriented programming.
We're also going to highlight enough design notes during the homework so that you know how to design
your systems.
Also, one of the good ways to enforce the design is actually the projects.
So there are also a few projects to help you doing that.
OK, so in reality, the company culture, the scale of the project, the team side decides how
the three are applied.
So let's say that you are working on a small project.
To some extent, all of these concepts might be applied by a small team in a very unified way.
So no one has this extension of, OK, these are the analysis step, this is a design step, this is a programming
step.
It doesn't go like that.
And this actually happened in the market
a lot like the same programmer is doing the design and programming by itself,
and this is actually what happened in this course.
The requirements are simple enough, which doesn't need analysis,
then you do design and you do programming. In large projects,
actually things might get more complicated,
you will notice more hires in the team.
Someone is named
business analyst is involved in the analysis here.
Another guy, sorry, this is a business guy like working with the business guys, system analyst doing
the analysis here,
and architects are also working on the high-level designs and tech leads at devs.
So big projects would require a lot of people to be doing these different steps, that's all.
In case you would like to read, I found the book C++,
how to Program is a very nice book.
However, I'm doing a very intensive coverage for the topic.
You will almost will not find something extra in the book.
So reading is more optional if you get lost.
One of the interesting things in books that they have typically some true-false questions after their
chapters.
I would say they are nice to try.
There is a nice book
called head first object-oriented design, I would suggest, for you to give a read for this book after
the course.
After the course, you would find the reading of the book much easier for you.
A good software engineer reads a lot of very deep books in software engineering. In future,
I would like you to explore this link and also this nice book and started to learn,
It takes time to educate yourself. Coding guidelines,
these are some coding guidelines like one from Google and another guy. In industry,
we write following some guidelines so that our code has good names and so on.
So also you feel free to familiarize yourself with that. That's it