Let's take some homework about that that might help us in the next subjects.
The first one about the date and time., the date is a very common data structure in practice. Let's
say that you are a software engineer, and your team lead asked you to think in a date struct.
So what might be the possible data members and member functions for this struct?
There are no requirements.
Be flexible and think about that.
This is an infrastructure struct.
What does it mean
Infrastructure?  In big companies,
you would find them identifying kinds of projects that everyone is going to use like thinking in a date
and time struct.
Everyone might need something like that.
So the infrastructure projects are typically used by a huge number of teams,
they have to be very clean, very well written,
they have to be very efficient because they affect many other projects.
Noticed there are many printing concerns,
for example, the user might want to print in different ways like maybe year, month, day, comma-separated,
month, year, comma-separated day, month dash-separated.
So think about that.
On the other side,
there is also a time class where you have hours, minutes, and seconds, ok,  hours, minutes, and seconds.
Find two ways to describe the member variables for the time class.
There are two ways to present that and think about the positives and
negatives of the two choices.
Let's say that you are debating with your teammate about one choice like you would like to take choice A,
but you would like to choose B, and it's taking hours for you to make a decision. How to be practical in industry
and make decisions?
OK, this is another class someone wanted to implement a date-time class, he implemented it in this way.
Let's say that this is is working very well and no problems.
I would like you to provide a critical design tip for this guy.
What might be wrong here?
There's nothing wrong with the code implementation itself, but something about the design itself.
We are developing a banking application, and this is the code of your friend, you are requested
to do a design review.
Design review in the industry means that you are reviewing someone's code or design and giving some comments
on what's wrong.
So think about the current data members.
Are all of them relevant to the person?
Are all of them relevant to the bank application
here? Are the data types convenient?. Thinking, probably like two missing critical data members for
this class and so on.
This is a drawing application, you have triangles, you have circles, you have triangles, and so on.
What is the common between these three shapes, and what is special about every one of them?
Think of that in terms of the member variables, the member functions, and the function behavior also
itself
someone implemented
this style,
he needs a queue of integer, a queue of double, a queue string.
They are all working very well,
but what is wrong here?
A Google search engine, if you tried to Google using Google, you would notice that you have very limited
interface.
You probably can write your query, you can do some settings, search for videos and images,
and that's it.
Thinking about the code base of Google, it is definitely one of the biggest code bases,
However, we as users only know very little about the code. We only know how to query them,
but nothing else.
What is good in hiding things from a user?
like am as a user, do I need to know that there are 10000 functionalities in the system internally that I
would never need.
What is good in hiding things from me?
What versus how, what means what we're going to do, how is how we are going to do it?
For example, let's say we would like to do summation from one to N, then this is the what? we would
like to sum the numbers from 1 to N.
How is how to do that.
I would like you to think in two different ways to sum the numbers from one to N. Now looking at
this application, the purpose of the homework, Snapseed  like some application that can help us to
manipulate images, doing rotations, cropping, drawing, and so on.
Let's say it's supported in Android, iOS and iPad devices.
The question is here in terms of the what and how, I would like to provide some thoughts about something
like filling the color in a rectangle.
Is it the same in Android, IOS, iPad?
...
What about reading an image from the device from your store?
Are these the same in the functionalities?
OK, let's say that we found one function that is buggy or even faster way to implement it.
How to structure our application codebase to do the minimum code changes that we might need.
Think about that.
Finally, I would like you to know this isn't homework. You, for a while, would think that the date
and time class are very trivial classes.
However, in reality, they were behind a lot of bugs in software development. As a reading,
I would like you to read about this link, why there are a lot of problems and also
how to use it correctly.
You don't need to do that right now, maybe just schedule it after the course.
There is an interesting thing here,
there are a lot of future tasks
for a while, you will think they are trivial like the date and time class,
but once you think deeper about them, you discover a lot of concerns. For fun,
there are a lot of problems attached to date like the year 38 and the year 2000.
This happened already,
and this is coming.
There's something called leap second that is causing problems in also date and time.
So this is like good educational links about the date and time issues. That's it.