One of the fundamental concepts in object-oriented programming is data hiding. So let's know what
is a class.
So class is something very similar to the struct,
you give it a class' name, you open braces, then you put a semicolon,
you start to put some variables and start to put some functionalities.
So it encapsulate also the data and functionalities,
but it is more of an OOP. Struct was originally coming from the C language and it kept evolving in a way
that make it almost like class, but class is more OOP.
So let's see how things in OOP world are. In a class,
we start to have something called the public section and the private section.
The public section has data and functionalities that the user can see and access.
By user, we mean someone who is trying to use our class.
The private section is a section that a user cannot see or access its data functionalities or data
members.
So who is seeing it?
The class itself.
OK, so this is how we implement it.
This is a private, and this is a public section.
You start to write here some data members, some functions, and you start to write here, some variables
and some functionalities.
If you as a user tried to use this class,
and you started to say queue
dot external
Is it in public section?
Yes, no problem.
Queue dot print, is it in public section?
Queue dot internal,
Is it in public section.
No.
So as an external user you cannot use this internal function, and you cannot call this get quote.
However, inside the public section itself, you can see your private section.
So we call them the access modifiers because it determines the accessibility about who can access what.
We can visualize them through this code.
This is our class, our object. Inside the class, the public and private see each other,
but if you are an external user to the class, you only can see the public section, but you cannot
see the private section.
So the private section hides some data members and some member functions from users, from external
users. As a very critical OOP design principle,
you are to reveal in the public section as little as possible and maximize your private section as much
as possible.
Let's think about Google search engine.
We referred before that Google search engine provides us with some interface that involves viewing results,
that involves some of the optional settings,
However, Google search is a very huge website, is a very huge codebase.
So we can say that all the complexity of the project is hidden from us.
Do I care as a user?
The answer is no.
All I need is just to know how to search for something on your website.
I don't care about any anything else,
only the internal classes care about that.
I don't care about that.
So it's more of the what versus the how.
So here is what might be the overall code of Google
like, let's say you are calling the Google search engine.
There is a private section that has a huge amount of data that no one knew about them,
and there is a public section that has functionalities to search.
You can send me a query, you can send me some settings and you are receiving a vector of results, and
there is some class for result and some class for settings,
but you have no access and you actually don't care about anything in the private section.
So this is how user
eventually, just give a query and some settings and he gets results.
The user here doesn't care how Google is going to find the results and what is hidden in Google.
No one care about that.
So the good here about having less access that it reduces the system complexity.
You do know most of it, so you don't care. So why data hiding? first
because it helps us to prevent the corruption of the data.
The less that you see to others, the less they can change in your own code. Such changes sometimes
even might be unintended or intended. In an unintended way,
someone or a hacker or whatever decided to break things. In an unintended way,
and this would actually happened all the time,
someone might access like, let's say going back to the struct, we didn't see this private and
public section,
so someone externally using your code can just change whatever,
but here you have some limitation.
So we might be able to protect our data members as much as we could.
There also a concept called the object integrity.
The word integrity refers that
things together are like looks like they are working together in a good way.
Let me give you some example.
Let's say you have some computer or a mobile or a car or whatever. You figured out there are some problems
in your laptop, for example, that something wrong in your adapter.
You then bought a new cheap adapter to replace the old adapter. The computer for a while seems working,
but after some time, the whole system failed due to, say, some voltage problem.
Where is the problem here?
This new component that you added to the system isn't integrable with the whole system,
and this what might happen in the system with the user, like let's say the struct has an array and
has length. The length is 100 and then suddenly the user
put the length with zero.
So we have data, but now the length is zero. Someone corrupted the integrity of the whole system.
We can also see that data hiding is reducing the system complexity and also it give us better code readability.
If you remember the Google search example, the main that was calling the search engine has very
little.
So you can read the code in an easy way because you don't see all of this
big codebase from the user. Data hiding versus encapsulation.
We already know about the encapsulation that it gathers together the data members
and the member functions.
So what's the difference between encapsulation and data hiding?
Encapsulation can be achieved at least with a struct. We saw in a struct that it collected
for us the member function and collected for us the data members,
but with data hiding,
we also split them to what is private and what is public.
As you see, data hiding is impossible without encapsulation like you, functionalities are spread in
the code.
You cannot make what is public and what's private.
OK, so this is the critical difference between encapsulation and data hiding. Be careful, people are mixing
them together.
Encapsulation is all about gathering together the data and the functionalities.
Data hiding is about reorganizing them into private and public sections.
So back to the system complexity point that I mentioned, the word system complexity is
achieved as following:
When you are enforcing encapsulation, the way that encapsulation is reducing the system complexity
is mainly by grouping things together.
So development is now easier,
and also if you are solving some bug, it's much easier because you have here now a class of date involved
with all of the things of the date.
You have a class of question involving all of the things of question.
You have a class of user involving functionality for user.
So designing, coding, implementing, fixing bugs is much easier with encapsulation.
What about data hiding?
the search of Google engine is a good example.
Like there is a lot in Google that we don't know.
So as a user I only care about how can I call the Google function and I don't care about anything else.
So this means that we are hiding a lot of the complexity of the system.
There is also a very interesting concept here, which is dependency (coupling).
You will hear the word a lot, and it's a critical concept in software engineering.
Couples mean that there is some dependency.
Thinking about the Google search engine, what is exactly our dependency?
We have only one dependency on a function named search that takes a query and takes some settings, but
nothing else.
So Google can be very flexible about its hidden functionalities.
They can change a lot of them,
and they don't care that the outsiders depend on our code because we only depend on a single functionality.
So if there are other one thousand functionality, we don't depend on them so they can internally change
them as much as they need. The less you depend on others code,
the less coupling that
is in system.
Finally, we already so far discussed the two fundamental concepts in OOP, encapsulation and data hiding.
I hope we now can figure out exactly the difference between them, we heard a lot of important concepts
that we hear a lot in software engineering, integrity, dependency, system complexity, user, coupling,
readability and security.
I would like you to think of a simple rectangle class that has just this kind of two dimensions.
Think about the potential data members and member functions.
This is the easy part, but think about what might be public and what might be private.
That it.