One of the fundamental concepts in OOP is the abstraction concept.
So let's introduce one feature of it.
So here is the rectangle class, and these are the potential members and potential functionalities
for it.
If we are thinking, say, a struct, we need to define the double width and height.
We might provide some useful constructors, and we would like to have a compute area functionality and
compute parameter functionalities.
If you would like to create an object, you create R1 and R2. You
access the width and height, you can compute area or use the constructor for the values, you compute the area and
set area, and so on.
Now, there is no here access modifier.
There is nothing that tells you you can access the variable or the function. Moving
to a rectangle as a class.
You will typically notice we write most, if not all, the data members as a private section so that we
prevent others from accessing our member data directly. On the other side,
we are going to put all the functionalities that are needed for the user like compute area and compute
perimeter in public section.
If we put the width and height as a private section, the external user now has no way to access them,
but what if you would like to access them?
This introduces the concept of setters and getters, and this is one fundamental thing of the abstraction
concept.
The user here is enjoying the ability to change the height and width of the functionality, but through
functions.
Given that he is calling functions, we can have a lot of control here.
We call them setters and getters.
The center functionality like set height is setting a value.
So it set height,
we change the height. The getter is returning the height.
Now, in terms of the class, we now can access using dot set width and set height, and we have our public
functionalities.
So the setters and getters also are known as getters as accessors and mutators as setters as I said,
the accessor can do the get to read and change the accessed value,
but the mutator can do the set to mutate or change the value. Based on your IDE, you might be able
to generate the setters and getters in an automatic way.
So what happens typically is you define say width and height, then in eclipse
for example, if you press the alt-shift-S inside the class, you will have a menu that has something
named getters, setters, generate getters and setters.
You can go and mark the get and set that you would like to get. There is also here an option to separate
the definition from the declaration (important to try), and then you click, OK, once you did that, it
is going to generate for you the getters and the setters for your data variables.
If you would like to change the style of the getters and setters, for example, you will notice I'm
using all with capital letters.
You can go to Eclipse, window, preferences, here, here, and then say here I would like get with G
capital and the boolean to start with is, and so on.
Let's go back to the accessor and mutator.
So for a while it looks like an easy issue.
We have variables, and we provide setters and getters.
Here is a point.
There is a debate between software engineers about setters and getters, and this is typically is an informal
in OOP classes sadly.
So there is a debate if they are evil or not, should we avoid them as possible or not, to what degree
they eventually break encapsulation?
If I provided people with getters and setters, eventually they are typically playing and changing
our data variables so they might cause problems, for example, in integrity.
So here are fundamental tips so that I would like you to use during this course and after the course
feel free to go and read these links and educate yourself more.
First of all, don't be the guy who just goes and generate setters and getters for every field without
thinking. The setters can allow people to inject wrong data causing problems.
The getters can return critical details out of your codes.
So you should think twice about what are you really giving setters and getters for it.
There is one of the very nice rules that you can apply.
Don't let users ask your class for getters and setters to do some task for you, do the work
by yourself.
What does this mean?
You have a class provide whatever needed functionalities using this class and minimize the dependency
on your getters and setters.
Some guys would make a class and just felt it with getters and setters,
and then you are calling the getters and setters doing a lot of logic by yourself as an external user to the
class.
The right way is you provide the functionality so that people really rarely need to interact a lot with
your getters and setters, and change a lot of things in your class.
This is the proper way to handle the getters and setters.
That's it for today.