Let's finish the abstraction concept, which comes to the data point about the what versus how. This
is a car, we all drive cars.
We mainly know about the big picture of how to drive a car.
However, there are a lot of very complicated details about driving a car.
Think back about the Google search engine, about what you see externally, and about all of the internal
details that I don't know, and I don't care to know actually about most of them.
So you have a lot of things in your home, TV, and car and blah, blah, blah, Internet browser,
you don't care really about a lot of inner details,
you care about how to use them. In C++,
you might call the power function with something like 3.2 .
You might not care about how this really is implemented internally?
If I'm implementing some application, let's say, to edit images, for example, I don't
care how the operating system read and write the images,
I just care that they really give me an image that I read or a file that I'm going to read.
So you typically take care a lot about the what not the how. The WHAT is what the function is doing,
what is it returning, but HOW is how it's implemented.
Sometimes the implementation is slow like the summation from one to N, sometimes it is fast like
the equation, sometimes there are bugs, sometimes it's more stable like internet explorer and Firefox,
sometimes it might take a very big implementation like Chrome versus Firefox.
If you looked at all of that cases, they are all share the same functionality as browsers
here,
but they are all implemented in different ways.
The interesting thing about spreading the WHAT from HOW is it only like we are making it simpler for
the user who is focusing on what he needs, but also think about our ability to change the inner implementations,
like let's say we discovered a bug in our software,
I would like to have a new release that has more features or better features or stable features,
and the user now doesn't depend a lot on us.
It depends only on the specific WHAT, and we can change a lot of the internal HOW.
So in terms of code like one important thing from separating the WHAT from HOW is about the colon
operator.
Remember, we already before learned how to separate a struct's functionalities from how the functionality
is implemented.
When you looked at the class rectangle here, what you see? you know that this class would have compute
area in the public section,
It has a constructor, it has compute_perimeter, it has some getters and setters. This the what of the class,
but how is it implemented?
The compute_area is implemented by multiplying the width and
the height.
If you are a user of the rectangle class, you care about the public section
here. You don't care about how is implemented.
It might be in future change it, improve it, blah blah blah.
We don't care about that.
So the separation of the WHAT from HOW starts with separating the class here
declarations from the definitions,
and this takes us to the abstraction concept in a deeper way. Abstraction is about hiding unwanted details
while showing most essential in a given context.
There are very three critical keywords here.
Hide, show context, hide, show context.
There are two ways that hiding happens under the concept of abstraction.
The first one is the getters and setters that we discussed the last time.
Remember,..., when we provide private and public
sections, we start to hide the private section and show only the public section.
So the public section is mainly about revealing only the relevant functionalities, like thinking about
the Google search engine,
you only see the search engine with the string query.
That is it.
So we do a lot of hiding using the private and public section, and we provided the accessors
and the mutators to facilitate more access to the functionalities if needed.
The other way of hiding here is hiding the WHAT from the HOW.
So the HOW refers to the implementation, the WHAT is what you call WHAT or what you call interface or
API. As we said, they could be really several implementations, the slow and fast, the one that
memory hungry, a lot of things.
So the word hide here has two parts,
what we hide in the private and public sections and what we hide in terms of the implementation
using the colon operator and what we will see more.
So going back to the abstraction, we now know about the hide and show, so we hide something and show
something either public and private or the implementation
WHAT and HOW. What does it mean
Context?
Let's say that we are in a Google company and would like to define a class to represent Google's employee,
and in another company would like to represent the employee in Toyota car company.
Definitely,
there should be some similar functionalities or data members,
for example, the name, the age, the birthdate, the national ID. They are common, but within
context of a Google's employee, we might have something about the Google's employee
itself or about it being a software engineer like maybe his software engineer level in the company.
Google uses levels like 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, for example.
But thinking about Toyota guy, it might be a very different concern, like, for example, the
commissions that this guy is going to get over
his sales, what is the percentage of that?
So this is what we mean by context from a class to another,
you think about the context.
If you are designing a class for a banking application, customer, user, you think what is really
relevant to this customer user?
So the word context is about what is really relevant here in what we are designing.
So thinking about the data abstraction and its relationship with encapsulation and information hiding,
you feel it like a bigger concept.
It involves encapsulation, we are encapsulating things. To involve the information hiding,
we have the private and public.
So it's a bit bigger concept.
The word abstraction is very common in computer science,
I would suggest you go and proceed with these links. People who have higher abstract thinking skills,
they can see the big picture,
they can see a lot of the WHAT and ignore the HOW
that isn't relevant to that.
One very relevant thing here in our software engineering industry is the managers like - think
about a company very big like Google or Amazon, for example, in the lowest level, you might have a software
engineer, above it
you have a tech lead, maybe above it
you have a manager level one, then another manager, then a third manager for this manager,
then a vice president, then blah, blah, blah,
till you end up say for a Jeff Bezos in Amazon, for example. Every one of these managers, if you
told Jeff Bezos about what is the design of specific functionality, he will know nothing about
it,
but he might know that this project exists in this department and that is it,
or the goal of this project is X, Y, Z,
but how is it implemented?
He doesn't know and he doesn't care.
One of the very common properties in managers, they can see in a high abstraction level, this why
they are really highly paid.
A lot of people need the implementation and this low level,
but to be at a very high level, managing fifty projects, and under you like 300
employees, you don't care a lot about the details
that aren't relevant to you.
You care about the WHAT and the very big picture from a level to another.
You see, what Jeff Bezos knows about the company. From a technical perspective is very less.
If you go lower in the managerial level, you find people who know more of the low level and less of
the high level.
You go higher in the hierarchy, you go higher and higher, and this takes to the concept of levels of
abstraction.
The higher the level, the less the details.
So you're thinking about the Google interface as a very high-level one.
It is the highest abstraction.
So, you know very less. Inside Google's search engine,
there are a lot of classes and a lot of components with different low levels of details.
So going back to the abstraction here in C++, we can see the abstraction exists from one side in the
private public section as an access modifier.
You see it also in the colon-colon scope resolution operator that separated for us the WHAT from the
HOW.
We also see it in the header files that we discussed before that separate the code into different files
so you again doing more separation.
This the header files if you remember.
So we create a header file for rectangle,
and then we started to put the declaration here for the rectangle, and then in the implementation file
you started to see how a rectangle is implemented,
and in your main, you just hash-include this rectangle dot-h. You as a user to
the rectangle, know nothing about how the rectangle is implemented,
and if we have a reason to change the implementation here, we just go and change it.
That's mainly what is abstraction.
That's it.