In this video, we will learn how to create a class using eclipse. You come here file, new class, and then
give the class name, let's say calculator, you notice it's going to create for us a header dot_h and dot_cpp.
...
When you learn about the inheritance, you can add here something that you are inheriting from it.
You can add a namespace, but I typically just go with the default
generation for me. If you clicked finish, two files would be created for you. A class ready for
you with construct and destructor, and the open implementation of that,
and then you keep going with them in the project.
If you would like to remove them, you just come here and delete them in a very normal way.
That's it.