In this video, we will learn how to create a class using codeblocks.
You come here new, and you select the word class, give it a name, let's say calculator.
You will notice there is a dot_h file that will be created for you, and CPP file which is looking at this header
file. There is also here
a bunch of other options like has a constructor, virtual destructor.
You will learn more about it during the class, you also learn about inheriting if there another the class.
You can create default member variables,
but personally I usually just created the default thing, added it,
OK, so now you notice we have now a class with the constructor and virtual destructor, we have here
the dot_h corresponding for it, and then you start to fill the missing here.
That's it.