The abstraction homework.
First, I would like you to create an analogy for the concept of encapsulation, data hiding, and abstraction.
In terms of your house components,
you have a bed rooms, store room, kitchen, beds, fridge.
You have some valuables that you should take care of, like money, jewelry.
You have things that have something that will work
like how works like TV, fridge, fan.
I would like you to try to make an analogy of all of these components to separate and realy ensure
that you realize the difference between the three concepts. The word context,
remember, we say context helps us to define what is relevant.
Let's say we have three separate projects, one for a kindergarten application, another for a college
student and another for college's gym application.
All of them has a student as a class.
Think in some common member variables for every one of them and think in one unique feature for each
one of them
given the different contexts between the three different items. Let's say that we have a building that
consists of apartments, elevators, each apartment has rooms, a bathroom, and so on.
I would like you to design and implement a set of classes in a simple way that represent the customer
requirements. The word
customer requirements is very common in software engineering.
This is what the customer really comes and asks us about it.
So think about some suitable member data and functionalities and think about what to provide a setters and
getters.
Invoice is a very common thing in hotels, online shopping, and so on. You are to design a simple invoice
class that has the following felids like - it just has some name, item number, some price and some
quantity.
As, for example, it could be an invoice for a single item that Acer laptop,
and this is a number, this is a price,
and this is a quantity that we took.
So we took here two laptops.
So it's like an invoice for a single item. Provide setters and getters for their functionality and provide
some function
like get total price, print to string, so get total price
now is two times this
number, to_string is returning a string like this guy, comma, separated. Implement them in one file,
but separate the declaration from the definition.
Feel free to separate also as a separate header file.
I would like you to read this program that has several set functionalities and get functionalities, and
guess the output of the program.
What is the name of this feature that has several functionalities of the same name?
Finally, we know that every variable in memory should have its own different address, but the question
here, in a class, would every member function also have their object
a different address.
For example, let's say we have an object lucky number and it has a print address functionality
and print it has a function, let's say print address, some functions name this way. Let's say we have
10 objects of lucky
numbers, would every one of them has a function that has a different address in memory, or they are sharing
the address of the function.
This exercise would like you to use this weird line, it says print, double quotes, and then it say
a reference of lucky number, print address.
This line is going to print the address of this function.
It's a C style, not c++. In C, it's is much easier to print the address of functionality. Develop a
very simple code to show if the address is going to be same or different for the member function from
an object to another.
That's it.