So far, we learned how to represent a group, I hope now you are very comfortable with graph representation.
You understand that the representation idea is a very generic idea.
We can build the many different representations based on our needs.
It could involve sets, hash tables, a lot.
A lot of things are based on our needs.
So I hope this idea is a good one.
So what we learned so far was how to represent the gap.
Now, the second part, which is the dominant party in graph theory, is the algorithm so that we run
on the graph.
There are many algorithms that we use on graph theory.
There are many of them.
And the reason behind that is graph theory is very powerful field.
We can find it everywhere around us, and we met a lot of problems during this course will cover assemble
of this graph theory algorithms.
I definitely don't intend to cover all of them.
So please said that the overall coverage would be pretty good if you have more more algorithms so that
you have an interest in them, go ahead and study them.
You will find a lot of materials out there.
But but the key message that I'm trying to get from the from the courts are here for you to know what
are the representation to be very flexible with them, to know how to apply some of the algorithms you
overdraft?
So let's proceed.
The first algorithm that we will will learn during the during this course is mainly the dips, the first
search algorithm.
So what is the big picture of that?
The graph traversal the what are the traversal mean just to iterate on something where they have an
array and enter it in all of its elements were traversing their array.
If I have a binary tree iterating all of elements, we say we are traversing the binary.
So graph traversal mean we have a big graph and we would like to iterate on all of its root.
Remember the printing function?
It's kind of a very simple traversal, but in reality, we need algorithms that are much more powerful
and do a lot of stuff.
So that is mainly two fundamental techniques for traversing the graph.
One of them named dips, a first search algorithm and another one named Deep Breath for a search algorithm.
And as a as a Titan's name with this one focused more on the going deeper.
But this one focused more on getting better, as we will at the depth of the research is mainly a recursive
technique and the recursion as we know, internet use the ability to stack when the other side.
The breadth is mainly an iterative technique, and it's usually used Q in that in the estimate, the
focus of this section is merely the depth of research.
The next one will be the breadth.
The depth already is based on recursion.
You must be like comfortable with the recursion.
I already added in the course of that, a basic review for the recursion.
This is mainly on what you need or in a different way.
You need to be comfortable with something like writing Fibonacci of and analyzing it.
Um, this kind of techniques work on all of kind of graphs directed and directed multiple.
It just looks like all of them are workable here.
So don't worry, don't keep asking, is this with the graphics?
Is the graph the algorithm works and all of them the same way?
So this is mainly the story of the traversal of the graph.
Before digging in the topic, in case you do know, I would like to highlight what does it mean to depth
and breadth in million our life?
So let me give you an example.
Let's say we have we have like a six about subjects of interest rate, language biology, chemistry
and so on.
And let's pretend that there are 100 books in every subject.
If you read too much of these books, like maybe 80 or more books, then it would be an expert here.
So as you see to be expert, you have to go deeper and deeper in something.
Now, every one of us has a maybe a specific measure in his life, like I'm a computer science student,
so I learned many computer science topics.
I am more specialized now in computer vision.
So I went to read deeper in this direction.
I learned a lot.
But if you asked me about maybe, maybe some networking of it, I would not have that much information.
Now this is what we call the Brits in the British side.
You do go deeper in something you explore in general.
For example, someone would like to have a breadth in these directions.
Well, let's start by reading maybe only one book on every subject.
So one subject here, one book here, one book here, one book here on book tour and book here.
Now this person has some kind of basic information about the different fields.
He is no way to be an expert in them, but he has pretty good background.
All of them.
Now what if the person would like to be more familiar?
It would take maybe one more book in every subject of that.
So to have a breath as a life concept, you explore different things without going deeper.
So you see, we keep exploring different things to have a depth, you keep exploring the same topic
and go deeper and deeper.
Now this is mainly what are the research topics.
The depth of research is about it.
So let's go back to our main topic here.
This is the first search is a recursive algorithm for traversing the graph.
The best thing really to to know what the defense is doing is merely to see how how to proceed.
This is the easiest way as a recursive algorithm and like many recursive algorithms, we can write it
like an iterative version using our own stack here.
But but this isn't of big interest for me at the moment.
So here is a flow of defense.
The defense starting from a specific mood will try all of the edges of this node for every edge it would
mark there the neighbor of this edge as a vista node.
This is very fundamental in terms of research.
And then it will start to recursive from this pivot and apply the same logic again and again.
And when the defense attorney back to this node and check the next edge, you first to check if it is
visited or not, if the neighbor is vested, it doesn't want to sit behind it.
Now, this could look like a very weird statements.
Let's see addressing a let's see a code for that.
Let's put that in a context.
This is a very common problem we call the reachability problem and the reachability women they would
like to know if yes and no due a ritual or not, for example.
But here in this graph, we see that no do and not for a ritual from each other.
Why?
Because there is some birth between them.
But we say that no two and no chicks are unreachable because the two cannot find the bath.
2.6.
So now let's let's have this simple task for every node in the graph.
I would like you to list all of the ritual nodes from it.
So, for example, here node number zero here has rechargeable of one and four and the three.
We don't care about those, I just lost them, but no one is reaching zero from here.
And also reaching forward from here and the ferry from here.
No, no to reaching No.
Zero and one and four, I'm sorry, node number three is reaching one, which also allow it to reach
zero and also allowing it to reach a full node number five, candidatura number six, number six reaching,
I think.
So this is merely the algorithm.
This is the reachability problem.
So let's let's put the the task for you in such a very high level.
Can you write a recursive could that we will give it an initial note and it tell us the ritual needs?
If you manage to implement that, you managed to implement to the dips of a social good at it.
Let's see the best thing really to understand the depth of her research is to check it's good.
So it is it is a good.
We have a function that tick the graph.
Let's assume for now the graph is a distance this this the this year, a disinterest.
Now, the reachability function is very trivial.
Iterate on every node.
It create a vector of Boolean.
Its size is vested out of it initially zeros and then it start to recurs with the defense function,
which is recursive function and say, Hey, here is the graph.
It is a starting node.
It is a Boolean array that all of it is vested.
So this is a very iterative, but we do it for every node from scratch.
Now that if this function does following, it is thought to by marking this node vested.
So it mark in the rate that this is listed node and then iterate on all of my neighbor's edge by edge
for every neighbor.
Like, if we have an energy to, let's say, starting from zero, let's say you have zero five an each
and we have zero and the nine as an edge.
So once enabled would be five and once would be night.
Now the first thing it will say.
Have we ever visited five before?
If the answer is yes, then we ignore it.
To understand the importance of this condition, imagine we have something like zero five and then we
have an to zero back.
So the decision is starting with not zero jumping to five, then five jumping two zero zero two five
five two zero.
This will go for infinity.
So what we do is we started with visiting not zero.
We marked that zero is wasted.
Now, zero has an edge to five.
We jumped to five here and then we mark five as Vista.
If I find that it has a neighbor that is zero, but zero is vested, so we don't use it anymore.
Now, when it comes to the gifts of could it say, hey, go ahead from grief to the neighbor here,
which is why, for example, imagine that this recursion is done and the listed array, which is by
reference, has been changing a lot.
When we go back to the new neighbor zero, the neighbor zero will continue the mortgages, for example,
imagine zero as ages seven and or nine, so it will start to recover from seven once a decision is done.
It will start to decreasing from that.
This is a high level forth happening here, which might not be intuitive for some of you.
So let's make a big and good tracing here.
I'm taking a small subset of the code here.
I'm going to trace for you what was what will the stack therefore like?
How is our stack step by step so that you can understand really what's happening here?
Assume that the reachability function a miracle here was Griffis and are equal to.
So let's see what's happening.
The first step in this algorithm is to mark visited Node two visited, introduced to the node is two,
so we mark visited here as to now a question for you.
Who are the neighbors of two?
There's only one neighbor.
So this for loop, will it read only one time in the first iteration, the neighbor will be zero.
So now the question would be is zero wasted, the answer is no.
Only two is wasted so far.
So now that it would recurs on the graph, but was able to zero.
So now we have a recursive call.
So let's go now.
The active call is the Office of Zero.
Division two is waiting for our return.
Now this is zero.
What a start.
By marking itself as vested vested, then who are the neighbors of note zero zero has two neighbors,
node number one and number three.
So this four group should work twice in the first time we were check neighbor for that one.
And then we will do separate occasion, maybe.
And after we return later, we will go back to the next neighbor, which is three.
So I would like you to keep this big picture in your mind.
Zero will go to one, then some recursive calls, and once it back, zero will try the three, but merely
trick of its visited or not.
Anyway, so far, zero has an issue for one and has an edge of three zero.
The chick is one visited.
No.
It started decreasing from from the one.
So let's see.
Now, the active recursive call is one and zero is waiting and two is waiting.
One has.
Three.
One has two neighbors, which are zero and four now, but no one is starting to trade with near zero
and then the neighbor thought and the neighbor zero, it will ask, is zero visited?
The answer is yes.
Ignore it.
If we didn't, we would go in an infinite loop here.
So this is very common to get a divorce and end up with an infinite loop.
OK, so zero is ignored.
The next is it.
No food, no food.
No food.
Neighborhood is for visited.
The answer is no.
So we recurs Ed Wood.
I would like you to get the sense that you are a visitor that you have so far retreated from not two,
not zero.
And now we are iterating to look forward.
And I also would like you to note that this age from two to zero is bolded because we made this recursive
call 01 is bolded.
We ignored one zero and no jumping to four.
So here to observe we have this three edges referring to our activist stack, the edges that we really
used, the dotted line here refer to an issue that we ignored.
Now we are at for.
There is only one neighbor here, which is not three.
So that recursion will iterate here at the nodes, which is just not three is that he visited.
The answer is no.
So occurs three.
So again, we go here at three three, has only one food, which is one nibble, which is what now that
occasion is one visited.
Yes.
Ignore it now, node number three, does it have any more neighbors?
So what would happen is this is now as it occurs.
This is the first recursive function that start to end.
So this function should go out of the stack and now we go back to the office of node number four.
And as you see, this edge has been ignored and this edge has been ignored.
Now the DFS at four continue.
But remember that difference of what has undergone a child, which is now done.
So this recursive could also done, though this function also ended.
So this function end and then fast forward is ended.
So recursion goes back one step.
At the first one, the first one had a child the year which was finished, and it showed the four,
which is also finished.
So the first one also as a recursion is done.
So now we are, there was the first one.
Let's go back.
No one will go back to the office of Zero.
Remember that zero has two neighbors one, two and three.
And we were in the active call of the Office of One.
When the occasion is done, a divisive one, we go back to zero.
It resumes to the next node, which it knew number three.
So this Farooq now iterating one more step to check neighboring country.
But you will notice that Vista of Neighbor three is true, which means that this one is already visited.
So this one will be skipped, too.
So now Node zero also is going to end.
It's it's a good.
Now we go back to node number two.
We go now to A..
Number two, I should make this that it sort of or that this one should be docked at once.
Now number two has only one edge, which is done.
So we are just finished.
As you see, node number two managed to mark in the budget array two zero one three four.
So the Boolean array represent who are the reachable nodes, the twisted array represent who are the,
uh, the visited nodes and observed in the reachability function.
We were resetting this array every time because in every state, every time we would like to start from
scratch from a specific node to cover all of its root just for fun.
What if node number two already has another child here, which is going from two to five?
If this is the case, then no number two after returning from node number zero would recurso node number
six five, which would recursive node number six, which will try to recursion itself.
But nothing happened.
Go back, go back.
So as you see, we we trade back here.
And I would like you to I would like to confirm again that this bolded edges represented that Beth is
that we took we call this bold edges, we call them tree edges, we call them tree edges.
No, that is something very interesting about being a researcher that you should know that this we really
ignore the many edges because these edges will create cycads, the remaining of the edges that we didn't
ignore under a tree.
If you thought about it, you would notice that all of this edges are a tree.
You will notice that they are a tree within only the eligible nodes.
OK, so the graph, for example, has zero one two and the five from here.
So four four four zero, let's say we have also this one and this one four zero, it will get this edge
and it will get this edge and it will skip this one.
And let's give this one and this one anyway, not reachable for us.
So these two represent like a depth of first tree.
So what is the depth of first the tree?
It is the bolded edges that we have from the tree.
And also, if you thought about it, it's actually a rooted tree and two is the root.
So every edge, as you see, if you try to grow that, it would be like the following two zero at this
level and five at this level five has six.
This level here zero has one.
Then one has four, then four has three.
So this is a rooted tree with the root is the value number two.
Um, I hope that this tree thing is good enough as you see every node, richard only through one edge.
That's why you must have it as a tree.
Uh, yeah, this is mainly what I wanted to explain in the depth first search.