Let's solve the homework, the first problem about the sub islands.
So let's see in this problem, we can definitely implement the problems in many different ways.
So here is the most efficient and even simplest one among all of them.
They do this following, and you will notice during the four problems.
I'm trying to reduce the problem to use the defense in a very standard and very simple way.
So here is the idea we will perform the standard connected component code on the grid to in a very straightforward
way.
Now we would like to mark for every phone component if it is inside the grid one or not.
So this is a minor modification we will do during tracing grid two.
We will notice if it's still in grid one or not, it isn't.
We just will discard it here.
Uh, yeah, that's it.
Um, by the way, I use this for educational purposes.
Mainly, I use the the grid itself to be a visited array instead of writing one.
So let's see here.
This is a normal directional race.
This is a normal is invalid, right?
I did hear a Boolean which would reset in every call to know if this is the status of Ireland or not.
Now let's go to them.
Ian Burt.
In the main board, I have here the count that we need, like a normal connected components, we would
iterate on all of the rules and all of the columns every time which is invested or not.
I use it the grid itself to market vested interest.
So if it is, if the grid get it to an RC, is it still would this mean it is a new connected components?
So are you?
Are you to set the Boolean value to be true?
I do the normal defense.
After I back, I would add one.
If so, Ireland zero, if not, so let's see the recursion here.
The RNC was great to too will perform a very normal defense.
We check if we are integrity or not.
We check if we are visited before or not.
We said it as visited as usual.
We treat on the forbearance and call it so this is standard defense calls.
Now, the extrovert is here in every location where there is a grid for two, an RNC.
There must be also grid around.
Get it to.
And obviously, if the case isn't, then we know that this isn't a sub island.
So we just return and we don't need to continue anymore.
So again, the idea was as following we would do this first in a very normal way on grid to why we are
tracing grid to.
We will make sure that we are still even but off grid one.
If it isn't, we just make ourself as if some island was false.
And that's it.
Uh, yes.
So this is the moral of that.
I hope the idea is in the thought.
Let's see the second, the problem, the second, the problem is about coloring the border itself.
Now, let's see here.
This time, I would like to to to take instead of the smartest approach, I will take the safest approach,
and the reason behind that is a good impression that there could be different ways that create several
bugs.
And I want to be as like as simple and as clear as possible.
So I'm going to do the following.
First of all, I would run a defense in the grid to market the reachability in the standard way.
We would only market the array as usual, would not touch the metrics as usual once we are done with
the defense.
I will do an iterative procedure that will check for me which nodes are the boundary?
We can do both of them together in the defense.
But as I said, I try to keep the defense good as a standard as possible.
So let's see here.
The direction there is valid and everything here.
Now this is a defense, it is a very standard defense.
We have the like, the flood code, the twisted array, the color to match, if it is vested, if it
doesn't match color return mark existed.
Do the four calls very standard one?
No, here I create the Vista array.
I do this first and a standard way.
And this is the nutritive function.
It the grid, the vista array and you cut it.
So let's see what happened in this function.
This function is very simple.
It just applied the two rules in the problem.
So we iterate in every cell and then iterate on that for directions.
This condition should be above you, but know it doesn't matter.
Now, if this cell is invested, it is in part in a way if my connected component, so I should just
ignore it.
Otherwise, I will give the neighbor.
There are two cases that makes me a boundary.
The first case is I am outside the grid has been said.
The second case is I have a neighbor that doesn't belong to my connected component.
So these two conditions are the implementation of the two conditions in the problem statement.
So again, the way that I took a safe approach is do normal defense, then find the boundary.
Can we do both of them together?
Yes.
But you need to be careful and maybe even bothering for you here when you think about it is very straightforward.
We separate thing.
The code is it's very easy.
I don't need to prove it or verify it or anything.
It's very clear that the defense is right.
We applied the boundary conditions correctly.
We are on the safe side.
That's all.