Problem number three, and we would like to find the closed islands.
Now in this problem, what will really make our life easier is assemble observation.
What really makes a connected component to closed?
Simply, it doesn't touch any boundary at all.
So we have here agreed here.
Now, let's say there is some connected component here.
It is definitely, definitely across the connected component.
Why?
Because it would be surrounding from here and from any internet, if any case, with other, with other
ones, with other values.
This is the definition of a connected component.
There is nothing else that can connect to it.
Now, if there is a connected component is here, this is definitely Boundary Y because it is has it
is enclosed because it is touching the extent of that of the boundary.
So it's actually in this problem.
If you understood the problem statement really well before just the jumping to solve it, you recognize
that if my connected component is touching this great boundary here or this grid boundary here or this
grid boundary here or this grid boundary here, it cannot be a closed island.
Otherwise, it's just a closed island.
So that symbol?
So the message here is sometimes you need to make some thinking, some analysis.
Don't rush with the first idea in your mind.
I know that you might eventually managed to get it accepted, but maybe you wrote a lot of unnecessary
goods.
Maybe you observe yourself in a wrong direction.
So this is a point here.
Think a little bit deeper now for educational purposes.
I'm going to instead of the building the the the Vista array as a Boolean, I'm replacing it with something
else.
I'm going to replace it with the connected component, i.e. no.
For example, let's say that this is a first connected component to meet.
I would give it what is one one one one one one.
This is the second communiqu convert that would make it two two to two.
This is the third connector, what, three three three three.
This is very useful in some other problems where we would like to know what are the exact indices of
a connected component or anything.
So this is another way if you if you need the exact values of the connected component, you can use
the values.
Otherwise we can use a Boolean for one.
So to see the could here, the goods are going to be very straightforward.
I have here a Boolean variable that say during building there, during building that connected component.
Have we ever touched one of the four boundaries the top left, top row?
Last call us through the first two column.
Not any of them.
If yes, then this isn't and is a closed island.
And here the implementation would be very straightforward, like any normal connected component.
We trade on the rows and columns and then, uh, CCI ID is the connector converter ID instead of the
Vista Ray.
So see here the connector computers.
You market them starting from one so that you can differentiate if it's listed or not.
So I would always from what you see here, the connected component is zero.
I will.
What I would like to make a device, I would make B+ Plus.
This is very important to avoid bugs, and it's not always connected computers from one.
So now the collector convert, it is zero then it never touched before, and in the same time, the
value should be zero.
They say that the zeros would represent their goods.
So what I said to the touch boundary was false to the defense increment if it never touched the boundary.
The difference now is very straightforward.
This is the normal part.
This is a normal.
I'm guessing here the current convert is.
So every time we visit the route, we give it the same idea.
Previously, we just put it one here.
Now, the only change is if we have ever at any point of time, Touch ID, one of the four boundaries
we just the market that is touch boundary is true.
And how is this function implemented?
Somebody, you have the row and column, you just need to check if you are the first through or through
the first column or the rascal, if any of that is false, then.
And if that's true, then we actually touched the boundary.
Otherwise we are on the syllabus.
So as you see, the problem is straightforward when you think in it based on this observation, otherwise
you might actually complicate the code.
As you see, this is the third.
The problem we are managed.
I managed to solve it with the standard defense as it is.
I haven't to change, like bring a new theory or any advanced thing so far.
OK, let's see the fourth problem which is detecting their cycle.
I added the second example here, so we would like to detect this like and now this might be might seems
for a while tricky, but I will show you that it isn't.
Now let's remember, why do we need Vistara?
I'm here at this node, and I let's maybe this is a better example, this one, this one.
None of them is good enough.
Let me let me build my own grades.
Let's say we have a grade here.
Let's pretend you have your ay ay ay ay ay ay ay ay ay ay ay ay ay ay ay.
Let's say you started here.
Why do we need the victory?
There are two cases.
The first one is well when we move to the next node.
Let's go and market this one here, market this one here, a market, this one here.
I'm lucky this one here.
This one here might go up to try this one here, but we visited it already.
So one reason to avoid their cycles is to use this array here so that I don't go to a node that is visited
or ready.
The other case, which is successful here, you moved from this one to this one.
This one will try to go back to this one.
So this one is like its appearance and it came to me.
Now we should also go back to that.
To the beer and to note.
So if you thought about it, this is why we use the mystery to avoid the infinite cycles, which come
for two reasons you are there trying to go back to your parent, the one that called you or you are
visiting and know that you visited before now thinking about the cycles.
The reason that we have a site is we are revisiting a route that we visited before.
So I moved from here to here to here to here to here.
Wait.
We visited this one before, so we would like actually to say, you know what, if you visited the node
that you visited before, this is like?
But there is a problem here now.
If I if am trying to visit my beer and let's say we have only here we have this food is OK, which is
the minimum length of the cycle.
So we go from here to here to here.
If this one is trying to go back here, it would say it is visited.
But wait, it is in a cycle.
This is your appearance.
So this is the node that generated you.
So this isn't a cycle.
So now it the trick.
We will we need the vista, Ray, to tell us if this node is visited before or not, but we need to
be careful about going back to where you came from.
So if we managed to split these two cases, we would be able to use the Vista Array as air signal if
we are a cycle or not.
Let me show you the implementation.
This might be a bit hard.
The idea is this following this is our defense.
We will use a very normal device.
We will have two extra indices for one column, which is the bit through and bittencourt it means which
Birand, which rows and column I am coming from them.
And never, ever try to go back to your parents, if you did that, then the visited array would be
visited only in one case if you are making a cycle.
So here's what happened.
This is very normal.
Vistara, this is a very normal defence.
We have the row and column.
We have the grid.
We have the brilliant array.
We have the color.
If it is inverted, you go back.
If it doesn't match the color, you go back.
Leave this one for now here.
Now we mark visited with urgency, as usual, we get the the election as usual.
Now this is only one condition Europe adding Here I'm say, let's say I am in this thread, which is
RNC.
And a zombie to this one, which is new or new, see here, but I know that my variant is this and see
if this one is trying to go back to the Birand.
Don't do that.
So actually, we will go only to three choices, not four.
So if I'm here.
If I was here and jump to hear this one would have only three choices go up.
Go ride, go down.
But it would not go to the beer and it would not go.
Go to the one that generated me.
Now, if this is a case.
Then the vista right here will be true if and only if we come back to a quote that we visited before,
and this would happen only and cycle of for already.
So we do need to verify anything about the rest of the second.
So let's see an example here.
Let's say we have a a a a a a and there is a B in the middle.
This one?
Go here.
This one cannot go to work to the bitter end, but can go here, which you can go here.
This one cannot go back here.
This one can go here, can go here.
Cannot go back and go here.
Can go here, can go here vested.
This means a cycle.
I hope you now got it.
This dirty trick is very common and very important and and you should see it in many times, it seems
like after the good, don't fix it.
So the moral of that is that this thing is happening from two things.
It happened from coming about going back to my beer, the one who generated me or actually visiting
something new, different.
Now in this good, the new trick is we split the two cases.
So this is case number one.
We prevent it here fundamentally from the beginning, and this is case number two at any point of time
who vested in this condition.
We definitely have a second.