I would like here to share with you something a bit advanced.
I would like you to know about it, which is the reductions to graphs.
What does it mean?
Would the reduction has a lot of meanings.
Sometimes when you read the problem, let's say I'm telling you you have a matrix and this matrix has
a cell here and there is a treasure in and out of the cell and would like, you know, if the if the
man can find the treasure or not, you can see that this is a matrix.
Every node is there.
Actually, every every word is actually a node.
You can know that because matrices are anyway graphs.
Sometimes you read the problem and there is zero connection with graph theory, and you don't even think
that this has a relationship with graffiti at all.
And with some smart observations, you can model it as a graph.
Why this category of problems is very hard because you don't see the graph, you don't have a graph
problem.
It is invisible at all.
So what happened is you don't consider graphs.
However, it is possible using graphs.
Let me give you a great example here.
Let's say I give you a bunch of fractions here, like maybe fraction number one, equal a over B symbols
and the values is that say, here are four B, let's say was value number three, for example, fraction
two.
It is symbols B oversea and let's see the value is half production.
Three.
Let's say symbol C over the and the value is four.
And I.
First of all, do you see any connection with graphs?
Can you spot anything?
OK.
Let me ask you the task, because that is what is the fraction value of E250 know mathematically, Eovaldi
can be committed from, um, from if one finds, if at all times everything we can do that by our mind,
this is the which will be eventually like a over b times, b over c times c over the.
It over the which is eventually three times before 12 would half is six value.
Let me ask you again, do you see any connections with graphs?
What what if I asked you for the value of be over, for example, or anything like that?
You have to make a lot of resolving, right?
Can you see a relationship of the graph?
OK.
It is a relationship.
If you thought that every symbol is A..
So we have here A. A.
It would be no see, no deal, and the production value represent an inch.
So we have an idea from A to B with the value of three and have an edge from B to E with the value of
one over three.
And we have an edge from B to C would have.
And we have an edge from sea to B was one Oberhof, which is two.
And we have an edge of from Setoodeh with um c 2D with wood and from D to C with one over four, which
is zero point two five.
Now, this is a graph.
OK?
What is the fraction value from A to Z?
It equals the multiplication of the ages from eight to D so far and now the multiplication of HD, which
is that here is an inch.
It is an edge.
There is an edge.
The answer is three times half times four.
What about that?
The answer from what is the value of C over eight, for example, is again, it is a best two.
And here is the best two.
So we can see that the answer of C over eight is just two over three.
Now you see, we can even with fractions in a very nice and easy way with just finding a better multiplying
its values.
So the key here is it's very hard to see that this problem is a graft problem.
Very, very hard, the problem.
But you see someone can spot that this is an edge and this is an engine, this is an edge.
Let me give you another problem.
This is a geometric problem.
Can you model it as a graph like assume that I'm asking you for the for the maybe, maybe this distance
or anything?
I will not go into details here.
What is the graph?
If you started to think about the intersection points here, like this point here, this one here,
this one here, this one here, maybe also this one here, this one here, you can think of this intersection,
but this may be as a graph and connections between them as it just that has some distance.
I know the folly of imagination and treatment of the problem isn't clear because I don't give details,
but I wanted to tell you.
You see how very far from graph theory, but you can spot some graph relationship.
It needs a lot of smartness and a lot of creativity so that you can figure out where are the graphs.
So there are no rules for that.
I cannot write for you some rules or even better for that.
This is one of the hardest types of problems.
And even practically speaking, there are a few problems that will have this this idea.
It happens a lot that we can like.
Maybe.
Generally speaking, we have some problem and we see that this problem can be represented as a graph
or maybe have a problem and see that this problem maybe can represent it as a geometry problems.
Uh, yeah, this kind of reduction is one of the hardest skills ever, and it takes a lot of time and
experience to develop them.
Solve.