Homeworker number three, in the defense, this three homeworkers are merely based on their graph reduction
that we just learned.
So I would like you to note that many of these problems might be solvable in different ways.
Now I would like you here to practice that, um, how to reduce a problem to the graph.
So you should only focus on solving the problem based on a graph observing that this is actually a very
big hint for you, that I told you that this problem can be reduced to a graph.
In fact, if the graph is the only way to solve the problem and you don't get this head, it probably
would be pretty hard for me for you to reduce it to the graph.
So anyway, you are just here practicing the scheme of reducing something to graph.
So let's see the first.
The problem is this following we had some graphs, so we have some array of unique elements, let's
say one two, three four, and then we forgot this array.
But we remember one thing, we remember the adjacent two beers, for example.
I can tell you that I remember that one and two were a decent.
I remember that four and three were adjacent.
I don't remember the exact order.
Like, I don't mean that food was before three.
I know that four and three were adjacent.
So how many adjacent to beer are in a reference in?
There are in the minus one adjacent two beers.
So the problem will give you in the minus one adjacent two beers and you have to recover their original
array.
The input would be completely correct, but observe the following There can be multiple solutions.
Any of them is okay.
Also, observe the values of the array itself are in a huge range.
Remember, they are unique.
Don't miss, uh, critical conditions.
So let's see, uh, an example here.
What we remember that two and one, three, four, three and two were adjacent to values.
So no one solution is one two three four.
So you see here, one two is a decent yes.
Three four extensions.
Yes.
Three two is a decent yes.
So this is a valid and this isn't the only valid one.
It is another case, I tell you.
Four minus two and one for minus three.
One is this is a does it?
Does it match four minus two?
Yes, they are here one in four.
Yes, they are here minus three and one.
Yes, they are here.
So this is adjacent beers.
Uh, yeah, probably number two.
We have a stringers.
And you will be given an array of beers.
So it's a victory, it is just two numbers.
They are zero based indices.
So beers of indices in within that within that length of the stick.
Now what is the point?
You can swap the beer, the characters in this in any bit of indices, any number of times you can make
such a swings in number of times.
So you can take beer number, for example, number two, and you find the answers to insipid.
You can swab.
As of two and as of seven.
You can do this works at any number of times in any order, in anything.
Now what is a good assume that we have all of the whistleblowers things that we can generate from this
operation?
We would like to find the leaks who graphically smallest one.
Don't be confused by all the leaks graphically.
It just mean, according to the English dictionary, it is the smallest one.
So it mean among all of them.
So to them and bring the first one.
So this is mainly what you should do in this problem.
Let's see an example here.
We have this strange guest this cab.
And these are our beers.
Now, if you try to swab, it's zero and it's a free coming from the free spirit.
So the new string would be said as we swab the zero and the three.
If you then swab the one and two from the second beer, then you could be back.
Now obesity is the smallest possible strength you can generate by applying the well, that's worse in
any order and in a bar of types.
Let's see another example here.
We have a bunch of of of elements.
Uh, uh, let's see this one because we will apply the same swab twice.
So we have here the string that is C, B and the.
So we have indices zero, one or two.
Now we can take the first to be of zero and one a.
So here is a first two beers so bright you could be C and E.
Now you can take the second beer and a blight, which will take the second two letters which are here
and Oblates.
It will give us B E and the C, then a back again.
The first two two indices, which are B, so serve them.
It's no e b and C.
Now ABC is a small list of possible string among all of the things that you can generate.
I hope you good the idea.
In the third, the problem we would be given unsorted array.
Now.
This array.
Have different sequences.
I would like to find the length of the length of the longest consecutive sequence of elements.
What does it mean?
Look to this sequence here.
Remember, the sequence can be any subsidy you don't have to be like consecutive here.
So if we notice this subsidy for and one and three and two.
If you try to search this number, you will be one, two, three four, which is what we call a consecutive
sequence of consecutive sequels.
So one two three four is the length of their longest consecutive sequence.
So let me say that again.
You would be given an array by some numbers inside it, such that when you sorted them, they are considered
of sequence.
Now, among all of such impossible sequences would like to find the length of the longest one here.
In this example, here, the array is a single sequence.
If you sorted out of the array, it would be from zero to nine.
And so maybe another example in case let's say I give you numbers like 10 to 11, three and 12.
So if you take these 10, was this 11?
Was this 12 and sorted, then they would be 10, 11 12, which are sequence consecutive numbers.
Uh, two and three are also another consecutive number, but just the rent is too, so actually we have
also two and three.
So the array has different sequences.
Some sequences could be consecutive and some are, and we would like to find the lens of the longest
one among all of them.
Notice that the array is big and the values are huge.
That's all.