It's all home.
Number three.
The first problem about the restoration of the.
I hope when I told you that this is a graft problem, you manage easily to figure out what's happening
like one might tell himself.
What if every number is ignored?
So if the input is, for example, let's say here?
Yeah, that's generally the case one, two, three four five.
If I told you the bill, we had one and two and another beer maybe was like five and four and another
beer with two and the two under three and another beer.
As for, uh, four and three.
So I give you that one.
Now, if you started to think, what if every number isn't?
Now, every every adjustment can be an edge you saw one and two is an adjacent edge.
And then five and four is an adjustment edge two and the three is in a edge, four and three is an adjacent
edge.
Now when you look at it, you observe that this is actually creating a chin, right?
Nothing more than that.
And clearly.
We have two solutions.
One two, three four five is a solution.
Five four three two one is a solution.
This two solution satisfy the condition.
So this is how we converted the problem to graph by considering every number as a node, every relationship
between two numbers as an edge.
And this is actually a common way like there are many of the reduce the graphs can be eventually based
on the different numbers are nodes and the different and the relationship between the numbers are ages.
So keep that between you.
You remember the fraction case when we mentioned it over B and B or C again, it was no and B is no
and that it isn't possible, isn't it?
So keep that in mind when you have a bunch of values.
They are the nodes and the relationships are between them.
These are the edges.
So all what we need is to build the graph and find the chin begin.
Now what is the champion begin?
There is a trivial observation here to know about that.
So let's say the graph is one, two, three and four and five.
We know that we can either start from the word, get all of this once or the five and get all of this
once, we would like in an efficient way to know if this is the beginning of the chin or not.
There is a pretty simple observer here.
Every node has two neighbors like two has one and three three.
A strong four foot has three and five, except one and five.
If one of them has only one neighbor.
So this means iterate on the values, and the one who has only a single neighbor is there.
Graph is a champion can be achieved begin, which would be only the one or five here.
Uh, finally, like many problems based on numbers, you should expect that the values would be pretty
huge.
So instead of using the normal adjacency graph, we would use that, uh, Will has to use a hash table
here.
So we already made this could be for the one that is based on the festival.
So here is the hash table.
Here is the creation of eight.
This is a device that if this would have this time and order the set and um.
And here we are iterating whether it was in the normal way, I would like to tell you something recursion
that is based on trees and.
So the first that is based on trees and the chains can get rid of the wasted how.
With the burden to track weeks to blend in the detective cycle problem, like, let's say we are at
one two three four.
Why do we need visited to not visit the news that we visited before?
So too will make a cycle only by visiting the parent?
So if you have a value that say which, which is my bit and you just you are to go to three, but don't
go to what you are three, go to four, but don't go to two.
So this is how we can get rid of the victim.
But anyway, I'm leaving it here because it's more generic treatment here.
Now we created the hash table graph iterate on the beers bit by bit.
I hope you.
You are familiar with that.
I'm trying to avoid too, using modern syntax as much as I could, because I know many people do not
study modern C++ like they simply don't care.
Many people stop before C++.
Even some people know about some features about C++, and this is the reason why I don't use a lot here
a modern C++.
But anyway, let me give you a very first idea here.
And when we say, Oh, two x equals one C++ compiler, we know that this is integer, so we remove.
Although it would be automatic and replaced by integer when we say all to be equal, make underscore
it of two and the three, it would remove water and make it like beer of int.
And then so the word or two here is just an automatic way, so always know that this is going to be
replaced with something now the adjacency the graph is actually stable, so it would be bits of fruit.
So so the the the for now, this is a second thing in the modern C++ here.
When I do four or do something for something, it's going to iterate an element by element.
So if you have vector of integer, you can say for integer X in Vector V or you can say four or two
x in V.
These are the same here.
Now we are iterating on what vector of vector of integer.
So for all to hear this internally, it would be actually a vector of integer.
So this one is as simple as fourth vector.
Of eight.
Beer ad beers.
OK, so the the the word 02 will be replaced by victor of integrated beer.
So now beer is just a simple array of two valleys zero and one.
I hope you got it.
But is the search for this interesting style and C++?
Now we created the graph by adding all of their relevant roots, and we created an ordered set up.
I'm using the DFS based on the like the connected nodes, the numbers so that we can return to them
actually here.
So I'm going to iterate on the graph adjacency list one by one.
It is, yeah.
The graph here is the nude, the second, which is, uh, the neighbors equity equal one, which means
that this node has a single neighbor.
So this is enough so we can divest from here and break it here.
And that's a tier that the defense is a very normal defense.
But this is, you know, instead of marking would add here that would for us to.
I hope overall, the idea is clear enough.