Let's solve the second problem, which might be a bit harder for you.
Um, but the problem would be pretty easy if you, Richard.
The very fundamental observation in the observation is is following let's say we have some beers, for
instance, following zero three three six, six, nine, nine and two.
Now, the observation is, is following, let's say I swab maybe nine and 12.
So the two characters here swept, then I swab the they're six and nine, then three and six, then
zero three.
What happened is we moved that character that was originally a 12 to the character at Index Zero.
So if you thought about it, if we have a bunch of related beards in this way who are connected with
each other, we can actually make the swab such that we move the character anywhere in the characters.
So then this is you two, three, six, nine and 12.
Here we can arrange their corresponding characters in any way that we need.
Why?
Because we can do the swings in any order, any number of times.
So if I would like to get that character, no later six at 12, I can just make what is one here and
then want to swap here for I would like to get there.
Maybe the three at nine here I can swab and swab.
I got it here and so on.
So this is the observation here.
We can make any number of flips and move the character anywhere within the connected values here.
So if we can do that now, all what we need is there could be a lot of beers and arranged in a very
complex way.
But if you thought about it, this arrangement is actually can be a graph.
So here is the idea.
Again, we would use the values as the indices this time would use the indices as our nodes.
So when you say we have, for example, 12 letters in the string would have to advance.
So here zero and the three would be a would be an edge.
Three and six would be an age six and nine would be an age that in what would be another age?
Now, let's say there is also in with like five and seven, then five and seven on edge.
OK, let's say that three is also can be swabbed with a four, then three can also be swabbed with four.
Let's say that also nine can be swabbed with five.
The nine can be also swabbed with five.
If I have a letter at five, I can move it anywhere between this indices.
So the idea is the following we would build the graph undirected based on these relationships, then
find the connected component of each one of them.
Now the letters of this connected component can be arranged in any way.
So logically, we would just sort them like, get the corresponding string and sorted.
This is how we need it in the original string.
Nuts are huge.
So be careful.
You have to make sure they cover all still linear in terms of number of adjacent vertices.
So let's see here the implementation.
The adding direct graph is a standard, the defense is a standard, not nothing, can you hear?
So this defense is just it built for us, the connected connected component, the nodes, as we did
before.
Now, let's see here we have the graph in inroads in a normal way, we iterate on the bears, I didn't
use the.
Here we add the other two graph from the 0.1 and one the first of the value of the second the value.
This is the normal Boolean array to before the connected components.
We start here iterating when the nodes one by one.
Every we see is this index visited before.
If not, then this index is a new connected component.
We bear with the nodes and the office.
Now, once we return it from the nodes here, this one, let's say in the is zero, three, five and
12.
This for once can be arranged in any way.
So we iterate on the original string and get the letters corresponding to the Index zero index of three
five.
And it will.
Now we would like to make this thing as lexicon as possible.
So here's what we'll do.
We will sort of there.
Indices then sort their letters, and we will put these letters in this indices.
For example, let's see then this is where five, one and seven.
Order them, they will be one, five and seven.
Let's say the letters of one, five and seven, whereas following like maybe this was later said, maybe
this was letter A. Maybe this smoother, uh, let's say this is B and this is a so sort of the string.
Also, it will be A and B and the Z now in index one.
What a an index of five would be in index seven, but Z.
So this way, in the corresponding budgets for this connected component, we put the indices to the
best of them and observe that every connected component is separated from the others.
I hope you enjoy this problem.
It's pretty, pretty fundamental and pretty pretty A. Problem.