Let's solve the third problem, the longest consecutive sequence this problem Lake.
Contrary to the previous two problems, like the previous two problems of the graph solution is playing
a big role in this problem is actually the right way isn't a great business solution, but we will still
show how a graph based solution can be used in this problem, which will certainly be very interesting
but still tricky to implement.
So the first the question here, how can we represent a set of numbers as a graph?
We did that so far several times, right?
This is the fourth time to do that.
So I hope that you note that how many times of this problem, the numbers can be represented as a graph.
So if we have numbers like one two three four five, what make it in terms of a graph as a conservative?
So again, again, let's say one, two, three, four and five are nodes.
Now let's see also that we have here it was us.
In terms of consecutive to create a graph, what makes sense is.
Conservative values need to be connected, so if that is it, it also we don't connected with anyone.
Why?
Because there is no relationship.
So the sense of here is as following if you have a bunch of conservative numbers, you better connected
them with each other.
So the idea now would be pretty simple.
Dig the array converted to graph that symbol.
OK, how can we build the graph efficiently?
We would like only to make it just between consecutive numbers.
How can I know if these two numbers are conservative?
As simple as the following.
Let's say I give you the input as following.
I told you that the input is one seven two three six 10.
Now we know that we have all of this as news for us, so let's say we have the rule number one now.
Now we know that there is between one two, but how to know that simply check if one plus one exist
or not, one plus one is two does to exist in the in the numbers.
Yes.
Then there must be one or two here.
Now take seven.
So we have seven, as in the civilian six exists.
What is after seven eight?
Does it exist?
It doesn't exist.
So leave it now to.
Does 2+1, which is three, exist?
Yes.
No, there must be an edge here.
Six, the seven exists.
Yes, then six and seven must be connected.
10 does 10 exist?
Does 11 exist?
No.
So the idea is very trivial.
We would like to build the edges between that and Verblitz one.
So for every value check of the next one for it, exist or not, if it exists, then we have an edge.
Now we build two there.
The graph, the graph consist of simple nodes like then here or a chains.
This is actually a bunch of chains, and the task now is as simple as justifying the chain that has
the longest number of nodes that symbol.
And as we did before.
How to know the start or the end of the chain, the fittest or the end would have degree of one.
But the middle values would have to.
That's all.
The problem is solved, but sadly you have to be careful in your implementation about a few special
cases.
One case, if the graph is empty, then the answer is logically zero.
Another case is the graph has maybe like, let's say we have like one in 10.
So this is actually two separate nodes.
And it might be tricky, like it depends on your implementation.
So for me, I need to make sure of if there are no edges and there are at least nodes, then there are
stability.
So the answer is one.
So let's see the implementation here.
One other one, one more, one more tricky here, like, as I said, you should be able to get a careful
implementation, doubling good values like, let's say we have 0001.
So you will go to the first number and say zero is what exists.
Yes, zero one here.
Exist now.
Oh, zero and one exists.
Yes, zero one exists.
Zero one exists.
What's the problem with that?
You will.
We will not be able to figure it out there first, the value of the chain.
So you only need to keep one of them because we said that the chain is mainly based on the one that
has only one neighbor.
But this now it has three neighbors and they are useless.
So be careful also about duplicate value.
Overall, it's nice, but it's a bit tricky to implement.
OK, we will use an order, the map, because the values are big.
This is a normal way.
This is a defense that returned their number of nodes in their.
We'll come back to it now later.
So let's go to the implementation here.
First of all, I take all of the victor values and add them in the set.
So now we have an order that has all of the values.
If the set size is zero, return is zero cinemagraph, otherwise create a graph iterate on the values.
This is how we treat on a certain model C++.
If the set we have the value here, let's say seven.
If this it has a value of eight, then we know that seven and eight are an inch.
Now the graph is done next.
Well, I'm going to initialize the maximum 6cm bullet with the value one.
Why?
Because now we know, we don't know there are some nodes, so maybe in the worst case, we would have
something like that.
So that said, in a way is one node that one values are considered consecutive.
Otherwise we will have a change of like one and two and three and so on.
So this is mainly for a case like one in 10.
In a very normal way would make our defense.
And here we will say the following if this note hasn't been visited before and the size of the decency,
this is one which you mean it is ahead of the adjacency test.
I'm going to make defense from this note.
The defense will return for me.
The size of the connected component, the size of the connected component.
Then I'm going to maximize on the slice, observe that I could do it in the normal way and attach a
vector of integer for then visited nodes and just use the length of it.
I would like to show you another way, given that we don't care about that.
The connected component values itself we could just connect about would care about the number of values
here.
So this good is is going to make a difference, but it will return also the total number of nodes in
the connected components.
But but actually it's for a team like we know the values are one two three and the four of you will
be like that.
So I'm doing the following whenever I have a neighbor, I see one blast there.
The first two from here, which will eternity.
And this is the first we have seen one plus difficile here.
One plus one plus.
I hope.
No, this is a pretty easy decision for you anyway.
It's pretty simple.
You can do it in many ways.
You can make here a reference counter zero and every time you visit and you just do calculus.
Plus this is would be good and valid if even you would like to make a difference.
A could a collector component to the number of nodes on a general graph like here, I'm assuming that,
um, is this as a chain, I'm returning with the first to neighbor.
What if we have a corrected graph like that?
The school do not return to the total size, OK, so maybe if you have here a reference for the total
vested nodes and increment here with every new node, then you got the total number of votes.
So now we implemented the code and we are we are done with that, by the way here.
This is very important.
I am iterating on that set, not on the array because they have duplicate values.
This one, does it have to be converted?
If you didn't do that, you would get I don't answer.
Now the last thing is, I would like to show you one more thing here.
A very simple observation.
How to do the chin first value without the it's up with the graph who said that if we have nodes, the
one two three four.
We mentioned that the Roots one and four will have only one neighbor.
How to know the answer without the graph at all?
Very simple observation.
So let's say we have the consecutive values 10, 11 and 12 and 13.
How to know that 10 is the fittest, the smallest, the value in the chain.
Simply, the value nine doesn't exist in the city, so at any point of time, if the value does it have
some value before it, it must be the first the value in it.
So this is a very interesting way to know that this is a starting value.
Now, this even means we can now, like in the previous good, I implemented the graph as a undirected
graph.
Now you can even be limited as a directed graph.
Like in the previous one, it was undirected and the like, the degree here was one.
And here was one.
Now I have one one one and this one has zero, so it's a bit different.
It doesn't matter a lot.
But just as an idea here.
So let's see the implementation.
No imitation is pretty the same here.
Uh, everything is set.
I'm just here this time, adding the wretched one.
Yeah, one simplification.
I don't need any vested values anymore.
I do need I do need the vista value here.
So because the graph is is directed, remember again and we stress that this it is important for two
reasons.
You visit your parents again.
You visit something that you visited before.
If you are in a dark.
Which is a graph that doesn't have cycles.
Direct one, you would never have these two cases.
So you do need visited array when you are there face on air directed graph.
You only need it in two cases.
If the graph is uncorrected or the graph is the electoral cycles.
But for DAG, you didn't need it.
When we built it, a graph like one go two to go to three.
This is a direct to the chain.
So this is a dag, so you don't need any more.
They're vested because you would never visited.
So here are the this is the second to tell you the time in the code we can make now a difference in
a very simple way without worrying about the vista that.
So I want to take the good here in two different ways.
It is the first one which is recursive.
I just.
Take the.
Return one, bless the naval one, bless the neighboring blustery.
If that doesn't have any neighbors, we return one.
And also, as we know that there's just a single chin now directed, we can make it very iterative like.
We have one, two, three and four.
I want to start from one count, one move count, one move, move, move.
We cannot anything else return so we can even return.
It developed iterative.
So as you see, this simple observation actually resulted in a could that is a bit smaller the crab
business, mortar and so on.
Now I want to tell you about something very weird that it wasted my time and I couldn't reach anything
in late could when I used an order.
The map for this problem, for one of the just two cases I think I listed down here, it feels, and
I don't know why the case on my machine works well.
The case on their machine doesn't work well.
So this is so weird.
So I ended up switching it to map to work well.
Somehow, the internet and validators, the internal literature are invalidated and make just that the
could feel.
I kept the bugging debugging, and I never did anything with lit code in this site.
But in a way, it doesn't matter what I think the code itself is valid and that it should be OK when
your personal machine.
Maybe something wrong with the compiler.
Unneeded code of sight.
I hope you learned something from this problems.