Homework, no food in the defense, it's a bit hard compared to others.
So the first one is is is a by Patricia de Bipartite is a very well known, is a very well known, uh,
probability in graphs.
It's very important.
The problem is actually no thought.
Just it might be a little bit in thinking twice, but eventually pretty simple and pretty direct.
So the bar graph is as following we have vertices.
So let's see here the examples.
We have a graph like this graph and we can like virtually split the graph to two groups the group number
one and group number two.
And here is the probability there are no edges between the nodes in the same group, and edges are only
between both of them here.
So you see the graph here like this is a very similar one.
If we divided this graph to this group here and this group here, we need to verify two things.
Within the group, there are no edges, as you see.
There is no such edgy energy here or an edge here between the groups we have edges.
OK, so here in this one, um.
So you see the color.
Like, let's say this node and this node and this node and this node, the are the same color, black
color.
And the second one are red color.
So now let's see in the black group, do we see any any edges between nodes like these two are connected,
not connected, not connected.
Now in the red, the group in the same way these two are connected, not connected, but connected between
the two groups themselves, the red and black.
We see the grouping here, so we see that this red is connected to this flag.
This red was this black say to this black and so on.
It's actually people call it the two color.
And the problem, which means you would like to color the graph such that some graph are black, some
are white and you would like.
There are no edges within the black group and there are no edges within the right red group.
And there are edges between the black and red or the black and white.
Whatever color gear so that this is following the graph is undirected.
You will return it through if it is a bipartite graph, which means there is actually a way to split
it into two groups the G1 and G2, such that connections are only between G1 and G2.
Feel free as a personal practice to even bring to their Group one and Group two nodes, which would
be which should be an easy task.
So this is mainly what is it by what that graph.
Here are some examples.
So this is the first example.
The answer is false because there is no way to partition the nodes to two independents, such as Split.
What about this graph?
So here is one way if you took zero and two as the group number one and one of three as the second group,
as you see zero two, there are no edges between themselves, one of three.
There are no edges between themselves, but there are edges between the first group and the second group.
The second the problem, um, we have a graph, the graph looks like a tree.
Remember the tree that is a one bath between every two nodes in a three, right?
There can be no cycles in the city.
But the tree definition is actually undirected.
The definition notes actually a like like a tree.
But the edges actually have of their texture.
So.
So there will be like in the minus one edges only in this graph, and there are no direct cycles here.
So now so they're given input is actually for air at three lake structure that is directed.
So connections here are directed digits and they will be exactly in the minus one.
And here is the question.
Some of the notes here is not number zero, let's say this note.
We would like to be sure that there is there, Beth, from every note to nude numbers you.
There is a bath from every nude to nude numbers you, but we know that the original graph is direct.
So this isn't the case.
This is this following we would a change the direction of some of the ages such that there is a the
age from every nude to every other nude.
OK, so here is that in this graph, for example, here you see the black ones.
Here are that, uh, the the original edges, the original directed edges.
Now when you look at here, is there a bathroom two to 2.0?
You see that nozzle can go to three, but it cannot go further here.
So if we change in the direction of this edge and the direction of this edge to be the opposite direction,
now no two can can reach zero and three and two once food can reach net zero already, but five cannot
because the edges here, so we will change in the direction of this.
EDIT2 So now we change at the edges.
The tusk is as follows You would like to change the minimum number of edges such that every node can
now reach the node number zero.
It is another example.
Number two cannot reach A. No.
Zero, if we change at this age, no two can reach zero.
Number three, was this a change you can reach No.
Zero.
Look no further.
Anatsui change also this world.
So now it is.
We needed to not only to make the change.
Problem number three.
And this is the previous two of those problems, by the way, are OK, they are manageable.
This one is a bit hard and it involves two combined algorithms together.
You will not be able to solve this problem by just using the office.
There is actually one more trick you can find a hint in the early in the solution of this problem.
So here is a task.
We have agreed to the metrics, and every cell has a value.
We are here at zero zero and would like to go to five and five.
Now the bullet as following were any birth we go, we compute the value.
The value represent that what we call the birth effort, the birth effort is defined as following.
It is the maximum absolute difference between any two consecutive values.
So let's see here this is know that both these two values, what is the absolute difference to these
two values?
What's the difference to this two values?
What is the difference two and here two?
So what is the maximum difference in all of these values?
The maximum is two.
So we see that the effort of this birth is to let's take another example.
Let's say we would like to go here, here, here, here, OK?
Remember would like to go from the top left to the bottom right now.
What is the difference here?
Just one.
What does the difference here?
Six The difference here.
Three.
What is the maximum value in the bar?
Six.
So six.
They represented their effort of the Beth.
Our task is we would like to go from the top left to the bottom right with the minimum effort.
So your task is to decide what is the minimum effort to go from the top left to the bottom right.
So you should find the path that find the minimum effort the best that it's it's it's so absolute difference
is minimum, but is read the problem twice.
If you are confused about that, it is rather case if you would like.
If we go through this path, who would notice here every two values has a difference of only one.
So the maximum is one, and this is the best thing you can do here.
A third example here, if you go this way, this way, this way, you would notice that the maximum
difference is zero, which is the best thing you can do.
So this is merely the the task.
The first problem there is no alone judge for this problem.
I'm not aware of a good problem.
The task is as following.
And actually, the implementation isn't the key in this problem.
You have undirected graph.
We'd like to return it true if it consists contains a cycle.
Remember, we did something that involves cycles before, right the matrix of problem.
Remember, we already did that, but review this problem because it's the key for this problem here.
Now, you can assume for simplicity that the graph does.
It has any silver loops.
Does it?
Has anybody ages?
You would like to do the following.
Uh, you would like to implement the dysfunction bullion wood to check if the graph has a cycle or not.
Now here's the key in this problem I would like to provide an O V algorithm.
I would like you to informally prove the correctness of your algorithm.
So this is actually the key here, I don't just want you to write an algorithm to detect the second.
I need you to make sure it is all the algorithm and I need you to verify that it is all the algorithm.
Now, after you're done with that, I would like you to analyze a directed graph like you will not implement
something here.
You would just analyze, adapt the graph and tell me why your implementation here is in the U.S. will
fail on this directed problem.
The written graph You can develop a trivial graph of three nodes early that can show you why your graph
on their case will fit.
So only used to use three nodes and implement that, like a simple example that showed the failure of
it.
You don't need to good that, uh, will address the directed graph seconds later.
Uh, yeah, for the for the distinction, I'm providing you with a simple file that involves some artistic
pieces.
So the file structure would be following the first number two would be a number of cases.
Two means there will be two graphs, then the first number is the number of nodes and the number of
edges, then three edges.
They would be zero based indices.
So the graph is like as we used so far.
If the graph has a cycle, you will print.
No.
If it doesn't has a graph, it doesn't have a cycle you would print.
Yes.
So this is a fight.
That's all.