Let's solve the defense homework here in the first one, we would like to do the, uh, graph paper
Titus.
Surprisingly, the code is easy, as I mentioned there before, state is actually a very well known
graph type and there are several algorithms related to it.
There is what we call the graph coloring.
The graph containing is a bigger umbrella where we would like to color the graph according to specific
criteria.
So the general topic part of it is what we call two color.
So we see a graph what is bipartite if and only if it is two color graph.
So when we say to color black, it means that you can find a way to color the graph such that you are
using only two colors for example, black and red or black and white, and there are no two nodes who
have the same color.
So for example, let's say we have the chin here.
Like this one here?
If I colored this one was black, this white, this black, this white.
Then there are no two nodes adjacent and have the same color, which means we can take this one and
want to be group one and this one and want to be Group two.
Anyway, you don't need this information to solve the problem, but I just want to give you more context.
So the problem actually would end up like the very normal defense, strongly connected component to
search.
So, so here is the idea.
Assume we have the chin zero one, two, three four, for example, and we would like to color it or
split it to two groups.
So let's say we'd like to Brussels number zero and let's say it is, it is the first group node number
zero and we would be in one of the two groups.
So let's fix this with number zero to be in the first two, which is the, for example, color zero
or let's let's see color one, for example.
What is it now?
If not number zero connected with good number one, I cannot put node number one here.
If we put number one here, it will be in the same color or in the same group, so it will fail.
So I cannot do that.
So look, number one must be in the second group.
No, no, no, no, no one is no Canada to regroup to mood, no one has been to.
I cannot, but no no to hear otherwise it will be the same group.
So I must.
The good brought it back here at mood number one.
In a similar way, no two has edged two to three.
So three must be here.
Three has enabled for so foremost to be here.
Now, imagine that for Britain, that four hasn't aged to zero, for example.
No food has an aged to zero.
I have to put zero here, but zero is already here.
It can, we cannot colour it.
So the moral of that is if the graph is colourful, we can take A..
But all of its neighbors in the second group and take every node and put its neighbors here in this
first group and take every node and put its neighbor in the second group and think it should here and
its neighbors here in the first group, if we managed and ended up that, we really split them.
This is perfect.
The moment that we we have here, let, let's say, a zero one two.
This is an audience like right zero one to take.
I put zero in there and then I must put two here.
But zero one two.
Two zero cannot be here, so you see this symbol like it, it's very clear that we cannot group them
in any way.
That's why we say that I'd like you will see this move later.
So this is a model of that.
Now, how can we implement that?
We can do that in a different way to implement it in a adukwei start with the device at not zero, then
device at the neighbors to be, let's say, such a device was going what the deficit neighbors to be
kinder to then take their neighbors and efforts on their neighbors to be colored one and so on.
So this is all what we need to do.
Just assemble the fence that just coloring the nodes.
So let's see here.
Here is the defense.
The defense.
Dig the graph.
Dig the current route to its colour, which is initially one, and this is a victor to know the colors.
Now he does a few kisses.
If this note is never visited before, we will assign it the current color.
What if this note has already a color, if this color doesn't match the assigned color, then this is
a conflict that let's say here again, the graph zero, one and two.
We started with zero and give it color one.
Qatar were.
And here we iterate on the neighbors and give it the opposite color.
I will come back to this equation.
So zero, both here and with no one.
I color.
No one is calling it neighbor, which is to.
And give it color one.
That's OK.
Number two is the cursing or no one to be was color too, but it is already ridiculous.
And different color.
So what's happening here?
Is this following.
We see if if it has a color and it isn't my color, then we conflict it together and we cannot be in
different groups and in same group in the Sun.
So it feels so we mark here this variable that is colored conflict with the rule, which means we cannot
divide them to two groups.
Otherwise, we iterate here on each neighbor and recurso in the neighbor with the opposite color.
So what does this nice equation?
Let's say that the colors are one and two.
So if my color is one, three minus one is to my opposite color.
If my color is two three, minus two is one.
So my color.
So three minus color is a simple trick to switch things exactly like the Boolean like.
If the number is Boolean one, minus zero is one, one minus one is zero.
So it is a symmetric but just on one and two instead of zero on one.
I hope now you understand the good now, and that is the case is that I provide for you the grief can
be multiple components, so you iterate on the graph.
If it is never colored before, if it's never visited, then we have a more defensive role here.
So they face from here, if there is a color conflict, then it cannot work anymore.
So this is merely the the algorithm and this is its informal proof.
Please dig a bunch of examples.
Make tracing on them, make sure that you understand the flow of that.
Eventually it is defense, but you just want to make sure that you really get it.
A few tips a year.
Any change must be bipartite like if you have mood number one two three four five in a chain must be
a bipartite graph.
So we just like mark them like, for example, here through a white, black, white, black, white,
black.
And so even if it's a tree, you can also market.
You look, let's say we have a tree here.
So this would be white, black, white, black, white, white and black white.
So any tree is actually not just a chin in a tree is a label tiger.
And this is a question that they mentioned, um.
Don't assume the graphs are just single connected components.
The graph is disconnected from bullets.
The last thing to know this is what we call the Connex theorem.
The theorem say something very interesting.
If the graph is bipartite, it has no takers.
Remember the example that they give zero, one and two?
The cycle, like what's the difference between zero one two and then one, two, three year?
In the even cycle, I can take this to to be in a group and these two to be in a group that's fit.
But when it looks like it, if I took zero one in the group worked to two, it is conflicting in both
of them in a similar way, if you zero zero one two three four.
If you try to put this like black, white, black, white, black, white, so you see, we want it
from one perspective, zero to be black and wanted it from another perspective to be white.
You cannot have an auto cycle in a in a in a in a.
In a graph.
So someone might say, OK, if you would like to distill the graph has cycles, is by about it or not.
Let's check if it does, it has Ortega.
This is true, but implementation wise is very tough.
So the trick here is we can follow another similar logic, like what we did today to know if the graph
is by birthright or not.
And this is a great to check if the graph has old cycles or not.
So a graph was even cycles can be bipartite.
A graph without cycles can be a very uptight graph with odd cycles cannot be bipartite.
That's all.