Let's solve the second problem, which looks scary, but actually, again, an easy problem as you think.
The first thing that you should remember, which is three, the three permits are very important.
Remember in a tree like this one here, there is only one bath from any note to any note, only one
bath.
So we know that the three is directed in a way, but it's in a way it's undirected.
There is only one bathroom here, so let's say this is nothing but zero, for example.
Then there's actually just one bathroom nude, no.
Zero to any food, and there is only one bathroom, any new Tunisia.
So, for example, this node will have to go this way, and this way, this node will have to go this
way.
This one would have to go this way.
This would have to go this way.
You see, in a very, in a very collaborative way, we would have to go to node number zero.
So now if the original edge is this way, we have to flip it this way.
If the original edge here is this way, we have to flip it.
So as you see with like symbol DFS, we can figure out what, what the direction that must be in the
problem.
So this is the key idea and the problem.
That the nodes in a way must take a specific bath to go to No.
Zero.
So all what you need to check is if this is the actual direction or not the remaining thing here, which
is a nice trick, how to implement that in an efficient way.
So it is an idea here.
Let's say we have.
This graph, again, it seems we have to do a lot, we have to take every note of them and get it to
defense and get the best through the road and then figure out which roads are flipped.
The idea looks are clear, but the implementation isn't.
So the first thing is what I call reverse the thinking.
And instead of thinking about the defense from every new tool, no.
Zero, which is the enemy in this one, their physicals.
OK.
In the mind of some difficult.
What if we just made the single device from zero to them?
So now we flip the problem, assume the original text, say I want to orient to the edges such that
zero can go to any one of them.
The good thing here that we just need to make a deal faster from zero a single day fiscal.
So here is a track implemented to be this way.
We would make a device from zero to all of the.
We will notice the direction of the edge, and if it isn't implemented, we will use it.
But just consider that we are in the reverse of the problem.
So in fact, if the edge exists, we count it.
Not the opposite.
That's all.
Uh, here is a practical example.
Let's say we have a lake, the chin.
The graph is zero one two three four.
Then the defense from zero will end up with this way.
If you try to reverse that the graph, it would be like four three two one zero.
Which means we need actually to flip zero and one two.
Um.
No, no, no.
Let me repeat, this is the original graph.
This is zero one.
And one, zero, one and one two.
And the three to.
And the four three.
This is the original graph, if you did a defensive from zero, it will be like zero one two three.
For now, the compare between the ages, but consider the opposite here, in fact, we wanted the graph
to be to be the following to be like four good two to three to go to two go to one but to zero.
This is what we are dealing with.
But this is actually the what exists.
So we iterate on the graph and we count to the edges that exist because we flip do that, we flip to
the edges.
So let's see them.
But the mutation here is going to be pretty straightforward.
I have an edge, which is include the two and Boolean if the original input in the graph is built or
not, add undirected edge here.
I'm going to make a undirected graph, but one edge is a given edge and the other edge is what I'm going
to build.
For example, if they say that zero, one and two is the edges, I will create them.
This will have the true value here.
And this back one will have faults are here and this one will have folds here so that I want the defense
to proceed as if it is undirected.
Graph Remember, the defense on the undirected graph is actually under the graph, so we need it to
be undirected here.
So I'm creating a graph with the original.
It just was very true and the opposite edges with value falls.
This is a very normal defense.
But what?
I am doing something here, this is the total number of edges that I will reorient and I see here if
the edge is built in, then counted as an edge to be flipped.
If the edges edges built, then we will flip it.
OK, this looks like weird, but remember we are doing the defense on the opposite direction.
Now, the last thing is we could hear the graph we do at the office, from the numbers, you go into
the reoriented edges and return it.
Now the algorithm is very trivial.
It is just Ebola's V.
So while it looks like scary and they begin on the idea level, it looks too scary in the implementation
level with a simple trick of flipping the wool graph.
We can note that we can proceed in an easy way.