Let's continue our discussion about the Dipasupil research, I would like to start with another three
who just to refresh the the terracing, but this time in a very short rest light.
So let's see, we'd like to make a defense of two here.
So in the first step, remember the defense tomb has zero three four five as the children, so this
rule will be running four times.
The defense zero will proceed after it come back from the region.
It will check with three after it came back from the collision.
If it did it.
It will come back to four, then five.
This is something very important to do.
So now that if you're going to start with the effects of zero, the first route is, you know, vested
no workers on it.
So now this is, you know, it would be bolded here as a three edged with us.
Now we are at zero and zero has only one node, which is one.
Is it visited?
No, we recurs air defense of one.
So now we won't be here and this now we know this vista.
And one has also won two children, which is forward is four wasted, no.
So we jump here to four recursively here.
A market as wasted food doesn't have any children, so it's full of bull, not work.
And then it will start to come back to one.
But one also doesn't have wanted children, so it will come back to zero zero.
Also, does it have more children?
So it's done.
Now we go back to two, which has three four and five zero three, four and five would be continued
from here.
Now the next edge is three defense of three.
So we jump to the first of three.
Is it visited more than John?
Be here.
And this is one more bolded edge here at three.
We have um.
No, no.
No three has no no for A. No.
Six now with three with a chick is four visited.
The answer is yes.
You know it is six harvested.
The answer is no reverse.
So with the cursor here and number six is it is accursed now.
Six.
It doesn't have any children so directly go back to three, which go back literally to two.
And the next step.
Remember, we go back to two to continue.
This is very important.
The next edges were four and five.
Now four node is four wasted.
Yes, ignore this edge.
OK, what does the next five now?
Node number five is this did not go from here, so five is listed and then five have one node, which
at six whenever is visited.
Yes, so ignore it.
So as you see this are we?
We managed to reach one two three four five six seven nodes.
How many?
Just one two three four five six.
So as you see seven nodes.
Six pages.
This bolded images are a DFS first three.
So this is mineral tracing in case you would like something to refresh.
Now let's move further to important questions.
The first question is what is the time complexity of the algorithm we just implemented?
Let's make it easy for you at the beginning.
Assuming we have a rota three as this one here.
Now, as you know, this one would have like an inwards and in the minus one edges, but pretend it's
in the name.
Now what's the time complexity of defense on this one here?
These take five or 10 minutes to think about it when you think about it as a defense.
Three, We will never meet a vested node.
Everyone would be treated.
So if I would go here, go here, go here, go here, go back, go back here, go back here, go here.
So as you see, every node would be visited, every edge would be listed.
So we say that this is oh in blossom.
OK, so in the next step, just remember that as Emma is already in the minus one, this actually,
practically speaking, is just because Emma is already in.
So this is like, oh, two enemies, this one, which is so and so very interesting, very, hopefully
easy for you.
Let's opposite to the actual case now, assume we have a directed Densey graph of any nudes and images.
What is the time complexity of this function?
Again, it is in Nablus.
Can you think why?
What do you think about it?
First of all, the recursive function itself, the device to not function, this function will be called
only at most times.
Why?
Because you never visit and that is visited.
So our recursive code will be made for the root if and only if it has never been visited.
And as we visit every node only once, then the defense code will will never be called more than in
the times.
So at most would have in the recursive calls.
Why not exactly, Nichols, because some loser might not be eligible.
Now when you reach A. Then you start to iterate on its neighbors.
So, for example, node number two.
So now we know that we will visit this once, once, once, once, once, once, once and once.
But no, that occasion might give us a hard time about what really happened here.
There are two ways to think about it.
The first way, which is the easiest way mathematically also possible is to think in terms of the total
number of edges, how this node it is used for ages.
This one will treat one edge, one edge, one two edges and so on.
So you might be puzzled because this four look will do a different number of steps in each school.
But remember that if you thought in a global way the total number of iterations he had equal to the
total number of edges, equal to the total number of edges.
So the total submission of this for loop here is actually well e it will just iterate on it at most
once.
So again, this end up in a closet.
If you'd like to think from another perspective, remember that the DFS created the S3 so very relevant
to the previous example the rooted tree.
Every edge users would be visited only once.
So even like if you if you have a if the graph has cycles, the seekers are all are ignored, right?
Like if if two five go to two and four go to zero and one go to two and three go to five on five to
six.
All of this edges are part of E, but all of them would be ignored because we are just creating a tree
among all of these cycles inside the graph.
So this is another way to think about it this time.
Complexity is very important, so please make sure that you get it.
Um, yeah.
What call the order of what the edges with this, yeah, this is just more more logic here that I already
mentioned.
What if the graph is adjacency matrix?
The code definitely will need to be changed.
If this is just in semantics, then you would have to iterate for integer I.
Equals zero and then oil is then end and plus plus I and then you need to check if a graph of node.
And the equal one, then this is right, remember, how do we trace on the adjacency graph for the brain
to function in that just as a matrix, we have to treat in a different way.
So this look is trading on a decency list.
Is it heaven that we have to iterate, treat allergies as the graph the now we are actually iterating
in the square on the wall graph, right?
Because we are rotating on every day.
So it ended up like in Nablus, in the square, in the square for all of the rules or just even in the
square overall.
So this is mainly the time complex and as you see the there that the blossom is generally speaking more
efficient here, especially the graphic spots.
What about the memory complexity?
We created a Boolean array of any nodes.
So this is all in.
And also we have a recursion that will do at most in the recursive calls.
And this is something that students always miss.
Remember that recursion has an auxiliary space.
So if you have, generally speaking, if you have any recursive calls and each school has it in local
memory, then this is all in memory.
Our algorithm body is all one memory.
So the overall is in accelerator space.
End the from here or in the from here.
In total, we have an all in an auxiliary auxiliary space.
I would like to give you a tip.
I explained it during my explanation.
Sometimes it is easier to think about the total number of steps of a block rather than a specific line
of code.
And the example that I give here is that neighbors, if you started to think about every node by itself,
you will get lost because this loop will do a dynamic number of steps, Bernard.
But if you thought you know what, all of the total steps here are just to the total number of edges.
So it's actually the submission of the neighbors of node number I, which is just E.
So this is in a way, the total number of coverages.
Generally speaking, traversal graphs are linear in terms of the time complexity in terms of the nodes
and terms of their just the device for their direct care for the American Graph is the same could,
as I mentioned, but just iterate on the different way.
Look, as I mentioned I0.
I listen in and the time complex is also the same.
There is just one minor change here in the office.
Every edge is visited twice.
What undirected graph?
Because if we have not no to go to rule number seven, then two has a seven as a neighbor and seven
has to as a neighbor.
So we trade on this issue twice.
But if the directed Graph two and the seven, then only two go to seven on the one, so the edges traverse
reverted here only once.
I would like to mention something, but I don't want you to get lost about it, it is.
It is something that you rarely used.
All I wanted you to know is just to.
You're here to to to know this name.
There is something called iterative living.
The idea is this following of this variant.
Let's say that the graph is very deep, very, very deep.
And let's see what searching for something that should be answered in the very early ages here.
The problem is.
That occasion would keep going very, very, very deep.
If we would like to force that algorithm to not go through DBR before finishing the early levels, there
is a race.
The nice trick?
Let's say you would like the graph to even never go beyond the 10 edges, for example.
Like if the graph has 100 edge, you just want to be limited to 10 edges.
You can add a depth of variable for your defense function, such as that.
If the current dips is greater than equal, the limit depth just return.
OK, now I would like to get, for example, the reachable nodes.
What should we do?
You will iterate in the mean.
Starting from the maybe minimum deposit that you need, maybe six, maybe up to the maximum depths,
maybe 15.
And every time you run your graph starting from the depths, but every time you will reset the vested
victor and then the graph will burst the graph up to this depth.
Let me give you some tracing.
Let's say that in the first time, maybe you ask, could the depth to be just one?
So graph of depth equals one.
So now the rule started from here.
Vested go to here.
Vested now who need good to hear it will come back directly.
Why?
Because the deep sea it is more than to it.
More than one should return.
Now try 021.
So this is the research was a divisive one would only try.
This news here.
Now, let's say we didn't find our target, so we need to expand our test.
But he said the vista vector and try dips too.
So now we try up to here, up to here, up to it, up to you.
If we imagine that there are more nodes here and nodes here and nodes here that what would be visited
early would be this.
To live apart so that say this is the reason behind this new iterative dipping, it means dry depth
of by depth iteratively and try to find your good.
Generally speaking, I rarely use this vision, even in competitive programming.
I used only maybe twice in my whole life, so it is neither like coming in in competitions or even in
normal algorithms, but said I wanted you to be familiar with it.
Uh, there is another algorithm that we will learn that could be a service which actually most of the
time would be used instead of this kind of iterative debate.
Of.