Let's solve the problem, number three, this is actually the heart of the problem here, like the this
problem is in an easy one, even for an experienced programmer who might get lost to here.
I will provide you with a single hint that will make this problem from the heart of the problem to an
easy problem.
The hint is to use binary search.
Remember?
That it could six, six, eight problem, the one about the multiplication when we have the multiplication
of in in values is very similar by necessity.
So how can you make use of this hint?
OK.
Here is the key.
Assume we have function that takes of the heights matrix and limit it returns through if and only if
the maximum possible absolute difference of some bears is less than or equal the limit.
And remember that inequality?
We mentioned that in the in decision.
The equality of inequality can help us to create a multi-ethnic space.
If I say equal the limit, it would be like a zero zero zero one zero zero zero zero.
If I said Lizelle Equal, it would be like zero zero zero one one one one one, which is monotonic.
Now again, I would give you the heights and a limit.
I'm asking you, can we find a Abarth such that the maximum possible difference is less than or equal
the limit?
Now think about it.
Assume that for, for example, limit number 10.
The answer is true, then definitely.
Those are true for limited living.
Like, if I can think of us was value seven, which is this an equal 10, then also equal 11 also deserve
equal 12.
That's why the social space like are zero zero zero one one one one.
OK, what is the.
I'm asking you for limits?
17.
Sorry if the minimum is 17.
So 10 doesn't work.
It even then.
Nine doesn't work.
It doesn't work.
So going backward will feel going forward will succeed.
This is clearly a monotonically increasing function.
So the first observation here, the possible function in this problem is a one trick function.
Now let's do a binary search.
Such that we would like to find the first limit that is possible, so let's say this limited add value
eat, so we actually return to eat.
OK, it is like a first occurrence, as we did a lot to like that before.
So the the homework here, we first decoded it using the binary search in a very similar way to the
case number three in the binary.
Such a case, as we mentioned before, the heart of the case where you are using something like that
to find a reasonable function.
And now using the limit, we would like to find the answer.
I hope you got the the algorithm so far.
Binary search on the limit find the first limit that the possible function is returning through.
No, the remaining question, which is easy.
How can we implement the possible function?
We have a matrix here.
I started from here.
I would like to go from here, but my limit is seven, for example.
So that's the idea is very easy to do.
Afloat fell and this graph.
And you cannot go to any vote if and only if it needs a more than seven that symbol.
Again, do edifice reachability office.
Remember the day on the grid?
You can go to the four directions.
Previously in the flat world, you go to the neighbor if it has the same color.
Now I can go to the neighbor if the difference between me and him, the absolute difference is less
than or equal.
Seven If this is the case, we can just proceed.
And in this way, we are done.
Now why this problem is a bit hard for an experienced programmer because there can be a lot of ideas
that can come to his mind.
Maybe the right programming problem?
Maybe backtracking.
Maybe Minkus smacks of law, maybe binary search.
So as someone who has a lot of tools, this problem can be confusing.
I give you this problem now where what what we have so far in the courts, we learned the sorting,
we learned the searching way in research.
We learned the defense, right?
So clearly, your toolbox is just consist of these three items, and we actually needed this to here.
If I give you the same problem.
After the end of what to do with, you know, all of these algorithms, all of these directions might
be bad.
So sometimes when you have more and more tools, while it is very advantage, but also it's a bigger
challenge here.
Anyway, let's see them alimentacion.
Um, here is the brain research I started with the minimum.
Zero, the maximum is just that the max, the value in the problem statement that we do normal brain
research.
And if it is possible, then we assign the result to the med and move to the lower body so that we can
mix them.
I'm mixing that less than an equal condition here, as we did many times before.
Now the possible function is as following the possible function is creating visited array on the size
of the matrix and starting from zero and zero, giving the heights array, giving the vista ray and
there the limit.
Now going to the function itself, this is as we did before, the directions of the AFC and um oh,
I made this function to be bullion so that it can directly stop once we found the field.
So here is a function.
It started from raw and see if we manage at any time to reach the end of their grid like we started
from zero to zero.
If at any point of time the DFS is here, then we are done now.
Otherwise, as usual, we market their sit as vested.
We trade on the news.
Now here it is our condition.
If it is invalid, sell cancel it if it is visited before cancel it.
If the difference between me and my neighbor is greater than the limit, cancel it.
Otherwise, we DFS on the neighbor observer.
This if condition, I say if true, which means that this direction managed to reach the said we can
return true.
I can implement that was the bullion.
We did many times before we defined here a variable we can say we can define here a boolean and say
is rigid and we run the defense the normal way a market is, Richard withdrew.
But this is a different way, another way to cool things.
The function itself is containing the Boolean variable.
This condition here is important condition.
I hope the idea is manageable for you.
It is in that nightmare.
You can still get its components.