Let's all the the, uh, the psychic detection problem, it looks at tricky, but actually it isn't
so for solving it.
We need to remember a few facts.
Again at three is undirected graph within nodes and in the minus one edges.
Right?
And remember, there is only one bathroom any note to another.
And also, as we mentioned before, there are no cycles in a tree.
And also, if you added a single edge, it must to create the fake ID like we have here.
Assemble three zero one two three.
This is a three or eight nodes three edges.
If you added any edge, it's going to create the cycle.
Now the idea is this following our normal defense is actually, Oh, we photograph.
This looks weird.
Here's the idea.
Remember, we already discussed about the cycles in the in the in the matrix.
The problem.
We mentioned that when you have a cycle, it comes from two sources in undirected graph.
You are at node number two, for example, and you move to node number three, node number two.
My number three might try to go back to its appearance.
Number two?
And this is kind of a useless cycle.
The second one is no number three is going back to number one, which is vested.
So now we have two cases, two reasons why we create cycles in undirected graph.
Why do we think that there is a cycle the berrent one which is fixated, there's actually no second
and there is a cycle from here.
So now let's see the good first.
The could this is following, we will write our like, very normal defense, OK?
We will have here an extra variable, which is a beer and over the beer end of the road.
And then if if the while we are iterating with the children or the neighbors, we will not go to our
parents.
So you are at number two.
Don't go back to number one.
You are not number three.
Doing good will go back to number two.
We are assuming here there are no multiple ages because there are like a multiple ages between one and
two, then it is actually a cycle.
Well, the two is its parents, but actually there is a cycle.
That's why in the problem, I told you, there are no multiple cycles, multiple ages.
So in fact, if there are multiple ages or what you need is to spot if there are multiple ages or if
there's any multiple ages, then we have a cycle here.
So you iterate on your neighbors and you don't go back to your parent because it's actually peak cycle.
In a graph without multiple edges.
Now, if it happened that you are actually visiting a node that isn't your parent and it is marked as
visited like node number one here, this is actually a cycle, so we stop it again.
I implemented the defense here to be like a Boolean one.
It's going to return true if it found this like.
Now here, I say, if DFS from here, from this node and with this parent is the could return through
this if condition is very important because it would stop the processing.
Once we find a site that you cannot forget it, you cannot.
OK, so now the remaining thing is to handle separate connected computers.
Now let's go back.
This is a device and it looks like the very normal good why this is over.
This should be it was V..
So here is the point.
Remember it.
We have one of two cases.
The first the case.
The graph is like a forest and forest is just a bunch of connected trees.
So this is a forest here.
This is a first of one two three four five connected components.
It has risen in the minus one aegis.
OK, but still like a first.
Now if we are if if the graph is just the first of the three, then anyway, the number of edges are
as simple as number of nodes.
So actually, it's E but o v because the E is just in a minus one.
So in this case, clearly the plus V is actually will be in the second case.
If we once found the cycle, we return it.
The idea is, in the worst case, you would need exactly energies to find the cycle.
So let's say we have five nodes you, in the worst case, moved from zero to one two three four.
Now we've listed all of the nodes in the graph.
If there is any extra energy from food, it must go back to.
One of them was it must go back because we already visited all of them.
And this means after India minus one, it just we would visit in the inner nodes with an extra edge.
We must visit back one of the nodes.
So this means even if the graph has a lot of edges only after energies, we will find the cycle, so
we stop.
So the moral of that is although the algorithm, the difference in the normal case is Ebola's V.
In the case of detecting cycles, if we didn't find the cycle, we will take exactly v v v v minus one
steps through that and the terms of edges.
And if there is our cycle, we will do that exactly in these steps as we are still being as early as
possible.
We will never exceed the edges.
So overall, still over.
So the moral of this problem wasn't actually in finding a new algorithm of 0V.
It was a noticing that the ablest V algorithm would end as well the algorithm if you stop as early as
possible.
And that's why this condition here is important not just for correctness, because without it, the
defense will explore the whole tree.
So you have to stop as early as possible.
Once there is a cycle again, you don't have to implement.
It was brilliant.
You can define an external variable is cycle.
And here in the early in the function, if if they could just return, then again and just edges, we
adjust.
You will figure out the cycle.
Uh, yeah.
Uh, that's all.