Let me comment on the.
Let me comment on the direct case, I asked, could you in the problem to think about the graph of the
charity case?
So let's say you have this very simple graph.
Three nodes of three edges, British symbol.
Uh, if let's say that occasion started and go from zero to one, so now zero is marked as visited,
one is marked as visited, one go to do two market has visited occasion, go back on occasion, go back.
Then zero goes to to find it visited.
You think, Oh, this is a cycle, but there is no cycle.
This is the great difference between directed and the director graph in the undirected graph.
Zero one two zero zero two one one go to two to go to the zero by itself, so find it visited.
Then there's a cycle in the directed graph when the recursion go back and zero, go try the two and
find it that you cannot consider it as a cycle.
That's the big difference between the two cases here.
So the cycle detection in undirected graph is pretty straightforward, but in the directed graph it's
a bit more complex than that.
And I didn't like we didn't talk yet.
How can we handle that?
And if you would like to really recognize the condition to figure out the cycle in that in the cycle,
in the deleted graph, it isn't just about being visited or not.
It is about the activist tech.
Like, let's say we are not zero, then let's say here, let's say that this is directed graph, but
they actually the edges this way.
Zero one two Recursion So the stack now has zero and one or two.
And to try to go to zero zero is in the stack and the act, of course.
So this zero must be in a cycle.
Now let's say here the the opposite case.
Let's say we are at zero one two and here now the decision to start at zero one and two, so the stack
is zero one or two.
And then the decision go back to to go to back to one, so the decision one and two go out of the stack
now zero tries to go to two, which is vested, which means you do not have to make again the decision,
but it is in the stack only if it is in the stack.
You can figure out it's this, like it or not, which a bit like it looks like more complicated for
you, you know?
But in a way, I just wanted you to figure out the difference between them.
So one way to know about the cycles is what we call the topological sort.
Topological sort is one way to know there are cycles or not in directed graph.
Yeah, that's a.