Um, to finish this section about the device, we learned how to use this first to verify undirected
graphs to verify if there's a cycle in undirected graph.
We enter this section by learning about the EJU classification, which helps us to learn how to effectively
learn if there is a cycle in a directed graph or not using the office.
In the next section, we'll learn about the topology concert and we will learn an easy way to figure
it out.
Also cycles in directed graphs.
So let's see.
So far, we learned about this cycle detections using undirected graphs.
But when we try to implement and think about that for that directed graphs, we notice that the Vista
array isn't enough and we give an example in the homework for that and the homework solution.
Notice see here in the in in in, uh, in in.
It is a problem, we have a vested note.
But the key problem is we do know.
We do not know if this new is part of a cycle or not.
That's why we were confused the visit information wouldn't do enough.
When you look to their lifting graph here, you will notice that not zero one two two one one two two
two zero one two harvested two now is trying to go back to zero zero is a cycle now here.
This is creating a cycle and we can see that zero is actually an ancestor of two because there is a
bus from here to here, but there is actually bus from two to zero.
So I am and sister for you and your ancestor.
For me, this is cycle.
In the second case, zero winter, two, one winter to two.
And all of them harvested now zero is an ancestor of two.
Then now we are trying to start again to two from zero to two two is again vested.
But this time the information is is as it is.
Zillow is still insisted for two zero still and still for two and two is descendant of zero.
So this is in a cycle.
This is a problem that happened with the device in directed graph.
Both of cases are vested.
This time, zero has a cycle.
Really, this time two doesn't have a cycle, so we know that the Vista array wasn't enough.
This means the note could be vested and can belong to more than one case in the recorded graphs.
And this takes us to a very new topic, which is age classification.
Now remember, this is a defense first three if you have a tree, if they face an undirected graph,
you end up with this deficit tree, which also exist in a directed graph.
We call this kind of this bolded it here.
We call them tree edges, and the tree edges are the edges that our.
The school used it, used it to navigate this ones that are dotted here, we ignored them because they
were four nodes that were visited already.
OK, now let's proceed more.
Let's do this first, this three.
We start at zero.
We go to one, go to two.
Good one, good, the two good to three to six so far, so good.
While doing this sort of kitchen, we will ignore the two zero edge because this vested will ignore
three one, because it is vested will ignore one two six because there's vested.
So these are the three edges that we have this one here, this one here.
This one here.
All the other will be cancelled, then we will start from four.
And also this will be cancelled, this will be cancelled and this one would be used.
This bolded one are there.
Three edges.
And we have a lot of cancelled the edges.
There are, in fact, when you study them, there are three cases for this see.
Cancel the aegis.
OK, now I want you to remember the following we have two separate defense.
The first, the first of zero, ended up with zero one two three six and the second the effects of war
ended up between four and five.
Also, observe this three edges here that we will cancel them.
They actually went between the nodes of the single defense.
This edge that were cancel the year would actually, from our defense nodes to alter their first nodes
like four to two, for example, would clarify that a little more now.
In graph theory, we can classify the edge of a directed graph to four types.
The first case is a three edge.
This is the one that we learned before.
This is the one that built the first three four four four subgraph.
Specifically, when we check the Node V. we noticed that V is unvisited.
So we use its edge and we call it a diff is it's the we call it a three h.
Now, if if it happens that the vista of V is true, we have three cases for that.
Gives no one is what we call a forward edge.
And in this case, you is an ancestor of the.
In that year versus three.
Don't forget, this segment will be confused.
You is an ancestor of V in the current DFAC tree.
We will see an example.
And this happened within the same single day for.
The second case, which actually creates cycles.
We discover that V is an ancestor of you in the deficit tree and you is also an ancestor of V.
So zero to one, for example, and one go to zero.
This is like we call them back ages the third.
The case, which we call the cross age you is neither any sister nor descendant of V.
They do not have a relationship and this happen in two cases, either within a single day physical.
Or in between multiple different schools, remember, previously we have the zero one, two, three
six in a diverse school and then we have the four or five in a call and we observed that Ford wanted
to go to two two is in the previous day for school.
So this is a cross.
It is crossing things.
Let's see a visualization for that.
It is a graph that we just, uh, drawn.
Remember, the difference is zero cover only zero one two three six.
Now.
This black edges are the three edges.
This I have coloured problems, this let me call it orange, this orange edge is back.
It will carry cycle zero one two zero one two zero one two.
This is creating Cycle one two three one two three one two three.
Zero, six and one six, we call them forward the edge.
Look, in the first three one is an ancestor of six in there, the first the three.
What is the relationship between one and six?
One is ancestor of six.
Here I am.
Your parent, your big bird.
What is the relationship between zero and six in the deficit?
Three.
I am your ancestor.
Now look to.
These two edges here and to.
In the deficit three, there is no relationship between four and two, so it is neither ancestor nor
descendant for it.
This is across age.
This is across age and I like it more when it comes from civil defense codes because this is a separate
the fiscal and it's going to cross to the second if history making like a connection to it.
If you don't remember the point of the deficit three, you will keep thinking.
But food is built to two, but food is built into two to know we have to face up to.
We have zero one two three six is a defense, three we have four and five is a deficit.
Three.
You build the relationship of who is the ancestor of whom in their defense.
Please don't move beyond this slide before understanding these four types.
Look, how can we determine the ages?
This is take us to the second think relevant to the um relevant to the age classification, which is
timing the timing.
The note is simply giving the time for the new data to started processing and time when we finish the
processing as simple as we could here to erase, one of them is started and another is finished initialized
to minus one.
And this is our defense good.
When we start, we give it time here.
Then we commit to the time, then do our recursion once our recursion finished.
We assign the current to finish time and then we increment to the time here.
Not that this time is incrementing through the other notes with simple comparisons, we can know their
age type of the three cases, the easiest.
The case is coming for the forward, the age, which are mainly if the sort of started of a who is this,
then it started off enable.
This must be forwarded.
The challenging one the second two cases is it across age or back age?
If you open the sailors book, you will find some comparison between the rules that can answer it.
But I will show you an easier way here.
Let's proceed.
I am auditing now the graph with the finish and the starting time.
So we started by not zero.
So starting is one, then moved here.
Start to move here, start the three moved here, start to four, moved here.
Start to five.
Then this would finish to finish is six.
This not finished vision seven.
Finish eight finish nine.
Finished 10.
Then we start the Note 11 for here at 11.
Then we started this at 12th.
Finish at 13.
Finish at 14.
Now, let's compare the starting times of things compare, for example, the Note zero with the Note
six.
You will notice that the start of zero is this, then it started off six.
This means while we are and say the difference recursion, this means that this must be for the edge
because I started before you am now reaching you.
And now reaching you zero.
Go this cycle to six.
First, then.
Now it tries to go from here within the defense called within the defense call.
Within the defense call.
So the rule is this morning as a starting time, which is a smaller than you.
It means I am forward for you.
OK.
What about if you if you if you thought about this note, it is starting after the finish of the last
year, so it's a start time in a way it isn't.
Before that, let's do some comparison.
Let's see the problem.
What is the problem?
It's two zero.
It's two and the zero here.
When you compare the start of two and zero, it would be greater than.
And this is cycle.
And if you compare it to Darfur and the two, it would be greater then, but this is a motorcycle.
So we can summarize that is following from comparison of the sorting.
If a start of a is less than a start of gee, this means this must be forward to each and I hope you
can see the logic I am coming to you.
I started earlier and now coming back for you again.
You must be my child.
Migrant, the child.
But we can see that the started relationship doesn't help with the cycle or not cycle cycle for baggage
and not cycle for the cross edge.
So now we need a smarter way to handle this.
Two things now here.
Let's see, how can we do that?
This is a question here.
What what really makes a big edge?
What really create the cycle?
Think here if we started from the physical move to the fist one two and then trying to go to zero?
What makes really zero is a cycle.
The answer is as following four zero to cause a cycle, it must be my ancestor.
This means it is active in this that cools.
It is active in the state.
So this means zero in the stack is squatting.
One one in the stack is going to do in the stack is calling zero zero is active in the stack codes.
That's why it is causing a problem.
Remember the second the case, the early graph, we drew zero going to one going into two and zero going
to zero one two would be active in the stack.
Then two will go down one, it will go down now.
Zero will try to now to access two again.
Two isn't in the stack cool, so the active roster could refer to who are all of my current ancestor.
So if religion is going zero one two three six zero one two three, our ancestors of four six because
they are active in this, their codes.
So all what remains to figure out if this visited node?
Is it part of the stack calls or not?
We can trivially know that from the finished.
Of the nude in the nude, is it still finished equal minus one?
It means that we never finished it and is still active in the state court.
And with this way, we can figure it out in a trivial way.
If the nude is actually gross or not, I hope you got it, OK?
Thus, think I showed you before the cross edge between toes to couple of defense?
I want to show you the cross edge within a single device.
First of all, look to this simple example here zero one to the wreckage and glass following zero.
Go to the next EJU.
It's one one go to two, which is to then return the kid.
Zero.
Find itself going to two, but the start of zero is less than the start of two, which means zero started
before me, which confirms I'm still your ancestor, so everyone is happy.
This is a case of forward age.
The second case is zero to one.
Then come back.
Zero good two, two two tries to go to one.
One is vested.
Now this is across age.
This is across age.
So as you see, this is an example of across age within the single DFS could.
Yeah, your.
I would like you to modify the school to find the cycles I would like to leave this implementation for
you used to arrays started and finished, your code should help with the class of each age.
You will just add three symbol condition.
Don't go beyond that.
I would like you to try as a sample of the lecture, the lecture segments.
Please compare your code.
I'm attaching my good.
Don't worry, you will know the right answer.
The first thing I would like to tell you in that if the graph we don't have for the ages and we don't
have Chris Hedges, we only have a three edge or back edge.
That's why if you find the note visited, you know that it is a cycle.
If you if you have entries to see formal proof, you can find it in the syllabus book.
This lecture was a bit heavy.
You need to view maybe two or three times.