Defense, homework, number one, let's try to play with the good little bit so that we get more experience
in the first task we would like.
Here's a simple description.
You will have a rooted tree and you will have a specific node in the tree.
You would like to return all the nodes that are below this tree node, including itself.
OK.
So I would like to tell you now about the context that lead could problem itself for described so that
it could say that there are bruises.
So we have a process here and there is some process behind it.
So this is a slow process here.
Let's say this is not number 100.
This is not number two.
Maybe this is not number seven, seven seven.
This is node number five.
This is node number 60.
So this is only a graph of five nodes.
But observe the values are very big.
So this is something that could happen in some operating systems.
You have several processes and every process has a Birand another process.
Now, if node number 100 as a user, you ask it to destroy node number 100, the node number 100, which
is a process, would be destroyed and all of their nodes under it to two and 760 and five would be destroyed.
So as you see, uh, the problem is 10, but that is just one catch here.
The ideas itself are pretty big.
The ideas are up to five thousand in terms of the graph representation.
They will give you the edges as following.
They would give you two arrays ID, which is a process ID and B idea, which is the beer and to process
idea.
In other words, this is a directed graph and b idea of AI, and the idea of AI is actually an inch.
I'm just trying to write for you the description in a simpler way.
Then I could forces but refer to their homepage.
Read the problem if you are confused.
So in this problem, here is a graph a given for you.
This is actually one example.
Also, I'm trying to make your life easier and you will notice, for example, that B-BBEE idea of two
equals five, which means that there is an edge from five to to be ideal for equal one, which means
that the parent of the parent of four is one.
So this image, if I ask you to kill five, you should return all of these ages, all of this.
If I asked you to kill two, then you need to return it to three six.
If I ask you to kill for it, then you just kill four.
So this is mainly the first task, which is an easy task.
The second task, uh, we have, uh, we have a company and employees, has structured every employee,
has an importance of value and we have some people that he is managing.
So you see here this graph Embree with idea number one, has importance.
Five.
This is a manager, probably, and he has two in Belize under his management.
One of them has already two and one of the papers idea three.
With this one has an idea of three.
And this one has an idea importance of three.
Now you will get a query here.
Two With the ID equal one, you should return to the submission of the importance of this note and all
of their notes behind it.
If there are more notes here, you also, some here and some here, if you had really some here.
So very similar to the previous problem.
This is a rowdy three and you would be given specific mood.
You would return its value and all of the note values.
So this is mainly the description of the note.
So this is a rotary.
Now how is the graph given the graph given as a vector of employees, vector of employees here and everybody
has I.D., has importance and has a list of ideas that he is managing.
Uh, this is your graph, but is write a code that is using this graph does not convert it to another
graph.
I would like you to trade on the graph itself as it is given for you.
OK, so this is mainly the second, the problem.
In the third problem, we would like to solve a very common problem in graph theory, could the connected
components.
We have a graph.
It's undirected.
It's unweighted, would like to count the number of connected components.
We explained before that the connected component is like a subgraph undirected where every node in the
subgraph can reach all of the other nodes in the same subgraph.
So you will take a graph and the total number neighborhoods.
The graph is following every vector of integer.
Here is just two numbers which represent to the from and to, and there are no multiple edges or silver
loops in this problem.
So here is an example if the given graphic is given this way.
As you see, this is two connected components here.
This is connected component and this is a correct component.
Visually, you can definitely use it.
Notice it like if I say that we have something like that.
How many connected components here?
We have five.
This is one component to three or four.
So every something that is connected with his neighbors end up in a undirected graph to be completely
connected because you can go to anything here.
Here, zero can go to one and two and three and four.
Four can go to one, one can go to three out of them can go to each other.
So this is one connected component.
This is merely the third homework.
That's all.