Let's solve the first the homework with the first one about the kill process here and in this problem,
if you noticed this is exactly the reachability problem, right?
I'm asking you for the reachability.
You have a three and all you need is just to list all of the reachable nodes.
So this is mainly the request, if I asked for this newly written this note on all of this.
So this is actually the reachability problem.
There is only one issue here.
The values are pretty big.
So in the usual graph, we have something from zero in the minus one.
But now this is pretty bigger than usual numbers because the Bruces ideas are very big and this could
happen in reality.
So you could have a small graph of only three nodes.
But the first one has an idea of 10000, and this one has idea of maybe 50000 and so on.
So many big ideas for only three nodes.
How to handle that?
We will just as simple as make some adjustment for the graph to depend on two things.
The graph representation itself will start to use an order the map.
So we will build the the edges such that there is a hash table from node, for example, one thousand
two node, for example, 2000.
So the edges here would be based middle and order map.
So this will use it to represent that graph itself.
The second thing we would like to mark the nodes as visited.
So with an order, the said for that, this end up with a time complexity the same as the normal algorithm.
This representation is very powerful for very specific graphs like imagine that there are a lot of isolated
nodes.
So this one could be, uh, be very flexible.
So it is implementation.
Uh, we have here an adjacent Celeste.
But all what happened is we used an order the map from an integer to a vector integer here.
OK.
Someone may, might even would like to make this like a hash, said this, that it would be like an
order the map of integer and has set.
That's OK.
But we don't care here now that much because we just need to iterate on the numbers.
So we have here an order the map of integer.
So now a key.
For example, what hundred would have the list of maybe seven, maybe 2000, maybe five, which is my
neighbor?
Sort of what we gained in just this flexibility.
And then we adjusted the ad directed edge to be in this way.
Now they give us the idea and idea.
We will iterate and add directed edges from the ID to be idea.
So this is how we build the graph when it comes to iteration, the iteration here is as simple as you
used it.
But now, instead of vector of integer, we need something that allow bigger ideas.
So we use the hash sat here and then we check it here.
Let's hold.
Anything else is just like a more or less implementation is counts.
In the second problem.
We would like to the Embley problem.
So this is again another reachability problem, and it's 023.
So what is new here?
The new is two things.
First of all, the value is the way it is with the road, not with the H.
So this time, but obviously we have a three this way.
Maybe this is exhibit this ID eight.
Now we have a value burn with like five, three two.
And I told you in the lecture before that even nudes can sometimes ever wait.
The second thing is we already are given a good, a good graph.
So maybe we can use it as it is without having to create our own graph.
Remember the domain and the standard of that?
I wanted you to try to iterate here based on the graph to make our life easy.
And to make things efficient.
We have a symbol stable that map for us an ID to its object.
So first of all, we will trade on all of the objects and then MEB.
The ID to the object, for example, would have an idea like 12 going to the object, which has zero
x one one two blah blah blah.
Then what does that do?
Reachability from this idea?
It will start by getting the ID then bleak or responding to this ID.
Then, uh, this is my current result, and I will iterate on my all of my employees and adding.
It's unresolved now, this is a race and recursive definition here.
So let's think about it here.
Let's think as a normal graph you have here too.
Uh?
OK, let's see.
Represented as following.
Will make a circle.
The first one is the ideal, it's collegial and valued, it's set well.
And then this one go to hear two and maybe three.
And value, which is 15.
And then another year, maybe two.
No, the number two and value 20.
And then this one go to here to rule.
No.
Maybe food and value.
Um, 13.
And this one go here to ironwood, which is five.
And value 50.
And maybe here six.
And value, uh, maybe hundred and one.
That it just happened, so now I would like when I recurs on this note here, I would like to to some
15, some 30.
If I requested on 12, I would like to return as the sum of 12, 15, 30, 50 to 100 and all of them.
So this is a zero to three.
Remember that so that the defense function is returning the submission of all of the values of this
note and all of its children, the legibility of this one.
So 320 the sum of all of the notes that are reachable from me.
So this is now the recursive definition.
So we start, for example, let's say the query is not zero zero zero, what occurs or not number three
and will come back to researchers.
Number two now think thinking recursive way.
If this function will return and do the job, what would be the output?
It would be 15 and 30 so added together, which is 45.
And this function recursively what we return the return of the submission, which is 20 and 50 17:00
170.
So we have here an integer result, Bernard and it take my current importance and iterate on every child
and and it's important for me.
So this is the extra thing here for the recursive definition that we need to change it little bit.
It is now just normal deficit, also like a normal defense that do some nice recursion result.
I hope that this wasn't a hard thing for you.
Overall, it's more of a resurgence.
Scales some good things.
Gets.
And the third problem, uh, let's make a separate bid you.