Let's solve a number three, the number three is the connected component, the problem.
This is a very fundamental problem.
You should understand it very well because you will meet it several times during the graph theory.
So let's see.
The good is actually overall is a minor modification from the reachability.
Could we know in the reachability?
The moral of it was to find the roots that are ritual for you.
So, for example, if we have year node one to.
Three.
Four and then five here, so starting from one, we go from one to two market to market three market
for market, we cannot go to five because the directed graph.
Now, when it comes to the connected components, it isn't about directed graph sexually, about the
undirected graph.
So we have here a component component and we have here another component.
So now how can we know?
They'll know that these are two components.
We will use the same device?
Exactly.
They did this following you started from another doesn't belong to a component.
Then you do a device from this note to Carl to mark all of their reachable nodes are from it, according
to undirected graph.
Once you're done, let's say this is not number one.
This is two.
This is war and this is five.
This is three, six and seven.
Now you started from one, which was unmarked and then you saw a lot of it.
After the end of the first third, one two with four or five are all market assisted nodes.
Now you moved in with number two revisited?
Yes.
Move node number three, I revisited no.
This being that node number three is in reachable from any previous component.
So we have a new component here.
So again, the device, which will mark three and seven and six, then we check in with number four
market five Market six Market seven market.
So that's old.
There's no more magic than that.
So it's a minor modification to the reachability.
Good to do that.
Feel free to stop the video at this point and to try to implement the good by yourself in the future.
This problem can be done in many other ways, like the Beerfest or the Union find or what we call digital
assets.
So let's see now the implementation itself.
Adding Building, directing graph, all of that is the same, even the defense is a theme.
Now the only change here is a function for connected component.
The first thing to notice is the twisted array.
It will be defined here as a shared among all of them.
Remember when we could the rich ability to bring to the reachable note from every node we were iterating
and iteration in each iteration, we create a new Boolean array.
Now we would like during the after the first to know which nodes are reachable so far.
So you need to make something that is shared and then iterate.
And if I found and would not vested, then this node doesn't belong to any serious connected component.
So we know we have one more connected component here than we did first, starting from this connected
component.
So in the first connected component, for example, this chain would be market in the second component.
Maybe this one would be marketed and the third component.
Maybe this one will be marketed and so on.
In every one of them, there will be at least one node that was never reachable from all of the other
nodes.
So someone may claim, OK, what if this node isn't reachable?
But this is reachable impossible because of this is reachable using the device or on directed graph,
it will cover everything.
So this is an informal group that whenever we find a node that is invested so far, it mostly means
that this is a component that no one ever recorded before.
So as you see, overall, the Defense Code, the building graph, all of the same and minor changes
to the reachability function.
Now what does the time complexity of that?
The same time complexity and the same memory complexity?
Why?
Because in the connected component case, you will just reach once upset that another subset than a
third of the subset and so on.
So eventually, governing all of the edges of the graph and covering all of the rules of the graph.
So this is merely that reachability problem.