So far, we learned the idea of the defense itself, which you work on any graph I would like to show
you today an example when the graph isn't like a standard graph, you will observe that all of the concepts
that we learned are exactly applied on a specific other domain.
So the goal of this lesson is to learn how to generalize what you learned, so don't get stuck in it.
Um, yeah, so let's refresh.
Also, this information there is what we call an explicit graph and an implicit graph.
The explicit graph is when you have exactly in the nodes and edges and all of that in an implicit graph.
The graph isn't really that that clear like you have to generate it, sometimes with a graph can be
generated in a very systematic way, like an image.
Imagine we have an image and we have full Niebuhr's here so we can trivially generate the neighbors
and build the graph, as we did in the home before.
The interesting thing here that creating the graph consumes time and money, but there is no use of
reason here.
Like, you don't see what is advantage of creating the graph really in this way, we already created
the graph in this way during the homework.
But in practice, what's the point?
Like, what's the window penetrating, giving number for every position in the array and creating edges
between them in an explicit way?
There is no point in that.
So it's make more sense to deal with the 2D array as a graph by itself.
Generate what you need from it by yourself.
So this is a one thing here.
The second thing is the graph also is clear, but has millions or billions of nodes.
We still know how to generate it.
But even this is really impractical to generate.
So this is another case where you work on an implicit graph.
There are nodes, there are no edges, but we don't build them as a standard graph.
This happened a lot, including Graeme's, because the search procedure would have a lot of states and
usually due to memory limits, we cannot generate explicitly the graph.
We have to traverse it in an implicit way anyway.
We will revisit this type of problems when we like go to the back tracking topic in later in the potato
of this course.
OK.
Let's move more to our problems, but before doing that, I would like to tell you about a nice name
in computer science, which is called the float fell.
If you try to open an application like a Photoshop like application, sometimes if it is a nice feature,
you click on the image somewhere.
So let's say there is a cow here.
Here is a cow connected body.
You select the color like Blue Collect, click only a single pixel in the cow.
Then the word cow would be converted to the blue color.
So we call it float.
Well, the word the float fell as a as the English name means you float from this starting position
to all of the similar regions here.
So here are a bunch of examples of float.
Well, so here in this image, we have three separate components.
If we started here, we started to float everywhere where it has the same color.
Here in this space image, if you started from here, you started to float everywhere, but you would
not get inside the eye because this boundary is a splitting external component from internal components.
And here is another image I would like you to think in all of this images as graphs.
This is something very important like this is a graph of this graph.
This is a graph.
There are edges, anything that any bits of that can reach another other.
So any pixel here in here or here and here or even inside here and here or here and here, this are
all.
It just that has the reachability but edges here.
Note that here here are intelligible to give it.
So try to get this sense of the generalizing graphs.
OK, so this is generally speaking the idea of the offload felt.
Now, let's proceed more.
Let's see how to make a deposit for research on a matrix.
Images are presented usually as a 2D sorry to the matrix.
Images are presented as a rectangle or a 2D matrix specifically.
And when we think about it, as we did before it yourself is a nut.
The neighbor of it builds the edges, but we are the neighbors.
There are different ways.
The most common way is the four neighbors or the vertical and horizontal neighbors, or the upper and
right and left down levers.
So when you see here this node, it has a maximum of four neighbors.
The node at the boundary here will have only two neighbors.
So this is the four neighbors this time and the neighbors, the style.
You actually look to the eight ones that are around you.
So this involved with the previous four ones and also a right of left and right, then left, sometimes
in computer vision.
You even can expand the more so you can have all of this region together and so on.
Even a problem might tell you that I just need this tool and this tool and this tool and this tool.
So for in a in a bigger range, sometimes it is just you would like to get this one, this one, this
one, this one.
So from a domain to another, that is what decides what is age.
So for now, let's consider the this kind of of food and eat style already to any food.
Now, let's let's think about building the graph.
We can build the graph in either an explicit way, like we did in the homework or an implicit way.
So in an explicit as we did the metrics we can indicate from zero to Earth and C minus one.
And then we have this formula now.
Every node has an ID, generate the edges that generate that their neighbors.
So for example, if this node has the label of 16, this node has a level of 17 and we can see they
are neighbors.
So we have an edge from 16 to 17.
And we did did that before in the whole correct.
Now, today we would like to generate on the implicit one, like, how can I make a difference on the
three if I am having to do that in an implicit way?
Now, let's solve the flood, Phil problem from late night church in the night could problem it tells
you you will be given a matrix representing an image.
Aitchison has an image which to represent a color in an image.
Now it will give you a specific rule and call them.
So let's say this big this position serves one, and one is to give you this one.
It would like you to find the connected component of this one.
What is a connected component of it?
What is a region of it?
It is the region that is reachable, and all of it has the same color.
So you see, this node can reach this one because they are only.
This one can achieve this one.
This one can reach this one.
This one can issue from here or from here.
This one can reach you from here.
So as you see, all of this work that is here was one are reachable.
So all of these are connected.
This one doesn't belong to them because it doesn't belong to this connected computer.
I hope this concept is now very clear.
It's exactly the same concept as a graph.
However.
We just this time find this the only neighbors here.
Now the task is you will start from a specific position, find all of the nodes that are part of my
connected components, part of my region and give them the new color, which is to so it gives you a
location which will have all the value.
All of the values within this region should have the new color.
So what makes?
Dubik says as neighbors, they must be four neighbors connected like Abdul left right.
And they must share the same color.
So this one here?
This one here as a starting point, has this one as never has, this one has never but doesn't have
this one as a neighbor and doesn't have this one as a neighbor.
This one here has this one as a neighbor and has this one as an answer.
I hope you.
You got it, and I hope you.
Visually, you see the way it did.
I would like you to stop it.
Just observe it.
You try to solve this problem by yourself, without without,
without rebuilding the graph in an explicit way.
So give a trial for that.