Let's proceed solving the problem.
First of all, I have here a similar external utility.
They try to take some position, RNC Animatrix and just tell me if this is a position within the utility
within the metrics are not so we have here to the metrics.
And I would like to know if this is a valid position or not.
So something that's here, something that's here, they are invited one.
So I verify the rules are valid.
The columns are valid.
If none is valid, return defaults.
Otherwise, returning to this is a requested function that we have to do it.
I started by creating a visited matrix.
Now remember, in the normal defense, we would like to make sure the node is visited or not.
So when we have any nodes, we created vector of any nodes.
Now we have a matrix of 2D.
So I created a 2D matrix of rows and columns that represent that the given Imbert and Sebastian one.
So the first the change here we use the Boolean matrix.
But to do this time, we started by calling the defense function, giving it the source and destination
and giving it the all the color.
And here is the new color to market.
Now let's see.
How can we do the defense?
We started as following, we've we've verified if The Matrix, OK, we started with sub RNC would like
to know out of this RNC invalid if yes, return is a cell visited before during the defense, if yes,
certain if the all the color we have doesn't match the current fiscal position.
Also, skip it.
So these are the different cases where we skip the values.
Otherwise RNC now would represent my Newt indices.
So a more currency was through here and I replaced the old the color with the new colors.
I hope you can see that the like the the correspondence between the Normandy office now we have four
neighbors, one of them at plus one and zero minus one and zero zero a minus one zero and the plus one.
And again, ambassador, all the color that we have in the new column have.
I hope you can see that we are dealing with each other in the sea as our roots.
When I tell you what are the ages of us we have went into from here, when, from here, when, from
here and from here, so we can build the four edges, see it in a different way, in a very similar
way.
And as this recursive function is making for calls, we are validating here the are within the boundary.
We are validating that we never visited this before.
We are validating that we have the same color.
If any of that is wrong, we return.
Otherwise market the cell node, iterate on the four edges.
I hope you can see the correctness of the good.
Now let's make things more elegant.
Don't proceed in the video if you don't 100 percent to get this good.
Now what if you have it Niebuhr's, you will write it lines of code.
What if you have 24 Niebuhr's?
You write 24 lines of code.
This is very, uh, stupid a slide.
We need a way to make it more elegant.
So how can we make that?
That's the question.
Think for 30 minutes about this.
This question?