Let's proceed and see how can we do it?
So here is a hint assume you are at position zero and zero.
And you would like to get your neighbors.
Can you create two one D arrays?
OK, one here and another one the array and record in each one of them.
The difference between the current position and the neighbor position like in terms plus one minus one,
for example.
How can that help you?
It is worth having if we are at position RC, if who would like to go up, we go to R minus one and
see if we would like to go diagonally.
Here we are at war and so on and so on, so we can see the differences from a position to a specific
neighborhood.
Now the question is what if we created an ad to erase and recorded these differences, which are here,
for example, for us mainly plus one minus one or zero, we call them the direction race, and they
help us to right the good in a smarter way.
So let's write the code to be more smarter than that.
We will have here two arrays.
One of them is the direction of rules, one of them in the direction of columns.
And it means the following.
So here we are, assuming we are a zero and zero if we would like to go up.
Zinke, clearly the rules would be minus one, and the current would be zero.
So this is the difference here.
If you would like to go here, for example, may be right, then the current would increase one and
this one would be zero.
So as you see, you can think of it as a delta from the current opposition to the naval position.
Or you can just write here zero and zero and list all of the relevant neighbors within the hour, your
list here.
So this is how we build this in an easy way.
Now the idea is following you iterate on all of your neighbors, the delta that you need and then the
rule of law is the current through the column of laws.
The change in the column is what you need.
Now what if I need to have, uh, eight eight neighbors?
You can write here your list of eight neighbors.
Then there will be just eight.
What about twenty four?
You can write the 24 on it right here.
So as you see, it ended up just a single loop iterating on the node and its input.
And that's it.
But I would like to tell you even a smarter and smarter track.
Hmm.
Let's say you would like to iterate on all of your eight neighbors here.
OK, if you created two four loops, one of them over the Earth from minus one to one and another for
Loop DC from minus one to one two from minus one to one.
The combination of this for this loop has three values minus one zero one.
This one has three values minus one zero one.
This represents the nine values that represent to this region.
So you can make only these two regions like remove this one here.
Use this for Loop, for loop and for loop.
And then just to call.
Then there's only one trickier you need to discard that went to the R and DC with zero values.
So this way you got these eight values without writing even the delta.
This is even more smarter and better if you would like to make it for the case of the twenty five and
instead of writing it any future direction, the changes would be very hard and very challenging.
You can make two four loops, one from them from minus two to two.
And another one from minus two to two.
Now this generic for you all of the possible directions, but this would cover five times the five values,
but you need only 24.
So again, discard that the are equal DC equity equals zero.
So this, in summary, are the three different ways to iterate on your neighbors on a grid.
The stupid way?
One by one.
The smart way for the virtual array, which is good specifically if you would like very specific ones
or their intensive iteration here.
That's all.
There are some minor improvements that you can do for this good.
One of them is you can move these kind of arrays outside of the function so that you don't create them
in every recursive call.
The second one, this recursive this very decision.
You can make it early here.
If you did that, you will not like, make an empty stack goal and then return here.
So you've verified before calling or were fight after calling the verification, after the coding,
the good advantage of the good advantage of it.
If the initial RNC something is wrong with them, we will catch it.
So I usually recommend for you validating here.
OK.
Um, yeah, that's all here.
Now, going back to the complexity, let end to be number of our time.
See that here.
It just in the maximum case, are for end.
So now the complexity of our algorithm was enablers e but E is anyway for N, so it's eventually open.
But but remember if something like R and C r 2000 this mean we have one million would to be careful
about.
Keep that in mind.
Very can trade up to the maximum of the number of so again, it is all in.
Always remember that that the region has an auxiliary space.
Um, one thing here also is good to say the internal stack of the occasion is limited size, so a huge
recursive calls will end up with a runtime error correction or could.
This is where the next the technique the DFS can solve this problem because it isn't iterative.
It's an iterative technique.
Finally, I would like to say a nice competitive programming tip.
Sometimes it a good idea to randomize the four directions in each school.
So this sometimes will be very good to avoid being trapped in a specific behavior.
Let me say this in a different way.
At the moment, let's say our array is up, right, down and left.
You're could we keep making a up as long as no of then?
Right, right, right?
No.
So they right that up above and so on.
This is good, but another strategy is inevitable, of course, of goal.
Randomized the internet for direction.
Then once you go up, right down, left in another recursive code, you go right or left it out with
another one down, left, right and so on.
So this means that if iterating in a very random way, which in general should have a better and more
stable performance, especially if the grid is a very degenerate grid that is designed such that you
in general will take a huge step.
So if it happened that you wrote a device and it seems like runtime error before right, rewriting the
good as a beef's just to try randomizing the food directions.
But the vectors of the rest of the poor direction must be looked at inside the function, so every one
of them has its own version of the randomized randomized the slide.
I hope you get the idea anyway.
Overall, as you see, theoretically, there is no difference to the DFS itself.
All what's happening is we were building the graph and defacing the graph in an implicit in an implicit
way, as you see, building the graph is very systematic, like you have a node and you have the four
neighbors.
So what is the point we just generated on the fly when we when we need it?
Observe that in some of the domains, real life domains, the generation.
The age of the generation is very slow.
In this case, you might think that building the graph in an explicit way is good, like imagine that
you have a state here, A. And there are maybe 20 neighbors, but you need, for example, for neighbors,
you need of EM Cube to build your edges.
So now you have a trade off.
Do you like to generate the edges in the cube and build the things on the fly over me better?
You just do the training the generation or fly it and use your edges.
It happened based on the problem and based on the trade off in the in the real life scenarios.
That's all.