Homework number two for the defense, so this homework is focusing mainly on how to make a defense on
a metrics.
Don't get scared.
The problems are in the throat.
The first one is named the islands.
So what's the sub island?
You will be given specifically two metrics metrics number one, grade one and the grade to the values
here, or just zeros and ones zero represent the promoter and one represent like a land.
Now, the island is merely a group connected to funds in the four normal directions up, down the right
and left.
So this is so far like the normal reachability we did.
Now here is what we want to do.
We would like it in an island, for the island, for an island in grade two.
We would call it sub island if it is completely existent.
Island one.
So let's see an example here.
This is great number one.
And this is good number two.
Now this one here has this Big Island has this island, this island, this is grid number one.
For grid number two.
When you look at it here.
Consider this grid, for example, here.
This one here.
Is completely inside this one sexually identical.
So this is a sub island.
Now for this one.
We see that it isn't inside any island from here.
So this one is an island.
This is an island by itself and this is another one.
They are in the Orange one island.
There are two islands.
This island, a subset of this island.
This island is a subset of this island.
So overall, there are three islands here that are sub islands here.
As overall, this one has actually much more than that, like this is one island, this is second island,
this third island for Island five island.
So Great two has five islands, but only three of them are Sub Island here.
So what should we do?
Is return the number of the sub islands that we have?
So this is this all.
Please read the description again if you are confused.
This is another example here we can see that this Big Island isn't part of this one, so it isn't counted.
This island is part of this one.
This island is part of the same island here, so we have two islands that our islands from that one.
Problem number two, coloring a word.
You would be given a single matrix and a specific rule and the color and a specific color.
Each value in the grid represent a color, so think of the think of the color here, like if the given
grid is just an image like the footwell problem and the connectivity is exactly as we did in the flood,
the four directions.
Now we would like here.
We want to color the wool grid, as we did in the UM, as we did in the flood.
For lecture, we will only color the border.
So what is the burden of a connected component?
It's actually given for you here as a definition.
The sill is a border in two cases, only the first case.
It's adjacent to a cell that isn't part of the current two component.
This is no.
One kiss number two, that the cell is actually a boundary agreed boundary, so on the grid boundary.
So maybe you will take this specific initial location, find the connected component, find the border
of the connected component and reshape it to the color.
There were the border just here.
Try to understand it in a normal way, like don't confuse yourself.
So to see here the examples we have a Matrix two by two.
The first value is one and one.
The second values is one and two.
Now it's, say, starting from zero zero.
So this is zero zero.
And then it asks you to recolor the boundary, the border only with three.
So this is actually the whole connected component.
As you see this three things all of them already are achieving the two conditions they are on the boundary
and they are even do not have a neighbor here.
The story this one has a different neighbor and this one has a different neighbor.
So this to here satisfy the two conditions this one.
That's why condition.
But in a way, once in a while, one of them satisfied any condition.
It is border.
So this would be three and three and the three.
Let's see another example here we have two times the three matrix.
And we have one to two and we have two, three, two.
So it's a rosy colored one, so we are at it now.
Let's see where is my where is my, uh, my connected?
Compare this to here.
Now we would like to reconnect with the color three.
All of them would be exactly the same case here, so it would be three and the three and three.
So overall, one three three two three three.
This is a year Casimir in this case, the wool gray.
The wool matrix is just a bunch of ones, and let's make it here.
One one, one one one one one one one.
Now it asks you for one one, so are at this one here.
Now let's find the converter to convert is all of this is now coloured with two.
All of them would be two.
Except this one, it would remain one here.
Why?
Because this one isn't the border.
It doesn't.
It isn't on the grid cell boundaries.
And it isn't.
It doesn't match any any that it doesn't touch any element that is out of the compound.
Here we understand it.
If you look at it, you look at the examples that are given out very bad.
So I think for you one more example here.
So we are given this grid here and we would like to find the border of this one here.
Now, in terms of the connected component, we have all of that with us.
All of that was us.
All of that.
And that's here.
And also this to one here.
Now this is a connected components.
So which one of this connected component should be marketed should be the boundary?
So this one here?
All of these tools are neighbors for something that isn't in their connected computer, so they are
all boundaries.
This two also are matching none elements in the connected components.
All of these tools are at the grid boundary, so all of them are outside the connect component.
Now, this, too, is neighbor for this forward, so it's neighbor for a dude that is outside of the
community with us.
These two are at the boundary.
This one here.
Is enabled for this for it's also a boundary.
Now this, too, is the only one that isn't boundary because it's surrounding with normal values.
So, so as you see, if a cell is surrounded with four elements coming from its same component, it
is.
It isn't about the otherwise boundary.
The goods are there the boundary.
I hope you feel it like, you know, if this is a big sea.
And this is an island.
So we say that this is the outside one here.
Israel is the boundary of the island, so this is a natural human concept.
This is the boundary of the island.
As you see, if this is the island, this is water.
So the boundary must be touching elements from outside the components.
And also here we have amended definitions, also touching there, touching the grid, the grid boundary
hidden, it's also a boundary.
So anyway, here are the two rules given by the problem statement.
Just apply them nothing.
Don't get yourself confused.
And theory the problem would like to count the number of closed islands.
So what defines Cruz Island is it's just following, first of all, the connectivity as we did before.
All of them are connected this way in this problem.
They flipped.
So zeros are the ends and ones out of the water.
So this problem, you ignore the ones and you depend on the zeros.
So now let's say we found seven connected components the close.
The island is an island that is surrounded totally by other nodes, by other values, which is once
here surrounded totally by the ones.
If the island is surrounded completely by ones, then it must be a closed island.
So let's see here.
So here is an example.
This is one island here.
This is one.
Yes, island here.
Now literally the condition is it completely surrounded?
Was once the answer is yes.
So as you see here and here and here, all of this from the external world is is once and internally
also ones.
So just round it from everywhere, internally and externally with once.
Another scenario is zero, which is surrounded by ones from all of the directions.
Now.
For this zero, it will not be considered y because it isn't surrounded from here and from here by ones,
the zeros are surrounded from here by by ones.
OK, so this is merely what defines what is surrounded, what it has to be covered from way.
It cannot be a boundary of the of the of the close.
The eye of the island is touching the grid boundaries.
It cannot be island and so on.
Uh, yeah.
This is one more example.
This is exactly this one has further direction here, so it's OK.
This ones are touching the grid, so they are in the boundary anyway.
OK.
The less the problem, we would like to detect the cycads.
So we are in a matrix symptoms and and uh, we would like to know if there is a cycle or not here.
So what makes a connected?
What makes a cycle?
The cycle must be of length of four or more.
The first of all, and you must the start and end at the same cells and you can move in the normal for
direction up, though in a lift.
But they must match of the same value.
So this is very close to what built the connected components in Philadelphia lecture.
So same values in four directions.
But this time we would like a cycle.
You cannot move back to the cell that you use it and consider it the cycle.
Like, for example, someone at one one go to one two, then one one is, uh, is invalid.
Uh, yeah.
Let me read that to make sure you cannot move to the side that you visited in your last move.
For example, one one one two one one is invalid because for one two, we visited one one, which would
allow us to visit the cells.
I honestly confused.
Uh, let me tell you what I remember here.
Uh, let's say you are your eight year.
OK.
Let's say you are.
Looks like very ugly.
Let's say you are right here.
So here is the best one, so you can go this way, this way, this way and this way.
So this way you made one second.
As you see the lenses for this is the minimal possible second.
OK, so no one can do something like starting from here, go to here, then go back to here.
This isn't a cycle.
As you see, the lens will be just the three and also you just return it back to your previous cell.
It shouldn't be this way.
OK, let's see the examples here, which will make things more clear here, this one.
If we started from here we go.
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go.
We made a cycle.
So this is one way to make a cycle.
Another one, which is the minimal possible cycle you go from here, here, here and here.
Yeah, that's it.
So this is now there are two possible, so I can see it.
Uh, another case will be here.
Uh, I have the impression that I just, uh, I missed an exam, but sorry for that.
This one should be example to hit his example.
Number three.
If you started at this big here, go here.
You cannot go back to this B and this one also.
So overall, there is no there is no psych in here.
So, yeah, just keep in mind the two things that I told you.
It is as normal as the reachability problem.
You go to your four boundaries.
This what create a connected component?
We would like to make sure we are in a cycle.
The lanes must be at least four.
You cannot go back to your your previous cell.
You cannot go back to your lost, Twisted said.
You have to go to a new set.
So.
So the matrix four times four would be the.
The best one that you can.
The smallest, ever cycle.
Uh, yeah, this is mainly how can you?
This is really the locus of the problem.
This is a statement that, I mean, I believe you say just.
Uh.
Oh, yeah, I got it now.
Sorry for that.
So let's say one based indexing you are at one one, which you say here, and this is one one two,
which is here.
Then you go here, you cannot go back here, which is which is what I was saying.
That's all.