In this session, we will learn about two core concepts in any programming language, data types and
variables.
A lot of data are uploaded daily on Internet, on social media
this could be your personal information, such as age and name, your images and videos and so on.
A lot of data.
But what is the data type of this information?
If I'm saying I am 52 years old, "52" here is our value, we call it a number definitely , but but when
it comes to programming language, we start to give other kind of names.
We call it in C++, integer.
So I am 52, 52 is a value.
We call it a number, C++, call it an integer.
If I say the baby is 2.7kg, 2.7, we also call it a number, but C++ differentiated
than the normal number and call it "double" or "float"  a double number, is a number that involve a fractional
part, a fractional part.
So it isn't just complete like this one.
I could say also my name starts with Z, "Z" we call it a letter, in C++,
we call it character.
Computer is for us a word, but for C++ we call it a string or a sequence of characters.
These all are similar to what we have in our real life.
There is one more special category in programming.
If I say that, are you male or female?
It seems like nothing special for humans, just the status of two things in C++ and programming languages.
We call it "Boolean", Boolean is something that has two different types only.
Let's elaborate more on the Boolean data type
It is something that is just true or false, something that involves only two things.
If I said male and female, then male is true, female is false or the opposite.
If I have a coin, it could be only head or tail two states only.
So we can think the head is true, and the tail is false.
Your light can be only on or off.
And we always say that computers only understand on and off, so "on"
here is a "True" and "off" is a false.
In addition to that and actually, this is how things are implemented, "True" is actually 1, "False" is
actually 0.
And in the very low level of a computer, it just understands this kind of zeros and ones.
So we learned about integer, double, character, String and Boolean, there are actually more other types
and details. In normal courses, they keep digging in a lot of details, but I would say a better learning
style is just to stop on fundamental things here.
And later, we are going to elaborate more and more.
The other thing that we would like now to talk about it, is that the need for names, let's say we want to
build a program for a hospital.
We need to refer to patients like, say, "Mostafa is 50 years old and he has two children!".
We have a doctor who has a name, salary and address and so on.
Now, we would like to represent this information, from one side
we need to put them in memory when the program starts.
Memory is something that you usually find inside your computer, inside your laptop.
Typically this way, it's where we store the temporary data for us.
So we need to put them in memory.
And also we need to give them some names so that we can refer to them.
So, for example, what is Mustafa's age?
It's 55
We need to refer it
Let's highlight more.
What is computer memory?
Computer memory is more like streets.
If I told you where do you live, you typically have some street name like I'm living in 127
John Street, so it seems like 127 is some location.
John is the name of this street and inside your home there are different types of people, some
are male, some are female, and we have also children and so on.
So, we notice here the memory, the memory has locations and has names and this is actually what a memory
would look like in reality.
Think of it like boxes.
Every box has some information, here in box
number 2, (like the street number) we have
"Age", this is a name we have a value of 55
we have a data type which is integer.
We have a 3rd box in the memory.
Its name is "Weight"
its value is 92.5.
Its type is double, and so on.
You can think of it like for (Example 6), 6 positions in memory
every position has a name and has a value and has a type, we call it variable.
So when I say data type I'm referring to, is it integer?, is it double?, is it character?
And when I'm referring to the variable name, I'm referring to Age, Weight, Group and if I'm referring
to the values like 55 and so on.
So over all, (Age=52)
We have a name: Age, we have a value: 52.
We have a data-type which is integer and it exists somewhere in the memory, somewhere in the RAM.
OK, as a side note, we call the variable name, we call it "Identifier" so we typically will use the
word "Identifier".
As a homework for you, I would like you to guess the syntax rules of C++ for the following valid statements.
Read them,
think about all the components of them and try to guess what they're meaning
till the next lesson.
That's it! :)