homework set number two, on the first problem, you will be doing a tracing mean to follow
step by step by yourself and guess the output as if you are the compiler, we did that before.
You will take this number one, number two, number three.
And then observe there is like a kind of pattern here.
So anyway, try to guess the output here, which is like mainly couting the number of three here.
And after that, educate yourself about what is fibonacci number.
Here is a link.
And the second program, we will do a swapping operation, swapping is a very common term
in programming
It means to exchange the value of two things.
For example, let's say you read 2 integers here, num one and num two.
And then let's say the input is seven and 231.
We can do a swap operation which will exchange the content of these two variables,
Number one, number two.
And then we print them.
They are two hundred thirty one and seven.
So they are now swapped or exchanged.
You are right, three lines of code here that will take number one.
And number two, do the Internet exchange so that the output is like that.
That' all.