Let's solve the second homework. The first one is about tracing, if you tried to run the code that I
provided to you, you will observe that the output is one, two, three, five, eight, 13, 21, 34
, fifty five.
And this is the same output of the Fibonacci sequence.
The Fibonacci sequence is a very popular one.
It has a lot of mathematical properties.
And if you observed, every number is the sum of the last two numbers.
For example, thirteen is a sum of 8 and fiv5, five is a sum of two and three, fifty-five is a sum of
thirty-four and twenty-one.
Twenty-one is the sum of eight and 13.
Fibonacci is very popular and very common and appears in many things.
So what does this code is actually doing, it is actually generating a Fibonacci sequence, if you observed,
I'm trying to say number three is number one plus
Number two, I'm trying to say the current Fibonacci is the sum of the last two numbers.
And I'm repeating the operation for many, many lines because it's very common.
I am moving number two in number one and the value of number three in number two and computing the new
number three, which is number one plus number two.
Anyway, none of that was your business
in this homework, all of what you had to do is just to keep tracing the code.
It is a good skill to be able to observe patterns in things.
Yeah, but anyway that's all about this problem.
In the second problem, we have to do that swapping idea, swapping is all about swapping two values
together from one thing to another.
Let's get the code from here.
I asked you to write three numbers to do the swabbing,
Maybe I can find some picture that would make it easier here.
Swap two numbers, images.
I guess there was something here that I remember it was.
Yeah, that photo is a nice one, let's open it.
Look to this image here, let's say you have two variables, A and B, and you would like to swap
their content.
So the idea is as following, you introduce a third temporary place and the idea is to move the content
in a in the temporary place.
Then you move the content of B to A..
Now you get back the content of the temporary to B, give yourself a minute to watch what's happening
to the two values here, 30 and 50.
So that's all because it will be very hard for you to swab the content without a third value,
although it is doable, but not our business at the moment.
So here is the code, we introduce a third value, which is temporary.
And I start to take the value of num2 and move it to num3.
Now, both num3 and num2 have the same value, now moving the value of num1
inside the value of number two.
Once you're done with that, you can get the temporary value and put it back here in number one.
It's very important to understand these three lines because this is something that is very common in
literature.
If it's still hard for you, you might also watch this video. That's all.