Homework set number three.
In this program, we will extend the swapping two numbers, to swapping to three numbers, maybe swapping
here is in the best name for it,
but anyway, what I mean by that, let's say we have three variables, A, B and c with these values:
One hundred and fifty two, any three hundred and one, then the new values will be 20 you see,
like the B content in A and then C and B, so three hundred and one and the A and C one hundred and fifty.
I would like you to read these three numbers and print them to apply the exchange that we mentioned here.
Try to do it in any way.
But if you would like to challenge yourself, you can do it only in four lines of code.
In the second program, we will read two numbers, A & B, integers, I'm sorry, during the course I read
the word the wrong way, but this is how I used to pronounce it.
The proper way is, I guess, integer.
But anyway, you get used to me saying it's like integer, you are to read  integers here A and B and B will be either
minus one or one.
If B is minus one, you will print two times A plus one.
If B is one, you'll print A times A.
I would like you to think of these two formulas as just big formulas
For example, it can be A times A times A times A because I found so many students are
trying to find a way to handle the printing part.
It's all about the B
here, you are to find a way to print this content based on the value of B try to think in a simple one
line formula to guess that the output here, in the future we will learn about the (if) conditions and you
will see how this problem would be much, much easier when we learn the (if) conditions later,
And the purpose of this homework is to see how when you have more and more programming tools, you can
do things in much more simpler and elegant way.
In the 3th program, you will write a program that read a simple integer and print the sum from one to
N, for example, if the input is N equal five, the output would be 15 because the sum from one to
five is 15.
here are more examples,
4 is output 10.
5 is 15, 3 is 6.
And so on, you need to find a simple one line formula to solve this problem, again
in the future, we'll learn something named for loops.
It will be easier way to do this problem.
However, with a simple formula, this solution would be much more efficient.
The more we go in the course, you will know that the same problem might be solved in several ways and
there might be differences in the efficiency of the solutions.
To get the hint for this problem, listen to the remaining of the of the picture.
The hint is as following,
Let's say that the input in is equal eight,
write
The numbers from one to eight.
Then think about the sum of the first and the last number and then the second and seventh number and
so on.
What do you observe?
Find the formula that is good for even numbers first, like N is even and then think of an odd N. as an
extra thing you might think about what is the maximum
N after it the submission from one to N will be more than the maximum of the integer?
You might think about that too.
That's all.