Let's solve homework
number three, the first problem is about swapping three numbers that we will read, there are two
ways to do that.
One might think, OK, what if we just swap the number one
with number two, then now number one and number two content is swapped.
Taking number two content and number three content to swap it is done then this should be fair enough.
For example, if we are here, if we swapped the content of A and B, you will observe that the a would have
value 20 and B would have value 115.
If you swapped now the B with 301, the B will have 301 and the c will have the coming from b (115)
So, you can use to swaps
to solve the problem.
But if you tried to make use of the problem itself, you can do something much more smarter.
And it's, as I said, similar to the swapping of the two values which is circulating the numbers.
If you observed, it seems num1 is going to number three.
Number two to number one, number three to number two.
So it seems like they are moving in a circle.
So I am introducing here a temp value moving number one to two, then making the circle two in one, three
in two.
Now we are ready to get the temp and put it in number three.
So this is what happened by circulating the number together here.
In the second homework, the print me, which I guess was a bit hard for some of you guys, the
idea is as following, the idea is to convert B to something that creates an equation of zero and one.
Let's see how. I'm going to create this equation here.
Eventually, the equation has the value of equation number one, which is a times a, the value of the equation
If the answer is negative one, which is two times a plus one.
So far, so good.
I'm trying to have a value here that would be either one or zero and this one would be either one and
zero.
If is_one is one, then is_negative_one
should be zero.
If is_one is zero, then is_negative_one should be one.
So, as you see, with any input, either this one would be printed or this one would be printed.
So this is the moral of the algorithm, you can think of this problem in a simpler way,
If I told you that B is either one or zero, if this was the case, then you just multiply here B and
one minus B, B would be one and one minus B would be zero, if B is zero, one minus B would be one.
But I made it a little harder and told you that B is one or minus one.
So the first thing I'm doing here is I'm checking if B is one or not, which is simple here for us.
I'm adding B plus one and dividing by two.
So I found this very simple equation.
Let's trace it.
If B is one, one plus one is two, two over two is one, that's perfect.
On the other side, let's say B is minus one, minus one plus one is zero, zero over two is zero.
So is_one so far is very straightforward.
In the other case I would like to get the minus one, so to do that, I just subtracted one from is_minus
one.
Now, if is_one is one, is_negative_one would be zero.
If is_one is zero, then is_negative_one would be one.
And this way the equation is ready for us to print the two, as I mentioned in the homework,
This problem is solved much easier and trivially using the if condition.
But I'm just showing you if we have fewer tools, how things are a bit more complicated. In the homework
number three, we would like to sum the numbers from one to n.
And if you like mathematics, you should find this problem very interesting for you.
The idea is as follows.
Let's say we have numbers from one to eight.
What is the value of one and eight, which are the first and the last number? 9
What is the value of the second and second to last?
two and seven is also nine.
So this is nine and this one is nine too and three
and six is also nine.
Three and six is also nine, four and the five is also nine.
And you should find an easy logic why they are always nine, they are always n plus one.
It seems we can divide this sequence into (n / 2) pairs and every pair has a value of n plus one
In our case, we have eight values.
We divided them to four pairs each
pair has a value of n plus one.
So if we used this simple equation, anyplace, n * (n+1) / 2, we should get the answer.
Now, the equation so far is good for even.
But what about the odd?
It also good for the odd.
But I would like to think about it by yourself to verify this one is working well.
Feel free to read this link if you would like. That's all.