In this video, we will start learning how to declare variables in C++. Let's define two variables
one for age and one for week.
Let's let's go and browse the code.
The first line here that we care about definitely, is "int age = 55;"
55, semicolon.
So let's decode this line, "int" here
represents a data type of this variable, "int" is an abbreviation for the integer data-type, age is the name
of the variable,
as I said before, it is the identifier. "=" is a message to assign a value.
So we take the value in the right side, put it on the left side inside the memory.
55 is the value that we put in the memory, we call it "literal".
So "literal" for the value, "identifier" for the name. One component two, three, four, five, five elements,
to declare a variable in memory.
If we started to say "cout << age" what does this line do?
This line goes to the memory bringing the value of age, which is now 55.
And just print it so we see it here below, we see 55.
Now let's declare another variable, which will be of data type double, "double weight = 92.5".
"double weight = 92.5"
And now we are printing a message of two components, cout << "My weight is: " << weight;
OK, it just cut from here.
Now if you see declaring the variable just consists of these basic elements that part here is about Eclipse.
So you see the word "int" and the word "double" that would have a specific theme so that you figure out that
there is something about the definition here.
Let's proceed more.
Let's take of the following program.
We declare the variable in memory like integer, number one, integer number two.
The interesting here, there is no equal value that we had.
So just three components, integer, number one, semicolon ";".
What happens here is that the compiler is going to in the runtime we assign a garbage value.
We mean by a garbage value that it could have some random value from the memory itself.
Sometimes students assume that this is going to be zero.
There is no guarantee for that and this is in a way a bad style.
Now in the second step, we started to, after declaring a variable, we did number1 = 30
semicolon ";".
Now, notice the line before in the previous slide.
We had this as one element completely.
Now, we also learned now that we can assign in memory, we don't need to say again, integer, we already
declared it.
So once you declare the variable, you can start to use it within the braces that you have here.
You can start to use it.
So number1 initially assigned a garbage.
Let's say it was assigned for value like -1.
Now, when you say number1 = 30.
The compiler in the runtime goes in the RAM for the location where number1 exists and put the value of 30
then we say number2 equals 10.
Again, it goes in the memory says number2
equals 10 and so on.
So now we declare the variable, we assign the values.
The third thing we can do here is get value.
If you started to say, "cout << number1 + number2".
Number one is a variable in memory.
So it goes in memory and get the value of number1, which is now 30 and add it to the number2,
which is 10.
So when we add them together, they are 40.
If we subtracted them together, they are 20, we can again re-assign a value.
So I can say, number1 = 50.
Now, we will go in the memory and put it now with value 50, we can print a new equation like number times 2 + 1 "* 2 + 1 "
Which would be 50 * 2 + 1, which would be a 101.
So what you learn from here is that we can deal with the memory to declare something in the memory,
assign something in the memory, get value from the memory.
Re-assign a value in the memory.
The identifier, which is a variable name, has some rules.
For example, it consists of letters and digits and underscores"_", but it cannot, for example, be
consist of dashes, for example.
It cannot consist of spaces.
You cannot start it with digit.
You cannot say integer "7core".
It will not work.
So it's, as we said, "Case Sensitive"; that we can say sum (does not equal) SUM.
These are two different variable names.
In C++ there is something called "Reserved Keywords".
These are a set of keywords.
The C++ use them like we saw the "int", "double", and so on.
There are more keywords in C++.
You can not say "int return = 6;", although the statement is valid.
But return is a reserved keyword in C++, so you cannot use it.
Initialization, if we would like to initialize a variable,
there are actually four different cases.
The first one is just to write it this way, "int age1;".
And this is, as you said, is garbage.
Avoid that as much as possible.
The second one is more coming from the C languages, so we say as we do it "int age2 = 52;".
This is a very popular writing style. During the course I will be using this
style all the time.
But I would like to say something.
The modern one from C++11 and beyond is this way.
Instead of writing equal, you use these braces, we call it initialization list.
This is the preferred way in C++, so please stick to it.
You are new to C++ so you can now get to the habit of writing it all the time.
So when you see me writing this way, it is a C style.
Nothing wrong with it.
Maybe a few cases where this style is important and more later when we come to something called object
oriented and learning objects.
This would be more valuable.
Yeah.
Let's now move to the other data types that we saw in C++.
We now know about the double.
There is also character.
We sayو "char group =".
You see here what we did, we did a semicolon before, and semicolon after, we defined the boolean, boolean is
male equal true "bool male = true;" bool like_football = false, and so on.
You see the true and false.
They also like look like a reserved keyword in C++.
We define age as we did before.
We can also say, 'string name = "mostafa" ' and we can start to print all of that.
One of the interesting things here to notice, when we "cout" the is_male, it's actually printed as
1 and 0.
OK, so actually the boolean, true and false, is eventually internally just a number (0 or 1).
Interestingly, even the characters are internally just some number.
Let's finish the lesson with this concept, let's say you would like to print the average of
two numbers, 10 and 21, in math, we know that (10 + 21) is 31 divided by 2
is 15.5.
When you start to write a program, you should start thinking about the right data type.
So here the guy said, Integer, I want (a + b / 2), it gives wrong answers.
OK, now we also get another way.
He opened two braces, and put (a + b) divided by two,
Also giving another wrong answer.
Why?
Because it should be 15.5.
The reason that this is wrong is we use the integer data-type.
But is the output here an integer type?
The answer is no.
The output is fractional part, so we need double data-type.
So these two lines are definitely going to be wrong
to compute the average of two numbers, the right way is using double.
So let's say we define now the inputs as X and Y, double, X and Y, and we started to do one
(X + Y /2), the answer is now 20.5.
This is again a wrong answer.
What's wrong here?
Nothing wrong
this time about C++ (about the data type).
It's more about the rules of C++.
When C++ say (X + Y / 2), it has to decide an order for computing
the result, will it compute (X + Y)
then divide all of them over 2 as we expected?
The answer is no.
C++ is going to divide first, then add later, then add the number.
So what would happen (Y / 2) is 10.5, + 10 is 20.5.
OK, so how now I could force the C++ to follow a specific order?
You can use this, this kind of...
I think it's named braces this kind of.
Yeah.
The brackets here.
When you say (X + Y), it is going to add them first, then divide by two.
This is the expected result.
So the lesson here is you also need to be careful about the right way.
you need to understand the language very well.
The language when it comes to some operators like that would have rules on which one we go first.
We call it precedence rules, will go to see them sometime later.
The last thing to know about is the as we said, the data types has a min or max value.
Integer has a range of minus this big number to this.
Character has a limit of this range.
Boolean is 0 or 1.
If you put a value less than the minimum value, we call it "underflow".
If you put a value greater than the maximum value, we call it "overflow".
So if you try to do that, you are going to get a warning that you are exceeding the limit of C++
for integer data-types.
That's it! :)