So far, we learned about printing, in this session, we'll learn about reading also. In previous time
we used what we call the "Extraction operator" '>>' to write to the console where
c is "console" and out is for "output", for reading.
We use something called "cin", 'c' for console and 'in' for input.
And this time we use the '>>' which is called "Insertion operator".
One of the very classical mistakes from newcomers is using "cout" with '>>' or using
"cin" with '<<'.
It will take time till you get used to that.
The way to read the variable is first to declare it and then just read it,
wait for the user to input number from a console. Here we say integer
number, we just declare a number.
It's now garbage in memory.
We ask the user to enter "your lucky number".
Now the compiler is going to see here "cin>>num" no spaces between them.
When we do that.
And here you see your program is going to be freezing till you enter some number.
So it will be red here all the time, till you enter number.
Once you enter the number it's going to print for you, let's say I input 10, is going to print for you 2
times
10 + 1 equals 21
Remember, do not enter a value less than minimum limit or the maximum limit, or you are going to face
some flow issues.
When we learned about printing more than a message in a same way, we can read more than a
number.
So I can say here, define a and b, notice how I use the comma here.
I define two variables together
in one line, I could say "int a; int b;"
I use "int a, b", to define more than a variable.
And then we say "cout" the message, and then I read two numbers, (a and b) and then printing the
multiplication and addition.
If we input 2 and 5 then the multiplication would be ten and the summation would be 7.
This way we can also read multiple numbers, in a similar way.
We can define more other variables and start to just enter them.
But remember, the data-type that you are reading, so I can define an age and say "cin>>age"
So I'm entering here 55, I can define double and write a double and read a double.
So it could be 92 or 92.5, I am creating a character and entering character entering
here character Q.
You don't enter a colon before and after you just enter the Q directly.
You are.
We are defining also here a name now we are reading name, so we are writing Mostafa we don't enter.
It was double quotes just Mostafa directly. Far from that
we can just print whatever we entered here, so we can read more than a variable in a single line.
We can read several, different data types. That's it! :)