One interesting type of variables is the constant variables.
So when you would like to define a constant variable, you just use the word "const" before it and you
must give it a value at the moment.
But what does it mean to be a "const" value?
As its name suggests, if you define a name as "const" it means, the value is going to be fixed.
So if you try to change the value here, the compiler is going to...
Reject that for you, like give you a compiler error.
So this is as simple as what is a "const" value.
It is something that you cannot change later.
you can define it to double,
you can define it to integer,
you can define it of character, can define it to string, and so on.
You cannot define it without assigning a value.
You must give it a value in the beginning.
So this is mainly the two common issues with it.
You cannot change its value.
You cannot define it without providing the value, on the other side C++ as a language has set of limits
defined already inside it as constants you can find them in the  "#include ".
So here you find in "INT_MAX" and "INT_MIN".
So if you cout INT_MAX, you get this big number, and INT_MIN you get this number.
There is one missing question here.
Why do we need "const" variables?
One important reason for that is preventing others from changing to a value.
For example, if C++ defined a max value like that and this value depends on the operating system
And the code is using it, if we allow the customers or users to change the value, we
will corrupt the whole software.
So we are preventing that from here.
There is another reason, a good programmer would try to communicate his intentions as much as possible.
So when I set "PI" as a const, I am sending a message that this is a const value and it isn't
expected to be changing.
This is a message that I read when I'm trying.
I got when I read someone else's code.
And if I try to change it, the compiler warns me that this is const, there are some intentions that this value
remains as const.
That's it! :)