Homework No. on this basic program, you will read 2 numbers and print there +, -, *
and / operations, for example, if the input from the user is 12 and three, you output
these four entries here with a + - / and *.
Try to think about, like, how to test your code in a good way, maybe considering zero as a first or
second number, maybe negative values, maybe even old values,
try to think about the max value of int, give some trials
this should raise up some questions that during the course you should get some answers for them.
In the second program, you will write a program that reads 2 students' information about math exam.
You will read per a student is name, ID, and grade, and then you will print them
according to the picture here, for example, we read the student number: name, ID, and grade second
name I.D. and grade, then you have to print them and also print to the average of the math exam.
So we have 20 and 30,
The average is twenty five.
So please stick to this input and output style, think about your selected data types like an industry,
someone like the teacher or the school will give you the following scenario, but you have to be careful
about your assumptions.
For example, is exam's grade integer?
So you have to think about that.
Even and Odd sum, in this problem, you will read eight space-separated integers.
Here are the eight numbers and then you should find the sum of those in even places and the some of
the odd places they even places like the second four, six and eight number, for example here.
the second would be 2 then 9, 4, 3, -1, you will sum them,
This is even places and the remaining are the other places,
So you should just print this even sum and odd sum.
That's all.