Let's see how to solve the problems of the homework, the first one, I guess, is very straightforward.
You just need to start to read the values here, I selected integer,
But I guess this isn't the best value that you should choose.
For example, the integer here will make a problem when it comes to that division.
So a more proper way is to use a float number.
So this is like a bad choice here, a proper way is to say, like, for example, double a and b, because
this will fit with more reading in the input and also fit with the output itself.
Otherwise, we are just printing all of them.
If you tried with yourself to divide by zero, you will notice that this isn't working very well.
It will actually crash if b is zero, the more we go in the course,
You should understand that and you should learn
how can you handle this division by zero.
In the second problem, also another straightforward, you should read and do the
the average part.
So let's see this code here. In this one here,
I started to read the first person.
So here is its name.
Here is the ID.
I selected double because this is a good choice for the average.
And then also in a very similar way,
Reading the second guy information here and after that, I follow the screen by printing the grade number
one and two, and after that, I am printing here the average of the two numbers.
I was tricky in the sample input, I used 20 and 30 which will have definitely the output as twenty-five.
But if I use something else like let's say twenty and thirty-one, then the output will fail.
If grade one or two is integers.
And also this isn't a double format like this point is zero.
So be careful about the used data types here.
In the third problem, we would like to get the even and odd sums, so it's all about the positions, this
would need, like a few thinking or a few minutes to think about how to do it in a smart way as an
advice.
When you have an idea to solve the problem, don't just go directly with it.
There are too many ways to solve the same problem, especially when the problem is a bit hard.
So give yourself the time to think about how to solve a specific problem.
The easiest way, in my opinion, I defined here four variables for even and four variables for odd.
And then I'm reading them in a direct way, odd one then
Even one, odd two, even two, odd three, even three.
This way the even variables are together and odd variables together are ready for me to just use
them and print directly.
So I hope this is like an elegant way to try the problem. That's all.