We start our discussions in the algorithms course with something basic,
uh, mainly to allow us to start to understand what is an algorithm really, and some concerns about it.
So, why the topics are easy?
The goal is mainly understanding about them.
In computer science,
there are two very popular topics the sorting topic and the searching topic.
So we start with one of the very popular topics, which is the insertion sort.
So, what is insertion?
What is sorting?
Probably, you know this problem already from the programming course.
Simply, we have a group of numbers, and we would like to sort them from small to large, that's simple.
Now we have here a group of items we can start to sort them, so zero is the smallest, two,
three, and so on. And we can clearly see that any element is less than or equal to the next
element.
And there is a mathematical property that you usually don't notice, but it's also good to notice about
them.
If I told you that two is less than five, and five is less than ten, logically this means two is also
less than ten.
We call this feature transitivity.
So also, the sorting involves this transitivity in the array itself.
So if you compared every element with only the next one and it's smaller, and this one and
it's smaller, and this one and it's smaller, then definitely this one is smaller than this one.
And also, I think it's very intuitive, but why sorting is important?
First of all, as you will notice during the course, there are many computational problems that actually
start by sorting the data because it makes things much, much easier, especially the greedy technique.
And you can also find that in a lot of real-life applications, for example, you might go to the LeetCode
website.
LeetCode website is a site that lists different problems, and then it wants to order its problems
based on the acceptance ratio,
or maybe you are in your Gmail and you would like to order the problems based on the size of the attachment
file, and so on.
So this is the sorting problem, and this is why it is important. Now,
It is very educative to talk about some very popular terms that people use from time to time.
The first thing is an increasing sequence.
Sometimes we say strictly increasing sequence, and this means that every number is bigger than the
previous one.
So three is bigger than two, and so on.
So in general, A[ i ] is less than A[ i + 1 ].
OK.
What if the sequence has duplicate values?
The concept of strictly isn't applied anymore because now A[ i ] is less than or equal
A[ i + 1 ]. We call this sequence non-decreasing.
So the increasing means no duplicate values, the non-decreasing means there are duplicate values.
Non-decreasing means it's actually increasing
but there are duplicate values. Notice that some sources might still use the word increasing to refer to
this sequence, and they use the words strictly to refer to this sequence.
So sometimes you need to check out the definition itself. In a very similar way, the decreasing one,
this is a decreasing sequence or a strictly decreasing sequence.
This one has duplicate values,
we call it non-increasing sequence.
Remembered, we say non-negative number.
OK, so the same concept.
Uh, what about this sequence?
It is neither increasing nor decreasing, so there's no order here in this sequence,
we need to sort it first.
There are also two other popular names the ascending order and descending order, ascending means we are
ordering from small to large.
Typically, this is as same as saying this is non-decreasing, and descending means to order them from large to small.
This is as same as saying it is non-increasing.
I like more
the ascending and descending because they get us out away of the definition issues in these ones.
But anyway, you should be aware of these concepts.
Let's move further.
The sorting algorithms, as you see sorting is very critical, and we learned in the complexity,
how sensitive the operations.
So we know the n,
and during the complexity section, we learned about n, n^2, n^3, and so on.
There is a new order that we start to introduce here, which we call n log n.
Remember, what's the log function? The log function of (256) is just eight, the log of
these four billion numbers is just thirty-two.
Log is a very decreasing function.
It decreases very, very fast.
So as you see, we have a new thing here.
So we used to say we have n and we have the n^2, but actually, in the middle, there is a new
order called n log n.
Um, now for the sorting itself, there are many, many, many sorting algorithms, sorting is historically
one of the very old problems in computer science.
So some algorithms are simple but inefficient like insertion, selection, and we will explain these two.
There is also the bubble sort, it is a bit not intuitive.
However, it's still common for people in explaining, these algorithms are n^2, and we will explain
them in this section.
There are also other efficient algorithms, such as the Merge sort and the Quicksort, I plan to explain
these two things in the end of the course.
The Heapsort is actually based on data structure heap.
I explained that in the data structure course, so it's more or less a data structure topic.
There are also some techniques that take a different path than these ones like what we call the Counting sort
Bucket sort, and Radix sort.
I will explain the counting sort, and the intuition comes from here.
What if all the values, for example, are just zero to 100, not just a general problem?
How can we make use of that?
So these are the different sorting algorithms.
And as you see, there is clearly a huge difference between n^2 and n log n.
For example, if n is like one hundred thousand, the n^2 even over four will be such a huge number.
But n log n is way smaller than that guy.
So it's actually like one versus two thousand and five hundred.
You see the difference!
It's extremely huge difference.
Before introducing the insertion sort, I would like to introduce you to the technique that insertion
sort is based on it.
It's called incremental thinking technique.
Very nice and simple idea.
The idea is as following, you would like to solve a specific problem.
Let's say sorting problem.
You ask yourself this simple question.
Assume we know the answer for the first N-1 elements.
Can we update the answer for the next element or not?
If the answer to this question is yes,
we can apply the incremental thinking.
Specifically, we start with the first element as a base case and keep applying this update operation.
Let's see that in the insertion sort context, we would like to sort an array.
So the question is as following.
What is the sorting answer for the first N-1 elements? So N here equals eight,
and here is the first N-1 elements.
Do you know the answer?
This is a question for you.
Do you know what is the answer?
The answer is simple, yeah, let's get these values,
let's sort them.
Now, the real question here, can you update this answer to the next element, element number  n=8
which is eighty-five?
Like if I told you, given this sorted array, can you put eighty-five in the right place or not?
Clearly, the eighty-five should go here between ten and ninety.
How can we do that?
We can start from the last element and keep going backward as long as we find
the right location for the eighty-five, which will be like eighty-five less than ninety, yes, less than ten,
no.
So it must be here.
I hope you got the idea of the incremental thinking, it's mainly based on these two questions.
Do you know the answer of the first N-1? Assume you know the answer.
Can you update it?
Now, how can we solve it now?
You simply do the following, you start with the first element in the array, which is nine, and now
you keep applying the update operation, put two in the right location, now put ten in the right location, put
zero in the right location, put five in the right location, and so on.
If this is confusing, let's make tracing together.
Assume we have to sort this array.
Now we know that the first element is sorted anyway.
We start with the second element, and ask ourselves, how can we put it in the right location?
Simply, two has to come before the nine.
Iterate from the backward, find a place to put two.
Let's go further. Now two and nine are sorted.
Remember the assumption of question number one, what is the sorted sub-array of the first two elements?
Just two and nine.
Now for the next element, can you update the array to put ten in its right place?
Yes, it should be between two and the nine.
That's simple.
Let's move further.
Sorry, ten here is in its right location, anyway it
will not change.
Let's move, the zero, observe this one now is sorted.
So the array is like the following a sorted part, unsorted parts, and we take the first element here,
and we put it in the right location. Where is the right location? Start from the back,
compare zero and the ten, less than it, compare zero and nine, less
than it, compare zero and two, less than it.
Nothing else.
So zero has to come here.
Let's move further.
The array is as following, these four are sorted, we would like to put five in its right location.
Can we update a sorted array with
five?
Yes.
Less than ten?
Yes. Less than or equal
nine?
Yes.
Less than or equal two? No.
Then it should be here.
As you see, it's all based on the assumption, we have a sorted sub-array.
Can you update it with the new element or not?
If yes, then we can increment our solution.
That's why we call it incremental thinking.
Let's keep going.
Here is the sorted part, can you put three in its right location?
Yes.
Go ten, five, two.
No, it should be here.
Let's go further.
Ninety.
It will not change.
It is in the right location already.
Now,
go back to the.
eighty-five
here, we are at this location.
Go back
one step, still, one step.
No.
Then it should be here.
So this is all the incremental thinking. Again,
How can you figure out that this is possible with incremental thinking?
You ask yourself this very basic question.
Assume you have the answer for the first N-1 numbers.
Can you update it to the new value?
If the answer is yes,
start from the first element,
keep putting in the right location,
keep incrementing, keep incrementing, keep incrementing, and so on.
The technique isn't very popular, but from time to time, you will meet a problem where incremental
thinking will make your life very, very, very easy.
Now we are done with tracing the algorithm.
I would like you to take this course as a very engagement activity.
Without that, the algorithms course will be tough for you.
Don't wait
from me to say everything.
Now, I explained an idea.
Stop the video and think about the correctness.
Think about the time complexity.
Think about the space complexity.
Think how can you code it by yourself.
Trace the code for different test cases.
This is very important skill.
One of the important skills in algorithms is testing.
You should think about the potential test cases. And also do more little analysis.
Here is a tip for that.
Can you find an array input where the algorithm we explained can do the fewest number of iterations?
Another test case for doing the largest number of test cases, and so on.
So these are classical steps that I would like you to try to do as early as possible correctness,
test cases, some analysis, time and space complexity.
And keep in mind that one of the reasons the algorithms topic is challenging.
You have to think, which is the hardest part, you have to code, which is a bit new for you.
You have to find good test cases.
You will debug too much.
You need to prove things from time to time.
That's all for now.