In the last question, I asked you to try to understand this popular count sort algorithm. I see many
courses when they try to explain to the students
the count sort algorithm, they start with this version, and I believe this is bad and wrong, and I
know they do just to follow some textbooks.
But this is a bad idea, in my opinion.
The version that I explained in the lecture is a way simpler version of the count sort.
Shorter code,
easier to understand.
Now, the problem with the previous code in the lecture is the algorithm wasn't a stable algorithm.
So the motivation behind this version is how to make the count sort a stable algorithm.
Um, so here is the point, we can see that the first two blocks are exactly the same as the previous
block.
We see another block that is computing the accumulative sum of the numbers, and we see that
there is some new way to build the vector output, and there is a vector output here.
Now let's try to compare this algorithm and try to understand the differences.
First of all, here are the new problems with this algorithm.
First of all, it involves more memory writes, when you have here adding count[ i ] over count[ i - 1 ],
you are doing more memory access to the count array.
Is it a problem?
99% of the cases,
no, unless you are working on some hardware where memory accessing is expensive.
So these two operations are going to make it slower.
The second thing which is very optional is the locality of reference.
If you studied computer architecture, you will know there is something we call locality of reference.
Let me give you a very informal idea about that.
We have
RAM, right?
This is our RAM.
And there is something called cache .
The purpose of the cache is being way faster to get elements.
So let's say you have an array, let's call it count, for example.
The array count is very huge.
We can definitely put it here in the RAM somewhere.
Now, accessing the array might be a bit slow thing, so maybe the processor will do something else.
Let's say you are accessing the cache array here in this range from maybe 400 to range 450,
and you are accessing this right now.
The cache will do the following, you are accessing this one, so it will only take
this small range and put it here.
The 400 to 450.
And after that, every time you request an index here, oh, it is in our range, we return it.
Let's say you started to access 451.
It doesn't exist in the cache.
What happened is as following, this one will be removed and we will get another one here from
451 to maybe 500.
So the cache is our way to make faster processing, but the cache is way smaller than the RAM.
Now if you have a 2D array,
and you access it row by row, we say that this is very efficient in terms of locality of reference,
which means that informally very, very informal way, the values that you are requesting, most of them,
will be existing in the cache and the in and out of the cache is very limited.
What happens if you have a 2D array and you tried to access it column the by column?
If you made 2D like, let's say you are tried to loop the matrix j, then loop i, which
is column by column, and you tried to do that for 10000 times.
This isn't the same time as looping 10000 times and accessing row by row.
You learned such stuff in computer architecture course.
Why?
When you try to access column by column, remember that the 2D array in the memory is just 1D array,
right?
If you have an array that is 100 * 100, it is in the memory just one single row of 10000 values.
So you tried to access the first value here in the array.
Good.
So we copied for you the first maybe 50 values. Now in the second time, sorry
you access this one here, but it doesn't exist.
We remove this one,
then bring this one for you from in the cache.
Then you access
this one, oh, it also doesn't exist in the cache.
Remove this one and bring this one.
Do you see what's happening? With almost every single element, we keep in and out of the cache.
But in the row order access, it's actually, uh, much faster because every, say, 50 elements will
be already in the cache.
I hope you got it.
This is very optional.
This is something from the computer architecture, something nice that I wanted you to know
about it.
OK, back to this algorithm.
Why it has a bad locality of reference? Because we have a big array and as you will see, we keep jumping
in the array in very different areas.
So I add something here in the output, then I go add something here, then I add something here, then
I add something here.
This jumping
in the memory will cause a lot of in and out of the cache.
That's why it's a bad locality of reference.
The third thing it's actually involving more memory because we created the output one.
So the previous implementation was in-place, actually not in-place, because it has
extra memory, but the input array is the same as the output array, here as we wanted to make it a stable array,
we have to create an extra output.
So the moral of that, this algorithm, all of it, is just to make it a stable array.
And some people try to implement this version, and they don't make the array work backward.
And this is wrong because they did a lot of code and they suddenly lost the reason why we do all
of this stuff in count sort.
Now let's try to simulate the array on an example to make your life easier.
Assume that this is the given array.
Here is the frequency, three is one time, five is two, seven is one, and nine is three times.
Now the second step in the array is doing accumulation here.
We are iterating and accumulating element by element. When you do that,
you will notice that the count of zero is zero zero zero, then three is one, four is one too,
five blah blah blah.
So practically speaking, is the accumulation sum of nine is seven?
Yes, because overall we have one, two, three, four, five, six, seven elements.
Now we don't care about these empty elements in the middle, we only care about the three, five, seven,
and nine.
So this is what we care now, and here is the core of the algorithm.
Why do we do that?
Here is the intuition.
What does it mean that the value, uh,
nine here has, I needed to mention here value nine, value nine has a frequency
three and has a cumulative sum seven?
It means, in array of seven elements,
value nine, which has an accumulation of seven, must be here in positions four and five and six,
must be, because nine has an accumulation of seven, so it should be in index six and its frequency is
three, so it must be here.
In a similar way, let's say the frequency of five is three.
It means from
from position two,
we must have two fives here.
So the moral of that is there is a relationship between the accumulation and the index.
And we wanted to build the output array properly, so we can use the accumulation to build the index.
That's why we did the accumulation step.
So actually, the last two for loops that are building the output are just using this fact.
Anyway, here is some tracing for you.
Let's say that this is just indexing from zero to six.
This is the original input and this is the expected
output. Now, when you trace the output, it goes as following.
In the first step, it says, OK, the value is seven.
What is the frequency of seven? Four.
So four means we need to put a seven in which position?
We'll put the seven in index three, which is the accumulation minus one, accumulation minus one.
Now the next value in the array is nine.
What is the accumulation of nine?
The accumulation of nine is seven.
This means index six will have a value.
Then the value five.
What is the accumulation of five? Three.
It means index two must have a value.
Now there is a trick. After every one of these steps, we decrease its accumulation.
So initially, we have three with one,
five with, um...
Wait a second.
What was the array?
Three with one,
five with two, seven with one, and nine with three and their accumulation is as following.
Three is one, five is three,
seven is four,
uh, three is one,
seven is four, and nine is seven. Now so far, we addressed seven, nine, and five.
So their frequency will be decreased.
Six,
and this one will be three,
and this one will be two.
Why?
Because we already put a value in the array.
So now let's trace it here.
Zero, one, two three, four, five six.
So so far, we put in index three, let's make it here zero, one, two, three, four, five, six, in index
three,
we put the value seven, and in index six,
we put the value nine, and in index of two, we put the value five.
Now,
next is value nine again, value nine now has a frequency of six.
It means we go to the five, do you see? We are putting indirectly the previous one.
So we put another nine, and now the frequency is five because we already put an element.
So the accumulative is decreased.
And again, what is the next three?
What is the frequency of three? It's one.
So one minus one is zero, we put three here.
After that, we have the value of five, which has a frequency of two minus one is one, so we put five
here.
After that, we have the value nine, which has a frequency of five.
We decreased five, we put it here in four, and so on.
I hope you got the
tracing. It might be a bit annoying.
I would like you to notice that we put nine, nine, nine
in this order for the nine, we put the five and five backward in this order
for the five.
I hope you now realize why the algorithm was in inverse order here.
The reason that we put in inverse order is because the last nine we know from the accumulative sum, its
index, this nine here at index six, you know that this is the last nine that we have.
So you put it first.
That's why we are processing from the back to the forward.
If you couldn't get this algorithm, for now, don't stop too much by it.
I just wanted you to know that one lesson to keep in mind, we can implement the same algorithm in different
ways.
Then the properties like, Is it stable?
Is it adaptive?
Is it in-place?
These are mainly based on the implementation.
Something like the selection sort is going anyway to has its own specific properties like it's stable,
for example, the stability in the count sort depends on the implementation.
So most specifically, stability is something that can change from an algorithm to another,
from an implementation to another.
Let me say that in a different way.
The properties that we mentioned with the algorithm are based on two things the algorithm nature itself
and sometimes also the implementation.
So you see here the properties of the count sort changed from not stable to stable based on the implementation.
So it isn't something I shouldn't tell you,
hey, the count sort is a stable algorithm, correct or not?
This is a wrong question.
We can implement it in a way that makes it stable and we can implement it in a way that makes it unstable.
Which one is a good
One?
It depends on the architecture.
It depends on the needs.
Do we need it stable? Use a stable one.
You do not care about stability.
Just use the more efficient version.
That's all.