Let's see the second homework in the sorting
lesson. Let me first share with you a few tips during the course.
First of all, you always have to compute the time and memory complexity for any code that you write.
Even if I didn't mention that. sometimes I might miss describing the time or memory complexity, sometimes
because it's very clear similar to other things.
Sometimes I just forget. If you couldn't figure it out by yourself, or you aren't sure, and I forgot to
mention it.
Just ask me, uh, to put the information.
Any moment I just mentioned the word complexity,
then I just mean the time complexity.
And this is the same for people in the industry.
There is a section for the online judge section where you can use online judges to judge
your
solutions. The online judge is a website or a tool that allow you to automatically evaluate your
code over many test cases so that you can know if the code is correct or not.
Some problems might not have an online judge.
That's OK, just test locally with some
personal test cases, generate a test case, run on my code, run on your code, compare between both
of them.
Sometimes on LeetCode,
there is a premium problem.
So it's a private problem, it's OK, just test locally, and so on.
Uh, the goal of the homework is to think in an efficient way.
So don't just solve with an easy idea.
Try to find something that is a bit efficient.
There are some common terminologies that you will see me using from time to time.
One of them is brute force, which, as simple as, means just try everything.
Let me give you an example, let's say we'd like to find all of the triplets
i, j, and k where each one of them has a value from 1 to 100, and their summation is one hundred twenty
five.
If I asked you to find a solution for this problem, you might think, OK, what about making three nested
loops, loop i over i from 1 to 100, loop j, loop k, and then you sum i+j+k, and compare with 125.
This is good,
but a bit slow, but the moral of that is it tries everything. With some basic thinking,
you can notice that we don't need the third loop, and we can end up with only two loops to solve the problem.
Now, this is still a brute force, but more efficient than that one.
It doesn't try really everything, it tries
most of the things.
So anyway the word brute force means try everything.
The second keyword is Ad-hoc, and Ad-hoc means there are no well-known algorithms for this problem.
During the course, we will study many popular algorithms, but some of the problems that you will meet in
the literature, in the online judges, doesn't have a specific solution for them.
Doesn't have a specific well-known algorithm for them.
We invent our own algorithm for them.
We call them ad-hoc problems.
Ad-hoc problems are typically harder than normal problems.
Why?
Because they don't have enough patterns like the other problems.
The third word is the word greedy and greedily.
Greedy is a well-known algorithmic topic.
The good news is there are a lot of problems that can be solved with your basic logic and basic thinking,
and actually what's behind the scene is kind of a greedy algorithm.
So whenever I mentioned the word greedy, you can just replace it with the word
logically. When I say greedily do something,
It just means logically do something, which in a way or another, we mean just basic thinking and
basic logic will do it.
Just basic observations.
Later, we will study the greedy topic to find some problems where there are more explicit fundamentals,
theoretical fundamentals are needed to solve the problem or to prove its correctness.
But there are a lot of problems that don't require that.
You will notice that many greedy problems start with the sorting step, so the sorting step facilitates
many of the greedy algorithms.
Finally, in this section, I would like you to use always the built-in sort as much as you can when
it's convenient.
To compute your total time complexity, you can assume the sort is O(nlogn), and the memory complexity
is O(1). You can find the sort function in the algorithm, and
if you need the limits, you can find them in the climits.
Now let's move to our problems.
And here is a very important tip for you.
Don't take this course in a very passive way.
Algorithms need active
guys, need engagements.
When I tell you here is the problem,
stop the video,
go to this problem by yourself,
read it once or twice or even three times.
Read the test cases by yourself.
Try to understand the problem by yourself.
Put this effort by yourself. This is going to improve this kind of comprehension skills on your side.
Especially, you will notice that you might be very good in English,
Meanwhile, you read the problem and you do not understand it.
It takes time.
So try to take always these steps.
Don't wait for me.
Go ahead, read, understand, and then come back here to verify.
Sometimes even I might not explain the problem in a complete way.
So always go and be active and understand the problem by yourself.
The first problem is the minimum absolute difference problem.
The idea is as following, we have an array of distinct numbers.
Be careful.
We would like to find all of the pairs in an array such that
they have the minimum absolute difference between any two elements.
What does it mean?
Let's say we have maybe four or five elements.
Try every pair of them and get the minimum absolute difference between all of them.
Now go back and find all of these elements
that have the same minimum absolute difference.
The minimum absolute difference is just |a - b|.
For example, if the difference is minus three, then the min absolute difference of minus three is just
three.
This is the function name that you should develop.
It takes a vector and returns vector of vector.
What is this internal vector?
It is just containing two elements of the pair, and we would like to find O(nlogn)
element. Let's see the examples in case you are confused,
I expect that. Here are four numbers in the input array.
How many pairs we have?
We have a pair from one to two and a pair from one to three,
and a pair from one to four,
and we have a pair from two to three,
a pair from two to four, and a pair from three to four.
So how many pairs in total?
One, two, three, four, five, six, around six pairs, which are (4*3) / 2.
Now, among all of these pairs, compute the absolute difference and get the minimum
one of them.
You will notice the minimum is one. After you're done with that,
find the pairs that have this minimum, which are [1, 2], and [2, 3], and [3, 4] because
these three pairs like |3 - 4| is one.
So two steps, one is to find the minimum, and two is to find the pairs that have this minimum value.
The second problem.
We are given an array of values.
We would like to build a triangle from them such that it has the largest perimeter of a triangle.
So in this case here, this triangle has two, one, two here, the total sum is five.
And this is the only valid triangle here. In this case
here, we have more triangles.
We have different ways to make triangles here.
Now there is a point here.
Some triangles, as we know, aren't valid. Please
google the internet,
What makes an array of edges or sides
abc a valid triangle?
So you should focus only on the valid triangles. If you cannot find any valid triangles, just return
zero.
Otherwise, among all of the different possible valid triangles, we need the one that has the largest
perimeter. The array size will be always valid, so greater than or equal three. Again, develop
(nlogn) approach.
The third problem is as following, you are given 2n integers, you will group them in pairs.
So here is the first pair, the second pair, and the third pair.
There is an operation that we will apply, the operation
is as following, you will get first the minimum of every pair, and then sum all of these minimums.
So, yeah, we will see an example.
Now we can make the grouping in many, many different ways.
We would like to find a way that maximizes the answer.
Now, I would like to tell you something, in the previous problem, we're finding the largest
perimeter, in this one,
you're finding the largest
sum. These kinds of problems are called optimization problems, which mean we find the best solution
among all of the feasible solutions, which typically here in competitive programming, usually
the minimum or the maximum value.
So these kinds of problems that we find the minimum and maximum things are actually optimization problems.
The second thing here, when I tell you to read an array of 2n numbers,
It means we have actually even numbers of items.
So here we have 2n numbers.
If I give you an array of eight numbers, it just means n itself is four.
So the word 2n just means even number of values.
Let's see an example if you are confused from the problem statement.
Here we have four values, [1, 4, 3, 2].
Now, there are different ways to make groups of them, so one way is to group (1, 4), group (2, 3)
together.
After that, you get the minimum of one and four, which is one, minimum of two and three, which is
two. Now the sum of one and two is three.
And this is another way to group, and this is the third way to group.
Now we get the minimum of every pair and sum.
We got three and three and four. Which one is the maximum? Four.
.
So the summary of the problem is to find a way to group pairs such that the minimum of every group,
and the summation of these minimums is maximum, we usually use this arrow up to mean maximize, arrow
down to mean minimize.
So this is mainly the problem.
Problem number five, something is called wiggleSort. You will take an array of numbers, find
any way to make it a wiggle sort. What is a wiggle sort? The first number is less than or equal
the second number, which is greater than the third, which is less than the fourth, and so on.
So it's like a kind of up, down, up, down, up, down, up, down, up, down.
Here is an example if I give you this array, there are many wiggle sort arrays here, so this is one of
them.
As you see, three is less than or equal five, which is greater than or equal
one, less than or equal six, greater than or equal two, less than or equal four,
and so on.
So you will be given an array and find any of these wiggle sort arrays. It is guaranteed that there
is a solution.
If you are building your own test cases, don't build an invalid test case.
The fifth problem has a very lengthy text, but let me give you some insights about it.
Please, go ahead and read it very carefully.
We are in a city, so I am in a city here, this is my city.
And I have a gun.
And there are some monsters who are coming to my city.
So let's say we have one monster here,
and one monster here, and one monster here.
This monster is far maybe, let's say, five kilometers from the city.
This one is far eight kilometers from the city, and this one is far sixteen kilometers from the city.
kilometers per minute, now in each minute, I can kill only
one of them.
I would like to kill as much as I can from them before reaching the city.
Now, each one of these monsters has a speed.
So let's say that this monster has a speed of one.
It means in every one minute, it just moves one kilo.
So this one will reach me after five kilometers.
Let's say that this one has a speed of four.
It means after one minute, it is here, and another minute, it's here.
So it takes two minutes only to reach me.
Let's say that this one has a speed of, uh, four, for example.
Then after four minutes, he can reach me. Once any of them reached the city, the city will
be destroyed. So I would like to kill as much as I can from these monsters in this problem.
So this is mainly the problem.
So here are the distances,
initial distances in km, and here are the initial speeds of them.
I would like to kill as much as I can.
So in the first minute, I can kill the first one.
Now, in the second minute, the first one becomes closer at two.
And the third one becomes closer at
three.
Now I can kill this one now here because they didn't reach the city yet.
Now, after that, we have this one at two, so after every minute, you have to update the new distance
of the monster, and so on.
So for example, here in [3, 2, 4], you might, for example, try to kill the first one, in
the first minute so you killed this one.
Now,
the speed of the second one here is three, and he is already at two.
This means directly after one minute he is already in the city, so he is going to destroy the city.
So I can kill only in maximum one of them.
The next problem is as following, we are given an array is named nums and some integer k.
And there is an operation that we will use to modify the array as following.
Every time we apply the operation, we find some index i and multiply it with negative one.
Now we need to apply this operation k times, and also the same index can be used multiple times.
What is the goal? We would like to maximize the possible sum. So find your way to apply this operation
k times such that the modified array has the maximum sum.
So let's see an example here.
We have only k = 1.
Logically, you would like to take the minimum among all of them and just multiply it with negative one.
So you get over all these ones here.
So multiply all of them,
you get just five as a summation.
Um...
Here you have to apply it three times.
Now, if you choose the following indices one, two, and two.
So if you choose index number one and you applied on it one times, so it's going to be
one.
And if you choose index two to apply it two times, zero anyway is going to be zero. If you choose this
one to apply two times, it is going to remain two.
So the summation is six, and so on.
That's all.