Let's solve homework number two.
Um.
OK.
In the first problem about the minimum absolute difference.
There is an observation here.
I want the minimum among all of the pairs.
Logically, the closest pair for every number is what could bring a minimum value.
So if you try to think about it, the sorted array is the best location to find the closest to me.
The one after me is the closest one to me.
That simple.
So the idea is to start by sorting the numbers, and from the consecutive pairs, just find the minimum difference.
And again, iterate on all of the pairs, again in a consecutive way, and find the minimum difference.
The trick here again is what really helps us to get rid of thinking about two nested loops
to compare the values is the fact if I have something like 10, 17, 19, 25, the minimum
pair for this 19 is only coming from the 25 or the 17.
It will never come from the ten.
It will never come from the thirty, it definitely comes from the neighbor, the neighbor in the sorted
array.
So this is the core observation.
So you start by sorting here, then iterate on every consecutive element to get the minimum.
Then again, iterate back on the array, check if they have the minimum, then we need this pair.
So how did we get rid of the comparison with all of the pairs? Because we only needed the
neighbors' values.
That simple. Let's a move to the second problem.
In the second problem, we wanted to find the largest perimeter of a triangle.
Now it's important first to remember,
uh, by the way, sometimes LeetCode itself has an editorial, and usually, it will have a lot of other
solution.
It is good to read about them, but skip the ideas that you cannot get it.
Sometimes the editorial is good, sometimes not, anyway.
Now, what makes a triangle is valid abc? In math for the triangle to be valid, the summation
of any two sides must be bigger than the third side.
So we have three sides.
We have three equations.
(a + b) must be greater than c, (a + c) must be greater than b,
(b + c) must be greater than a.
If you have a triangle with these conditions, this is a valid triangle.
Now there is a trick here. If a, b, c are sorted, such that a is less than b, is less c, then you only
need to make one check
among all of these conditions, which c here is the largest.
So (a + b) is greater than c.
Uh, yeah.
So this is a good condition to remember. If the numbers are sorted, you only need one of them.
Now going back to the problem, which one can generate for us the largest triangle? As simple
as the largest three values.
But the largest three values might not be enough for the solution, why?
Because they might be invalid.
So the idea is you will scan from large to small, and take every three consecutive
values.
If it happens that they are valid ones, then you don't need to check anyones anymore.
First of all, start by sorting the array from large to small. In C++,
we can do that in different ways.
One of them is just to use rbegin() and rend(), which is the reverse iterator.
Now, after that, iterate on the array normally, take three values,
nums[ i ], nums[ i + 1 ], and nums[ i + 2 ].
So let's say the values are maybe 20, 18, and 10.
So now all what we need to do is as following, we would like to sum these two ones, which is 8 and 20,
and compare them with the largest one.
If these two ones are greater than me, then I definitely found a proper triangle.
So this is the sense here of the solution.
I will leave for you to think more about the proof of this code, like could be something that we need
to do more.
Is there a case that we really to be sure out of it?
For example, in this
code, I assume the following 20, 18, 10, 7.
I assume if these three ones are invalid, then we move to check these three ones.
Could it be that 20, 10, and 7 a solution?
Here we are skipping that.
.
Could this be the case?
Think more about that.
Anyway, this is the second problem.
So let's move to the third problem. In the third problem, we would like to partition group of 2N
numbers.
Um, two groups such that the minimum of the pairs, and the summation is maximum.
So this involves some kind of observations.
Now here is the idea.
Um, let's say we have the following numbers from one to eight.
Now, I know that if I have a pair of (a, b), I take the minimum.
So my target is to keep the large values as much as I can, right? So that I can make it a minimum.
And when you think about it, the value one anyway is going to be assigned with someone, and it will
be the smallest, let's say we have values like 10, 20, 30, and 40. Ten is going anyway to be
part of the summation.
Why?
Because it's the smallest one, so regardless being of 20 or 30 or 40.
It must be part of the output.
So here is the logical thinking.
I have now the minimum value, which is one, and I know that
the answer is going to be one anyway because one is the minimum.
So now the choice is I would like to greedily or logically as we mentioned before.
I would like to keep the large values as much as I can.
So if I said, OK, I'm going to take one and eight, which is one, I lost the value of eight.
But if I took something like one and two, this is more smarter because we got rid of two, but we kept
all of the other bigger values.
When you think about the logic from this perspective, you can think the following.
If I have a bunch of values like that,
I can simply
start from the smallest number,
pair it with the second smallest number, which is two, and then the next is three, three anyway must
be now part of the output.
I will pair it with the next smallest number, which is four, and so on.
This is what we call, by the way, greedy.
So anyway we will end up splitting the values from one to eight to pair one, two, three, four, five, six,
seven, and eight.
Let me show you first the implementation.
The implementation is now straightforward.
Sort the numbers, and now we know the summation will be the first value here, the first value
here, the first value here, and the first value here.
So we take nums[ i ] from this group of pairs, and I'm here
jumping with two.
That's why we sorted the numbers so that we take the smallest number, pair it with the second smallest
number.
Let me go back here and tell you what do I mean that this is a greedy algorithm.
So greedy is about problem
and sub-problem, we will explain greedy later in details.
So, what is the problem?
The problem that we have here is to make pairs of the values from one to eight.
We logically or greedily, sorry, one, two, three, four up to eight, one to eight.
OK.
Why when we're pairing one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, we found that the best choice
is to take one and two together?
Now, what is the next? The next is to apply the same solution to the remaining numbers, we call the values
from three to eight a sub-problem, and we will apply exactly the same logic on the sub-problem.
So this is what we call a greedy algorithm.
We made here a smart choice, and reduced the problem to another sub-problem that will be applied
in the same way.
Three and four will be applied the same, so we get a new sub-problem for the numbers five, six,
seven, and eight, and so on.
.
If you don't get this,
this is totally OK.
What I wanted you to know is we have a problem,
we have a smart choice that reduces the problem to a sub-problem, and we applied exactly the same logic on it.
Every time we say the world greedily,
It means we have a problem that we converted to another problem of the same type,
smaller size,
and we apply the same procedure to solve it.
That's it.