In this problem, we would like to do what they call the wiggle sort.
So just any output is a good output.
So let me discuss two different ways for this problem.
.
And this is important for you to remember that different perspectives can generate different solutions.
Assume for a while that we sorted the numbers from one to eight.
So these are our numbers.
We don't care about the values.
We just care
they are ordered.
Now we see that the first number here represent the smallest number in the array, which is
good one because we need the first element to be less than or equal to the second element.
So the smallest one definitely is satisfying this condition.
Now, what is the next one?
There is something I call boundary thinking, and you will notice several problems involve this
kind of thinking, like when you think in terms of boundaries here, what is next after one, maybe
the smallest one too, maybe the largest value too, maybe this one, maybe this one.
So we can try them.
Let me start with the eight.
If I took the eight here, which is the largest available in all of the numbers, what is the remaining?
Two, three, four, five, six, seven.
Now the first number one is less than or equal
eight. The eight was the largest in the whole array, so it must be greater than or equal to whatever comes
here. Now,
regardless of how you will solve this problem, this part must be correct.
And this one here is what we call sub-problem.
Remember what we mentioned in the previous video about the greedy.
I took two values, and they are in the right position because one is the smallest, which is correct,
and eight is the largest, so it must be greater than eight or equal it, and it's greater than all of these
guys.
So it must be correct.
And this now is a sub-problem.
This is a very clear example of what does it mean to be a sub-problem.
And this means I can apply the same logic.
Take the smallest, which is two, take the largest, which is seven.
Now the eight must be greater than or equal two.
And seven is anyway greater than the remaining, which are three, four, five, and six.
Now we ended up with one way, which is pretty good. To implement this solution,
you will need an extra O(n) memory to build the solution.
So this is one way, and I'm happy to show you this.
What do you mean by greedy?
This is a problem from one to eight.
This is a sub-problem of the remaining values.
.
Let's see another perspective to the solution.
Let's go back to the one again, so we have the one, which is the smallest, which means any element
in the array is OK. Let's try
the two. Is two a good choice?
The two is a bad choice because nothing after two is less
than it, so nothing can work here.
So two doesn't work.
OK, what about the three?
The three is a good choice because the three is greater than or equal the one, and there is a number less than
or equal it, which is only one number which is here the two.
Now the point here is given that one and three are done,
and there is anyway a number that is less than the three which we get it here at two, then we
are sure that we can build
the solution too. Let me say this in a different way.
I started by taking the one and three.
Are they valid? Yes, because one is less than or equal three.
The next one will be the next smallest value also, which is now two.
And it's actually the only available value too. What is there after the two?
We will not take the five because there is nothing less than five anymore.
But we can take the seven.
So take the seven here.
Now the good about seven,
It is greater than or equal two.
Now, the seven has only, uh..
We should take six not seven.
The six has only one choice that is smaller than it, which is five, and so on.
This is again problem and sub-problem, but it is less clear because it assumes you must take anyway
the minimum from here.
This is different from the previous solution.
It's more flexible.
Anyway, the good thing about that if I take the input [1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7,] the output
is just 1, 3, 2, 5, 4, 7, 6, 8 which, as you see, is just you swap these
two and these two and these two.
So going to the solution here, we can notice that
the second solution that we implemented is just starting from the one and keep iterating
two values and two values.
And this is the first idea that I mentioned.
We need an extra memory here.
We will iterate.
I have an iterator in the beginning, iterator in the end.
You start to take the first, you take the end.
You need to carefully implement it.
So it is not just an extra memory, more code, and you need to be more careful.
This idea is shorter in the code, it is easier, not easier to understand,
both of them are easy to understand.
And what else?
Yeah, and no memory.
So it's a pretty good idea here.
Uh, yeah.