In this problem, we would like to eliminate these monsters that are coming to the city.
You would like to maximize the number of monsters.
So the question that should come to your mind is which monster to kill first so that we maximize them.
If you started to think about it, you will find that, logically, you would like to kill the monsters
based on the order of arrival to the city.
If a monster will arrive after two minutes, and another one after 10 minutes, it doesn't
make sense to shoot first the one that will take 10 minutes, the one that takes two minutes
will arrive faster.
And this is a logical choice,
a greedy choice.
Now we would like to know which monster will arrive first to my city.
We know this simple math equation.
The time equals the distance over the speed.
This is a simple rule that we learned in the physics.
Please keep this equation in mind because we will use it in several problems during the course.
So now this is an equation, I can simply now, for every monster, compute this value.
And I will know the time, and in every single minute, I will start to kill them one by one
until one of them arrives the city, that's it.
So I believe this is an easy problem.
Now there are different ways to implement this problem.
The first one is to use double values, just divide the distance over the speed, and sort the data.
Let's see an implementation for that.
Uh, which one?
I call it two or three.
I call it two.
So this one here. I have a double array.
I iterate on the monsters.
I divide the distance over the speed to get the time.
I start to order that.
So this is I'm calling here the arrival_time.
Now keep iterating on the arrival time list.
And as long as, the i is less than the arrival time, we can simply kill him.
So keep kill them, one by one, unless one of them arrives.
So, simply,
let's say the arrival time of them is like maybe three, maybe five, maybe seven.
So in minute number one, you will kill the three, in minute number two, you will kill the five, in minute
number three, you will kill the seven. So you actually killed three of them in three minutes only.
Let's say the actual input was like one, two, two, two.
So in the minute zero, you will kill this one here.
In minute one, you kill this one here, in minute two, a monster arrived.
So you die.
So you iterate on the arrival times,
and just as long as the current time, you're simulating, you're killing them one by one, as long as
the current time is less than his arrival time,
you can just kill him.
Now there is a minor problem in this problem, and it might be a problem, but I would like you to just
keep it in mind.
In C++, comparisons based on double values are wrong because the double values internally could
be something like, the arrival could be something like that 2.9999,
which is actually three.
So this one, there might be a problem when
it comes to sorting something like 3.12, blah blah blah, 3.12 blah blah blah,
and they are different. In this problem,
my impression is it will not be sensitive, but anyway in general, be careful whenever you are comparing
doubles or sorting doubles.
Another way which is just simpler idea.
I'm going to compute an integer value for the arrival but in an integer way.
Let's say the distance is eight,
but the speed is two.
8 % 2 is zero.
So this means it's divisible.
So eight over two is just four.
What about eight
modulus three? Not zero.
So it means the answer will be two point something, but anyway we know that we kill them in integer minutes,
as the problem said.
So anyway, you can ceil it up from the beginning.
So this is the second way here. So we can do that in a very trivial way here.
We can do that here
as in the equation, the arrival time now has integer values.
If they are divisible, I can divide by the speed. If they aren't, I can add plus one, which is ceiling.
By the way, there is a different equation to compute the ceiling, we will visit it in another problem
later. I asked you for a challenge to try to implement this equation without anything that involves
any kind of division or modulus. Why? Because they are slow operators.
This is for fun.
Nothing else.
So here is what happened.
First of all, I will create the arrival time to be a pair of integer and integer, which are
the distance and speed. And now, we will sort the pairs.
OK, so now once we sorted them, we can iterate on the arrival time, and do the computation.
OK, easy so far.
So let's see. Now, the arrival time needs to compare my arrival with this arrival.
So this again involves computing the time.
So let's say my time is a/b, and his time is c/d, like this is t1 and this is
t2, and I would like to compare t1 / t2, which means I need to compute again the division.
But here is the trick.
Mathematically, this equation is as same as multiplying b, d in the two sides.
So this one goes and this one goes.
So this is d, and this is b.
So now you need to compare only these ones here.
So instead of making division to compare, we can actually use the math properties to switch it.
And this is something that sometimes people in competitive programming need it, and something fun
to know. The last thing again here we would like to do some here division
to check if the current time is enough or not.
Again, with some multiplication, we can just get it correctly.
This is the third way, and it's just for fun,
nothing else.