In the last problem, to be able to solve it,
we just need to do some analysis, and the analysis skill is an important skill that you need
during algorithms.
So sometimes the observations are very clear, and sometimes it isn't.
So anyway, let's first start with the array values.
What if all of the array values are greater than or equal to zero?
Logically, their summation is maximum.
So your k value might harm this summation.
Let's start with k = 1.
If I told you the values are maybe like 10, 20, and 30,
and 40, they are all greater than or equal zero, k = 1.
What can you do with that?
As simple as the logical choice is, the greedy choice is just to take the minimum value and multiply
it with negative one,
and then sum all of them together.
Why?
Because this is the best you can do, just get the minimum and multiply it with negative one.
OK.
What if k
is three?
The observation here is if you multiply the number twice, then the value is just as it is. So if I
multiply twenty by minus one and then minus one, it's just back to twenty.
So k is three is as same as k is one. In another way,
it's all about even and odd.
Let's say k is two.
If k is two, then if we applied it twice, its effect is done.
So back again to our example, k is two just applied twice on ten, so it doesn't add value.
So if k is even, we don't care.
If k is odd, it just as same as applying it once, right?
So if K is nine, this is as same as applying it once because anyway, eight of them will
cancel each other.
Remember, all of the values are greater than or equal to zero.
And we just want to flip the smallest one of them.
Now let's go back.
I would like you to learn how I analyze things.
OK, so you see, I'm thinking, Oh, maximum sum, positive values, negative values.
Let's go to the other case.
Let's say we have two negative values, for example.
Or maybe three.
Now, if I can multiply every one of these negative values with a negative one, then I'm maximizing
my summation.
So let's say you have k = 7.
Then I would go multiply first
this one with negative, and this one with negative, and this one with negative.
Now we have k = 4,
and an array that is
all of it is positive, go back to our previous logic where k is even, cancel it.
k is odd, just multiply it with the smallest one.
So now we reduce the case of even and negative values to the case of
all of it are positive values.
I hope the idea overall is clear.
So this is just the moral of the implementation.
So first of all, we sort all of the values.
And I'm going to iterate in the whole array.
As long as we have a k value,
and a number is negative, just multiply it with a negative one, and multiply the k, and keep summing
the current numbers, and keep taking the minimum among all of them.
Now, if k % 2 is one, it means we need to flip one number.
So let's say the current numbers were like maybe 5, 10, and 15.
I already add all of them together, and the minimum is five.
So the current sum that I have is actually thirty, right?
The current sum is thirty.
But what I actually need is to add a negative five here. If you would like, with less code, to switch
it, you can just make something like sum - 2 * min.
Why? We know that this equation
5 + 10 + 15 has an extra five and we actually need minus five, so as five need to be removed
twice, if you added here -2 * 5, you will reduce the summation to this one.
I hope this trick isn't an annoying one for you.
If it's an annoying one for you, just find the minimum again, and cancel its summation, and add it.
I'm just making it in one single step here.
It's a math trick.
If I know the summation and I know the minimum value, and I would like to multiply
the minimum with negative, I just can cancel it by multiplying it twice.
That's it.