Homework number three. In the first problem, we are given an integer array, and we would like
to find a sub-array that if we only sorted this sub-array, then the whole array is sorted.
We'd like to find the shortest such sub-array.
We can definitely take the whole array and just sort it.
That's OK, but we would like to find the shortest sub-array.
I would like you to start by developing O(nlogn) solution which will depend on sorting.
But there is another efficient solution that is O(n) only, it doesn't require sorting.
When I mention O(n), don't just think, Oh, I would like to make it count sort, don't think this way.
Count sort is very specific and we are done with it.
Um, just a general approach.
So here is an example.
This is an array here.
If you notice, if we started to sort the sub-array from six to nine, then the whole array will be
sorted.
So this is the goal, find the shortest sub-array to sort to get the whole array sorted.
This array here is completely sorted.
This one has a single element.
That's OK.
Problem number two.
We have n jobs, and we have m workers, and you will be given three arrays.
One of them is the difficulty, the profit, and the worker.
So the difficulty and the profit are both of them for the jobs.
So they will be of the same length, the same length here, which is n. The third array is worker,
which is about the worker.
And it refers to what is the difficulty that the worker can afford to do something?
Uh, now each worker can be assigned one job only or at most one job, but the job itself can be applied
several times.
Now we would like to maximize the profit of the workers, we would like to maximize the profit of the workers.
Um.
Oh.
I forgot to put examples.
OK, anyway.
So let's say we have here worker number one,
worker number two.
Let's say this person can work in a job that has a difficulty of at most five.
And this one can work in a job that has a difficulty of at least eight.
Now we have maybe different jobs.
The first job has a difficulty of one and profit of three.
Then the difficulty of two and maybe profit of five.
Difficulty four and profit two.
Difficulty may be six and profit ten.
Difficulty eight and profit seven.
Difficulty twenty and profit hundred.
Now, no one of these two guys can do this task because its difficulty is way harder than five
rate.
The five one can do the one, two, and four. The eight one can do one, two, four, six, eight.
Every one of them will be assigned only one job.
Now you would like to assign it such that the added profit is going to be maximum.
For example,
this person here, he has a profit eight, so he can do all of these tasks, which one has the highest
profit? Ten, so we assign this task for this one.
Now, this person can only do one of the first three tasks.
So he can only do these three, which is the maximum here? Five.
So he is going to do this one.
So the profit now is fifteen.
This is the maximum one.
What if I told you that the profit from this task is fifty?
You can assign eight to this task.
So the same job can be done by more than a person, but every person will do exactly one job.
Among all of that, you would like to get the maximum profit.
That's it.
You will assign for every worker one job such that the assigned jobs are perfect in terms
of difficulty and the profit is maximum.
The third task, I simplified the text a little bit to make it a bit easier.
The task is as following. We have an array of integers, we would like to make all of it to be equal values.
So
here is the given operations. In every step,
You take the largest value, let's say it's index i, and find the next largest value, but must
be strictly smaller than it, let's call it index j, then reduce i to j.
So nums[ i ] is going to be nums[ j ]. Now we would like to know the number of operations to
make all of the elements equal.
So simulate this process to know the total number of operations that you will need to do
that.
So the process is known.
But we would like to know how many steps it will take overall.
And I would like to find that in O(nlogn) time.
Uh, here is an example.
Let's say we have the input [5, 1, 3].
Let's apply the operation, where is the largest? Five.
Where is the second largest? Three, reduce five to three.
So now we have [3, 1, 3].
Now, where is the largest?
Three.
Where is the second largest? One, reduce
three to one, [1, 1, 3].
Where is the largest?
Three.
Where is the next largest? One.
Reduce three to one, then [1, 1, 1].
So we needed three steps to reduce the whole array to the same value.
And
this one is already same value.
We are done. This one, we take it.
So the three will be reduced to two.
Now we have three twos, three ones, keep reducing them one by one.
That's all.