Let's solve the hard challenges.
There is something here that I would like to confirm, the course will have different hard challenges,
and early in the course, you will not be skilled enough to tackle hard challenges.
As I said during the getting started section, my advice is you can delay all the problems that you
can find hard to the end of the course, just in your notes,
mark where are the problems that you should solve.
Or another way is to tackle the problem, if you found it really to be hard and you cannot understand the
solution,
just put it in your ToDo mark.
Don't just try to insist on solving it early in the course.
During the course, you will solve a lot of problems, and these problems will enhance your skills.
So your weak skills will grow up over time.
And what was very hard in the early of the course is going to be way smoother and easier in the end
of the course.
It's important to learn in the right way.
Do not get disappointed, as we learned, the course anyway is going to be challenging for you.
So let's solve this problem.
I first asked you for an O(nlogn) solution and another O(n) one.
It needs observation skills.
It doesn't depend on sorting as a procedure.
The O(nlogn) one is a pretty straightforward one.
I hope you managed to figure it out.
In the (nlogn) one, it's based on a very simple observation. If we sorted the array, we
can compare the old array with the new array to figure out where are
the unsorted range.
So let's say we have the array here like that, and let's say we have one, two as valid, and let's
say seven and eight as valid.
And let's say we have here like five, six, four, three, four, if you compare the sorted
with unsorted step by step.
Once you figured out the first element that is unequal, this is the first element.
And again, from the backward, once you figured out the first unequal elements, this is the end.
So we just need to sort this interval, that's trivial.
We can find the solution with simple, smart coding as following. You iterate,
the first number that isn't equal must be the left one.
OK, during the processing, this will be different,
this different, this different.
I need the last one in them.
So the first difference is the left and the last difference is the right.
So I will keep updating this right variable,
as long as, there is difference, I will update it.
The left is once only updated.
The right will be updated with every difference here.
Now, if (left == -1), then it means there are no problems.
Otherwise, we need to sort this (right - left + 1) window.
This is the easy solution.
Now let's go back to the hard solution.
There are different ways to implement an O(n) solution for this problem.
First of all, just for clarity, this is the input and this is the sorted vision.
Let's divide it to three parts.
The sorted array, which let's call it here A, and the last sorted array, which we call C, and
the unsorted in the middle B.
We need to figure out this B. Remember from the programming course, the early numbers in an array
we call them prefix, the last array we call them suffix.
So we would like to find these A, C, and B. Logically, we would like to find the largest A, and
largest C so that B be as short as possible.
Now there is a simple observation about sorting, what makes 70 a valid number here in its valid
location? Seventy must be greater than all of the previous elements, greater than or equal, and must be smaller than or
equal to all of the next elements.
This is what makes an element really in its right location in a sorting way.
Now, if the values have this part that needs to be sorted, we need to figure
out,
let's focus on the C
first. I want to find this hundred, the first value C[0] of the sorted postfix here.
I need to find it.
This position will be as following, it must be greater than or equal to all of the previous values,
and its C must be an increasing sequence, must be increasing one.
OK.
I hope the idea is clear.
The question is, how can we implement that in an efficient way?
I will end up (n^2) this way to find them.
Here is the simple idea. If you kept the maximum while iterating from the left to the right, kept the
maximum while iterating from the left to the right.
So the maximum here is 10, 20, 30, 40, 50, 60, sorry, the maximum here is 90.
The maximum here is 80, being 80 and this one is maximum so far is 90
means definitely this isn't in its correct position,
and anyone before that. OK, again, seven and ninety are not in their right location.
Sixty and ninety aren't in their right location.
Now, the maximum here will be updated again, being updated means this variable
there is a high chance now it be the valid choice.
So the moral of that is to go from left to right while maintaining your maximum variable, the first
variable, you don't have to update its maximum anymore means all of the values after it
are valid, all of the values after it are valid.
So here, once the hundred became the maximum of all of this array, it will not be updated again.
Imagine if there is here 200, 300, 400, the hundred
sorry, we will keep updating it, right? Because there are new
.
OK.
Let's specify it in this way.
We need to make sure that values don't go below this value.
Let's see the code easier.
I here iterate from left to right.
I will keep the maximum with me.
I will keep it, so it will be maximum 200, 300, and 400.
What really tells us that we have a new valid start is, am I greater than the maximum or not?
If the maximum is greater than me, then definitely something wrong
on my side.
So let's see here again.
I have values like 10, 20, 30, and suddenly 17, then 40, then suddenly 5, the maximum here
is ten, the maximum here is twenty,
the maximum here is thirty.
OK, now comparing the maximum with the current
number, it doesn't work.
The maximum here is still 30, but I'm 17 smaller than you, then
this means that this is the last invalid position we found.
OK, go back here.
Forty, the maximum here is 40 versus 40.
It's OK.
This is an OK value.
No, the maximum here is forty again, and this is five.
It means this one is again could be the end of the one.
So now five, forty here is the valid right location.
This is the end of the shortest path that we need to eventually sort it, that we need eventually
to sort it.
I hope you got the idea. If we iterated from left to right, kept the maximum with us, and kept
comparing with the maximum, every time
the maximum so far is greater than the current element.
This element must be part of the array to be sorted, and we will keep updating it.
Let's say here we ended up with 50, 60, 70.
So this maximum 50, 50, 60, 60, 70, 70.
There are no more updates here, which means these ones are valid ones.
So I hope,
You see now how we implemented it.
We can do the same processing from back to forward to get the first element, which is going to
be here 17, and 30.
So we once go forward to go to the right, and we once go backward to go to the left.
And the key idea, as I said, is mainly A[ i ] is valid if it's greater than all of the previous one, better
than all of the next one.
But the real challenge was how can we implement that in a smarter way, just maintain the maximum
so far and compare it with the current element, with any element that is less than the current maximum,
It's definitely part of the array to be sorted.