Let's solve the next problem about the maximum profit, I added the examples here in the slides.
So how can we solve this problem?
Definitely, the brute force is very clear.
All what you need is a couple of nested loops.
One for the workers, another for the job, if my difficulty is higher than the job, difficulty
greater than or equal, then I can just keep maximizing among all of the profits.
This is very clear and this is O(NQ)
where N is the jobs, and Q is the workers or the opposite.
Now I would like to process this thing in a way that's a more efficient approach.
There is a very nice observation here.
Let's say that worker A has a difficulty of 10,
worker B is 15.
Now, observe that worker B can do all the tasks that worker A can do.
Now let's say that worker A checked himself again in jobs X, Y, Z and found that his profit is 70.
Worker B doesn't have to check again X, Y, Z.
He can just start after that using the profit of 70 so far.
This is a very nice observation.
Now, how can we make use of that?
The moral of that is there are duplicate operations.
If you tried to start B to check again X, Y, Z jobs, you are duplicating the operations. And in algorithms,
One way to improve your implementation is to think, this
what we call the root cause analysis, we would like to know what is consuming the time.
So in this one, the consumptions come mainly from duplicate operations, and you usually need some smart
ideas to skip the duplicate computations.
So here is how we can do that.
First of all, start by sorting the jobs and the workers, but based on the difficulty.
So here are the difficulties, and here are the profits of them.
And let's say you have two workers 10 and 15.
Now, worker A will scan the jobs starting from here from five and keep going as long as he can do
the job, which clearly he's of a difficulty two,
he can only do the first two tasks, which have seven and two.
So the profit for the first worker is just seven.
Now, worker B with difficulty 15 can do the first four jobs but do not start from five again.
We can directly start from after 10 using the profit of seven so far, and just comparing the profit of
seven with six and three to take the profit seven again.
This is an example of smart processing that avoids duplicate variables.
Now what is the time complexity of that?
Just you will need to sort the two arrays, so (Nlogn) and (Qlogn).
And the profit calculation, which is the last part, is (N + Q) doesn't matter.
The space complexity is O(N) for the jobs vector, as we will see.
OK, let's see the implementation here.
The implementation goes as following, we create a pair of jobs for the difficulty and for the profit, and we'll
just sort the workers and the jobs. The jobs here, which is our new array, is based on the
difficulty.
They are sorted
from small to large.
Now this is the maximum profit so far.
This is the total profit that we will add for it.
You go for the
workers, one by one.
You take the first worker and iterate over the jobs, the limit as long as my difficulty
is greater than or equal the current difficulty.
Through all of that, I'm maximizing my profit and adding it here.
The critical observation is when the second worker comes to the scene, he will keep working, starting
from the job, which has index job zero here only after the for loops and incremented here, which
means the second worker will continue directly from after
the last job from the first one. So the first one covered three jobs and stopped.
I will cover maybe the next two jobs, then the next one will cover the next four jobs.
Everyone is making use of the history that we have.
So one key to avoid duplicate values is to utilize the history, utilize the history computation.
Don't repeat the history computations again.
That's all.