The next hard problem is about the reduction operation.
One easy way to solve this problem is through what we call simulation. Simulation just means to simulate
the target operation.
Just make a while loop and keep updating the operation.
This is very slow, but it's a well-known idea, simulation algorithm.
Now we want to do something better than that.
So let's analyze the problem.
When you think about it,
every number will anyway have to be reduced in a series of steps to the next minimum and the next
minimum.
So 50, anyway, will have to be reduced to 40, 30, 25.
The other 50 will have to be reduced to 40, 30, 10, 5.
The 40 will be reduced to 30, 10, 5.
The 30 will be reduced to 10, 5, and the ten to the five, ending up with all of these fives.
Now, in other words, every number will be reduced based on how many unique numbers less than it.
For example, the 50 has four values less than it.
This 50 has four values less than it.
This 40 has three less than it. This 30 has two less than it.
This 10 has one less than it.
So if we can find, for every number in an efficient way, how many numbers are less than it, we can do that
in different ways
O(nlogn). In the next section, we will learn about the binary search technique, the lower bound and upper
bound, and you will know
how can we implement this idea of unique numbers.
And this idea anyway can be implemented in different ways.
I would like to share with you one smart idea to implement this task, and please keep the following
in mind.
When I share with you some smarter code or very short
code, I do that because I would like to teach you how to write smarter codes,
how to write fewer codes. If you found my code is harder, not convenient,
in the Discussion tab in LeetCode, there are too many other solutions.
Just go and learn anyone of them as long as you satisfy the complexity, but take a chance to understand
these other codes.
So there is another observation that is good here to keep in mind. When you think about this array here,
the sorted array,
we have four nines, every one of them will be reduced to seven, five, three, one.
Why keep doing all of them together if we can do them all at once?
We call that batch processing. In batch processing, we are doing a group of processing
together.
So the moral of that is you can't take the four nines, and
reduce them to seven in one step.
So like computationally one step, but we needed four steps for that.
Once you're done with that, you have now five sevens, reduce all of them at once to five.
Now you have six fives, reduce all of them to three.
Now you have seven threes,
reduce all them to one.
You see, how easy is that?
So you don't have here to keep updating the array itself, you just iterate from large to small.
And keep updating every time you find this less value, we know
we need to reduce all of them together.
So let's see the implementation here.
This is the implementation.
I'm sorting from large to small, iterating on the numbers, and whenever I find that the current number
is different than the previous numbers.
So let's say we found the seven, and we are now at an index of zero, one, two, three, four.
So it means there are four values before me.
All of them will be reduced to seven.
So we reduced them to seven. That's why
I'm adding here +i because i here represents how many numbers with value of a number of
i.....
There are minor mistakes here, numbers with a value of nums[i - 1],
this is correct.
And there are i numbers with value nums[i - 1], this isn't correct.
I meant to say there are i numbers with values of nums[i - 1],
and we will reduce them to nums[ i ].
So we have here at i = 4,
we have four nines, and we will reduce them to seven.
One step after that, we find in the array five.
So five doesn't equal to the previous one.
It means all of the previous elements, which are now five elements, will be reduced to five.
This is a very smart, and very interesting processing way.
I found someone is coding it this way, so it's a very lovely one.
The code is usually like better than you, take it easy.
Just learn from it.