Let's continue our talk about the insertion sort, um, so the question is now, how can we implement
this algorithm? If you tried to think about it,
we are implementing the shift right operation, which simply means if we have an array of values,
and we would like to
get this value here,
where these values are just moving, this is actually like a shifting operation.
So consider, for example,
this array here.
The first four values are sorted values, two, four, five, six.
Now we need to put one in its right place.
So the one will take a journey going back, and with every element that is less than it, the number
will just be shifted right
one step.
So six goes to the one position.
Five goes to the six position.
Four goes to the five position. Two goes to the four position.
Then one is empty and ready for us.
This is a very classical right shift operation, right shift.
So keep it in mind.
The opposite is left shift here.
So the moral of that is I want to insert something here,
I shift right
all what I need to
put, then I put the value in this location.
That simple.
So in terms of implementation, I hope you ended up with something close to that.
We start with (i = 1), because (i = 0) is already a sorted
sub-array.
Remember, the assumption of the internal operation is the numbers from 0 up to (i - 1) are
sorted already
sub-array, and all what we want to do is to put a value in its right location.
So we start with the Ith element,
call it here
key, and we will start from the back.
So the last element in the older sorted sub-array is (j = i - 1).
Now we will start from the back and keep moving back to the front.
So, what is the ending condition?
J is greater than or equal zero, or more efficient you can say j is greater than minus one.
So we'll keep going forward.
And as long as the current key is greater than the element, then this one should be shifted.
So we go to j + 1, and shift it here, and then we move to one element before that.
So notice that the value of the nums[ j ] is gone.
We don't care because we took a value already here.
So let's say we have something like maybe 10, 20, 30, 40 as our sorted sub-array.
And now, we would like to put the value 17.
So first we take seventeen a copy in the key, and then compare forty
with key, which is seventeen.
Is it greater than?
Yes, move forty here.
So forty is here. Now thirty, thirty and seventeen,
it's greater, so move thirty here.
Twenty and seventeen,
Yes, greater, move twenty here.
Ten and seventeen.
No, put seventeen here now.
So once we end up at a position j that is smaller than or equal to us, we put in the next
element the value, this element now is empty, is waiting for us at the moment.
So this is the moral of the code.
I hope it is pretty easy for you.
I don't want to invest time in easy things.
I see some courses that try to take too much time in what is really very clear.
So I hope this is clear for you.
When you think about the time complexity of this algorithm,
like, what's the worst case?
We definitely have this complete for loop to be done here.
So this is O(n) one.
And inside this loop, we are iterating back on the whole array
one more time.
So this is another O(n).
So clearly, this is an O(n^2) time algorithm.
Most of the time, when the time complexity and the memory complexity are very clear for me, maybe
I forget to mention it. If it happened that there is something missing and you cannot figure it out by yourself,
just please raise up a question in the Q/A.
So this is mainly the algorithm.
Now the second thing, which is a very important skill that you should build during your career is
the testing feature. When you are a software engineer,
you will implement too much code, some of it very small, some of it very big.
You have to test your code before asking people to make a code review for you. And the algorithms course
is one way to enhance
this test case.
One critical thing here is how to think in a systematic way, it's a skill.
But this is something important.
It isn't about just finding some test cases.
It's about being systematic so that you cover what needs to be covered.
So thinking about an array and sorting it, maybe I need an array of length(1), length(2), and length(3) as some
small arrays.
If we have some known max N, maybe some max N or a big value like ten, for example, you need to
think about this kind of boundary thinking.
So when I think about a very small array size, very big array size, this is boundaries and this is
very important. In terms of the values, one might think about odd and even, although they are irrelevant here.
But what is important here is the duplicate arrays or unique values.
This is something important because we wanna make sure the duplicate values are handled correctly.
In terms of also, you might have interest to know what if the array is completely sorted.
What if it's almost sorted?
What if it's completely not ordered?
Does the algorithm behave properly or not? In this problem,
as I said, what matters is mainly the length one.
And then some random test, and some test for the duplicate values.
This is what I meant by systematic thinking.
So try to be that systematic.
OK, so let's proceed, assume you are done with your testing, I would like to show you some observations,
and it's very important sometimes to make some analysis about your algorithm.
This is, in many cases, a key to make better improvements.
So one think is assume the array is sorted or almost sorted.
What do you think is the time complexity?
Please visit the code and try to answer this question.
You will notice that the second loop is trying to put an element in its sorted location.
If the element already like, let's say we have the first four elements, and we want to put five, the five already
is greater than four, the second loop will not work here in this case, again for six, and again for seven.
You will observe that the algorithm is O(n) if the array is sorted or almost sorted.
This is what we call best-case performance.
And specifically, it refers to when exactly can the algorithm do really the best of it.
Now, observe the opposite.
What if the array is sorted from large to small?
So we have initially seven, then six go here, five have to go here, four here,
three
here. Do you observe? The second loop will do full iteration.
It will go a complete looping.
This is what we call the worst-case performance.
Now, in practice, most of the time, we don't care about the best-case or worst-case because
they are anyway rare cases.
We care about what we call the average case. Computing
the average case is seriously a hard thing, and in some domains, it might depend on probability and
expectations.
But anyway, you should have some sense that this is O(n^2) algorithm. Probably when the
arrays are like random arrays,
we expect that the second loop will be partially or fully executed most of the time.
So anyway, if you got confused about what is the average case, then just use the worst case.
But sometimes this is tricky.
Many algorithms have really seriously bad worst-case algorithms.
Meanwhile, their average case is pretty good one.
If this is the case, what does it mean? Like, let's say out of every one thousand different test cases,
only one of them like, let's say, in every one thousand test cases, the algorithm is like O(n long),
and only in one case out of every one thousand, it's O(n^2).
And let's say we have a website or a service doing that.
It means, occasionally from time to time, the algorithm will be slow for this very
special test case.
Otherwise, it's working pretty good.
So this is one thing that you should be careful about it.
Although the worst case can give us a good impression about what's going to happen, but actually,
it could be the case that this is only a few cases and most of the time we're doing something much better.
Let's take another scenario, the hash table.
The hash table is very common in industry.
If you tried to analyze the hash table, you will notice that it has a very poor worst-case behavior.
However, there are two things that we keep in mind.
First, if the hash table implementation is a good implementation, like the built-in implementation.
Second, there is a sufficient size, which is based on the expected number of entries in the hash table.
Remember, the load balance thing in the hash table.
If you have a good implementation like the internal one, and you properly use the hash table, and
you also had a good hash function, most probably 99%, the hash table will do a very good job.
So while the worst
case behavior looks like terrible,
however, the devil in the details with a good implementation, with good
size, with good
hash table, proper usage, you are in the safe side.
So here is the take home message.
Don't be so systematic.
We aren't machines here.
It isn't about computing
what is the worst case and claiming this is the average case.
Uh, it isn't like that.
Try to have some intuition, some deeper thinking about the typical usage, or how can we make
the usage in a better way.
So, yeah, this is the point.
Like, forget about the style in academic courses,
where you have to keep computing the worst-case analysis,
the best-case analysis, the average case analysis, and all of this nice stuff. In practice,
Don't be systematic,
think deeper, and try to get a sense about what might happen for your code.
Correctness, remember in the introduction, we mentioned that the algorithm value is really actually
about being correct.
So we have to prove the correctness of our algorithms.
But there is a catch here that I have to clarify.
You'll find that some books go very formal, and they might take a few pages explaining a lot of terms.
So the proof sometimes is very lengthy, and many people might find it very exhausting for them.
Understanding the proofs is still very added value, but most of the time, it is an easier experience
for people with mathematical background.
Now I need you to try to read formal proofs.
But this course is trying to take you to the easiest way.
It just tries to make it very informal because it's way easier to explain things. If you have an interest
to read formal proofs,
you can check out the very common books, the CLRS book, which is the introduction to algorithms,
there are like three or four authors for that.
I learned from this book when I was back then in 2005 in the university.
It's very mathematical.
It gives me a lot of hard times.
But I believe it was very nice experience.
Some other books, like Algorithms Design Manual by Steven Skiena, is more practical one.
You don't need this book.
The course is already doing a great job in this perspective.
Feel free to have it.
OK, so here is what I suggest, so that you have a faster learning experience about algorithms, and
this is very important because many people take too much time in algorithms courses, and they have a
very limited productivity.
First, I would like you to focus too much on the intuition itself behind the approach.
So don't just jump to read a couple of pages algorithm proof.
I need you to focus on the intuition.
There's something here worth sharing with you, you probably aware of competitive
programming,
like ICPC, Codeforces.
The talented guys and the senior guys can solve very hard problems in a few minutes, only based
on their intuition, which is corrected to a large extent.
So I want you to develop this intuition.
You can read many hard problems, and figure out what is the solution in a few minutes.
It takes too much time to reach this stage, like figuring out in five minutes, for example.
This is a very tough skill, but intuition here is a very important key.
If you had good intuition about the problem, the second is to try to implement it or understand
the code, try to think about
test cases, play with the code and the test cases.
Try to think in informal thoughts about the correctness, like, why do you think this is correct?
The third thing is to solve a lot of problems. When you solve a lot of problems,
you will be really very strong about what you are doing.
The last thing is to go formal and read the proof, which is optional.
You don't need it.
In many cases, however, I still suggest it, at least you can do that for some of the problems.
OK, let's go back about the insertion sort.
You probably can find in a very informal way that insertion sort is very true.
Like, I don't need to read a couple of pages that are trying to prove what is insertion sort doing.
So we can see that clearly when n = 1, the array is definitely sorted, and we can see that starting
from n = 2, we have a sorted sub-array, and we can linearly go to definitely find the correct position.
Then according to that, with a proper right shifting to the array, the new array is a new sorted
sub-array with the current elements from zero to index i.
So this way, we are sure that the array is actually sorting elements because in every single step,
It has one more element, and it is already sorted.
So I hope just this informal proof is more than enough for you. Now,
It is useful sometimes to discuss some properties about sorting algorithms.
So one of the most important features is what we call the stable sort.
Stable sort means the following.
If there are elements of equal values, their order doesn't change.
Imagine we have an array [ 1, 2, 5, 5, 3, 5 ].
Or just showing you what does it mean to be equal keys, and marking five here as 5A, 5B, 5C, but
just integers.
If you change the code, you will notice the following, when the algorithm order them, it will be
5A, 5B, 5C.
So this means that this element of five will never be before these guys because we keep going
to the left side to lower values.
And once we are less than the current value, we just put ourselves.
So this means the values will be in the right place given their original relative order.
This is what we mean by stable algorithm.
The second feature is in-place algorithm. In-place algorithm will do changes for the given
input itself without taking extra memory or maybe very limited memory.
If you notice the function that we wrote about sorting, it was updating the array itself, and it doesn't take
any extra memory.
We call this an in-place algorithm.
These are the most two important features. For fun,
there are other few things, online feature.
Online means we can keep receiving more elements and update our content smoothly with them.
Think about that.
We have some online service, and we keep receiving numbers from it.
When you think about the insertion sort, it can easily take the new number,
put it in its right place.
So in O(n), with every new number, we can put it in the right place.
This means insertion sort is very efficient for online services. In the next algorithms,
you will see that this isn't the case, and we have to repeat the whole processing from scratch again.
The last thing is maybe the adaptive feature.
Imagine that the data was almost sorted, does the algorithm behave in a very efficient
way or not?
As we mentioned, when the array was almost sorted, it took only O(n),
right?
So here is the definition.
The time complexity is O(kn), where we have no more than k elements far from their right position.
Now, if the array, all of it, is sorted, this means k = 1 because every element is in its right
position.
So let's say every element is like two steps only far from its position, the array will take 2n
steps.
So adaptivity means, does the algorithm care about the data content, and does it affect it or not?
If the algorithm taken into consideration, the values such that if the array, for example, is fully
sorted, it almost do nothing.
This is an adaptive algorithm.
If the algorithm will do exactly the same processing, regardless of the values, we say this isn't
an adaptive algorithm.
OK.
This is what we call a comparison-based algorithm.
We will see another comparison-based algorithm when we study
the selection sort algorithm, but there is something interesting.
It's theoretical.
Some courses mentioned it, and I like to mention it also that a comparison-based algorithm, first
of all, is the algorithm that compares numbers or strings to decide something, or objects.
Now, the best efficient algorithm known for comparison-based algorithms is O(n logn), but this isn't
the interesting thing.
The interesting thing is any comparison-based sorting algorithm must make at least (n log n) comparisons
on average.
What does it mean?
We will never be able to find an algorithm that uses comparisons and is better than (n long). In some strong
courses, people will be required to prove this property, so you might search for how to prove it.
Now, there are other types of algorithms, as we will study, like count sort, they aren't comparison-based
algorithms. So these algorithms, in some scenarios, can be way efficient than (n logn).
But in practice, we don't use them.
In practice, we typically use the standard sorting algorithms.
So the key here is to understand that (n logn) represents like a lower bound.
And the good thing about proofing lower bounds is, as a scientist or as a researcher, you don't
have to try to find an algorithm that is working based than (n logn) and still based on comparing
items together.
You know that this is impossible.
By the way, sorting is one of the problems that we heavily studied in computer science.
You'll find too much sorting algorithms in literature.