The last thing that I would like to discuss before ending is something about STL.
So as we know that STL already has built-in sorting functions.
If you have a victor, for example, you can say sort ( vec.begin(), vec.end() ).
Now, what is the internally used algorithm?
Here is the problem.
We can see that every algorithm has some pros and cons features.
So just depending on one algorithm isn't a good idea.
So you will find, for example, STL using something called IntroSort, which is simply a hybrid
approach of quick sort, heap sort, and insertion sort.
So the idea is as following, if the arrays are very small, we use insertion sort.
Otherwise, for big arrays, we run quick sort.
Now, during the quick sort, we try to keep in mind how many operations so far are done.
If it seems that quick sort is taking too much time,
we stop it and we switch to heap sort.
So this is how STL is trying to solve this problem. Python, on the other side, is using something called
Timsort, which is a hybrid algorithm again mainly derived from merge sort and insertion sort.
Suppose it is designed to be working well in real data. As you see, insertion sort is common
between both of them.
Why?
Because insertion sort is very efficient on small arrays, and especially if the arrays are almost
sorted.
The second thing that I would like to show you is some people might use STL sorting in a wrong
way.
So observe the following code, this array has 10 to the power seven elements, all of them of value
five.
I would like to sort, C++ let me give a comparator if I would like to compare.
So there are like two comparison functions.
One of them is using a <= b, and one of them is using a < b.
If you tried to run the code using this comparison, it will work well.
But if you tried to run it using this comparison, it will take too much time, then just runtime error
will terminate.
This is due to the current internal implementation of C++ STL, which is based on what we call the
logical ordering.
So here is the point. If you will provide a comparison function,
iI must behave logically the same as E1 < E2, not E1 <= E2.
If this isn't satisfied,
the internal implementations will go
in infinite recursion and might runtime error.
Observe that, in the future, the implementation might be changed, so this behavior might be changed,
may be. OK.
Here is, anyway, some thoughts about that.
If the comparison between E1 and E2 is true, this means that E1 is smaller than E2, which means
logically that E2 with E1 should be false.
Now, if E1 is false when it comes to comparison with E2, there are actually two cases now,
we start to compare E2 with E1.
If E2 and E1 are true, then this means that E2 is less than E1.
If it is false, then it means E1, E2 are false and E2 is E1 false, which means, is E1
less than E2? False.
Is E2 less
than E1? False.
So this means they are actually true.
So this is how internally C++ know
is it less than or equal.
They infer the equality from these two ways comparison.
Please don't miss up with the current STL implementation, always implement it to be less than not
less than or equal.
As you know in the C++ course, STL also allows us to compare objects like we can have built-in comparisons,
but you can have something like the employee class
and sort based on it. That's all.