Let's move to another popular sorting algorithm, which is the selection sort algorithm.
So far we've learned
what is the sorting problem.
We learned how the insertion sort is based on incremental thinking. Now, insertion sort is a,
this should be selection, selection sort is another algorithm, but again, slow algorithm, it is based on
simple observation. The idea is as following, the first element in the sorted array must be
the minimum in the whole array.
For example, here what is the first element?
It must be the minimum here.
Now, what is the second element in the array? After we discard zero,
it is again the minimum here, which is the second minimum now, which is two. What is the third
minimum?
It's three, and so on.
So if we tried to keep repeating finding the minimum in the remainder of the array, we will get the
next element in the array.
Probably, this is more intuitive for you than the previous algorithm.
So here is some simulation anyway.
What is the minimum in this array?
The minimum is zero three.
Right?
So this is the current minimum.
Now, we will swap this element with the first element in the array.
Now, the array is two parts for us.
The first part is the sorted sub-array and the remaining sorted sub-array.
So again, what is the minimum element in all of this array?
It is in index
seven value two, this one.
So, again, swap it, but with which element? With the first element in the unsorted array,
which is index one now.
Repeat the process, this is the sorted sub-array, and this is the unsorted sub-array.
You get the minimum in this one.
What is the minimum?
It is index five value three.
Swap it with the first element in the unsorted array.
You get this new sub-array,
and so on. So again, what is the next minimum?
It is five in index four, swap it, nine and ten are in the same position.
What is the minimum here?
It is eighty-five, swap it.
We are done.
I hope the algorithm is easy for you.
It's very intuitive.
I would like you again to try to code it.
Analyze it.
Think about the correctness.
Think about the properties
like,
Is it stable algorithm?
Is it online algorithm?
Is it an adaptive algorithm? Think about these properties, you will find the answers for them in the quiz.
Now, let's move to the coding of it.
The implementation is fairly simple.
We have here a for loop that tries every element, in every step, we iterate on the remaining of the elements,
keep the index of the minimum of them.
Then we swap it with the current element.
So this way the algorithm is done.
We definitely don't need to go for the last element because there is nothing after the last element.
So the moral of that, you get the minimum, swap, you get the minimum, swap, and so on.
So you just need the minimum index.
I think the idea is pretty easy for you.
Now let's think about the worst analysis and best analysis here.
If I give you an array that is completely sorted one, two, three, four, five, six. What does the algorithm
do?
It will get the minimum, which is one,
put it here. Then go all of that,
get the minimum, which is two as it is, three as it is.
The point here is the algorithm
.
doesn't depend on the data, the algorithm doesn't depend on the data.
Regardless it's sorted or unsorted or whatever, it's going to do the exact number of operations.
And this means the best analysis and the average analysis,
and the worst case analysis are the same, why? The algorithm doesn't care about your data.
This for loop will be done anyway, regardless of your data.
So this is another case, which takes us to a nice tip that you should keep in mind.
To what degree your algorithm is based on the data, algorithms that are based on the data are the ones
that could have best case,
worst case, and average case.
Algorithms that are systematic, will just do the exact same number of operations, regardless
of anything. Correctness,
I hope it's very trivial for you to think about it. As a tip,
whatever very intuitive for you,
just don't waste time, which will happen a lot in trivial algorithms.
This is the last thing.
It's very optional.
Specifically, if you studied the heap data structure before.
Now, there is some correspondence between the selection sort and the heap sort, the idea is as following.
Remember the heap sort, the heap has a tree, which is internally
represented as an array.
It finds the largest element, which is typically at the heap, and puts it in the last element in the array.
And after that, it removes it from the array, so some numbers are going to be
shuffled, and gets the largest again, puts it in the last element of the array, gets the largest,
puts it in the last element of the array.
If you thought about it, the insertion sort is the opposite.
We get the minimum and put it in the begin, begin, begin, begin, so they are the opposite
of each other.
What is the difference?
The heap sort can get this element in only O(log(n)),
which is making its all of process O(nlog(n)) to sort numbers, however, selection sort has to
get the minimum in O(n). So heap sort gets the maximum in O(1), and removes it in log(n), selection
sort gets the minimum in O(n).
This is what makes the heap (nlog(n))
versus the (n^2) from the selection sort. I just wanted you to show that there is some correspondence
between both of them.
That's all.