So far, we learned about comparison-based algorithms where we mainly have to compare values.
But the count sort belongs to another family. So let's give the problem here, I'm calling here version
two.
You still have to order the numbers from small to large.
However, there is an extra information here.
The range is from zero to 500.
What do you think about this as an extra information?
Does it matter?
Some people would just go to the general version of the problem with ignoring this kind of specific
information. In many problems in your career, the success will depend on specific information.
So whenever you are given such extra properties, extra constraints make use of them.
So try to take maybe five or ten minutes to think, can we develop an approach based on knowing that
the values are of a small range or not?
Recall that any algorithm that is comparison-based has some lower bound that we cannot get rid of it,
(nlogn). Count sort doesn't use comparisons.
It uses frequencies. So here is a hint for you, compute the frequency of the input array.
For example, if this is the input array, we can see that three repeated twice, the nine repeated three times,
and the other numbers are repeated only once.
Can you develop an efficient algorithm based on this frequency information?
Here is the procedure of the count sort.
First of all, you compute the maximum value in the array.
Second, let's say the maximum is 90,
You create an array of ninety-one, so you have to add +1, then create a frequency array of all of these
numbers.
That's why we need the +1 because the array of ninety will be used here.
After that, iterate from zero to max value, which is 90, so from zero to 90.
If the current frequency value has a frequency, use it to spread it in the output.
For example, let's say we computed the frequency, as you see, arr[0], arr[1], arr[2] all of them
are zeros, so ignore them.
Arr[3] is two, which means we have two threes.
So put them here three and three. Arr[4] is zero.
Ignore it. Arr[5] is one.
So add one five here. Six, seven, eight are zeros, ignore them. Arr[9] is three.
So add three nines here. Arr[10] is one.
So add one ten here.
Arr[90] is one.
Add ninety here.
Why is that
a sorted output?
Because we are iterating from zero to max, so we go to them, value by value, in order.
So definitely this must be a sorted output here.
Now, we would like to take this idea, and just try to implement it, and then analyze it.
There is two implementation ways for this algorithm.
So here is how to implement it.
The idea is as following, first of all, I will iterate through the array to compute the maximum value
in the array.
After that, I will create a vector where the length is mxValue+1.
The default value in C++ is zero.
Then I will iterate on the array and create the frequency of every element, so every value, I will just
compute its frequency value here.
After that, we will spread back the values over the array, so iterate from zero to the mxValue.
Then, we make here a for loop on the frequency of the value.
So let's say that i, now, is three.
And let's say that count[ i ] is seven.
This means we have seven threes.
So I have here an index that I keep incrementing with every iteration.
I keep adding element by element to the current array.
This trivial to code algorithm is what we call count sort. In the homework,
You will find another way, very popular, to write the count sort algorithm that has different types of properties.
So now let's think, what kind of properties do we see here in this algorithm? Is it, for example,
an in-place algorithm? No, we have to create here the frequency array.
OK, let's analyze first the time complexity.
This for loop takes N steps.
OK?
And this for loop, another N steps, then this loop is a bit tricky.
It is iterating on the max value in the array.
That's OK.
Let's call the max value just M, and then it has another loop that goes to the frequency of the value.
Now, what is the
time complexity of that?
Maybe one would think, Oh, this is O(MN), but this is very bad
worst case, actually, it isn't even a worst case, it's more tricky. When you think about it, this internal
loop, what is the total number of operation it will do?
It is just iterating based on the frequency of the elements which represent N,
the number of elements in the array.
So let's say
the array has only one value, maybe one repeated 70 times.
This for loop total number of iterations will be just 70 because it is just the frequency of the different
values in the array.
This means these two loops are actually O(M+N).
These aren't nested loops.
This is fake. This one will just be iterating on the values of the array in a different way.
This takes us to this nice analysis here.
If K is the maximum value in the array, we definitely have O(K) space, and definitely, we have O(N+K)
uh,
time complexity.
Now it's very important to notice here, given that you depend on K as a value,
this algorithm, sometimes, could be dangerous, but let's say that K is around N^2.
So actually we ended up with N+N^2 values.
What if K is up to N^3?
Then actually, we have O(N^3) algorithm.
That's why when you try to apply the count sort, you must be aware of the min and max values.
In other words, usually, we need something like maybe 1000 as a range or so.
So that it'll be really added value.
Anyway, keep eyes on the min and max values.
The last thing is about the properties of the current implementation.
First of all, it isn't stable.
Why?
Because we lost the values when we just created a frequency array.
Second, it isn't adaptive.
The procedure doesn't depend on the data.
It will do the same operation from a run to another. Third,
It doesn't fit for online processing.
Why?
Because we have to compute the process, all of it from scratch.
Or if you have the frequency array, you have to update it, and then again, do
the O(N+K) operation to get the new output.
Finally, this isn't an in-place algorithm because we needed extra memory.
Don't think that this is a negative thing.
They are just the properties of it.
Uh, for example.
OK, you are happy.
.
You don't have any problems with that.
You just have like maybe 20K values always and just you need count sort so that you guarantee
something that is efficient based on the values, nothing else, and so on.
That's all.