Sorting homework number one.
First of all, I would like you to rewrite the insertion sort algorithm as following, I would like
you to do things. First, make it to be sorting descending order from large to small.
This is a trivial change.
Second, I would like you to utilize the swap function to implement the insertion sort. You can write
the whole code in just three lines of code using the swap function.
So write it, then compare which one has the total number of fewer operations here.
This version or the lecture one?
The second algorithm, actually most of the comings are count sort algorithms.
This one is count sort, but the values now are negative, specifically from -50000 to 50000 values.
So, how can we use count sort given that we have negative values?
This problem on LeetCode is used for sorting.
You can use it to test your algorithm.
It uses an online judge from LeetCode.
What is an online judge and how to use it?
Please refer to the online judge section.
In this version, we have very huge value from -10^9 up to 10^9
.
Clearly, count sort doesn't work.
However, there is an extra information.
The difference between the maximum value and minimum value is less than or equal
500.
How can we solve this problem? Again.
try it
with count sort.
Let's move to count sort on strings. You would like to sort an array of strings based on the first character.
Here are the constraints, every string is of length one at least, and only consists of lower letters
from a to z.
The sorting is only based on the first character.
So if two strings have the same first character, they are equal strings.
The algorithm must be stable, which means if two strings are equal based on this definition, they
should be sorted and the relative order should be respected.
For example, let's say the vector has ziad, belal,
adam, baheir, and ali. Now, we would like to sort them, the output should be as following, clearly adam and
ali before belal and baheir, but notice here belal is before baheir.
Why?
Because belal is starting with b and baheir with b.
So from this condition perspective, they are equal.
So, belal came first in the input, it came first in the output because we want
the algorithm to be stable. Observe here,
there is e here before a, but we don't care here.
Let's make it a little more complex.
Instead of comparing based on the first character, we will compare based on the first two characters.
And here is another example.
Finally, there is a very popular count sort algorithm that people usually start with it, I believe it
is less educative to do that.
So here is the new algorithm for count sort, it takes a vector of integers and tries to sort it.
It returns a vector of integers,
the input is constant, and doing the sorting algorithm.
I would like you to study this version of count sort and try to understand it by yourself.
Observe, the first two blocks are exactly the same.
The real difference is how to represent and build the output.
So this is where actually you need to put effort of tracing to understand this code.
That's all.