Let's solve the first homework. In the first one, we just would like to rewrite the insertion sort.
The measure of the focus of the code is mainly the swap function.
So let's see here.
The implementation is going to be straightforward.
Instead of this right shift operation, all what you need is to make swapping for the current element
with the previous element.
This will have the exact same effect as the normal operations.
So instead of just shifting, you're just swapping them.
The only advantage here is you don't have to take a copy from the key to assign it later.
Like, let's say.
Maybe.
Yeah, if the array is sorted, and you have, let's do here an example.
So let's say we have so far something like 10, 20, 30, 40 and you have now the value 17.
So what's going to happen is you will swap 17 and 40.
So this is going to be 40.
And this is going to be 17, then yeah, we still have to do go.
So this is going to be swapped.
So this is going to be 17 and this will be 30.
And again, here we will have to swap.
So this one will be 17.
And this one will be 20.
And now nothing else, so we stop.
So you just like implementation skills,
you rearrange things so that you keep going. As we keep moving the index for us,
So it's actually a comparison between the index [ j ] and [ j-1]. The index [ j ]
will always have the current key.
So we don't need anymore to put it here. Given that we now would like to sort from large to
small, we're actually using less than here, nothing else. In terms of operation,
If the swap operation is internally like three steps, you can expect that this code is going to be
slower.
So although it looks like a nicer code, it's actually a bit slower code. Which one you should implement
in the industry?
In the industry, we care a lot about the efficiency.
But if the two codes are very almost of the same complexity, like maybe O(n^2), and nothing is really
sensitive, you should always go to the readable code.
So if the code is readable, you just go with it.
I would say this code is more readable, but the other code is also readable.
So anyway, you just go with the more efficient one in this case.
Sometimes there is really an efficient way to write an implementation, but the code is really complicated.
You don't do that.
Readability is more important.
Some people will come in the future, and they will need to understand your implementation.
OK.
The second problem, the remaining of the sessions is all about the count sort in this one, as you realized.
So here the new point is we have negative values.
So how can we adjust our implementation to have the negative values?
This is the
first problem that we are using the LeetCode online judge for it.
So here is what we will do.
First of all, I would like you to notice that the LeetCode shouldn't be submitted with a main function.
The main function shouldn't be submitted.
You can copy all of this code, but you don't need the main function.
If you did, you will get a compilation error, so don't do that.
The second thing that
you will always need to put your codes inside a public solution, at least the target function here.
Uh yeah.
And if you would like to test, you can test by yourself or test on their website.
Now going back to the problem itself, the idea is very straightforward.
The idea is as following, we now have negative problems.
If I told you the array has positive problems, would it be a problem?
The answer is no.
So the problem is mainly coming now from the negative values.
What is the smallest negative value? -50K
What if just we added 50k to all of the values?
So if all of the values are from -50k to 50k, adding positive 50k will just switch them
from zero to 100K.
Now, the current array is positive values again,
non-negative values. So now we can do count sort normally.
So here is the idea.
You mainly will start by adding the shift factor here, which is 50k, you will add it to all
of the input array, then do the normal operation to do the count sort.
The only thing when you return the value here, you should minus shift it again, the 50k that we added.
The third
problem is very similar.
But the problem here is we wanted in this problem that although the values are extremely huge, they
are following a very small range.
So here is the idea.
Let's say we have an array of 10, 20, and 30, and 10 is the minimum.
If I subtracted 10 from all of this array, it's going to be then 0, 10, and 20.
Now, we can do count sort on that one, and return values back again.
So the same idea here, we know the difference is up to 500.
So first of all, get the minimum in the array, and also the maximum.
And now when you try to compute the frequency, subtract the minimum from the values.
So now although the value could be like one billion, for example, but one billion minus one billion
will be just zero.
So the array anyway is in the safe side.
Um, and when you are trying to return back the values, just add the main value, so we subtracted
million, we added back to the values here. For the range, it should be one plus the difference between
the minimum and the maximum.
So this way we managed, in general, to handle, this code now is generic.
It handles negative values.
It handles positive values. It handles that the values are extremely huge, but the range is small.
These are the different scenarios where the count sort can work beyond the initial scenario.