Let's solve the third problem. We would like to make a count sort on a string, but mainly on the first
letter.
The implementation isn't tough at all.
It just needs some skills from you to be more generic.
So
we know the count sort is all about the frequency, so the frequency of the values.
Now previously, value seven repeated three times, we say seven three.
That's it.
Now character 'X' is repeated in seven different words.
We just cannot say 'X' is seven.
We need them.
So this will take us from, instead of
the vector of integer,
to vector of vector of string, in terms of the previous one.
If we have seven strings, we will have here a vector of seven strings. And a very similar to the count sort,
instead of having like a maximum of maybe 500 as a value,
we know there are maximum 26 letters, so now we go and iterate on the strings one by one,
and take the first letter of the string.
Let's say we have a string like "bcd".
So 'b' - 'a' is just one.
So now we say that letters to strings of one, please push back for me this "bcd". Once you are done
with that, we have a count sort representation, but on strings. If you observed here, the strings
are added here in order. Now, we would like to print them. In a very similar way, we iterate on our maximum
range.
And instead of iterating with a frequency, we iterate on the string list itself, and start to get one
by one. As we are pushing back in order and getting in order,
this is actually a stable algorithm. In the second one, I'm just making it a little bit harder for you
by focusing on two letters instead of one.
So the first thing here, implementation-wise, instead of having only 26 letters, how many now,
in general? We have twenty-six choices for the first one,
twenty-six
choices for the second one.
This is actually like 26*26 choices, right?
If I told you, if this is harder for you, you can always think in normal numbers, something like
a number of two digits is ranging from zero up to 99, which are 100 elements.
What are these hundred elements? 10*10, ten for the first digit, and ten for the second digit.
So in a similar way, we have up to two letters.
The first one is twenty-six, the second one is twenty-six, we have overall 26*26 letters. So now, we have this
range as number of elements.
And we have here the printing, nothing new. Now, the question is, if I have two letters, how to
convert them to a number from zero to 26*26 -1?
How can I convert them to this range?
This is where my function here comes, I take the first character,
convert it to digit, second character convert it to digit.
Then, with this equation, we convert it here.
There is two ways to understand that one.
First, how do you convert a 2D array to flat index?
Remember, if I told you we have an array that's 3*5, I tell you to flatten it to an array of
15 elements.
Remember the equation, you say i, which is the row, times the number of columns, plus the j. This is the equation
that you converted.
This is exactly the same.
Another logic is just you think in the two digits that we were mentioning.
If I have something like sixty-seven, and I only have the six and the seven, how can you convert it?
You say 6 * 10 + 7.
This is how you convert it.
So the moral of that we were just trying to build a function that converts for us from a string
to an integer, so that we can use it here in the array.
I hope you learned a nice trick.