In this video, we will discuss a very special kind of recursive function, but first of all, let's
introduce something about it.
Sometimes we can decompose a problem to a set of sub-problems.
For example, let's say you would like to print all prime numbers that are palindromes and less than
one million.
So we have here two sub-problems, is a number prime? is a number palindrome?
These are our two sub-problems.
If we solved these two sub-problems, then we iterate from one to million and count these number
that satisfy condition number one and condition number two. There's
an interesting question here,
What if the sub-problem is of the same type as same as the problem itself?
This is called recursion.
Let's revise what is factorial.
Factorial 6 is a multiplication of the numbers from 1 to 6 , factorial
5 is a multiplication of numbers from 1 to 5 and so on.
I would like you to stop the video for a minute and think, what is the relationship between Factorial
6 and Factorial 5?
There is some mathematical relationship between them, in another way,
Can you factorial 6 if you know
factorial 5?
Think about that.
Here is how we code the factorial code, we just iterate and multiply numbers from 1 to n.
When we try to think about the factorial of numbers from 1 to 5,
here, and the relationship with the factorial to 4, surprisingly, we noticed that factorial 5 is
factorial 4 * 5, now factorial 5 is our problem.
Factorial 4 is a sub-problem, but it is of the same type like our problem.
That is, we multiply the number from 1 to the target number. in a similar way,
Factorial 6, and factorial 5, factorial 6 is factorial 5 * 6, and factorial 5 is 5
times factorial 4, and so on. this is a very interesting case when the problem and the sub-problems
are of the same type. here,
The problem is of type factorial.
We need factorial 6, which is 6 * factorial 5, which is a smaller sub-problem.
So let's say we would like to solve the factorial 6 problem, which is our problem, which we can definitely
solve as just multiplication from 1 to 6. another way to think of it, is as following, factorial 5
is a simpler sub-problem,
If we multiplied it with 6, we get factorial 6.
So can we go forever in smaller sub-problems, for example, 6 needs factorial 5, factorial 5 needs 4, 4 needs 3,
3 2, 2 1.
There is at some point we have to stop.
And this is, for example, in our case, when we come to factorial 1, which is defined as factorial 1
with 1, and factorial 0 with 1.
This is something that we call the best case,
This is where there are no more  sub-problems.
So what we know so far is, there are a problem and sub-problems.
Sometimes, the sub-problem is of the same type as the problem itself.
So one way to solve the problem is by solving the sub-problem, and the sub-problem will need another sub-sub-problem
of the same type.
And the sub-sub-problem would need a sub-sub-sub-problem of the same type.
But we cannot go forever,
We have to stop at some point,
And this is what we call a base-case.
So let's do some funny code to implement the factorial 6, using the logic that we have just
sketched.
So we are going here to print "cout<<factorial6() "
as a function, but we know that factorial6 is just 6 * factorial5 as a function.
So factorial 5,
Forget how is it implemented,
Think like factorial5 is some function that is going to return the answer of factorial5 correctly. Once
factorial5 is returned, you multiply with 6 and we get the results.
Now let's think about factorial5. Factorial
5 is actually factorial4 *  5.
This is very good.
Now, regardless of how factorial4 is implemented, we know it is eventually 5 *
factorial4. Factorial 4
also is 4 * factorial3,
3 * 2, factorial2 is 2 * 1 and 1 is returning 1.
If you try to think about the overall here, 6, calling 5, calling 4, calling 3, calling 2,
calling 1.
This is actually the result will end up, for example, for factorial6, as 6 * 5 *
4 * 3 * 2 * 1.
And factorial4 is 4 * 3 * 2 * 1.
I would like you to try to do some tracing for this code and think about it.
Moreover, I would like you to think, is there an elegant way to write only a single function that
save us from doing all of this repetitive task?
That's it for today.