Let's solve the second set of the homework and recursive functions.
And this is going to be incrementally harder and harder.
So don't feel bad if things didn't go well, like it's a matter of an iterative learning.
I would like you to keep going in the course, because most of the course does not depend on recursive
functions.
And from time to time, come back and try to fight more with one of the examples.
And the first function would like to compute the Right-Max.
We previously computed the left-max, this time is the right side.
So how to think about that?
I'm here at one.
I need to be the maximum of me and all of my right side.
So maybe recursively I can do the following; if I can get the right max of my right side,
I can just maximize between myself and him.
So this encourages to make a recursive call on your right side first to compute its right max.
So the function would be as following. This time
we need length
and for making it easier for you,
you need the starting position for this time.
So it would be like first
I am at the starting position zero, then one, two, three, four, and so on.
Let's see.
Some couldn't see if we can trace it or not.
I'm writing here two versions in the first version, I say the following.
The starting position will start by zero and keep moving to the right side, up to the end of the
array.
So once we are at the end of the array, we're done, finish it.
Now we start by calling.., compute the right max for the array.
But starting from position plus one, what does the call mean?
It means please compute for me the maximum of every position and its right positions.
But do that only from the position one.
So what is the expected result from this recursive call?
If we are given here one, eight, two, ten, and three, we say, hey, one isn't your job. Compute the
right maximum of my right side array, which would be...; when you compute about it,
it will be like we are here computing it by hand not recursively.
What is the maximum side in all of this interval?
It is ten.
What is the maximum side of all of this interval is ten and ten and three.
This is the result
I computed by hand, not by code.
Now, once this one is done, I am saying, you know what?
The right
maximum of me is the maximum between my value and just the value directly after me, which is max
between one and ten, which is also 10.
I hope that this isn't that hard for you to get.
The moral of that is; you, in a very clear way, define
what does your function mean. Here,
it means if we compute the maximum from position, for example, four then if we call this function with
position four, it should compute the maximum for position four up to the end of the array.
That's it.
This is all what is required from it.
So I compute the result, and then I take an action based on that.
OK.
Why did I give you the start position equal zero?
To make your life easier while coding it.
Now there is a challenge.
Can we do it without the start position at all?
Can you do that?
Here is a trivial way.
First of all, with this recursive function we don't a length anymore
so if the length is one or less than or equal one, there is nothing to do.
Now look to the following.
I'm going to call with array plus one, which means we'll call with this sub array here and length minus
one, because the length now decreased.
Now, when we compute this answer,
it is going to update the array again to be like that.
Once we are done with that, array of zero is going to be the maximum between my position, and my right
side.
OK, so the moral of that is; you call with the array changing itself, you are giving this sub
array and telling him, please compute the maximum,
right maximum of this sub-array.
It will compute this right maximum.
Then all what you need now is a comparison between position zero and position one. That's it.
Please don't get trapped in tracing the code for infinite number of sub-codes.
Just think, what does this function do?
The following:
Every time I will see this function call, I will just apply by hand
what does it mean?
Not by code.
I'm going to ask, what does it do?
x, y, z, apply x, y, z.
That's all.
OK, let's see the second function.
"Suffix Sum" and the "Prefix Sum". The suffix sum would like to sum the last N elements.
So here in the code, the idea is as following.
I'm going here to pass length and count. Length is a total array length and the current count. Now,
with every call I can say, I don't think we should no, we still need it here.
I'm going to tell it I would like you to compute the suffix sum of the last count minus one elements
from this sub array.
But there is a problem here, like the function will get trapped
how can it be...?
Uh.
Yeah, I don't like the fact that I needed to use length minus one this way and let me stop this code
here.