Let's continue the homework from this lecture and also from the recursive lecture and some
homework in this till end would be using a new markers, so don't wonder why the remaining of the
course doesn't have something to point on the screen.
Um, so what's next?
We wanted to implement this function, I was a little puzzled in the last session for a reason.
But anyway, so we would like to sum only the last N elements in the array.
So in this case here, we have this input array and we have these three numbers.
Then the last three elements would be seventeen coming from them.
So to design a function for that, here is what I implemented eventually.
We have the array here and we have the current counter; the current length of the array.
So for example, here, if we have the one, eight, two. ten and three, so initially we have five elements.
So the length is five.
Now, if I would like to print the last three, get the last three, I would like to get this three elements.
So when you think about it?
You either try to get this element and then get the next one or maybe get this element and go this one.
So this is are the two thinking perspectives.
So from here, I would just go with that.
I would just go with getting the last element.
Now the idea is as following, I need a counter so that I can know if I am done or not.
This is a must. No way you can get rid of the counter.
So here we can easily define the base case.
If we do not need any elements anymore, we are done with tracing the task.
OK, now what is this element here?
Three is the array of length minus one.
So we know that we need this variable with us, we need this index with us.
OK, so we got it.
Now let's define our recursive problem.
When you think about it, it seems that we need to work on this sub-array.
Right.
So in terms of our function definition, this seems to be the suffix sum of the array, but its
length now decreased one element and also its counter decreased one element.
So this way, we can define simply the recursive function.
The thing that bothered me last time that actually the length it doesn't really express the the function.
But but anyway, that's what the function definition I see is still valid.
The function is given an array and the length and the count elements just get them for me.
So when you think about it, the function is valid now from the tracing perspective that we learned
before, the function is doing as following, like according to the definition, what is suffix sum
of five and three?
It is just the submission of the last three elements.
What does this function
do? It says I would like three plus the submission of the array of length four and two
elements.
This is array of length four and two elements are two and 10.
So you don't have to keep tracing the function.
You just by the function logic
you can simply decide what is the goal of it.
OK, so let's see, what else do we have?
The second task, which is the opposite,  we would like to compute the prefix sum. Now
this time is a bit easier, but just different perspective.
And this time, if I would like the three, it would mean the first three numbers, which are here
eight.
Now, how can we implement that? Similar logic
but there are some advantages here.
OK, so let's use exactly the same strategy as the last
one.
We have here our array, which is one, eight,  two, ten, and three, I would like to get the first three
elements, which are these three elements.
So now if I would like to think recursively. Again, I have two thinking strategies, either I would
like to get this one and then try to get the eight and two in the recursive way.
Or I can get the two.
And recursively, I will try to get the one and eight.
So this is how I would arrange my thinking strategy.
So let's go with the first one.
The first one will be exactly the same logic as we did before in the previous suffix sum.
So the idea would be as following I would need the length.
And I also need a counter. If the counter is zero,
we are done with that task.
Now, if I would like to get this element where its  position, its position is array of count
minus one.
OK, we got this one.
Now I want to define my sub-problem.
My sub-problem now is the array is as it is.
But the counter here is two.
What about the length?
The length actually didn't change.
I do not think that we need to
We don't need to do this minus one, because anyway, we don't depend on it.
So now when you think about it, my new problem is, hey, in the same array count for me, the first
two elements, which is just one and eight.
So this is how recursively you think about it.
When the count with three I was saying, please count for me, sum for me these three elements.
Mathematically, what is the sum?
Just add it.
OK, if I told you please sum for me, the first two elements, then the mathematically we just
one and eight is nine.
So this is how we trivially can trace it.
Now given that in C++, we can trivially decide a new array start.
We can make use of this add factor to code it in a different way.
Which is this following in the array here, one, eight, two, ten and three who will do the
following, I told you I can take the last element and get the first elements.
What if I get need to get the first element?
OK, the first element is one.
OK, so we got one plus something.
What did the remaining of the function?
It is the array from eight.
And the count is two.
What is 8?
Eight is array plus one.
So given that C++ allow us to do that, which might not be the case in other languages or at least
not efficient, we can define also the signature in another way.
So this function has this advantage, given that we depend on the begin.
This wasn't possible with the suffix sum.
So this was easy or doable here
much more compared with the previous functionality.
Uh, let's proceed.
The third one here
is for Is Palindrome, we would like to decide if the array is palindrome or not, and I would like you
to define the signature of the function.
OK.
So I'm defining here two definitions for is palindrome.
One of them where I have to use a start and end and another one, I will not have to use a start and end.
So let's see how. This is
palindrome array, we see that one is one, eight is eight two in the middle.
This is a palindrome array.
So here's what I'm going to do now again, we would like to think recursively one, eight, two, eight, one.
What is a palindrome array?
It's an array recursively that its start is as same as its end, and the middle is also palindrome.
So this is how you think and implement it.
I'm first of all, comparing the start with the end.
If they are not equal, we return false.
Otherwise I am shifting the start pointer here and the end pointer here.
To check if this is palindrome or not, according to that, what is the function definition?
The function definition is given an array, check if the values from this start to this end is palindrome.
This is the function definition.
So initially, if you pass zero and four, then it means if this all is palindrome or not. The next step
when you pass one and three, it check only if this is palindrome or not.
And the next step will check if two and two is palindrome or not.
It will be, yes, because if there is a single element, then we are done.
Again, in practice, you shouldn't keep tracing the function, you should only ask yourself, what
is the definition of this function?
The definition is, is it palindrome in this range or not?
We check the boundaries, we recurs on the body and then we just ask, is it palindrome or not?
This is the first way to do it.
Now I'm going to make use of the fact that we can adjust to the C++ in an easy way.
So here is how I will implement it. In a similar way,
now the definition is as following given an array and its length; 'end' here represents the length,
just a check for me if this is palindrome or not.
So now one, eight, two, eight, one, according to the recursive definition, if I give it all of this array,
it should work well.
Right. Now, we need to make some tracing. How can I check if I don't have a start?
Now the definition of the function is the whole array, not just from the start to the end.
If the whole array is palindrome or not, 'end' here is actually, um uh, let me think about something.
Yeah, 'end' here is an index; 'end' represents the last index of the array, not the length of that array
The length of this array is 5.
So 'end' is actually an index and 'end' here is index two, end plus one is the length.
Here is the base case.
I'm saying if we have only a single element in the array, then definitely this is a palindrome.
And the second one, I would like to compare the first element in the array with the last element in
the array.
This is end position and this is zero position.
So is it not equal, if not equal, we return false.
Now, after that, I would like to to prepare my new definition.
I know that I want to check from here and I need this end here.
So I can say the following: through this, I can say, Hey, I need array plus one, which is this 8.
Now,
what is the end from this perspective?
This is zero, this is one, this is two.
Previously, this was zero, one, two, three, four.
As you see, the new end is two steps minus the previous end; this why I shift here end minus two?
If you want to think of it from another logic, we actually are done with two characters.
So the length or the end must shift to be by two parameters.
I hope the second definition is clear for you.
We are making use of C++, but we are defining it in an nicer way.
I would say the second one is more nicer than the first one because the definition is much more logical.
You are saying something like, is this a palindrome array or not?
And then you are preparing your new array.
I hope the overall idea of this part is clear enough.