Let's proceed, in this one, we would like to check if a string is a prefix or not.
I'm trying to help you here that you can have something like the starting position in the string, uh,
in a real company actually
this two ones would be like with a constant, with reference, and you cannot keep changing them.
Now, let's see how to implement that, uh, the function is going to be pretty easy.
So what is the definition of the function? Always the first thing to do with recursion is to focus
a lot on how do we define the function?
The function is defined as following we have a string and we have another string and we would like from
this starting position to make sure that this string is matching this one.
For example, if I have something like 'abcd' and I say I have 'abc', does it match?
yes, it
matches.
But from which index? match from index starting position equals zero
What about 'bc'?
Does it match from starting position equals zero?
No, it does not match.
What about 'bc' from starting position equal one?
Does it match?
Yes, it match. Why?
Because from starting position one, we have a match here.
So this is a function definition from this starting index.
Does this prefix completely match this part or not?
The answer is yes.
You might think, Oh, OK, but wait a second,  like, this isn't a nice string definition, why? like the
name here is not good because when you pass a string and you call the function prefix, then it
isn't a good name.
This is true.
I would say a better name is something like is substring.
And we give it a starting position.
Now the definition is going to be pretty good and 'is prefix' is just a substring with a starting position
equals zero.
So in practice, your company should say, Hey, you know what?
This isn't a smart name.
Actually, it can act like just a substring.
And when it's substring, it will be much more logical because when I say is this one a substring
from this one starting from this index?
The answer would be yes.
So what is the lesson here?
The lesson is you should think about your function definition and it should be logic, and it should
make sense.
Anyway, let's go back to our problem here.
Pretend that this is like substring of the....,
It's confusing for you.
Now, the first thing we need to do is, uh, what if we are done with tracing the function?
so we can say, Hey, if we are done, if a starting position equal equal the length, we are done.
This is true.
If you would like to secure yourself, you can also say here if the position is after the prefix size,
return false. This would be good in software engineering, why?  because it takes care of people who
will misuse your library, like if someone give you a very big starting position or a negative starting
position.
This code will runtime error.
So in a more cleaner code in software engineering, you would actually validate the starting position.
But for now, let's pretend everything is still good enough because we anyway wanted this function
to be used only for is prefix.
So we assume that people actually would not pass starting
position equals zero.
OK.
Let's go to our definition.
We see here.
If the current start doesn't match the current prefix position, return false. For example,
if the big string is 'abcde' and the small string is 'xy'.
And the starting position is zero.
So the first thing we do is; we compare this
person with this person; does x equal a? no, doesn't. Then it cannot be a prefix anymore.
OK.
What if this actually was something like 'ab' ? Now,
Does 'a' match 'a'?
Yes.
Now what is the new sub-definition?
We need to match this remaining of the string with this remaining of the string.
So let's prepare our recursive call. The recursive call will take the two strings as they are.
But now my starting position just shifted one.
So I'm one here and one here.
Without tracing the function by function definition, especially if we renamed it to be is substring,
it would be.
I would like to match of this string here.
This big string here and this big string here are matched starting from the index one.
And it will keep.
And it will keep going.
For example, let's say let's pretend we have something like 'abz'.
So the 'a' would match with 'a', and we recursively jump at index one 'b' match with 'b', recursively would
jump at index two , 'c' with 'z' doesn't match.
So we just return.
If it happened that this actually 'c' then 'c' and 'c' match.
Yes, jump next.
The size is done.
Then we return true.
I hope overall you understood how to think about it
here.