In the next problem, we would like to trace what is the output of these two functions.
This is very close to the triangle example.
I hope you notice the following: tracing the first one is easier than tracing the second one.
So let's see what's happening here. In the first one,
let's give it something like let's use something like 'n' equal one two three four five.
So let's see what's happening here.
We remember what's our goal with the recursion?
If we would like to understand it simply, we would like to know what is the function definition, what
is the goal of the function?
So this is the goal now.
We start by printing n%10
10.
So what is n%10
here? It is
five.
So we print five.
And then we recurs on what? n over 10, which is one, two, three four.
So when you think about it, what happens so far is the function
printed for me the last digit.
And then it recursed on the remaining of the numbers.
By definition, the function will keep doing the same, it would print the last thing and go to recurs
on the remaining.
Then it would print the last, which is three and recurs on the remaining.
What does this function do?
This function is printing the number digit by digit in a reverse order, so we can say that this function
is actually print-
Reverse it.
This is actually what's happening here.
I hope you notice how I'll try to....,  I don't have to keep digging with the recursion forever.
You have to..,  like from the first steps you can guess what does this function really
do?
Now, the second one is harder because the action is happening in a very late time.
So let's see what's happening here.
Uh, let's view the code.
Here is the second function here, the function now is going to recurs first, then do the printing.
So let's again pretend to trace something like one, two, three, four, five and six.
So the function is doing the following.
First of all, it recuses to do something.
So there is something happening here.
But happening on what? it happening only on, again, the first five digits.
What's it doing after returning? it's printing the last number.
OK.
But there is something happening before here.
So the last number that would be printed would be printed after what happened here.
So this printing would come in the end because something from here will come first.
And we see that it actually decreasing removing one digit.
OK.
Let's make one more step for tracing to make it easier for us here.
When we recurs again with this number,
it will again go to do something with one two three four.
And then, print for me the last number, which is digit, but I hope at this moment that you can
see that this is actually is going to end up with one two three four five.
So something like printing the digits of this number.
Uh, probably tracing the second one is a harder.
But you have to think in this way, you have to think something is happening after it,
I would make use of its output and build over it.
And so on. I hope overall that isn't annoying for you.
This is very similar to printing triangle like that.
We did it before or printed like that.
It's exactly the same idea.