In the next challenge, we would like to count the prime numbers in a given range.
However, we ask you to not use loops at all.
So as usual, like this function with loops is easy.
Now we'd like to do it without any loops.
And also, I'm asking you to try to compute the answer for something like that big.
Now, let's see what's happening here.
Um.
OK, so let's go, the first function that we need is to count the primes.
And the second function is is_prime.
So these are two separate functionalities, so let's just pretend that we have functioned
this code is_prime that can tell us if the number is prime or not. Now, for this function, start
and end.
We can say that this function, by definition, is counting the primes from start to end.
Now, think about the following if we know if the current element the current start is prime or not,
and we recursively code start prime from +1 an end, then we are done with the results.
So for example, let's say that we have the numbers one two, let's say the start is one, and let's
say the start is one and the end is 10, for example.
So the function does as following.
You can reverse these two lines if you'd like.
It says Here, please count for me, the primes starting from +1.
So let's say count primes from two to 10.
Now, by the recursive definition, this is going to count the primes, how? I don't care.
So what are the numbers from one to 10 one two three four five six seven eight nine 10, the primes
are three and five and seven.
So when I say count the primes from two to 10, what does it happen?
it all what to do it will return for me four.
Why?
By the mathematical definition, this function is counting the primes.
So it's going to do that.
So this function here will return for me
four.
And the next step is I'm checking is prime of
start. The start is one.
So is it prime or not?
one is false.
Also, by definition, is_prime will return for me true if this is a prime number.
We are done with tracing from this function respective. Just to make it easy for you.
Let's trace one more step.
Let's say that the function actually counted
count primes starting from two, so it says now
here count the primes from two to 10.
The function will do as following.
First, it would say, Hey, get for me the result as count the primes of three and the ten, which return
the three, four, three and five and seven.
After that, we check if two is prime or not.
If it's prime, we increment one.
So plus one, which is total four.
So from this function perspective, we are done.
And as you see, the way I handled the request for canceling the loops is just to keep recursively recursing
on that next index.
That's it.
Now let's go for the second function.
I would like to check if a number is prime or not without loops.
So let's say I'm asking you to check for me
number like 17.
In the normal case, we loop from three, or even from two.
We loop from two up to 16 to check if the number is divided by them or not.
Now the trick here is again, and we will replace this loop by recursively
recursing on the next index.
The function is doing the following.
It adds here a default values that is the current test number.
So in the normal case, we have for loop the current test number starting from two up to less than
n and we do the check if it's prime or not.
Now this variable will be actually just the parameter here in the recursive function, which says if
this is this number is
Is prime starting from this number or not?
Like if I kept starting from testing from this number is going to be prime or not.
For example, let's say we have number like five, OK?
And I say f of, let's go back to 17,  f of 17 and six.
What does it mean?
Does 17 is divisible by any number from six up to 16 or not?
This is the function definition.
I hope you got it.
So the function is starting from this number.
Is there any number that is divisible by, uh, this number and any number
after it or not? This is the function definition, why the function definition is important?
We will use it in tracing.
OK, I'm handling here two as a special test case, and I'm handling here negative numbers and
even numbers, and I'm handling here
If we reach to the end of the number. like m is 17 and the test number is 17, we're done. The only remaining case is
to start to test actually this number and the numbers after it.
So let's say we have f of 17 and initially three here.
This three condition doesn't apply, it say here does 17 is divided by three?
The answer is no.
It say recurs on 17 and the next number, which is 14.
So let's say does 17 is divisible by any number in the range four to 16 or not? which were recurs
to does, uh, f of 17 and five is 17 divisible per any number,  from five to 16 or not? this is the
function definition.
So again, we swept, we replaced the loop with an index in a recursive function.
And this trick is very important in a topic named as dynamic programming.
We remove a loop and replace it with an index in the function.
So remember this trick?
So how can we get rid of loops?
You just make them...,
Sorry, here at the start, you make it an index in a function.
I hope the idea is now clear for you and again keep in mind what is the function definition?
This is how you can trace a recursion in a very first manner.