In the next problem, we have a grid like a 2D matrix; like the one that we see here. Three times three
grid and we have a robot.
It starts at position.
It can only go in three directions either to the right or to the left or to the diagonal.
I wasn't clear to emphasize that it must be only this diagonal, so we have only three choices.
We cannot go this backward diagonal.
OK, we can just go to this one.
And now the robot have a very deterministic operation, and we can't even implement that in an iterative
way.
The robot starts here.
It consider the three destinations if they are available, and then see which one has the maximum value.
And remember, the values are distinct, which mean they are different.
Then there must be only one of them is maximum.
According to that, it will move to this cell based on the maximum value, for example, the robot
would start here at one, then it checks 7, 10, 2. 10 is the maximum, so go to the diagonal at 10.
Then it checks 11, 9 and 5.
11 is a diagonal.
It goes here.
Then it only have one choice here at the 9.
So there is only one specific path we can do, and we can implement that trivially
using a loop like we can start looping from here and keep moving.
Maybe you should try to implement that in a loop first before trying to..., try to implement it
in a recursive way.
So this problem, more or less is just a way to administrate this.
This is kind of switching from like iterative code to a recursive code.
So here is how we can implement that in an easy way.
First of all, we will use the direction arrays that we learned in the course and the
direction array we have here three directions only so I'm representing them here the our three positive
directions.
Now this should be a common part of the iterative code.
I'm going here to iterate on the three directions and store in the maximum index which one has the
maximum value.
So I'm computing the next row and column and making sure they are valid.
And then I'm comparing with the maximum value so far.
If they are less than the current maximum value, I will just
I will just use here the current maximum value.
Um, I think it is more proper to initialize this max value to something, maybe even in some scenarios
there is a bug here, but I didn't.
So anyway, this one should be initialized to a proper value.
Now, once we are done with deciding which one of the 3 direction is the minimum, we can
know the exact position that we will move to it.
The remaining step is instead of making a loop that keeps going, we just call the function path_sum
here.
So the function path_sum; it takes our current grid.
It takes the total number of frozen columns and also it takes that uh.
Uh, it takes the initial row and column.
Now here in the code, this first three parameters are the
same.
And I just here now pass it the new location.
So initially remember the values
we were here at the one then, here at 10, and 11, and 9.
So initially we start with zero and zero.
And then it will find that the maximum is coming from one and one.
So the function will be called with position one and one at the 10.  The one and one will find that the next
one here, which is at one and two, is the next maximum.
So it will call the rows and column with one and two.
This one doesn't have any choices except two and two.
Now this here takes us to our base case.
The base case is when the number of rows and number of columns is at the end.
So this is where I'm going to end it.
So in summary, we instead of writing it in an iterative way with a loop, we just did something that
keeps recursively call at the next starting position.
That's all for this problem.