Let's move to the next problem.
We would like to compute the Fibonacci sequence, which is a very popular mathematical sequence.
As you see, every term is just the submission of the two previous terms.
For example, five here is a submission of two and three.
Eight is a submission of three and five.
That's why the recurrence here is like Fibonacci of N is for fibonacci of n-1 and plus fibonacci of
n-2.
So Fibonacci of six here is coming from Fibonacci five and four, which is 30.
These three values here.
Now there is something very special in this problem compared to all of the homework and all of the practice
that we met.
This one depends on two recursive calls or two sub calls, not just a single one.
So this one depends on 2 calls. All of the previous problems that we solve are called tail
recursion, which means that every recursive function is only coding a specific and one other recursive
function.
For example, factorial n is only calling factorial n-1. Factorial n-1
is only calling factorial n-2.
So that's why all of what we learned can be replaced with a trivial loop; only a single
loop can do all of them because in a way, we have only one new state. Now in this problem,
we have two states, which is very different from all what we learned before.
When it comes to implementing that, it still should be straightforward.
Like, not that a big challenge here.
So let's see.
The function is as following.
We start with the base case here and say if n equal less than or equal one, then this base case is done.
Otherwise we return for fibonacci of n-1 and fibonacci of n-2.
Now the first thing I would like to emphasize here is the
How to trace it properly, remember?
What is the sequence?
It is one one two three five eight 13.
So mathematically, F(1) is one.
F(1) is one,  F(2) is one, F(3) is two,  F(4)
is three, F(5)
is five,  F(6)
is 8.
This is the mathematical view.
Now if I would like to make sure that at least the tracing skills, let's say I'm asking here
for f of six, the base case doesn't work.
It asks for F(n-1).
So F(n-1) is F(5), which is five.
And it asks for F(4) which is three; for total eight. Now, go back to your sequence, does it F(6)
is eight? yes, we are done.
Do not keep tracing forever.
This is wrong.
This is time waste.
Don't do that. When you would like to trace recursion, all what you have to do:
Make sure every recursive call has been used once.
If every recursive call has been used once and every line of the code has been passed once, the
code must be completely correct.
Meanwhile, tracing this one is pretty useful.
I asked you for a challenge if we can run Fibonacci  40, or Fibonacci 50.
If you try to run something, like Fibonacci 50, you will notice the code is taking forever or something
like Fibonacci of maybe 60, a lot of runtime.
Why?
Remember, this isn't a trivial recursion anymore.
It has a branches, it has two cases here.
This is through a simple tree to realize the problem. Assume for while I asked you for Fibonacci of
50, Fibonacci of 50.
Now what is happening here?
This function will call for Fibonacci of.
49.
And Fibonacci of 49 is done,
it will also ask for Fibonacci of 48.
Let's go in details. Fibonacci 49 will compute Fibonacci of
48 and Fibonacci of 47.
Fibonacci 48 will call for Fibonacci 47 and Fibonacci of 46.
Fibonacci 48 will call for Fibonacci 47 and Fibonacci of 46. Fibonacci 47 will call for
Fibonacci 46, and for Fibonacci 45.
45.
And here again, Fibonacci 47 will call for Fibonacci 46.
46.
And also for Fibonacci 45.
There is a very critical observation that we can find at the moment without drawing all of the possible
branches that would happen.
Can you spot it?
The problem is as following, do you notice that this is F(48) is exactly as this F(48).?
This F(48) would build a very huge tree.
Now the question here is when this function keep repeating the same one, F(48), it's going to take
the same time of that guy.
And this one F(47), which is the same as F(47) here and this F(47), it is as simple as F(47) here.
Do you notice the problem?
We are duplicating the competitions a lot, how much? this three will keep branching.
You will learn that pretty good when you learn about trees.
But what's clear here,
This one will create a tree of two to the power n nodes, something like that.
So it goes as following: like it would be here.
It will go this way.
Then this one will go this way, then this one will go this way and this one will go this way.
And this one will go this way.
And this one will go this way and this one will go this way.
Now we have one call here, we have two calls here, now four codes here, we have 8 codes here.
Everyone would open two.
This one would be 16.
Now we will keep going up to n levels.
This means the total number of recursive calls are one plus two plus four plus 16 plus 32 plus
64.
Blah blah blah.
Up to
to the power n; for a total mathematically to the power n+1.
This means if you call this function with F(50), we need
F(50+1) recursive calls, do you see how you did that?
That's why the Fibonacci call will take forever.
Almost forever.
That's why it doesn't work well.
And you never met this problem in all of the previous homework, because it doesn't have this kind of
branching idea, it doesn't have this problem.
It doesn't have this problem.
Now, if you understood this problem, there is a trivial trick that can solve this issue.
What is it?
Still recursively.
The idea is following, we know that the core of the issue is F(50) called F(49) and F(48).
F(49) called F(48) and F(47), now, the point here is
How can we make use of this previously computed value, for example, if this value is computed before
we just use the value here?
The idea is very simple, and I will not go into the details of that now.
You define an array outside here.
Let's call it answers.
Every time you compute the answer of the array, you put the answer inside the array and the code will
do the following before it starts to compute the answer for n, it will check
does the array have my answers or not?
So 48 will finish the answer.
Let's say the answer is 173, for example.
Then it will say here answers of 48 equals 173.
When this function would like to get the answer 48, it would check the array first.
Do you have the answer?
Yes.
What will happen?
It will just use it so it will not do all of this branching, branching ,branching.
Now we realize that the core of the problem we are repeating the competitions to 2 to the power n+1 times.
Now, the key is array of 50 values that say if you target a fifth, let's say array of 1000 values
is enough to keep computing and saving the answers before doing the recursive calls,
you check if the answer exists or not.
And if it exist, you just use it.
Now think about it how many nodes, how many values should be in this tree?
The values are only from one to 50.
So this means instead of having two to the power n+1 calls, we would only have n calls
because there is no need for more than that.
So let's make it simpler.
Let's say you want to compute F(7),  F(7) will go and compute F(6), F(6) goes and
computes five, which goes and competes four.
which compute three, which compute two, which compute one.
Now memorize two in the memory.
This second circle means saved in answers.
save in
answer, now 2 needs
one and one which is OK.
Three needs to.
Three needs two and need one.
OK, good.
Now 4 needs three, which is done and need also 2, wait.
Two is computed already.
So just use it.
So do nothing here four. Now,
five need 4  and need 3. 4 is already there and three is already there because let's use both
of them directly.
Sum them directly.
Now we have five. Six needs five and four.
Both of them are stored then get them directly six needs five and four.
Just add them here. Seven needs six and five already exist.
Add them here. Now,
seven needs here
five already exist.
We are done.
So the tree now has only n nodes
Sorry if the word nodes, the word the tree are a bit new for you.
We call this circle node and we call this shape atree in algorithms field.
Uh, as you see, we change the performance from 2+n to only n.
What does what, what?
What I was just describing is called dynamic
programming; a very important technique to reduce the time complexity of recursive functions.
You don't need to implement what I was just saying or even if you get lost, just drop it for now.
We will visit it in the algorithm
course will learn more about dynamic programming and how to implement it.
Meanwhile, the idea is very simple.
What I implemented is specifically called memorization.
Um, so feel free to try to implement it.
Feel free to skip it for now.
But I wanted you to understand this very critical example.
Don't skip it if you don't understand why you have 2n+1 nodes.
This is very critical to understand why this F(90) didn't work.
Well, that's all.