In this video, we will see how the factorial function can be written in a recursive way. a recursive
function, is a function that calls itself with a smaller input, which is a sub-problem
'till reaches a baseline.
So let's see the code here.
The good is as following,
Calling factorial(6), factorial is a function that takes an integer and returns an integer. For a while
I would like to assume that this function is a magic that is working very well and I'm teaching you
a very elegant way to learn how to trace recursive function.
So now factorial is a function that does some magic and computes for us a result, if we give it 6
it is going to compute factorial 6.
If we give it 10, it's going to give us factorial 10.
So the function start with printing "function call: factorial: n" which is initially 6.
Now if n == 1, we are returning 1.
This is the base case handling.
Now, if this isn't the case, like let's say we are calling with 6, so the function is going to do
the following, it is going to call itself factorial(n - 1), which is now 5 * 6.
Now remember what I was saying?
think in factorial(n-1) as some magic that is going to compute the answer somehow.
So Factorial(5) is going to be computed, which is 120, and it will be multiplied
with 6,
And the result is returned,
OK. this is how we trace recursive function.
Now let's think more about it.
If we call it with factorial(5).
Let's let's go back again.
6 here is going to print 6 and then it's going to call factorial(5).
So Factorial(5) is going to print 5,
Then going here again, it is going to compute factorial(4) * 5.
Factorial(4) is going to come here, printing factorial(4) and then factorial(4) will call 3 and 3 will
call 2 and 2 will call 1,
1 is going to stop here.
So it's going to come back to 1 * 2 * 3 * 4 * 5, and so on.
This might be hard.
So let's see two ways of visualizing it.
Factorial 6 will ask is 6 = 1?
It will say no.
So it's calling factorial(5),
And the result is going to be multiplied by 6.
If you would like to trace the recursion in an elegant way, stop thinking at this moment and tell yourself
what is the result of factorial(5)? it is 120.
What happens if we multiplied it with 6, it is going to be 720.
We are done, but let's go.
More in tracing. Factorial(5), check if
It's one? no, it is going to compute factorial(4) and multiply with 5. 4 is 1?
no, call factorial(3),
call factorial(2), call factorial(1),
is 1?
true, it is going to return 1.
The one is returned here multiplied by 2.
Returned here as 2 multiplied by 3, returned here as 6 multiplied by 4.
Returned here as 24 multiplied by 5, returned here as 120 multiplied
by 6.
Returned here as 720.
Let's do another visualization, just to make sure that you really get it.
This is the main calling factorial(6),
factorial(6), calls factorial(5) * 6,  which calls factorial(5)
again which is calling factorial(4) * 5, which is calling again factorial(3) * 4
which is calling again factorial(2) * 3, which is calling again factorial(1) * 2,
which is calling factorial(1), here we reach the base-case. Factorial(1) is returning 1 here.
So now it is 1 * 2,
Now this is done
2, we return it to factorial(3).
So factorial(3) has here now 2 * 3, which is 6, now 6 is returned here.
So 6 * 4
24.
returned here,
So it's 120,
returned here
720.
That's it.
But remember this isn't how we as programmers trace recursion in reality.
In reality, we trace a function call only once, and we ask ourself, let's say that this is magic,
how the magic is working. in this way,
That is it for example, factorial(6) calling factorial(5),
What is the result of factorial(5)? 120
We stop in practice tracing at this moment, but because we know really how recursion is working, that's
it for today.