Let's do some practice on the recursive function. In this program we would like to print the following
triangle on the left side. a triangle of five different levels.
You definitely know, how to print such a triangle using looping for five times.
I would like you to think for a while,
How can we print such a triangle using recursion?
Give yourself a trial to stop the video and think, how could you write the code?
Now, let me show you the code for this task.
We have here a function of printing triangle(5).
The first question is, why is this a potentially a recursive function?
This is a recursive function because if you look to the output row by row there's seriously a relationship
between them, that the second row is the same printing as the previous row, just missing one printing.
So it's actually very, very relevant.
In other words, thinking about what is the relationship between a triangle of five levels and triangle
of four levels, the triangle of five levels is just one extra level, than the triangle of four levels.
So Triangle of five levels, is five stars plus a triangle of four levels, and triangle of four levels
is four stars plus triangle of three levels, and triangle of three levels is three stars, plus a triangle
of tow levels, and triangle of two levels is a two stars plus
a triangle of one level, and triangle of one level is just one star and nothing else,
And this is the base-case.
So this encourages us to implement a recursive function for the print_triangle.
Let's see
How can we do that?
First of all,
we are going to make a print_triangle() here and it has integer levels.
I'm saying here, "if(levels == 0) return;", which means we cannot draw anything of just zero level. at the
ith level,
for now, let's say the level is 5.
So we are iterating here.
Let's trace, print_triangle(5) is now here, it is printing 5 stars and then it is calling print
of levels - 1, which is 4.
So what happened is as following:
we printed the 5 stars and we called a recursive function that is capable of printing a triangle
of 4 stars.
When this function call here goes with 4, it's going to check is 0? no, It's going to
print 4 stars, and then it's going to recurs call to print 3 stars and so on, 3
2, 1, 0, done.
Let's also do tracing to make sure that you really get it.
The function is print_triangle
taking five, it's going to print  five stars here and going to call print four stars.
The function print four stars is going to print four stars and then call print_triangle of 3
levels, print triangle of three levels, will print three stars and then call the print_triangle of 2
levels, two levels is going to print two stars and calling print_triangle of 1 level, one level is
going to print one star and call print_triangle of zero levels, zero level is done,
then just we return and return and return nothing.
That's it.
trace
the code,
Think about it.
A question for you, can you print
using recursion, the triangle reversed ?
So first row is one star, second row is two star, third row is three stars and so on.
That's it for today.