Recursion is a hard topic, so let's do more and more practice, even we are still on a very simple level.
In this practice, we would like to print the triangle, but this time, reversed. actually a more
normal way,
So a triangle of five levels is one stars, two stars, three stars, four stars, five stars.
The problem here is in the recursion semantic.
Like we know that a triangle of five levels is the same as printing five stars, followed by
a triangle of four levels.
But this looks like this time as we are printing from bottom to up,
which makes it not intuitive this time.
So how can we do it?
We do it with a very simple trick.
The trick is to swap the printing call with the printing loop here, specifically,
let's see the following.
If, let's go back to the logic,
If I would like to print a triangle of 5 stars, you should first print a triangle of four
levels, then print five stars.
Remember in the last time the logic was print five stars, then print triangle of four levels.
This time we want to say print a triangle of four levels, then print five stars.
So this is how we do the logic, you call print(5), which says initially print four.
So the logic here is print(5) is asking print(4) to print four levels and after the four
levels are done, you are going to print a fifth level. One more time,
We as experienced programmers, we do not in reality keep tracing the recursion 'till the last moment.
We don't do that.
We think like think in recursion, one step only.
So here is the logic.
What is print_triangles supposed to do? print_triangle()
is a function that takes levels and the prints a triangle incrementally, row by row, here,
so if I asked here to five, it's going to print five.
This is the logic of the recursive function, here,
I see here a recursive call,
I don't go in practice and trace it, I ask myself what this function should eventually do?
print triangle of levels - 1, eventually,
should print, given that level as 5, should print a triangle of four levels.
Now I ask myself if four levels are already printed, what I should do, I should do one loop to print
five stars.
Remember this method of tracing in practice so that you don't get lost like others
in tracing recursion. In all cases,
I still would like to show you how this function is going to work, like, as a compiler wise.
So the compiler is going to call print(5),
surprisingly, print...(5), just call print...(4),
call print...(3)
print...(3), call print...(2), print...(2) call print...(1), print...(1) call print...(0)
So far, nothing is printed on the screen.
once print...(0) is done we print one star, using print_triangle(1).
Then we print two stars using print_triangle(2).
Then we print three stars using print_triangle(3).
Then we print four stars using print_triangle(4), then we print five starts using
print_triangle(5).
I would say this kind of tracing causes more confusing than actually your mind can
afford.
That's why in practice we don't do this kind of tracing.
We trace only a recursive call once and we then ask ourselves what is the meaning and the final output
of this recursive function.
If we can build over it, we guarantee the correctness of this recursive function.
That's it.