One more practice on recursive functions.
There is an interesting thing that is named 3n+1 sequence, this 3n+1 is as
following, you start from some number n,
if this number is even, the next number in the sequence, is n divided by two.
If this number is odd, the next number in the sequence is 3 * n + 1.
If this number is 1, the end of the sequence. For example, if we started by 5, then five is
odd,
So we multiply by 3 and add 1,
it's now 16, 16 is even; divide by 2, even divide by 2, even divide by 2, even divided by 2.
Now 1, the end of the sequence. Another case, let's start with 6 is even, divide by 2
is 3, odd, 3  * 3 + 1, is 10 divide by 2, 5 * 3 + 1 is 16,
Then we are going to do the same sequence here.
So we would like to print this sequence, starting from a specific number in a recursive way.
But why recursion?
If you looked here, the logic is the same.
You would like to print a sequence and every step is doing the same logic; n divided by
2 or 3n+1.
Definitely, we can do this using a single loop, but let's do it for recursion
For the sake of practice. We are going to call a function with the number 6,
So the function logic should be as following: it is going to print the number,
If we are done like n = 1, we just return.
If the number is even, we call the same function divided by 2.
If the number is odd,
We are calling 3n + 1.
So let's trace. Here,
the first call to 6 is going to print 6, and then call recursively  with 6/2, which is 3. print
3, then call recursively 3 * 3 + 1 which is 10.
Print 10 and call with 10/2, which is 5 multiplied by 3 + 1 which
is 16.
Divide by 2, divide by 2, divide by 2, and 1 just end it. In a similar way,
as I said more than once, the way that we think of it is much simpler,
You tell yourself what does the function do?
It's supposed to print the 3n+1 sequence.
Then you just verify, you are done with it.
I would say here, I'm going to trace one case for the even and trace one case for the odd and then
stop from here.
If I did these two cases correctly
in tracing, I'm sure that I covered the even and odd cases.
I don't need to trace it anymore.
But anyway, for a beginner, it still makes sense to do more tracing.
'till your mind be a recursive mind.
It takes time to be good in recursion.
And all of the recursion that I'm offering in this section is basic recursion.
In future, we might discuss more. That's it.