Homework set number one for recursive functions.
First, I would like you to compute the length of 3n+1 sequence.
So the final function (int length_3n_plus_1), takes integer n and tells us the length of the
sequence.
For example, if we give it 6, it's going to give us 9.
Power function, we know how to do the power function in an iterative way, and this one, you are
going to do it in a recursive way.
So (my_pow) should be a recursive function to compute the power of a variable. Array maximum, compute the
maximum of array, using recursion. all of these assignments should be done with recursion. Array sum, compute the sum
of array using recursion.
Array average, compute the average of the array using the recursive function, please don't compute the sum
and just divide by the length in the main.
Let the function by itself handle the average. Array increment, you are to increment each array of
'i' with 'i' for example, if the input is 1, 2, 5, 9, then the new array should be 1 + 0,
2 + 1, 5 + 2, 9 + 3,
So position 'i' is incremented
with 'i'.
So this is the output of the array. Array accumulation, accumulation is popular processing step that we
need, which means that the position at any array, is the sum of all numbers from 0 to 'i'.
For example, if you have the numbers, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, then the position 4
would be the sum for the number from 1, 2, 3, 4.
If you are 6 and the sum is 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6 and so on.
So the new array is 1, 1 + 2, 1 + 2 + 3, 1 + 2 + 3...and so on.
So every position is a summation of the numbers from 0 to index 'i' and so on.
And this is one more example of it. Left-max, change element at position 'i' to be the maximum of a numbers
from index 0, to the index of 'i', for example, if we are here at position 7, get the maximum
from the position 0 to 7, which is now 7.
So it's 7, here, at 4,
Get the maximum from position 0 'till here, which is still 7 and this one also is still 7.
So this is called Lift-max.
That's it.