It's solve the first recursive homework.
But first, I would like to teach you something,  tell you something. Recursion,
is one of the most hard topics in programming.
You would notice students in the second year and third year of computer science, and they
are complaining about recursive functions.
So if you found difficulties in these lessons or even in the next few years, I would like you to
know that this is the standard.
This is the normal.
After some time, you find yourself, you became pretty good at recursive functions. In the
algorithms
course, you would meet many types of recursion.
Every one of them will give you a lot of hard time.
But at some moment, your mind would be reshaped to be to think code trace in a recursive way, in an
easy way.
So it is a matter of time.
So I would like you to not run away.
It just a matter of time.
You are going to pass with this difficult moment.
There are no shortcuts.
And you will have to pass way.
And it's in about different resources to read from them. Almost
it's going to be the same harder way, maybe from one resource to another that might be better visualization,
but eventually, recursion is going to give you a hard time.
So give yourself the space to that.
The second thing is there are two separate skills in recursion: the tracing skills; your ability to trace
a recursive code.
And coding the recursion by itself. The nice about the
tracing recursion is that I believe my way is pretty nice and it can be very educative.
You might fail to write a recursive code by yourself, but you can easily understand a given recursive
code.
So try to sharpen this skill, tracing recursive code. From it
you can directly move toward being able to write your own recursive codes by yourself.
So all that I'm doing today is not about explaining how I was thinking in the recursion.
I will teach you how to trace it.
And I believe over time, this will sharpen the coding skill by itself.
So let's see.
The first task is the '3n+1'.
We learned how to print the sequence.
Today, we will learn how to get the length of the sequence.
So remember, the rule of tracing is as following
and it's based on induction.
You tell yourself, what does this function
do? You tell yourself
What does this function do?
And every time you see it in the recursive call, you don't keep tracing it.
You don't keep tracing it.
So the logic is as follows.
Let's say we have
length 3n+1  of six.
So the function here is 3n of six.
Is it one? No. Is it even?
Yes.
OK.
What is the answer of one plus length of three?
You don't keep tracing length of three.
We can do that.
But this is a big waste of time and a big source of confusion.
You start to think in a recursive way.
If the function is correct, then this call is correct.
What is the length of three? something.
Let's say I forgot.
Length of three is what?
Three is odd.
So let me write the sequence here.
I forgot it here.
So three is odd,  three should be multiplied by three, then plus one it will be 10.
Then it's odd.
Then we divide by two.
It's five.
Then it would be 16, eight, four, two, one.
And we started by six, right.
Yeah.
Six.
So one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine the overall sequence six is nine.
Now, the question here, what is the lenght of three?
The length of three is eight.
So the function would say I am one plus
the length of the sequence from eight, which is nine.
We are done.
The tracing is done.
Now, is this could completely correct?
We are not sure yet.
Why?
Because we didn't trace this part of the code at the moment.
So here is a tip.
If the function has, say, four recursive calls, your function is completely correct
if you trace the different examples such that you reach all of the four different calls.
So at the moment, we implemented, we traced something that gets us here.
But we never traced at this moment.
So we need another example to make sure that we reach this part, which example? maybe five.
So let's start with five, is five equal one? No. Is five even? No. Then one plus the length of three
times five plus one, which is 16.
Now, what does the length of 16? Don't they trace it.
The length of 16 is two, four, five numbers, then one plus five is six.
So this means that the length of six is...,
is six. the length of five is six.
That's all.
You don't keep tracing, tracing, tracing, and then you feel that you are confused and you don't know
what you are doing.
Don't do that.
If you traced every recursive call and you came closer to every return
function once, then you are sure that this function is correct.
I hope you now understand the tracing of this function, we are done with it.
We are done without keeping, tracing, tracing, and tracing.