The next function is the power function, which like a value of power, and we just would like to repeat something
many times, we definitely can do that in a trivial way with a single loop.
But
for educative purposes, we would like to implement this function.
What is the base case here?
The base case comes from the power.
If the power equals zero, then  the answer is one.
So this is mainly your base case.
Let's see how to implement that.
The function is very trivial as following.
You tell yourself if the base equals zero, return one.
So we are done with the base.
Then you say I am value times my power of the value and 'p-1'.
It's trace.
Let's trace my power of seven and three.
Uh.
Let's go.
Is power equal equal zero?
No, the power is one, then it says seven times my power of
seven and two.
So now we will not trace this function.
What is power seven times or to power two?
It is not seven times seven, which is 49.
So it is the result now is 7 times 49, which is correct.
We are done with tracing the function.
Nothing more than that.
If we access every return statement and we trace the every recursive call, then the function by induction
must be correct.
Let's see what is the third function. Array maximum; we have here a bunch of examples that were all very
similar.
So the  array maximum is you are given an array and the length and you would like to compute the maximum.
So let's see.
The function is doing the following.
First, let's first investigate the function, we have one return statement here
we need to trace it.
We have another one return statement here.
We trace it.
We have a recursive call here
We must trace it. If it happened that we trace every single line of code in the code,
we are done.
OK.
If it had been that we traced every single line of code in the function, we are done.
Now let's say let's trace array of 5.
I say its length ==1?
No, just a single 5.
Is this a good base case?
Yes.
So the base case is done. Now,
the second thi ng it says as following: compute the array maximum of array and the first of four elements.
Should I trace it?
No.
Don't get inside that recursively.
Ask yourself what is array maximum of array and
first four elements?
The logic of the function should to compute the maximum of all of them.
So what we should do is we compute the maximum of all of them, which is 10 by our eyes, by our logic.
So sub_result will be 10.
And then it will compute the maximum of 10
and 3, which is still 10.
So the logic of this function was as following.
If we computed the maximum of the early elements, then I take the result of this maximum and maximize
with myself, we are done with the function.
OK.
I hope it's now clear for you.
Let's see.
You use another example.
Let's say that it was like that five and four here.
Now let's trace. Length equal one?
Yes.
No.
Now compute the maximum of the first three elements.
You don't trace that.
What is the maximum of the first three elements?
Eight.
Then it says maximum of eight
and the ten, which is the last element in the array, which is 10
and the return it.
We are done with tracing the recursive function.
You do nothing more than that.
So all of it is about what does this function do? the following and then apply it here on the recursive
call without recursively tracing your code.
This is the second function.
Now would like to get the "Array sum", if you understand this one,
the logic is going to be exactly the same.
We will get that sum of the first n minus one elements.
Then we would like to add the current sum.
And the base case is just to return to the first element.
This is exactly the same code structure.
Then the average, the average is very similar to the sum.
But it has one little math trick.
Let's see.
Now, I would like to get the average of these five numbers.
I will tell here, please find the average of the first four numbers.
What is the average of the first four numbers?
It is 1+
8 +2+10 over 4.
Now, I would like to get the average of the five numbers.
So the first thing is I will multiply it by length minus one, which is four.
When I multiplied by four,
the sub result would be only 1, 8, 2, 10.
Then I add the current number, which is three.
Then I divide by five.
So the moral of this multiplication is to convert the average to sum, OK.
So the function returns for us sum over length minus one.
By definition, when I multiply by minus one, I get back the sum, the sum of the previous array.
Then I add the current element.
I get the current sum, then I divide by length.
So as you see, what makes the function easy is the logic, the logic that we try to trace something
without going deeper in its meaning.
I didn't say
and what is that average
and keep the tracking of length minus one, and length minus two and all of this waste of time.
I thought to myself, what is the return from here?
It is the average.
OK, but I need now a different average.
OK, get rid of that denominator.
Add your value.
Compute your new denominator.
We are done.
"Array Increment", a very similar logic.
So what do we have here?
I have a function that say if length equals zero, do nothing.
Why?
Because we will not increment.
So we are done.
I would first tell it to increment the array of length minus one.
And then add the current length minus one, length minus one.
What does it mean?
Let's see.
First of all, we know that the array increment is incrementing the I th position of
every one.
So I am incrementing here, zero one, two, three, four.
Let's call this array with this five.
It will come here and say, hey, increment for me this array with length four. When I call this function
with length four what is the output of this statement?
I do not trace
again, the output will be adding zero here
one, two, three.
So the return array will be, or the updated array will be   one, nine, four,
I think how..., it would 13 may be.
Yeah, 13.
Now the array is handed for the first  length minus one number.
What I need to add now? I need to add for the current index the length minus one value, which
is length of five; length minus one is four, three and four is seven.
So again, as you see, exactly the same logic.
After that, we have the accumulated array, which is as following. You will add the current
value to the previous accumulation.
This is very similar to the power function we implemented before.
So the idea is as follows.
Let's say you would like to get the sum here.
And instead of trying to competed by yourself for this way, the idea is simple.
What if I accumulated the older array?
What I will have? I would have 1, 3, 6,
and 10. If I added the 5to the 10, I get the 15.
If I added the 6 to the 15, I get 21.
So we don't have to go and do it this way.
I can just utilize the previous submission.
So here in the example I do the following.
I, first of all, tell it, hey, accumulate for me the first length  minus one numbers, OK, which will
take that 1, 8, 2, and 10 and compute the accumulation, which is going to be one and eight is nine
and two will be 11 and the 10 will be twenty one.
Now, I would like to add my current step, and I would like to get my accumulation without making
any for loops.
All what I need is to get the previous element, which is 21, and add my current value to it, which
is three.
So 21 and three is twenty four.
You see, the implementation is trivial when you start to think in a recursive way, you tell yourself,
hey, go ahead and do this step.
Then we accumulated this array.
Then all what we need now is handling this one, utilizing what we did before.
So,
that simple, nothing more than that.
I know when I say that simple, it looks like trivial for me.
I know it takes a lot of amount of thinking from you.
But I'm trying to show you that you shouldn't overthink during the tracing of recursion.
You shouldn't.
And this will make your life much easier.
The last function here is the Left-Max function.
So we would like to compute the left max function of what we are doing in a very similar way.
You ask yourself, hey, go and do left-max of my left side.
Now, what is my current left-max?
It is the left side of me; maximum between my left side and the current side   .
So here in the left-max, you ask the left max of the early numbers.
Then your position would be the maximum between the current value and array of length minus two, which
is the left-max from the previous one.
Let's trace here.
Let's say that we computed .., asked left- max of the first four numbers.
OK, we will now compute it by hand, not by the code, which is going to be one then eight then eight
then 10.
Now, this is a result of the first four numbers.
We don't know how it was calculated is it is just done for us.
All what we need now for the current position is maximum between three and the 10, which is maximum
between the current position and the previous element.
That's all.
As you see, tracing the recursion
isn't that hard. If you understand that,
it's all about induction.
It is all about having a correct base case and having a correct recurrence.
How to make sure that we have over all a recurrence?
Make sure that you trace every line of code only a single time.
Nothing more than that.
That's all.