The set number 2 in the recursive functions for the homework includes some of the medium and hard problems.
The first one is Right-max, close to the Left-max problem,
But now we are doing it from right to left.
For example, the position at 5 here is taking the maximum from here, this position till the end
of the array.
I would like you to introduce a new parameter to be helpful for
You, "int start_position", use it to help you implement this task.
Suffix sum, you are to sum only the last elements of an array, for example, if this is an array
and you would like the last three numbers, then you need to sum 4 and 6 and 7.
I'm not going to tell you how to define the function this time,
Define its signature by yourself.
Prefix sum is the same concept,
but this time you are summing the first three numbers, 1, 3, 4. Is Palindrome, define a
function that takes an array and tells us if it is palindrome or not.
Is prefix, you take a string main, and a string prefix, this is a helpful variable for you,
and also check if is prefix or not.
Tracing, I would like you to read this code, you shouldn't run the code, by your tracing
tell us what does this function really do?
And I would like also to answer another question,
What happened if we switched line 7 with line 6,
what is the output of that?. Counting primes,
I would like you to give a start and an end to count how many primes between start and end, inclusive,
you shouldn't use loops at all.
So if I give you 10 and 20, there are 4 primes only between them.
There is also an interesting question,
Can you compute answer for range ten to this
Five millions or not?
Grid sum, there is a robot starting in a 2D array at position (0, 0) can only move to the right
or left or diagonal.
It will select the one with the maximum value like we did before.
I would like you to print the total path sum of this robot.
So define a recursive function (int path_sum),
It takes a 2d array and the current row and current column and the maximum row and the maximum column.
You should call this function definitely with (0, 0).
The robot is starting here at one is going to go 10 as a maximum, then going to 11 as a maximum
and then 9 as a maximum.
Fibonacci, Fibonacci is a sequence that we saw several times where every position is the summation of
the two previous summations, so Fibonacci can be written recursively as following: Fibonacci(n) =
fibonacci(n - 1) + fibonacci(n-2).
There is a very unique property in this problem
Comparing to all the homework and the practice, this is the first time you have to make two calls to
the recursive function.
Before that, you have to make only one call like (print_
triangle) of Level five is calling (print_Triangle) of level 4. but Fibonacci(n) needs a summation like
here 13, 13 is Fibonacci of this guy and this guy,
So it's the two previous before it, anyway,
code it.
Can you compute fibonacci(40)?
Can you compute fibonacci(50)? why?
Think about it.
That's it.