In this project, we will implement a simple version from Expedia, that website, so as you know,
the website is something that allow you to reserva flights, to reserve hotels, to reserve workers,
vacation packages that include a mix of all of that cruises and so on.
So you create an itinerary, itinerary and activity to come, which could be very complicated, for
example, which you can have several itineraries.
And each itinerary can consist of, say, two flights or four flights to OTES two cars and so on.
You can define very big, very big reservation or very big package.
OK, for now, for our first minimal viable product, something very simple.
Consider only two things.
Flights.
One way or transit and audience.
But remember that in reality we can have all of this bunch of choices.
So make a design that be very extensible and itinerary item can be the following.
Let's say its flight or hotel.
It would have its own cost.
And also it has some information, let's say that if you have a flight, it could have a request from
the selected flight and so on in an audit.
It can be the cost to be the total nice time, the price per night.
I would like to think about that in terms of logic, what might be the different logical items for a
flight for and for a OTRANTO on?
The total cost of it is the sum of every internal cost to have flight with one thousand dollars.
Another flight was five hundred dollars and hotel booking with one thousand dollars.
Then the total is two thousand five hundred dollars for simplicity in this project, do not use the
project is big enough and also use the mydata when convenient.
There are two types of of of users here, the admin and customer, but focus only on the customer part
in the bin.
Here is the here is the interface of the user.
The user would see something that allow him to log in or sign up.
When you say login was one, you exit the user, you start to say hello, the name and then user view.
Then you are allowed to view your profile, make an itinerary or list all your current ones or logout.
Let's let's make an itinerary.
It allows you here to add a flight or at a hotel or you are done.
So we can keep adding things like add a fly, then fly the no fly then and until then and until then
I am done this how you are making itinerary of several items.
So we are not telling him we would like to add an item here.
It's telling me
enter number and range one to four.
We say until then it started to say,
I got confused.
Sorry, we are here, we are here adding a flight number one.
It says from then which date.
To which date and then says how many others, how many children, how many infants you are providing
all of them together.
And after when I give all of this information, it lists it for me for flights to on Turkish Airlines
and to on on Air Canada lines.
So these are the information on your select one of one one out of four of these three trips.
So I selected this third line.
This data is Adami Data and creating in the project to make it easier for me.
So I selected the third the choice here, which is two hundred dollar trip.
Going back to the Choices menu, I said I would like to add an item.
So adding an order it say from date
this should be to date, not from date, and then saying the country and the city and adults and children.
So this is the input of my hotel reservation.
They are listed for me, all of these six choices for Ottens.
Also, this is the mydata and here, let's say interior view, six available units, the price per night
and the from to this, I made the choice of choice number four, which is this Marriott Hotel.
One, two, three, four.
Yes.
This Marriott Hotel, which costs 320 bed a single night.
Again, going back to the menu, I said, I'm done so so far, I added one flight and one autumn.
What I'm going to say which option today is a debit card or credit card I selected here, my debit card.
Then let's say here the money withdrawn successfully, reservation confirmed and itinerary resurvey.
This means that we are actually managed to reserve the flight and the hotel and we also managed to to
be the money for you from your bank accounts.
If I back to the top menu and say here list of my itinerary is going to list, the first one is the
preservation of the airline.
It is a reservation for the hotel.
It is the total cost of my reservation.
Now, there is a function requirements here about the FBI.
We discussed this before and we had some homework.
So it's now we're going to use it here, which is that Expedia as a website.
He knew nothing about the flights and the course, the details.
He doesn't have a database of that.
What happens in reality?
Expedia is going to contact the FBI is of the flights and all the hotels to get the information.
So we as developers, we typically visit their sites, check and check out their eyes and see what's
available to call it remotely.
Expedia, also Web site, would like to allow one payment strategy.
There are many, many payments in the eyes.
But but typically you have only a single one that's activated in your system.
So we are contacting separately eyes for the flights, but only a single eye for the payments.
At the moment.
Our system will have to support the systems, but just one of them will be active in usage.
Assume for simplicity that we have local ice to cool.
Yeah, just just you don't have to make really remote.
This is outside of the scope.
Just consider them locally.
Buy something that you are going to call.
When we investigated the FBI for the Air Canada FBI, we find some here, some customer info class.
We found the flight information like from and to the price and then the you go to get flights to get
vector of Air Canada flights you provide here it is in the function.
As you see, I'm sitting here some dummy data.
There is a function that they serve with the flight.
It takes the flight and the customer information retrieval.
So I'm assuming that this is going to just return true for now and also you can cancel it.
So, again, just consistent with the rule for the Turkish flight just now, they have also their own
API, which was their own naming.
For example, you can hear the function here are static discovered function.
You create an object.
And you said this kind of information, this is the available function.
It's just returning the flight here for the hotels in the Hilton room.
It has a struct for little room with the details of the room.
That function is static for searching the room.
It takes this information that the static data and return to them for the Marriott.
One would also had that it was static function function.
That takes some parameters, but they aren't necessarily in the same order embedding Marriott rooms
and returning it for us.
As you see multiple flights in the eyes, multiple authors eyes, they share similar things, but they
are using their own definitions.
For the payments, when you look to the people, we found that they have bibel credit card information
here and they have here like sit in and make payment, you pay money, you get that money and so on.
For the these guys here, they are using JSON information, so not the following.
They have this user info card info.
So far so good.
They have sort of these guys have a normal withdraw function that takes the money for you and return
it.
But the guys from the square, Ippei, which will have to support, also are taking just one query.
So they just don't they just think, where is something like that?
So this guy is taking the information here in his trucks.
But this guy would like a stringer that represented your son and you have to pass that adjustment to
get back the there's just an object information.
So thinking it needed business logic, let's say I created an itinerary of two flights and two cars.
I ask it to be and then we manage to confirm it the first flight and the first item, but then we fail
to reserve with the next flight.
In reality, what happens to us following one scenario is that Expedia is going to cancel your first
flight, cancel your first cancel its abatement, and then we cancel the flight and the hotel and cancel
the payment until you.
So the moral of that, if it's having a problem in the middle of the of an itinerary, we should cancel
all of what happened so far.
I would like you to think of what you're missing in the logic, in the eyes and whatever.
And this project is a huge space of polymorphism and zany choices.
So think twice.
My optimize school is like one thousand five hundred with some dummy data.
You will definitely go beyond that.
This is totally OK.
That's it.