In this section, we will learn the "STL" or the Standard Template Library. Every strong programming language
like C++, Java, C#, and so on, would have something that allows you to make use of the available
data structures and algorithms.
But let's first try to motivate that a little bit more. So in computer science,
I view the fundamentals in two layers, in the first layer we have four things: programming, algorithms,
data structures and OOP, this course is mainly about programming and in its first half and OOP
in its second half and design.
There are also two things:
the algorithms and data structures,
algorithms are very computational problems like think about sorting a few numbers, during the first part
of the course
you were already exposed to many computational problems like you have an array of n the numbers,
find the three numbers of sum X.
This will require a lot of competition.
So you already are exposed to algorithms.
You are also exposed implicitly to the data structures,
and this is what you will see right now in the queue example.
As a side note, there are more fundamentals in computer science, like your next step would be software
engineering, design patterns, databases, operating systems and networking, and in any strong software
engineering you will meet in your career is to a good extent, very good in these fundamentals.
Anyway, let's go back to our topic.
So the queue data structure that we used before in the hospital when we wanted to add in the front end
and the end and print, that was, if you remember it internally, had an array and just supported
to adjust to the array to do these functionalities for us.
So now thinking that in many cases we would need to organize and process and retrieve data in very specific
ways, something similar to the queue. Thinking about the queue,
this is a very repetitive task,
we will need it over and over.
So it is the STL here comes to save our time and say: okay I'm going to implement to the queue for
you.
So this is why we have STL, these classes that support some data and operations
on this data.
we call them data structures.
Okay, that's why we have the word data-structure, they arrange the date somehow
and they provide a lot of functionalities relevant to this data.
And as I said, in practice, the structures a lot.
So STL comes and provides us with a bunch of containers to implement these data structures.
In a typical basic data structure course, you will learn something called
queue, dequeue, vector,
linked list, binary search tree, in more advanced sense you might learn something like hash table
balanced binary search tree, or even sometimes, trie and segment tree.
So the STL is just implemented it for you
All of these data structures in really in a very efficient way.
They call them containers.
And interesting thing about learning STL early is they are actually the black box of these
data structures,
so when you go to really study the structure course itself, you find like you already
know about how to use them and just now how to make their internals.
The C++ is using templates which allow it to be very generic containers,
So you, for example, laterally you will see us defining a queue of integer or queue of string or a queue
of employees and so on.
And without templates, you will have to make a queue for integer, another class queue for strings and
another class queue for employees and so on, which is impractical,
so templates would help a lot us with that.
Also, the language provides us with something named iterators. iterators help us in a very generic way to
iterate on the containers,
so the algorithms this way would be independent of the data types using templates and also the iterators
would be independent of the container itself using algorithms.
This a bit puzzled at this moment, but this would be clarified more in the next videos.
Thank you.