One of the interesting features in C++11 is the range-based for loop.
This isn't an STL topic, It is more of an iterating style
but you see its power really when it comes to STL. Before the looping style, I would like first
to introduce also something in C++11 that makes our life much easier.
So when you define an integer X equals 10, You are defining the data type of X by yourself.
Now, In C++ also the auto keyword can deduce for us the data type.
So let's say I wrote x2 equal 10 so we can see that 10 here must be an integer.
So auto would be resolved automatically to an integer, 10.0  would be resolved automatically
to double.
If you have double quotes this way, It will be automatically resolved to a string.
This is the best way.
This is like we are dealing as in the STL, as you will see, with complex data types.
You can just put it here auto
so it's going to make your life much easier.
Also, there will be no wrong conversion,
for example, if you wrote here integer X equal 10.0, there is a conversion from double to an integer.
So there is no conversion here.
It makes your code also clean.
There are more details specifically in C++ 14 and 17
but I would like to keep it as simple as that right now.
So now going to the iterating style, I would like first to show you that this iterating
style is by itself available even for the arrays.
So, let's say we define an array of three items, 1, 2, 3, so we can do the syntax as follows:
We can say for, int-val or auto-
val, colon, the something that we would like to iterate and just close it.
So now, notes this is a for loop that has two components only with a colon in middle.
So, on the right side, you write the data type. On the left side, you write the type of the element.
You can write here int val.
You can write whatever data type that you would like to access.
And then you cout val, which is val.
So automatically what happened here is the C++ is going to start with the first element, move to the second
element, to the third element and so on.
Let's try it on STL.
So here is a definition of the dequeue of five elements.
We saw different iterating styles
but look to that,
this is one of the best ones. I can say for, say const, auto, reference
val, colon,
queue, then this is going to iterate on the queue one by one element.
You can even have a C++ initializer list here, and then you start to iterate on it.
Remember a string is just something that we can iterate it letter by letter, so we can again iterate here to print
its letters, a letter by letter.
So, what do we write here on the left side exactly?
It is up to you, but it should be something of the data type of.
queue. Typically one of the best ways is to use auto because just automatically resolving this type.
Otherwise, if you would like here, it should be character-val and here it should be an integer-val.
If you would like it to be by copy, so you should just use auto-val. If you would
like it to be by reference and this is more efficient, you should write with reference,
but be careful if you updated here
this val, the array would not be updated, but if you updated here this file, the queue would be updated.
If you used const, it just means that no one is expected to change this val.
So, this is the most preferred way to iterate on a queue as long as you don't need to change the value
itself. In the next times, you will see more complex usage for range-based for loop that's it.