So one of the most important data structures in stl is vector, and we could say that this is the one
that you're going to use really very frequently.
The idea of the vector is to act like an array.
But the point is it's more dynamic, typically an array is fixed,
Like if you define an array of hundred elements just 100 elements, it will not be expanded.
But the idea behind the vector that it acts like an array but also can grow up in a very good way,
so, here we do find an initial vector,
this vector is now is an empty vector,
it doesn't have any kind of numbers,
so, one way is you can start to push back numbers.
If you started to push back 30, 10, 20, it just go in the normal order.
So one interesting thing about the vectors, you can print to them like an array,
so if you asked v1.size, it returns three elements,
now, 3, 10, 20, you can just iterate and print it, in the future we will go into details
but whenever you are calling the size of one of the data structures, it's highly better to custom
them to integrate or so, and be very careful about subtracting some number from here.
This is good as long as your vector is really has like a very, very, very huge numbers, which is
a very rare thing.
So in a way, notice here the first wey of printing vectors,
it goes as normal as the normal array printing.
So so far, we have an array of three elements,
there is another way that we can define
we can build a vector, we define a vector of length 5 and initial value is 7,
so so far that has five numbers
each one of them is seven.
Now we are adding a 6 element,
so now it will be six numbers,
If we tried to print, it will be like five sevens then six.
And here we are just printing in a different way,
This is a recommended way to print or access the vector as long as you need maybe some index here.
OK, so there is also like the queue, like the deque, there is a good add method which is support
for you exception
if it happened that you access something out of bounder, there is something that involves a lot of complications,
the emplace back, it's something similar to the push back more of performance concerns,
but we will discuss this a bit later,
So for now, you can define an array, an empty, push_back, or you can even create with some size and start
to push back.
OK, so let's go more here is a simple exercise, we would like to, we have an initial array,
initialized at list, I would like to remove all of the negative values from it,
one of the things to be careful with them is to be careful from removing items from a data
structure during iterating over it,
If you want to do that, you just have to do it in a careful way,
so I would like to show you an exercise on how to do that.
I'm here iterating in a different way on the iterator with the v.begin - v.end and I put ++
So we would a number, notice here, I didn't put the it++ here,
so we go using the iterator and then we ask, we get the *it, so we get the actual value,
Is it less than zero?
If so, I would like to remove it,
So we have the iterator so we say v.earse(it),
OK, one of the important things to keep in mind is this
it would be, the iterator, would be invalidated after the call, so a new iterator would be returned,
so sometimes in some cases and some of data structures, you will notice that you didn't put the assignment,
but this is very risky,
It might depend on the implementation or whatever or be specific data structure
So the advice is if the erase function is returning an iterator, you have to use it
OK, now the question is, if it has been used, what is its return and what is the value? here
you will notice that it points to the next element,
okay, so if the number wasn't negative, then we would back to the next element,
but if we removed it, already, the returned value is looking to the next element,
so we don't need to increment it,
and then if we try to print it again, it is going to print in the normal way.
So again, it's better to avoid removing something from a data structure like Vector during iterating,
but if you'd like to do that, you have to be careful with it.
here is a third way, there is an algorithm that name find, you will know what is an algorithm soon, but it
helps us to search the vector.
So here I am searching the vector for the value minus two.
So I'm giving it the range to search in, it is the   v.begin to the v.end if iterator not equal v.end
it means we found that such a vector.
I would like now to insert a small vector inside this vector,
so we found -2, which will be here,
We are going to insert the small vector 8, 9, 10, add this position here.
so then the new array will be 8, 9, 10 here and then -2 and so on.
So how to do that?
We do that through the insert method.
We give it the iterator where we would like to insert in the v and then we give it the beginning and
end of the vector to be inserted.
A common mistake is to to make some switching to the beginning and end, maybe to use it from the
old vector or so,
so be careful.
This is insert a director of the first vector.
This is what we are going to insert.
So so far we see how to insert and how to erase and how to push back.
I would like to finish that with some notes about how a vector works because this very interesting data
structure, inside the vector, there is actually an array of some initial size
it depends on the implementation.
sometimes 0, sometimes  bigger value,
so let's call it its code capacity
so let's say that there is an integer capacity as an initial value with 200,
now, let's say that you push back 10 elements.
Now, the size of the vector is 10
but the number of elements that you pushed is ten,
but the actual size of the vector in the array in the memory is 200,
you usually deal with these ten, but behind the scenes there is
Now let's say you pushed another one 190 elements
so now you consumed all of the current size which is 200
so the size and capacity is 200, capacity usually greater than or equal to the size
not the whole internal array in memory is complete.
If you try to insert the new 20 elements, the vector has no extra memory space to do that,
so here is the trick,
the vector creates a new array, typically with double size.
not necessarily typically,
so let's say that it's going to define the new capacity with four hundred, it is going to create a new array
with a 400 size then copy the old two hundred numbers, sorry not just 100, the 200 numbers
then add the new 20 elements.
So now what is the current size of the numbers that we had?
What is the chemistry of the vector is 400 the new memory size.
So some performance steps,
First of all, if you know the actual size of the vector, like you say, I know, I'm sure that I am
going to need one million number then through from the beginning create this one million number vector
why? because you will keep pushing back and then it's going to remove all the memory, create new memory,
then pushing back, create, remove, pushing back, create, remove,
So this is would be a big waste of time,
So if you created an area this way is going to make the size from the beginning one million and typically
the capacity too
OK, what if I'm not sure about the number of elements that I would like but I know they are big?
OK, then you can call the function reserve,
the function reserve is going to create capacity with this number, but not the size.
So the size of this vector is zero, but the capacity is five hundred thousand,
again, the both tricks are about you are creating a big initial memory from the beginning
you only need that if you really have like a hundred thousands of data.
This is really where it makes sense. That's it.