Let's know more about the vector, but this time we would like to discuss the 2D vector and the
3D vector.
So, the first interesting thing is: Let's make a vector of string,
this is very intuitive for you.
You make a vector of string, which mostafa, ali, me, that's so far so good,
but remember that each string is actually a 1D array,
so actually we are creating a vector of something that is actually by itself is a 1D array.
So, it looks like a vector of vector,
so it's actually 2D vector.
OK?. So, if you thought about that, as a 2D vector, we actually have a 2D vector of three rows,
but every row has a dynamic number of columns, and this is one of the great things about vectors you can
now have like this dynamic features even row by row.
So, if you try to print matrix of that size, it will get 3.
So, here matrix-dot-size is about the big picture about the number of commas here.
So, the matrix-dot-size is just 3.
This is like the number of rows. If you tried to iterate row by row and say matrix-of-i, dot size,
so matrix-of-i is the ith row, so the ith row size here, 7, 3, 2, which is the number of columns
here.
So make sure that is intuitive for you.
Now, let's go little more complex.
This is defined as a 2D vector of integer by us.
So, here vector of integer, row, 5, coma, 1.
This means that we have 5 values, each is one.
Now, look to this syntax,
We are defining a vector of vector of integer,
What does this mean?
The first vector means we have like a row of numbers and a row of elements,
What is the value of each element?
It is another vector of integer.
OK?. So, we see here vector of vector of integer, v2d, three is the number of rows,
and this is the value of every row,
but the value of a row itself is another row of five numbers,
so it's actually like a matrix 3 times 5.
So, if you tried to print this matrix, it would be like 3
ones, 5 ones, 3 times 5 ones.
Let's check out the printing function. We have here a vector of vector of integer,  v2d to
print. If we did for, auto, row, v2d, then we are iterating on it  now
row by row, Right?
So, every row is actually vector of integer by itself.
Now, let's take the row and iterate over it.
We know
It's actually the row is vector of integer.
So when we iterate over it, It is a vector of just numbers,
so just integers.
So, if you did that, you're going to printed it
row by row. It is very important to feel comfortable with these 2 styles.
So, the way to think about it, I'm having a vector,
so this vector of some items and each item is a vector of integer and so on.
Now, let's do some changes, some lines with that.
First of all, the number of rows and columns, the number of rows of the matrix
can be found from the main vector, vector-dot-size so now we have the number of rows.
The second way to get the columns is here, get inside the first row and execute dot-size,
so you get the columns.
Be careful, make sure that there is at least an element here.
If this is empty, this would crash.
Now, we know the number of rows and the number of columns, what if we would like to manipulate the array?
so we can put the first row here, the first element in it with 9. We can go to the second row
and push 2 values, 5 and 6.
We can go to the third row and erase the beginning of it.
OK?. Notice here, v2d is a vector,
and this is a row,
so when I would like to erase something, put
this (v2d)  as a row.
So when you try to print this, you see here, it is 9.
here it is 5 and 6.
This one lost 1 here.
So now you see we have a 2D dynamic vector, which is very interesting.
Let's complicate things further.
Let's create  a 3D vector.
OK?. So now
here is the logic.
A 3D vector is vector of vector of vector of integer.
So here is how we think it in logic.
I need a 4D vector then vector of vector of vector of integer.
So this is how we define it in a very systematic way,
and then the initialization might be a bit tricky. It is like you define first the number of rows.
( Let's call here the number of depth, rows, columns)
So you define here the depth of the 3D vector, then this is 5, and then every one of them
is 2D vector.
So, you initialize it like a 2D vector of vector of vector of integer of 6, and the row value is a vector
integer and seven.
So this is a 5 times, 6 times, 7 matrix.
This is how you get the values.
If I would like to print it, you can iterate it on depth by depth like depth
step by step.
So, you iterate on v3d dot size, v3d of i is actually a 2D vector
now, you can call it to make a print.
So the syntax isn't easy, but you need to read it several times and think about it.
That's it.