One of the very useful data structures in STL is a string data structure, we already we're using this
data structure from the beginning, but it is actually one of the C++ data structures.
We already know how to initialize it,
how to compare it like equal, equal, less than, greater than, and so on.
So the string, it also has a lot of very several functionalities that we are going to see,
but let me tell you about something that's a bit interesting. You see this weird
hash include.
It includes all the hash includes that you might need.
So, let's say that you wrote something here and it doesn't compile as you are missing the right hash
include. If you use this hash one, the compiler error is going to go.
So this is very useful as you are facing such a compile error. Usually for young guys
I do not advise using it because it much useful for you to know where exactly what like hash include
vector, hash include stack, and so on, but you can feel free to use it if you are in trouble
or something.
Anyway, let's go back to the string and check out what are the other functionalities that we have. Here
we have a string like hi, space, A, B, C, blah, blah, blah.
The sub-str here is a function that gets for you a substring, for example, here
we want to find the substring start from the position 3.
So this is position number 3 in the array,
so it cuts all of that for you.
What if you give it here 5?
... You now have a starting index and ending index, so it gives for you 3, 4, 5.
Notice, this is in length, it's actually starting and ending indices.
You can also search for a string like dot,
find, a, b, c is going to find the first position where ABC appears which is here.
If you say, find ABC from 5 here, it means to start from position 5, which is the 6th character.
So it is going to find starting from here, which is at position 7. What if you are trying to
find something that doesn't exist?
If you try to print that, it's going to give you a very huge number.
If you tried to cast that to integer, it would be minus one.
This is actually something called string, colon, colon, no position (string::npos).
So C++ return for you this variable
when you don't find it.
So you can customize and compare with -1.
but a more professional way is to compare with string::npos.
There are also functionalities that search for a character,
so be careful of that.
When I say find the last of C, A, B, It is going to search for these characters one by one in the string
and for every one of them, It is going to find the last position for it and return it.
So when we say C, A, B, It is going to search where is the last C here, where is the last B here,
where is the last A here.
So C is the last one is going to return it.
So this isn't going to search for the string
CAP, It is going to search for letter by letter,
for C, A and B. In a very similar logic, find the first of
A, I, C.
So you see hi,
so the i is here,
this is the first character that appeared here,
so this is 1.  If you search it set for A, I and C starting from position 4, It is going to give you
the 5th letter here.
The letter here in position five, sorry. In similar logic,
find first not of A ,I ,C, which is here h in the hi.
The high h is the first letter that doesn't appears here.
So again, the find underscore functionalities here are about searching character but don't find
here is searching for a string.
You can also do a replacement. If you say replace from this position this number of characters with
this string,
it could be many characters.
So if position 4 is here at a 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, starting from the B. If you say
replace 3 characters, It would be B and C and A, this three characters would be removed with sub-string
X, it can be X, Y, Z, whatever.
OK, that's it.
There are a lot more functionalities in a string, but I think this would be the most common one
In practice,
I think most of what I use is the dot find and comparing if no position or not,
and also the replacement functionalities. Sub-string also is a useful function. That's it.