Let's practice. In this task, we named a three-stack max sum.
You are giving like a three stack of numbers, a three-stack of different numbers.
For example, we have here A, B, C.
The first setup of numbers is 1, 2, 3, 4, 2, 2, 2, 4, 0, 0, 3, 3, 5.
Remember the stack,
If you would like remove, you remove first the end of it.
The target is we would like to make the sum of all the stacks to be equal.
So you are allowed to remove something from the top of the stack one by one, as you like, but just
remove them from the top.
The target is we need it to be also the maximum equal sum.
So if we looked initially at these three stacks, the sum of that is 10, 10, 11.
They are't equal.
If they are equal, then this is the best.
OK, and remember, all numbers are positive, by the way.
Now, if I would like to make them a bit equal, here is the best way, you can remove from A the top of it,
which is 4, and you can remove from B the top 2, so you remove 4 and 0 and then you remove from
C the top, which is five.
Now the sum of every one of them is 6, 6 and 6,
this is the maximum sum. on the other side,
Let's say that C has 12, not zero here, 12, 3, 3, 5.
Now the maximum sum is zero.
You cannot find a way to make all of them equal except removing and emptying all of them.
So you are to implement a function called max 3 stack sum.
It takes 3 vectors, each vector represent this
stack.
So we are using here a vector because just more convenient in in competitions for you than just a stack.
So think, how can you do that.
So here is the idea, let's first develop a convenient function sum that takes a vector, sum all
of its element and return the sum for us.
Now, when we start the function, we compare the sum of A, the sum of B, the sum of C. After that,
the idea is as following: so you have now 3 stacks,
each one of them has its own sum.
If I would like to make them equal, In a greedy sense, you would think like let's get the stack that
has the biggest sum and removes only one item from its top. This way
step by step, you are trying to figure out if there is a chance for them to be equal or not.
So the procedure is as following:
As long as the 3 stacks aren't an empty.
Your first double-check, if the three stacks are equal, if they are equal, then we are done,
then just return the sum of any of them.
Otherwise, find the stack that has the highest sum and just remove one element from it.
So here we say, Is sum A greater than B and C? If so, remove from A, otherwise from B, otherwise
from C.
So this way, step by step, we are removing from only the highest stack in hope that we can get them
equal.
That's it.