So far, we have discussed a lot of data structures. A data structure is something that provides you
with some member functions and member variables that would help you to achieve some task like queue,
vector, stack, and so on.
There is also a very interesting thing in stl named algorithms.
Algorithms are something that we actually have did with it a lot in its basic format.
When we ask you given an array, find the three numbers with a specific sum, and you
start do three loops or optimize into loops and you notice it is very computational intensive task.
So these are what we call algorithms. An algorithm is a step by step procedure to achieve a specific
goal,
and we usually use it in a context where we have really a computational problem.
One of the very interesting computational problems is sorting.
Let's say I'm giving you an array of 1000 numbers, how to sort it from small to large?
There is actually a bunch of algorithms to do that.
C++  STL in the hash include algorithm
already provide you with a sort function with
one of the best sorting functions. If we have here a vector of 5 numbers that we entered here,
say 10, 9, 8, 7, 6,
and we would like to sort it using STL from small to large. We provide an iterator for the beginning
and iterator for the end.
For example, here I provided the v-dot-begin plus 1, which means that we are here at 9 and
the v-dot-end, so it means we are after the 6.
If we say sort to this range, It is going to sort of from here to here.
So you see 10 as it is,
but then we have 6, 7, 8, 9,
and in a similar way, I can sort the whole array, the whole vector,
so it's now 6, 7, 8, 9, 10.
So this way we are sorting from the beginning to the end.
We can also use the reverse iterator to reverse that.
So now from the end to the beginning — like the last line here.
In addition to that, there is a reverse function. The reverse allows us to just reverse the content
of the array.
If this is the input then
this is now the output.
That's it.
There are many algorithms in C++, but I thought these are the two basic for now to learn about them.