The STL also provides a very powerful and useful data structure named set. The set helps us
to maintain the objects sorted.
Remember, the priority queue when you insert an item is always sorted.
The set is very similar to the priority queue, but it also provides much stronger functionalities.
So we here are defining a set of a string, the set exists in the hash include set.
So we started to insert Ziad, Mustafa, Mustafa, Mustafa, Ali so that it is going to do two things:
First, It is going to remove any duplicates so all of them will be unique.
So if there are three Mustafa, only one of them would be remain. The second, It is going to sort them. If we try to
print to the set, it would print Ali, Mustafa,
and zyad.
So how is it to print a function? It like just the normal for-style like range-based loops to print it
Now,
one of the functionalities in the set is just you can dot count Mustafa to see if it exists or not.
So this is an easy way,
It's a bit slower way.
There is another faster way, you can use the dot find function. The dot-find is going to return an
iterator.
So what is the type of the iterator?
It will be the same as the data structure, set of string, colon, colon, iterator. In C++ 11, you can
just save your time and write auto so that you can just skip all of that.
I like auto because it makes the code sometimes much easier.
If the iterator isn't at the end, then we know it exists,
you can also remove it like say dot erase with the iterator. So you can count is a bit slower but more
convenient,
you can dot find and get the result in an iterator and compare directly with dot-end.
Now, if you try to print here, it's going to be empty.
So this is a set.
There is another thing that called multi-set.
The multi-set is same as set, but it allows duplicates.
So if you inserted 3 Mustafa, It is going to have 3 Mustafa here.
Then again, you can find Mustafa and you can erase it, and  when you erase it,
you will erase one of them.
So you have Mustafa here and another Mustafa here.
So what if I would like to insert objects of type say employee in a set?  We know that if I made
set of integer, it would define them from small to large. string?
It would define them from small to large,
but I'm having my own class.
The issue here is how the C++ is going to order
the struct? Actually, It doesn't know.
So we have to provide a way to compare them.
Here is one way to do that.
The syntax is a bit weird for you at the moment,
We will know that when we study the operator overloading  topic.
So you provide syntax as following: bool operator, less than,
then you give an object name like const, employee, right-hand side and make it const function.
So you always write this line and just change here the class name.
So you are comparing the internal variables here with the variables of this one.
You are to return
true if the of the employee's local objects, this operator here, is less than the right-hand side
information here.
So again, if you would like to use a set of employee, you have to write all of this line. For your
own class, remove this employee and write your own class name.
Return true only if the current object is less than the send object to be compared.
Now, here I'm using some logic to compare 2 integers in one variable.
There are like different ways to do it.
So one way like as we did before, you can compare first with  not equal, if name number 1 is not
equal number 2, then you are returning based on this one.
If they are equal, you move to the second feature. If not equal then you return based on that, otherwise you
return the final segment.
This is how you should structure it as logic.
You can actually do it in an easier way.
Let's say you would like to use the pair that we learned. So I can do it as following:
I can create a pair of item on another pair of item.
So this way I'm creating a big pair for my 3 variables and I can also create a pair for the
other 3 variables,
Then I can compare both of them
normally. The standard way to use is it can be using the std- tie.
You can tie the 3 variables in the order that you wish.
So we would like to compare in order
number 1, then str 1,
number 2 with the object
num1, str, and num2. The tie is the easiest way and the one that is this roll
but I'm just showing you the logic of doing that.
So here is a set of employees,
we have inserted the employees for Mustafa, Ali, Ziad, and Mustafa.
Then we did an auto loop to print.
So it printed for us here based on our sorting criteria.
So if you defined your own struct to use it with set, you may need to provide the operator
less than function. That's it.