Similar to the C++ set, there is also a recent data structure, the unordered set. The unordered set from
its name is very similar to the set, but it doesn't order the elements for us, so...
they aren't sorted for us.
So he redefined the unordered set and we started an initial set of an unordered set with these bunch of numbers,
then we also inserted 2 numbers.
Then, let's use the auto range-based for loops to iterate and print it.
There are 2 observations.
First, they are unsorted. Second, if there are duplicate numbers, they are removed.
That's it.
So let's search for a number in the unordered set.
So here is s1, dot-find. When you give it any value, It is going to give you the iterator value. You can
print it also.
Now, let's try to change the value, C++ compiler will complain.
So this is one more feature about the unordered. You cannot change the values once they are inserted.
The only way that you can do it, you can insert or erase it.
So if I would like to change the value, the right way is you find it, remove it and insert a new one.
Now, I would like to tell you a track with a note that most people don't realize. If I would
like to find an element here in an unordered set or even in many other things,
there are 2 ways.
The first is to call dot-find in the data structure.
The second way, as in the algorithms videos, you know, there is also find a generic one that you
can give it begin and end and value and you find it.
Now, some people do notice that the performance of this find function is very different than the performance
of this fine function.
Specifically, this find-function considers how an unordered set is implemented internally.
So it's typically very fast.
But this find function is generic,
It uses a generic iterator to iterate item by item,
and this is one of the key differences for people who understand how really STL is working from
the inside.
So the more of the advice is as following:
If your data structure is supporting a function by itself, then you have to use it directly,
Just go ahead and use it.
It would be very efficient, only if the function isn't available in your data structure.
You can try to use the generic function then the generic function
Know nothing about the internals of your data structure,
and this is key property in STL, It is very generic.
This generic once with the iterators and a general way for iterating items, and generic once from data types
of prospectives.
So this is intended.
So something like finds here, the general one is generic, so it doesn't know what's happening inside
this data structure.
Finally, you can also get the size, and you can erase also an element from the set.
I would like also to tell you about another thing which are actually more common with other data structures.
Let's say you have an array here.
You can initialize your unordered set using this array, like you defined here, and you give it an array
and array plus 3.
So it's very similar logic to the iterators arithmetic.
When we learn pointers, you should have more sense of why this is a valid syntax.
You can also do some swapping operations.
Let's say you have s1 and s2. To an unordered set, you can swap their content.
This is same for many other data structures also.
You can also initialize another data structure from a data structure like, let's say you have a sorted
set,
and I would like it to be initialized from this array or from this unordered set.
You can just give it the beginning and end. Some final notes,
There is no reverse iterator
in the unordered set, because it doesn't make sense, the items in a way don't order.
There is also an unordered multi-set, very similar to the set and multi-set relationship.
The multi-set just allows you to have duplicate operations.
Here is a very interesting thing to know about an unordered set is that unordered
is very fast compared to the set, to the map, and to compare to the erase and find in the
vector and all of these things.  unordered set
is really very fast.
Why? It is internally built based on something named hash table. Hash table isn't a straightforward structure.
When you study a data structure course, you have to learn it because we use it very efficiently,
and you will know why this one is working fast and also will know how to use it in a more
stronger way,
like you have to know hash tables very well to know how to use effectively something like an unordered
set. That's it.