The map is one of the very useful and interesting data structures.
So remember, when you would like to access an array, we access with some index like an index of zero,  index of
1, index of 2 and so on, in the array.
What if I would like to access the index with something more complex?
What if I would like to access with double, with string, and so on.
This is where a map would come to help.
So a map of string and integer is how we define a map.
It looks like very close to the pair definition.
You define a map and you say it would be a map from string and integer here.
So the string here means this is the key, and int this is the value. In an array,
the key is typically an index,
The value could be whatever.
If you define double numbers array, then you can access any value here.
So it would be here like double, but this is more of the index.
Now, let's access the map.
You start to access a very normal array.
You say a map of the index equals 10.
In normal case, you say array of zero, array of 1, array of  2,
but here we say that the key would be of type string and then you provide different keys and assign
different values.
So it looks like in reality something like that.
The key can be like key3, key1, key4, key2, and you start to put your own values.
So this is how we really a map is defined.
So you can think of it as a generalization to the array.
Let's print the map.
So one of the things to notice here when we go to print it, it would print to Mustafa-40, Saad-20,
Mustafa-30.
So what was input here?
We have Mustafa-10, then saad, then Mustafa again with 30.
So think of it as an array.
So the first array value was 10 then we override with 30,
while here another value Mustafa with M capital as Mustafa small and capital are different things.
So we have two different entries for it. To some extent also
but we don't count on that,
they might be
looks like they are ordered here.
What else?
Yeah, let's check out the printing function. We are passing here the map with the reference,
so we are looking to the same copy in the memory.
Const means we will not change it,
we promised to do that. So we can iterate it like just normal iterating,
but the question here, what is the single item if we are iterating
on a vector, on a queue ( we know that we are iterating with integers ),
but what are we iterating here?
The map internally has a pair for every item that it can provide it with you.
So a map of a string of int will have a pair of string and int as an item.
So this is how you iterate on it.
You see item dot first, item dot second. The dot first give you the key and the dot second give you the value.
In a similar way to the set, we can find and we can erase.
So I say in here auto it iterator dot find saad. If iterator is not equal to end, we know it exists, then we can now
remove it and we can print again.
So be careful from printing inside the iterator.
So this is the way how to find and how to erase a map. Let's go a little more complex.
Now, what if we would like to define, say, a map from a character to a vector of integer?
OK, so I like you to think of it as a very general generalization.
You are mapping from something to something.
So here the form is a character and the to is a vector.
It can even be mapped form a vector to character,
this is OK too. let's define a single vector.
We pushed back 3 numbers, 1, 2, 3.
Then I said here that the map from the character A is a vector X, but here is important to be careful
about something if I say now X dot push back 4,
and try to print, let's access the vector here in the map and get the size, you will notice the size
of the vector is 3, the old values, but the X is 4.
So actually, there are two copies in the memory, this X vector and this one but it is inside here now.
So if you like to change more, Do changing here, at least this one safe way.
Now, let's get the my data A in a vector here.
This is again, a third copy.
So now you have three copies in the vector itself. what if I would like to get the vector here and access it directly
and it's still in the same in the memory, then put here the reference.
So the reference means I'm pointing in the memory to this one directly.
So if you change it x3 only, it will change the map.
The other things like the X and X2 will not change the map.
So be careful with complicated data structures. that's it.