Let's know about the STL queue, recall the structure that we already built in the hospital
and remember that a queue is following what we call first in, first out strategy.
If you went to a restaurant and you are the first one to come, then you are the first one to be served,
and so on,
the last one to come would be the last one to be served.
An interesting question here is how many projects might need a queue property, like something like a structure queue
to do something for it?
It seems like a very repetitive task.
So it STL comes here to save our time and give us a ready to use implementation for it.
But in reality, I might need a queue over integrase, a queue over doubles, a queue over employees,
this is where we use C++ templates, so it also provided us as a queue of int, queue of employee, ok?
That's why we call it a standard template library.
it provides us these implementations using the template property and like we expect in a queue, we can
push to add element, we can front to get the top element,
we can check if it's empty or not,
we can know the number of elements in the queue right now.
So in summary, the queue is a first in, first out data structure that STL provided us with templates
property.
Let's check out some code.
This is what we hash include here: #include queue, queue of integer
then we started to dot push 10, dot push 20 dot push 30, so notice here that this is a
template usage of the queue.
We are saying we were in a queue of type integer and then here we started to do the pushing.
You should expect that this is as simple as the
The queue that we did before, for example, we expected that, in our array, for example, to have value
10 then 20, then 30.
If we tried to print to the last element in the queue, we can do that using q.back
This is going to give you the last value, which is now 30.
Now, let's print the queue, an interesting way to print the queue would depend on two functions,
double-checking if the queue is empty right now or not, and getting the front of the queue and also removing
the front of the queue.
So the process goes as follows,
remember that the queue has value 10, 20, 30.
We first a check is the queue empty?
If not, we get the top of the queue, which is now 10, and then we print it, then we remove it.
So q.front get the top, q.pop remove it, now with a queue has 20 and 30.
Is it empty?
No.
Get the front, 20 print it,
remove it.
Now the queue has 30,
get the front.
is it empty? No,
get the front 30
Remove it, now
is a queue empty?
Yes, the queue is empty.
Remember that the queue here at this moment has no elements.
We can also create queues of other things,
for example, we can say a queue of a string,
we can push Mustafa,
we can get it back from the front and so on.
That's it for the queue.
Please go ahead.
And practice it.