Let's a practice another example.
You are to be given an expression of the following types of characters, the open brackets, the closer
brackets and other open brackets, close brackets, and this process and its closing braces.
A string input is valid if  every open bracket must be closed with the same type of bracket in a way that
make the overall like in correct
order. For example, here, This one is open then closed of the same type and proper order?
Yes.
This guy open-close, open-close.
Perfect.
This one is open here,
and this is a closing one.
Then here, open-close, open-close.
You feel it like over all balanced one. Here
Open, close, open, close.
This is OK.
Looking to this example,
for example, this one is open,
here
it's closing in a proper way.
Here is open
one, here is closing in a proper way.
This one here, open and it's closing and open and it's is closing and so on.
So the brackets are closed in the correct order,
and everyone when it comes to closing, it's correct all the same time.
These are on the other side wrong examples.
For example, here, this one is opened, but there is a closing one from a different type,
so this is now wrong. Here,
open, closing from different type.
This one has an extra closing, but there is no open here, and so on.
So I would like you to think about how to code that.
The idea is as following: For us to be able to do matching,
we need to whenever we have a closing bracket, we need to verify that the closing bracket is matching
something from the open bracket.
The problem is we need the history of the brackets so far.
So the idea is following:
We are going to maintain a stack of characters representing the current open parenthesis.
For example, whenever we have a closing one, we check with the top of the stack, if it is right
one or not.
Now thinking about why stack? because stack would give us the top of it whenever you have
an open bracket and then you come to a closing bracket, the closing bracket should be matched with
the latest open brackets,
and if there is another closing bracket, we need another recent open bracket and so on.
So the stack would help us for that.
Let's make some tracing. You have here
an open? put in a stack. You have here an open? put in a sack. You have here a closing? then find
in the top of stack,
What do we have?
We have an open parenthesis of type bracket.
Match it together,
We are done. Now,
move to the next one,
We have a closing bracket,
What is the top of the stack?
This open bracket, match them together,
and so on. So to implement this idea and I hope you get it right.
First of all, I am developing a very simple map that takes closing bracket and give me the open bracket.
This is just to make my life easier.
You can do that with if-else, but I wanted to make it with a map to make my life easier.
I am here defining the stack of characters and iterating with a string.
If the map dot count the character is zero,
It means it is an open bracket because it doesn't exist here in the Keys.
So we just add it here.
So if it's open, we just added. Open? added, open? added. Once it's closed one, now we first double check.
Is it an empty stack?
Like first,
If it hasn't, it means that there's a closing bracket for something that doesn't exist.
There is no open to match it.
So we know this is false, this is first condition to match.
The second thing is there are some open brackets of some type already.
We get the open of the current closing bracket.
So let's say I'm facing these braces here, then it is giving me the corresponding open one.
Now, this open one should match the top of the current stack so we get the top from the stack and
compare.
If they are not equal, then we are actually closing something that isn't the type of what we opened
it.
So again, this is false.
Otherwise we pop it and keep going.
There is a chance actually on the other side that when we are done with it, the stack isn't empty.
Like, let's say we just entered a single open bracket,
then eventually the stack will be not empty.
So also we need here in the end to verify that
the last line that the stack isn't an empty stack. This is overall. Trace a bigger example, and
try to trace it step by step to make sure that you get it.
That's it.