Let's continue our practice. In this one, you would be first given N full names, what is a full name?
It is like  — your name more than a K words.
So it starts with K for the number of words in your name, then the list of keywords.
For example, as an input, you take first, 5, five her is for 5 full names, then every full name
starts with a number. let's say 3, then Mustafa Saad Ibrahim.
These are 3 words for my full name.
3 Mustafa Saad Ali, 3 Asmaa Talaat Morsi, and so on.
So as you see, you have here like — a number of full names, then the number of words per
a name then the three words here.
Now for queries, you are also reading queue for Q queries.
each query is a sub full name. It again starts with K then K words.
For example, one query will be here,
3 queries.
One query is 2 words,
Mustafa Saad. You are to find all full names that start with Mustafa Saad, which are
if you go here one step back.
This is start with Mustafa Saad,
this is start with Mustafa Saad, and this is start with Mustafa Saad.
So we have 3 names starting with that.
So you are given full names as an input and the sub full name as a query and you are to find the sub name.
If we give one Asmaa, it's going to give you Asmaa here and Asmaa here, 2 entries.
So you print this vector of all of the items that are starting with this sub full names. Give yourself a couple
of minutes to think about it and maybe put it.
Here is one nice way using the map, we're going to build a map of string and vector of a string, and here is
the idea, here is how we will build this map: For every input full name, we are going to generate all possible
sub full names from it,
then we are going to map them to the full name.
For example, if you have the full name of Mostafa Saad Ibrahim, which consist of three words, we will
add 3 entries in the map from it.
You notice here, the two is the full name, Mustafa Saad Ibrahim, Mustafa Saad Ibrahim,
and so on. This is the full way.
Here are the three possible generation,
It could be the first word only Mostafa, the first and second Mostafa Saad, the first and second and third
Mostafa Saad Ibrahim.
So if I give you a name of 5 entries, 5 words, you are going to generate five
entries for me.
Once you generated all of that for every map you can, simply for a query, build its sub full name
and just go and check in the map
its list.
So here is how to code it.
We first defined the map, and we read number of inputs.
We read here the number of K words and then we iterate. We have two things here,
I have a current full name,
this will be the concatenation of the whole names.
So if I give it Mustafa Saad Ibrahim, it will be a concatenation of  Mustafa Saad
Ibrahim with a space-separated. The vector of string names here is the list of all the sub full names.
So I go on the input, one by one, take the word, let's say first I take the word Mustafa, then I
am concatenating it to the string and pushing it in the string, then I took the word saad then
I'm concatenating it here and now pushing back here the word saad. Now I'm taking
here the word Ibrahim, concatenating it here and then I am adding here also Mustafa Saad Ibrahim.
So notice here, this current full name, we are building it step by step and we are adding it here.
So now we are added so far 3 things.
... OK. We have now here in the names 3 things, Mostafa
as a string,
Mostafa Saad Ibrahim as a string, Mostafa Saad as a string.
We iterate in all of the strings and we start to push back
the str that we have, Mustafa, then Mostafa Saad, then Mustafa Saad Ibrahim to that full
name, which is just Mustafa Saad Ibrahim.
By the way, this is inefficient iterating,
you better use the reference here.
Let's go more. Now for the querying, we are reading a query here, we are again going back to the current full name
in the same exact way.
So if I give a query, like Mostafa saad, two items, It is going to be one string Mustafa, space, Saad then I'm
double checking the map,
does it exist?
If it exists, we retrieve it and we just print it, that simple.
So I hope you see how the map here can make our life much much easier than probably the iterative way
that you were thinking about it.
That's it.