Let's continue practicing. This task is easy in a slow way, but a bit hard when it comes to making it
more efficient.
The task as following:
Let's say we have an array as given like that, and some number K with three.
So for K of 3, let's say you are having these first three numbers.
Now think of it like a fixed window, a fixed
start and end.
Now move this window one step to the right.
Now it's focusing on these next 3 numbers.
Move it to the right, the next three numbers, move it to the right, next three numbers and so on.
This is for every time get the maximum.
So in the first time, these three numbers have this maximum number.
The second number is also the maximum between them is
3. The third case, the maximum between -1, -3, 5 is 5, and so on.
Keep going until you reach the last three numbers here, which have a maximum of 7.
Now, find the maximum between all of these numbers, which is 7.
So what we're moving here, we call it sliding window,
It's a fixed size,
So the size of this sliding window is always a three,
and as I said, the task here is to find the maximum among all of them.
I would like to give yourself a few minutes to think in a solution and then try to think in a faster
solution.
We can easily do two nested loops to identify the answer, but if we would like to make it a bit fast,
it takes more thinking. We're going to show a solution with the multi-set.
However, I'm going to attach an optional reading for a faster solution using a dequeue,
but it's a bit harder than the last one.
So here is the logic, we are going to simulate something like what we see here as following:
This is a vector input and K. We're going to create a multiset, a multiset here,
and we're going to insert the first K elements in the multiset.
So in this case,we will insert 1, 3, -1.
Now, I'm inserting them with the negative because this will make the multiset just sorting from
the big to the small.
There are different ways to handle the ordering, but this is an easier way.
So we are always inserting it with the minus and getting the value with the minus.
Anyway, when we entered the values with the minus, just think like we are getting it with the maximum
first.
So, the dot begin here
when we get it asterisk and multiply back with negative, It is going to be the three.
So internally it would be like the reverse of 3, 1, -1.
So we are getting the maximum now, which is just 3.
So now we have the maximum of the first window.
Now, we would like to move to the second window.
Here is the trick,
we are going to find the first element and just remove it,
and we are going to get the current element and just added. This easy way using only 2 steps.
You have the new window and it is ready to get the maximum out of it.
So here is what's going to happen,...
We are going to start from K because we are done with inserting the first key elements.
So starting from K which would be this guy.
So here in line 19, we inserted it,
but in the line before it, we find the first element in the map, in the multiset
should be, which is now 1, we find it from the array input and we remove it.
So we find it then remove it. Once we are done with that,
we are to get the top of the multiset, OK, then we put it, by the way, we want you
to return the values of all of the sliding windows, not just the maximum.
So, again, the logic was as following:
If you have in the multiset, these 3 numbers, you can remove the first one, then you add the
current one and that's it.
Then remove the first one and add the next one,
and that's it.
Then remove the first one and add the next one.
This way,
The multiset in every iteration, using only a couple of operations, has the updated set of numbers,
so we can just get the beginning of it and multiply with minus because we put them with negative values
here to get the maximum value.
If this is a bit hard for you, this is OK. That's it.