In this practice, we just would like to show how our library system can be rewritten in an easier
way when it comes to the STL.
So remember, the user class has previously an array of books,
when we would like to return to the book ID, we need to verify where is the book ID and then we need
to make a shifting in the array to remove something.
If you would like to borrow, you have to iterate over all the array to make sure that it exists
or not.
Now, if you'd like to move using the set using the STL, you can use the set with the user.
It would easily allow you to remove and sort the books.
So that's it.
If you would like to borrow a book you just inserted in the array and if you would like to return a
copy, you find where is it in the array and then if it exists, you just remove it,
you don't care now about shifting,
It will be done for you.
If you would like to know if the book is borrowed, you find it and double-check if the Iterator isn't
null. If you'd like to print, you just iterate directly and print it. From the library system perspective,
you can switch the books and users to be a couple of vectors, you can sort now using the beginning
and dot end, and you can use the range-based for loops to iterate and print the users.
That's it.
As you see, there is some code reduction that happened, and the less code you do the fewer bugs
you would introduce to your code. That's it.