In this practice, we also would like to highlight how the hospital system can be written using
STL. Remember, we had a queue, we implemented it by ourselves,
It has an array for names, another array for the status,...
...
Sorry, if we would like to add at the end, it was easy, the front was a bit problematic.
Removing from the front means that you have to remove something, so you have to do some shift lifting
in the array and so on.
When it comes to the STL, you think which thing would allow me to insert in the front
and in the end. This is as easily as that the dequeue itself,
OK, so we can use easily the dequeue for that. You might think, what about the priority queue?
It would be a bit problematic because you cannot print the priority queue without freeing it.
So going back here, adding end, it's as simple as push back,
adding front is as simple as just push front,
removing front is as simple as get front and remove front.
This way, you are done, that was with very less code.
The hospital itself would be like a vector of hospital queues.
So it was like a vector of queues.
Now, this is a hospital queue, but in our case, we just were going to use our personal and defined the queues.
There is no much changes here.
That's it.