So I want to share some, like, final notes about the STL.
Remember, we said before that the STL already just provided us with a bunch of data structures that are very
common in use.
We named them containers, and studying them early would make your life and the data structure course
is much easier.
We noticed that during our study that there is a usage of templates on data types.
So using these templates, the algorithms that we defined were very independent of the data types.
So if you would like, for example, to sort a bunch of numbers, you don't care that
they are numbers.
You care only that they can be like — comparable, either like something like integer or you defined
your own employee class with some operators less than, and so on.
So the templates help the algorithms to be independent of the data types themselves, which
is great.
You can also from another perspective, think like I can create a container of vector of integer, vector
of employee as like. It is same class,
We just are using it over and over again.
We also saw how the iterators are very generic interface.
They allow us to iterate on the containers.
You don't care how this iterating is happening behind the scene.
It's actually very different from a data structure to another.
But again, so these kinds of iterators make the algorithm itself independent of the container.
So the algorithm all what needs is to move to the next and next and next,
how this next is happening?
We don't care.
So some minor details about the data structures, there is something in the algorithm's code named complexity.
Complexity is all about how fast is such an algorithm in some criteria.
So I would like here to give you some basic notes and then later, when you have the algorithms course, you will understand
that it in details. In general, the data structures like a queue, or a vector, or a dequeue
are fast with their default implementations, and the unordered set is also fast, but not like them.
These are some operations
here are what we call like O one.Things here
also a bit good to some extent. Any erase or find operation is typically slow in the data structure,
maybe unordered set
is one of the fastest when it comes to the erase and find relative to others. The set, multiset
,and map are in general slow,
So be careful.
I met some of the software engineers who just you overuse them and they didn't notice that they are, for example,
slower than a vector.
So don't use unless there is a good reason,
but they are very frequent data structures.
I would say from my experience, the vector is one of the most used structures,
so this is very important. There are a few notes about the capacity and the push-back,
lot of push-back is very slow,
If you can initialize with some initial capacity, if it happened that you need that, then just go ahead
and use it. Set and map make our life very flexible,
but again, consider that they are a bit slow. If you notice the set and priority queue has a lot in common,
but also notice that set can do the priority queue does, but the opposite isn't true, so set is
more generic.
I'm not sure it might be some cases where the priority queue is a bit faster,
I'm not sure. What else, you might want to find a specific feature about the data structure
or even facing some errors,
I would just advise you to just Google it and try to find the answer.
Here are some other fancy things that you might think about it just like minor homework,
maybe like defining 3D vectors,
I think we defined it.
Maybe you can create a 3D array using maps, so far,
you might ignore that.
That's it.