For the first set of homework in STL. First, you are to reverse a queue using a stack so you will implement
function reversing a queue and it will take a queue by reference,
and you are to use inside it a stack to swap the content of a queue. For the second homework,
You are to implement something called our stack, which is a stack of integers.
The functionalities of push, empty and top would be acting exactly like a stack.
So the interesting thing here is we would like to implement the stack using an internal data structure
of the queue. So you have the pop, top, and empty implemented but you would like to implement the push
function such that it acts really like a stack.
So you are going to use this queue to implement a stack.
Reverse a number like 1, 2, 3 to the integer 4, 3, 2, 1 using stack, use this functionality.
Word prefix, you will be given N unique strings and then Q queries, each query has some
prefix and you are to find all the words that start with this prefix, print them using their input
order, for example, these are the N strings and these are 4 queries.
If I give you a letter M, there are three strings that start with M. You are to print them in the
same order as the input order so you don't print Marwa
first, you print Mostafa first.
If I give you 'mo' then Mostafa and Morad are the answers, 'mos' then only
Mostafa is the answer. Remember, they are unique strings.
A similar program is reading N strings, but they aren't unique.
You are to print them without duplicating and print them ordered.
For example, if I give you here query m, then the answer is Marwa first then Morad then Mostafa.
So you notice 'ma' here is first in the dictionary before the these guys.
Mostafa here is duplicated, but here will print it once only.
In this program, you are going to read the string s and you're going to apply some removal operations.
Specifically, every time you find two characters equal and adjacent, you remove them.
Adjacent means they are like one position and the one after me, for example, if I found B and B,
I remove them directly, after that
the string is A, A, C, A.
Now, A, A are adjacent,
you remove them.
Now, you have 'ca', nothing else to remove. That's it.