Let's solve the first homework we would like to reverse the queue.
However, we would like to do that through a stack. Now,
Um, okay.
So if we have a queue here, as you know, like let's say the queue is one two three, one is front,
three is back.
Now when we reverse, it is going to be three two one.
How can we use a stack to do that?
This is a bit straightforward.
The idea is stack like by design is actually about reversing data and in the data structure course,
you would notice that a lot. The stack here,
the idea is I would create an empty stack and let's say we have here the input one, two, three and
four.
I'm going to iterate on the queue element by element.
Get its front, add it to the stack,
remove it, so get the front, one, add it to the stack.
It's going to be one in the stack.
Then the next number would be two,  add it to stack, two, then three, then four. The major difference
here is the front of the stack is no four not one.
While the front of the queue was one.
Now let's get back the data from the stack itself and push them back to the queue.
What is the first element that we will get from the queue, from the stack? four, push it into the queue,
we have four. Next one is three, next one is  two, next one is one.
That simple.
So the idea was to push the queue to the stack, Push the stack to the queue.
But why that this process reversed the queue?
Because the stack by definition is making the last thing our front thing so we can use it to
do this trick.
OK, let's move to the another problem.
In this problem, we would like to do the following.
We have a stack, we have a queue built-in STL.  We  would build our stack with push and pop
top and empty functions.
However, the inner of the data structure is using the queue.
So how to build a stack based on a single queue like that?
You cannot define any extra things like another queue or another stack.
You cannot.  How to implement a data structure using another?
This is the question behind this point here.
So let's see how can we do that?
It isn't trivial, but also not hard.
So let's think about it and try to have an organized thinking mentality.
We know if..., let's say, someone pushed for us values one, two and three in order, according
to the stack, let's say the stack would be like the three, two and one.
Where here is its front.
OK, now the problem is if we pushed in the queue that queue would be like one and two and three.
So it doesn't represent it, actually.
OK, let's make an assumption.
Let's assume that our queue would be exactly ordered as same as our stack.
For example, we would always have the queue this way: three, two, one, such that if you asked me for the top,
I would just get the queue front in 01.
We are making an assumption. Now if we would like to make use of this assumption,
the push and pop should be perfect enough for the assumption to remain holding. Let's say
and remember, the cue is like that three, two, one, somehow.
And three is its a front.
Let's say I asked you to enter value seven.
Now, this 7 should be the front of the stack, so the new queue should be as following: seven, three,
two, one.
OK.
The problem is, this is our current
queue and this is our target
queue. The question is how can we get this one?
The problem is if we have three, two, and one in the queue and we try to push 7, it will be here.
But we wanted it to be in the front.
So the question is how can we convert this 3, 2, 1, 7 sto 7, 3, 2, 1?
Can you think in a way to do that?
The idea is simple.
How many elements here?
Three elements get them one by one and push them into the queue.
Get three.
So here, get three, push it.
Now it is here.
Get two, push it here.
Get one, push it.
Now we got 7, 3, 2, 1, our target array.
So here is the implementation.
First, you start and take the current size of the queue, then you push seven as a normal way.
Then you keep getting three elements
or s elements exactly from the queue. Each time you get it and you push it in the same time.
So you get it from the front, push it to the back, get it from the front to push it to the back. In this way,
we switch the 3, 7, 1  to 7, 3, 2, one idea.
This solution looks like a scary for you to get by herself.
However, by a very organized mentality, you can reach it like you can see, as I told you, Um, I
have here that, uh, I have here the queue.
The queue must represent the stack.
So anyway, let's make it like a stack.
Now the new push will not make it like a stack.
How can how can I fix it?
OK, get these items and put them here.
And the more you solve, you will get this talent faster and faster.
Okay.
So what's next?
The next task is to reverse a number using a stack, to reverse a number using a stack.
So let's see, how can we do that?
Uh.
Remember in the in the recursion, when we take some number, like three, like six or five, like one
two three four five six and we start to take a modulus, then divide by 10, take modulus, divide by
10.
We can do that recursively, such that the number is actually printed in recursive way.
I hope you remember this exercise.
There is some similarity here.
The point is that the recursion itself has a stack inside it.
So this is actually like more or less simulating to this process.
We create a stack here and we take the last digit and push it to the stack.
So here we take the last digit, which is six, so push six to the stack.
Then the next number will be five.
Push it to the stack.
Then four, three, two, one.
Now this is our stack and this is our front here.
You will iterate back on the stack to get back the elements.
So now, first we get one.
We get one here.
After that, we get two, multiply one by 10, which is ten, add two, it's 12 now.
Get three, multiply this by 10, 120, add three is now 123, multiply by 10, add four, multiply by 10,
Uh.
No, wrong, this will occur corrupted..,
This would give us back the current element as it is. Again, we have no like one, two, three, four, five.
We push it to the stack.
It would be five, four, three, two, one.
I would like to build this number to be reversed.
So the idea is I'm going to count to keep the counter of the number of 10s so far with me.
So here the number of 10s would be just one, then 10, then 100, then 1000, and 10000 and so
on.
So in the first step, we every time get that top multiplied by the current 10s.
So here is what happened. In the first step, where number is initially a
the number that we get from the stack initially is one.
OK.
Um.
There is an observation here after this loop, 'num' would be zero.
Remember that so that you can didn't get confused in tracing. Now, num is zero.
I'm going to get the top which is 10 multiplied by tens, which is one and just add zero.
It's going to be one.
And the next step I multiply 10s with 10 so one.
So now 10s equal
ten, I get the next number, which is two multiply it with two and add one it is now , uh, it's
now twenty.
It's now 20 and add one, it's now twenty one.
Multiply 10s by 10, it's now 100, get the next number, which is three, multiply three by 100, it would
be 300, add it to the current value, it's 321.
Now multiply this by 10, get four, multiply 4 by 1000 is 4000, add it here, it would be 4000 and 5
and so on.
So the moral of that is we've maintained this counter.
So that while we add values
we keep adding them here one by one.
I hope the idea is clear now for you and sorry for the confusion.