In this homework, we would like to, as you see, to make some kind of queries like when you give a
query like 'm',  it gives the current name, 'mo' gives the current names.
Do you notice this like auto complete service in Google?
This is something like that.
There is a constraint here to use the input order
as I explained, if we ask it for 'm', then we have these three words with the 'm' and we should respect
the input order as it is now.
How can we implement that?
What kind of data structure that would be pretty good and flexible for us?
Um, the data structure that I selected to solve for this problem is the map data structure.
The map data structure can map for me from something to something, so what is the point?
The point is as following: for every given string, I will generate all of the prefixes of it and create
a map ranging from the current prefix to the string.
For example, let's say I have the string 'Mustafa'.
How many prefixes are here? using this loop here, I can generate all of the prefixes, which are 'm', 'mo',
'mos', 'most', 'mosta', 'mostaf', 'mostafa'
So all of these prefixes are part of the word Mustafa.
Now in the map, I will map from the prefix to a vector of all of the strings that have this prefix.
So now, for example, um, let's say in the 'mo' map, we will map and will have here mostafa.
The next string, for example, was 'morad'. Now 'morad' also has a 'mo', so it's a prefix will push back itself
here, 'Morad' and so on.
In this way, the map is ready after this competition, such that every prefix is
pointing to a list of all of the strings that have this prefix as a prefix.
Now what's more interesting is: given that I was just pushing back the elements,
then these elements would be in exactly the same order as the given input.
So I also this way maintained the current input. I know that this kind of usage for these data structures
might not be easy for you.
But over time, you will get used to it.