For the second set of homework in STL, the first one is the score of parentheses.
Remember, parentheses are like that, if the expression is balanced, it means every open parentheses has
a closing parentheses in the right way.
Sometimes the expression is very nested like that or they are separate balanced expressions.
For example, this one has this one and this one,
they are two separate expressions,
All of them are balanced.
We will give a score for every expression as following:
If it's just open and close, you give it one.
If it is two separate expressions, it is just the summation of them.
Otherwise, for an expression, it will be two times the score of the internal expression.
Let's go with examples. Here for this guy,
the expression is 1 from here. For this one,
it is a nested expression,
so it is two times the score inside it. The score of this internal is 1,
2 times 1 is 2.
This has two separate
expressions, this is one, this is one, from this rule, 1 plus 1 is 2. This one has a nested expression.
So it is 2 times the internal and the internal we know from here is 2, 2 times 2 is 4. This
one has an internal expression,
so let's go inside it.
This guy is 1 and this guy from here is 2.
So 1 plus 2 is 3, 2 times 3 is 6.
This guy is the same expression here plus this guy,
so 1 plus 6 is 7.
By the way, this homework set isn't easy, so don't feel bad.
Asteroid collisions, we have some asteroids that are moving, they have size. If the size is positive,
it means moving to the right.
If it is negative, it means moving to the left.
They are all moving with the same speed.
Now, there is a chance that some of these asteroids collide and do a collision.
If they are all positive, they definitely would not collide.
If they are all negative, they also would never collide.
But now the problem is what if there are some positive and negative, there is a chance of meeting.
If two asteroids meet, the smaller one will explode.
If both are the same size, both of them would explode.
So let's simulate here.
You would be given this array and you are to find the final set of asteroids that will not explode.
So here for example, you have -5 moving to the left, 10 moving to the right, then these
two will meet when 10 meet -5, 10 is bigger,
so -5,
this one will explode.
So this is the remaining one. In this case, both of them are of equal value, moving in opposite directions,
they will meet and explode,
so nothing will remain. In this case, 2 will meet 5,
so 2 will be destroyed,
then 10 meet 5, then 5 destroyed because 10 is bigger.
In this case, these two negative values are moving to the left,
and these two positive values moving to the right,
they will never meet,
and so on. Finally, given an array, you are to find for every number the next element after it that
has a greater value.
For example, here in this array 10, which a number after it of a bigger value, where is the first one?
15.
So for 10 we print 15. For 5,
the next bigger one is 7. For 7,
it is 15.
15 has nothing greater than it. After it,
11 has nothing greater than it. After it, so we just print -1.
Here is another example to trace 8 numbers,
then you have the eight numbers.
We can solve easily this problem using 2 nested loops,
but can we do it in one iteration style? we can, for example, by using a stack. Try to find that.
That's it.