Another interesting data structure in the STL is priority queue, priority queue is a queue that involves
some priority,
Remember, in the hospital, we have the case that we can add in the front or add in the back,
we did this workaround to maintain some priority, but C++ has something very interesting named the
priority
queue, the priority queue is something that always will order the numbers from the big to the small,
You define it as following is also exists in the hash include of queue, you define priority queue of type integer
priority
queue. You start to push 3 and then push 5,
when you push a second number, it is going to put it in the right order, which is the biggest first,
so now it would be 5 3.
If you push the 1, then it would be 5 3 1,
notice they are sorted from big to small,
if you push seven, it is going to be in the top,
so now 7 3 1, if you push 0 is going to be in the lower.
OK, what if I would like numbers to be sorted from small to large?
One workaround for now you can use negative value,
there are other ways, but this is like one easy way for you.
Let's print a priority queue,
if we print the priority queue, we can just use a function very similar to the stack,
where you say while not empty top, get a top and remove it,
notice it was like front in the queue, but it is now here top in priority queue, a good programmer make
choices that make sense, in a priority queue,
we need something that is the best among them,
that's why we call it top function.
This how we print it.
Also notice this priority queue has here a reference,
so this priority queue and this priority queue are the same in memory.
If you try to check the size of the priority queue here, it will be zero.
So use a priority queue whenever you would like to enter items and they remain sorted according to some
criteria. That it.