I have rerouted the task of this link to be a bit more standard.
So this description is a bit different from here, but they are actually the same.
So the task in its simple format is as following: we are giving an array. For every number in the
array,
find the index of the first number after it of a higher value, -1, if no such number.
For example, here 10,5 ,7, 15, 11. For 10,
What is the first element greater than it?
15.
In index 3.  For five,
what is the first element greater than it? 7; index two. seven? 15. For 15?
There's nothing greater than it after it. for 11?
There's nothing greater than it after it.
So for every integer, you find the first number after it and just use its index, if nothing, use -1.
-1.
And here is another example.
Please verify.
Let's solve the problem again.
If you have any question, ask them. If you have any assumptions, state them.
Think of the test cases are good enough.
Are there any special cases?
And so on.
Let's start thinking about the solution.
Start with the brute-force, the brute-force is very clear here.
Two nested loops are more than enough. For every index,
you just iterate and find the first one after it. That simple. 'n^2' are very direct to brute force.
Now the problem is this is very slow.
So we start to think about the faster approach.
Is it easy?
The answer is no, actually.
Like, if you try to improve the brute force, it will mislead you.
So sometimes improving the brute force is a very nice idea and sometimes is a time consuming task.
So be careful about that.
There is a chance that you get stuck in the interview in this problem.
So if you are really stuck, ask the interviewer for a hint. There is one of two hints that the interviewer
might provide you. Another one is try to think from an opposite perspective.
And what is the forward perspective that we are trying?
We take an element.
We iterate and find its next one.
What do you think would be the opposite of such a perspective?
The opposite would be to take a number and go backwards.
So now we take a number to search about his next greater element, which is a single element.
The opposite would be you take a number and go backward, go backward to do what?
To assign it to the different numbers that I am there next
perspective; that I'm next greater elements.
Anyway, the second hint that the interviewer might provide is use a stack data structure.
This problem is solvable in O(n) with a stack data structure.
So one of these two hints you might be provided.
Anyway, the solution is as following: it's more of reverse thinking.
For every index, you will find the previous indices that array of index is there next greater value.
So this is, as you see, this is the opposite direction of the brute force, and sometimes it is
what I call reverse
thinking is the way to go.
An example of that here, the value 15 is the greater element for whom, for the value 10 and for the
value 7, not for the value 5.
OK, so the question is how can we develop a stack based on this approach, this opposite perspective?
This is reverse thinking's style.
So here is the idea, we will maintain in the stack the indices that don't have any greater elements so
far.
Let's take an example.
If you have something like 15, 10, 13, 10 has a next greater element of 13, but which indices do
not have a next greater element?
15 and 13 at positions 1 and 3.
OK, now if we added 12, 12 also don't have now next greater element. If we added 20, 20 would
be the next the greater element for all of them except itself.
So as you see this here, we are maintaining the indices of the next greater elements without
the next greater elements.
What I would like you to think about is if I have this case 1, 3, 4 as elements without next
greater element.
And now, you got 20.
What can you do with this
20?
Simply, we can take the 20 and go over the stack element by element, for the 4 and for the
3 and for the 1, one by one and keep it checking.
If I am greater than you, then I am your next greater element.
Get out of the stack.
I am greater than you,
then I am your next greater element. Get out of the stack.
Keep doing that.
What if we met an element that I am not greater than it?
Then it means he is greater than me, so I can stop at this moment.
Let's see an example here.
Let's say I took 13 and I signed it for 10 as the next the greater element.
Then I found 15.
When I find 15, 15 is greater than me.
I cannot keep going in the stack because the stack has elements greater than 15.
Greater than 15.
So I have to stop at this moment.
Let's repeat that again before the i-th step, the stack will have all of the positions that aren't
assigned their next  greater element. If you try to take a big example and analyze it, you will notice
that the stack must be sorted in a decreasing order.
So if you at the moment, for example, and found, for example, 14 as a new element, you take
12, assign it to 14.
You take 13 assign to 14.
You take 15,
you stop, you stop and never go before 15.
Why?
Because if 15 isn't next greater for anything before it, I will definitely as a 14 will not
be a greater element for them.
I hope the overall idea is clear.
It might be a little bit challenging to write a code for it, but give a trial.
The good, surprisingly, is very small.
Uh, this is O(n) time and O(1) memory because I will update the vector itself.
But if you have to like...,
This is O(n) the memory, sorry, because we are creating a stack anyway, so forget about that.
Let's start with it.
I will go through a vector, through the elements one by one.
And then you see here line 38.
I will always push myself because I am a new element.
I still don't have a next greater, right?
I'm like, 15 just arrived.
It would get inside here.
Now what's happening here?
We mentioned that the stack would have the elements that I am greater than them.
We keep iterating over the stack as long as the stack has elements
and my value is greater than the top of the stack. If this happened,
we will assign..,  the stack is a stack of indices,
we will assign the vectors of the given index 'i'.
So we are putting that this index, next greater element, is 'i' and then we remove it.
Once I find that element that I am not greater than it, I have to stop that.
So what happened is as follows: we first push
3, then 15 come finds 3 in the stack, so assign it as a 15.
Now the stack has only
one. 10 comes, and then 10 checks with the top of the stack.
15, no way then stop.
13 comes, 13
finds itself a greater than 10.
So 10 gets out of the stack and its marked. Now,
when 13 compared with 15, 15 is greater.
We stop. Now the next is 12.
12 is less than 13, which its index number 4. 0, 1, 2, 3, sorry index number 3. 12
is compared with index number 3, which is 13.
I am smaller.
We stop.
Next is 20, 20 compared with index of 4, which is 12, yes, I'm greater.
Mark myself as greater.
Next is 3, which is value 13.
I am greater mark myself as a next greater element.
Then Index 1, which is 15.
Yes, I'm greater than 15.
Mark myself as next greater element.
Nothing else, stop.
So always as you see, the new element would be pushed in way to the stack.
But I am going through the stack, find every element I am greater than him and marking myself as
his next greater element.
The vector here initially would be vector of values, but I'm updating it by reference, so it's going
to be eventually vector of indices marking the next greater element.
In another case, you would just create a copy of the vector.
And now there is one point here. After we are done with that, some of the indices would never have,
would never have a greater element, next greater element.
So we iterate on the remaining of the stack and mark all of them with -1.
If it happened that you create a vector for the answer and initialized all of it to -1, then
you don't need this loop because it would be already assigned -1. Please take an example
and make sure you understand how this internal loop works.
Overall, this is a very nice problem.
It's also challenging. Why?
Because it has an ad-hoc problem.
This is one reason. The second reason because the problem is involving this opposite thinking
point, which is also another challenge.
The third is the writing style of the stack isn't that common.
So overall, it isn't an easy task.
This problem is very, very, very important, and the reason is it comes as a sub problem in many
other problems.
So in other problems you will find yourself copy-paste
this code and using it.
That's why this problem is really important.
There is a variant here
for this problem, it's a premium problem.
I'm copying the text here for you.
Think about it.
You will notice it's very relevant to the problem we mentioned.
I would like to show another variant. This next
greater element will go circular.
This means the element can go circular in the array to find its next the greater element.
So previously, if there is 100, 70, 30, we will have all of them -1 because no one of them has
next greater element.
But if we can go circular in the array, the 70 can go circular and find 100 as the next greater element
and the same for the 30.
So this is the difference now in the output.
How can we solve that?
Here is a hint for all of the problems that involve circular arrays, please remember to double the array.
This is your first approach.
So if you doubled the 100, 70, 30 twice here, now with our normal code, the 100 would have
the next as 100, sorry the 70 would have 100 next.
And 30 would have 100 as a next.
This is very popular trick.
Do I need to really duplicate the array itself in terms of the memory?
No, we can do that virtually.
So actually, we would not use an extra memory.
We will use the same array, but we will process it as array of 2n length, not just O(n) length. Try to code the
idea and compare your solution with the discussion. That's all.