One of the very nice features of the modern C++ 17 is the structured binding, It isn't an STL
topic.
However, it makes a lot of code simpler, especially in STL.
So let's see how this feature is working.
Let's say you have an array here. If you would like to take  some variables to point to the array's elements,
you have to write something like integer A equal array of zero, integer B equal array of one and
so on.
So C++ is trying to make this a bit simpler, something like in Python, for example, and here is the
syntax of the structured binding.
You can write the word auto, then you open two brackets, your list of variables and equals something
that has a structured way in its coding,
then after this line of code, you will notice that the value A1 B1, C1,
and D1 are matching these 4 variables.
Now, there are two ways here.
Are you matching by value or by reference?
This is matching by ending by value,
but this guy here, if you put the reference here, you will bind them by reference.
For example, if you try to change C2 here and printed the array element itself, you will notice
the array element changed.
The number of elements here has to match the size of the array, which is 4, for example. Please
take a moment to make your eyes familiar with the syntax
style code.
By the way, when you see these errors in code, you notice that something is wrong.
This is an eclipse problem
Eclipse so far, we are here in 2020, Eclipse is supporting
so far C++ 14.
So when it sees syntax from C++ 17,
It doesn't work well.
I think maybe Visual Studio would be one of the ides that doesn't have this problem at the
moment.
So in eclipse, this is what call syntax checking.
The compiler itself is working well, but Eclipse doesn't figure out the syntax. Let's go more,
If you have here a struct of an employee with like say something like a name and salary and then you define
it here. You can bind by value
this way, you can say auto str1, val1, or whatever equals emp
or if you would like to do this by reference, you can do it this way.
Now, the public variables here from the struct will be taken and binded here to these two values. If you
would like to make it const,
also you can make here a word const.
Now, there is one only thing that I hate about the features so far. Notice,
these are like variable declaration,
so you have to make a new variable every time you need to use it.
Also, what if I don't need the second variable here?
These are at the moment of C++ 17 aren't options, but maybe in the future, they will be available.
But anyway, the point is you can decompose this struct elements to these two guys in a single line
and we'll see how this feature will be very helpful during the remaining of the session.
The pair, you know, we can define the pair like pair of integer, string, p, 33, Belal.
We are defining a pair here.
I would like to tell you that the pair can be, also in C++17, constructed in two different ways.
You can say something like auto B equals pair of 33
and some name here.
OK, what about the integer and string? In C++, there is what we call template argument deduction.
The compiler will know that this 33 must to be an integer,
This must be string.
So it doesn't need to define them, or even a simpler way,
you can say pair P of the arguments, and again if the compiler can deduce the arguments, you don't
need to write them, so its like a better syntax.
Now, in a very similar way, you can do something like auto reference these two elements,
for example, equal the P, so now we are defining it.
Let's see more of that, let's say you have a function, I am defining here a global pair, and
trying once to return it by reference and another one tring to return it by value.
So if you have here again a function returning by reference, you can take them by reference.
But don't try to take by reference what is returned by value,
this will be a compiler error.
There are two ways to do that.
The first one is just take it by value.
Later, when we will learn the semantic moves,
you will know that we can put here reference reference to take what is returned by value.
Skip that for now.
When we go to semantic moves, we will learn about that.
So as you see again here, something like the pair, we composed it in easily here.
You will see several applications for that in the next slides.
In a similar way to the pair, there are tuples. I can make a tuple here. Let's say I have a tuple,
then I can construct it here
normally. I think you can remove all of that and just write auto. The make-tuple again
can use a template argument deduction.
But here's what's more interesting
with the templates, you see here, we are defining variables
M, N, Q, and we are initializing them in a very simple way. In a normal way,
one have to write three lines.
You would write a character M equals A, integer N equals 123, boolean
Q equals true. Here, with the mix of the structure binding in the tuple, we did one direct initialization
for the three variables,
and this is very interesting,
you are initializing different things in a single line of code.
Let's see another example, the map, let's define a multi-map, and let's also make an addition to
what we say about the map here.
If you defined a multi-map before C++11, if you would like to insert some elements initialized with
some elements, you would have to use the insert function.
You have to call pair of integer and integer for matching
here, you have to push the parameters.
All of this verbs code to initialize a multi-map. In the modern C++ and with the template deduction
and uniform initialization all of that together, you can now define it in this very nice way.
You just open one big braces and then for every pair here, you just put braces for it, so it will
be initialized directly.
So now this is perfect code.
Let's now iterate on the map.
We know we can iterate with const auto and get here a pair that we can print
its value,
Right?
So we know that the map's iterator is going to return a pair of type integer and integer.
You can also decompose it easily to just reference key and value.
So now instead of getting an item of type pair, we are decomposing it directly to key and value and
using it. Another similar application,
let's say you would like to get all of the elements from the multi-map that has a value
one as a key. This function in multi-map called equal range.
You give it the key, it's going to return for you — a pair of the first iterator and end iterator.
So again, you can here take it in a pair and then say pair dot  first, pair dot second, but we can
combine it directly and say iterator-start, iterator-end, and then use this iterator start and end to just
go and print all of the values,
and every iterator here will have a first and second for the pair here itself.
So this is returning a pair for the start and end, but this pair is for the integer and integer.
So as you see, again, the pair here is playing a nice role in initializing these guys. With insertion,
again, we can see how the pair is very nice in that. In a normal case, when we would like to insert
something, we know by default it returns a pair where the first is an iterator and the second is true or
false if it succeeded.
Now, we can directly again, instead of receiving in a pair and using dot first and dot second, we just
take it here in one pair directly and binding it directly.
But notice that the function is returning by value,
you cannot here take a reference, and also you can make it with the selection initialization.
Remember, this lesson in the if condition,
If you say here if, auto, st.insert, this is going to be like binded to these two variables and
then you can here check if success or not.
So this is an if condition if you managed to insert the object or not, and you can get inside the object,
but you still have the iterator here. Previously,
if you don't want to do that, you will say " st.insert 15; " to check if it's true
or not,
but what if you still want to the iterator with you?
This, again, is going to make your life much easier.
All of that are applications for the pair.
Here is one more about how the pair can be very nice for us. Let's say we have a string here, and we
can make an 'istringstream' over this guy, which is going to return an 'iss'.
So we see how initialization can help us here in a for loop. We are going to declare
and initialize two variables,
iss and line.
The line would be initialized to string, and iss is going to be initialized with the istringstream.
And now, we can keep going and get-line from this iss here and using it here.
So in a single line, we are now just creating our objects in the for-loop
directly. Previously, you would have to define istring stream here, which would be...
..., in a bigger scope in the function here,
but now we are defining it directly here. So the auto with the pair or auto with tuple can
give you great power in the initialization.
The last thing is about structs with arrays.
Let's define an integer array here.
If you try to do something like integer-salary for an equal array,
this will be an error.
Remember that the array is like a pointer here,
...
You cannot make this line.
It would be like converting from an integer pointer to an integer.
Now, let's say that we have here, yeah,
this is now a pointer here.
Let's say we have a struct, and we initialized its array with aggregate initialization
to these three items.
And then if you started to decompose it to an item here, it's actually going to be an array.
So the purpose of that is to tell you that it doesn't work like this guy.
It will not be a pointer,
It will be an actual array.
Here is a way to verify that what is returning it from this guy is actually an array.
You can use what we call type ID.  Every variable will have a compile-time data type.
So we are saying here what is a type of the return my-array dot salaries from here, which
is an array, and we are comparing it with the type of this guy. If this was a pointer for example,
...
This should give a compiler error.
So the moral of that are two things.
The first is by default,
...
This is an integer pointer,
but here it's actually an array, and also the type-id can help you to make verification about the different data
types.
That's it.
Try to make use of it as possible.