Another usable data structure is that the deque, so we know that the queue you can allow us to add usually in the
in the back and it's more of like first-in, first-served, the deque allows us to add in the front and to add to the
back and to remove from the front and to remove from the back.
This is actually very similar to the queue that we wanted to implement to the hospital to implement to the
emergency case.
So it support a full of functionality:
push_front, push_back for adding and the front and the back to get the item, pop_front, pop_back to remove
to remove the item, size for how many elements, empty to check if there are any more elements or
not.
so yeah,
as you see, we can now if would like to do some printing,
you have to ask yourself, do I need to print from the back to end or end to back?
this is very fixable data structure.
So here is the code we are defining here a deque of integer,
and then I started to push back in the front as it is empty it will be "20", push back in the "30" so it push
back and push in the end "30", push back "40" is pushing back "40".
Now we are pushing in the front "10",
So it's going to the front and put "10", then push back "50",
It's going in the end and push "50", push front zero is going to put in the front "0".
If you used an assignment operator this way, you can make a copy of your queue, this is a deep copy,
so this object is now very different from this object,
if you changed the deque, the copy will not be changed.
Now, let's say we would like to print them.
The first function is "print back" for the q, so (print_back) is going to print from the back to
the top,
so here is the back so going to print 50, 40, 30 and so on.
So here is a printed back function, it is taking a deque and in a very similar way
while not q is empty, q.back, q.pop_back.
So the observation here we are printing the back first, then we're removing it.
The (print_front) is very similar but it is printing the front first, then removing it.
here's an observation, the print_back(q)
is not using reference
this means that this
queue will be a copy of this
queue so now in memory we have two queues this one in the main and this one in the print_back function, by
the end of the print_back function,
this queue here in the function is empty, but this one in the memory is as it is, now calling print
front,
I'm using the reference, the reference means it would be changed,
so now this guy and this guy would be exactly the same in the memory.
by the end of the print front, the queue would be empty,
so if you try to print the front again, it will print nothing.
So let's go back to the queue, to the copy,
If you printed the size it is 6, there's another two interesting functionality in the deque, the first is you
can deal with it as an array so you can say copy of [1],
so think of this as an array copy of one is at position "10", you can also use the function copy.at
one
So what is the difference between them? the function .at is doing verification if you are accessing
elements that exist or not,
for example, if I try to say that .at(1000) it will throw an exception for you that
you try to access an index that doesn't exist,
but this function will crash a program directly.
What else?
You can clear the copy and then just check the size
it would be zero.
This is what the deque, so I would like to make
with you like one funny practice with the deque, let's say that we have an "is_palindrome" function using
a string,
before that we used to stop at the first and the end and walk to the middle, then verify.
so we check is with A with A and B with B.
I would like to see how the deque implementation would make it like a more easier to code.
First of all, we would iterate on the string put its character by character in the deque, so by the end
of this operation that would have A, B, B, A,
now, the idea would be as following.
we will iterate on the whole palindrome, take character from the front, and take character from the end,
so here we take the character from the front and we remove it, character from the back and we remove
it,
if they are an equal, we just return false.
So it first takes A&A, then takes B&B.
So this is how the front and back would be very helpful in something like this
palindrome and there are some cases here, there is an interesting serie here,
You see, I say "cout boolalpha", this is an internal flag in C++,
If you did that instead of printing in zeros and ones, is going to print true and false.
That's it.