Another interesting data structure is named stack, stack is completely the reverse of a queue, you can
think of a stack like a box of that have some books,
you put book number one, book number two, book number three, till book number 10.
If you would like to get a book now from the stack, you have to get from the top of the box.
So this means that the last one is the first one to get out, on the other side,
the queue was the first one is the first one to get out,
so queue here was first in, first out,
but here in the stack, it is last in, first out.
So when you enter a stack, it is more like a box,
The one get first just got trapped down there,
but in
in a queue, the one who gets first just get outside of the queue,
so looking to this stack, we enter the number one, two, three, four, five, if you would like to
pop
the five is the one to get outside,
think of it always like a stack of books. In terms of code and a very similar way,
let's define a stack of string,
you start to push Ibrahim, Saad, Mostafa, and then you print in a very similar way.
But what is the output here?
Would it be Ibrahim Saad Mostafa?
No, it would be the reverse would be Mostafa Saad Ibrahim.
OK, so the queue would print them Ibrahim Saad Mostafa, but stack would print them Mostafa Saad Ibrahim.
That's it.