Let's do some practice on STL, with every practice, I would like you to try to allow us to stop
the video and think by yourself for some time,
this is a very good exercise for you.
When you think and compare with others, you are learning a lot more than just reading the solutions.
So in our first problem, we would like to sum the key K numbers of a stream,
so I would like you to think of it like you have a stream of numbers,
let's look here,
we have some reading for Infinity,
we are just reading (while),  (cin, number),  (cin, number), we are calling this struct, we are calling this struct with something
called next and we are giving its number here.
The target of the stream is to keep printing only the sum of the k numbers.
Let's see, the stream numbers that we read here: it is one, two, three, four, five, six, seven,
eight, nine. with the first number the last four number are just one, with the second number two, we
have only two numbers.
So we just sum them, three
we just sum them, four we just sum them, with the fifth number,
now we need to get the last four numbers in the stream, which are two, three, four, five,
after that, the next four numbers are three, four, five, six and so on.
So this processor function.
has here a function
named "next" with every number it receives, it computes and returns the sum only of the last K numbers,
and we are initializing here for example with four,
so it has a four in the constructor here and then
just returning the sum of the last key numbers.
Note that although you should implement this one, but you shouldn't store more than K numbers.
so how to implement that? what kind of data structure would make our life easier when trying to do
this task?
So, think about it.
The way I'm implementing that is as simple as using a queue, the idea is as follows.
We will keep in the queue only the last K elements.
Whenever we have more than a key element, we just remove the first element that we have right now in
the queue.
So it goes as following, with every new number we add it to our queue and add it to our sum, initially
the queue is empty and the sum is 0
Now we have a check,
if the queue has more than K, let's say four,
if it has more than four elements, we know that we are now like five elements,
exactly,
so we started to remove the first number that we have,
then we remove it from the sum and then we remove it from the vector,
for example, if we have now the numbers, one, two, three, four,
we expected the queue
to be have the four numbers
and expect the sum to be 10
If you have a new number five, we add it first to the queue and we add it to the sum,
now, the sum is fifteen,
but now we have five numbers,
then we go and remove from the sum the first element which is one, and remove it also
from the queue so the queue now have two, three, four, five, and so on.
So the idea is that the .front in the queue would help us to do the task here.
That's it.