One of the useful classes from STL is the pair class, the pair - is its name say - it means two
things,
the interesting in the pair, it can be pair of any two types,
so, for example, you define it this way,
you say pair, you then you open this  here, and you put say integer, string
it means I would like a pair of items that have only the first item as an integer and the second as a
string.
You for simplicity,
you can think of it like you are defining your own structure that has int and has string,
So the p.first it would be here the integer, and p.second would be the string here.
the way that we create pairs, it really like using the function make pair
You call make pair and give it value that matches this value and its value here, that matches the datatype
you would like to print the content, you say p.first, p.second you can make things like,
say, I would like to define a stack of pair of int and string,
then you started to push these items of pair
so this way it helps you to create items of different types,
you can go more complex,
like, let's say I would like to defined three variables,
I can say pair of integer, pair, integer and string,
so this means that p.first would be the integer, p.second would be this pair, which is
pair by itself.
So I can say p.second.
.first it would get this value
p.second, it would get this value, to create it again.
think in the same way,
I would like to make pair of a value and its second thing is a pair of two things like 20 and
"ali" here, or an easier way, you can make it like this way,
no here a value of ten and here a value of p.
nicely, since  C++ 11, there is a new thing that's named tuple so that the tuple
can allow us for a lot of more values
so you can think of pair as a special version of this tuple that allow a lot of more values.
The interesting thing about the pair is that it's supports the comparisons like  ==, or greater than
or equal and so on,
so let's say you have a set of pairs like that, OK?
This is values, pair of integers and pair of string in it,
and let's say that you would like to order them or like thinking about their order, for example, typically
the default comparison would be on the first element if they are equal,
the second element, if they are equal,
the third element, for example, if you are comparing P1 with P2 then P2 is the smaller because
seven is smaller than ten.
If you are comparing B three with before B three before you start to extend.
This cannot help.
In comparison, we move to the second element,
Ziad - Mustafa Z is bigger,
Mustafa is this smaller,
So P4 is less then P3 and so on,
So it keeps going element by element to do the comparison. pairs very useful class in many cases.