Similar to the pair, There is also a tuple in C++, Tuple is more of a generalization of a pair, So in pair,
It allowed us to have a specific couple of items but in tuple you can have as much as you code.
Remember, In pair and in tuple,
The interesting really thing is you have like a data structure of different data types,
So you can think of it as an array of different types. Here we are defining a tuple close to the definition
of the pair of three items.
The first would be char, int, and string to create a tuple to initialize it to these items.
One easy way is to say t1 equal make tuple and then you start to assign values corresponding to
the values here. The way that we get and send the value is a bit inconvenient.
Your write here get then you write here the position then you write the tuple name,
So get zero is for the first position,
Get one is for the second position. In a similar way,
You can set it this way.
So just try to use it in this syntax.
The weird thing here is like you are trying to use a position inside the less than and greater than.
Similar to the pair, The comparisons are all supported in the tuples.
So you can start to compare them, It is going to compare them one by one.
So if the first element is equal then it moves to the second element, If they are equal, It moves
to the third element and so on till it comes to an element that is different then it is used and applied
the comparator based on it.
There is also something interesting in C++ named tie.
We use the tie several times for comparisons.
So now it's time to know that the tie is actually more of kind of creating a tuple here.
So one thing here that the tie is helping us in breaking items, unpacking items.
So let's say that you would like to separate these three items and really three different types.
If you did tie with this Syntex equal T1, It is going to break this representation to
these three items, If you are coming from something like Python language then this should be very
easy for you.
It usually can break something into the corresponding items this way.
Finally, there is also in C++ the tuple cat, Which can take two tuples and just concatenate them
here.
So this is tuple number one and we are creating one more tuple with like one value here and so on.
In C++ 17,
there's a different syntax for that
but be careful.
Don't run an example for C++ 14 unless you are
make sure your compiler support 14.
Don't write it for 17 unless it supports 17. That's it.