In this video, You will learn about one of the fundamental things in STL named iterators. Remember, we once had
a queue like say here
a queue initialized with five members.
We want to print it from front,
So 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 would go ahead.
As long as it isn't empty, We will get a front and then remove it.
So this is enough to print it.
We had a simple issue here with that.
After this iteration, The queue is empty.
OK, As the queue is a reference this would make this guy is now empty.
I just wanted to print it, OK?
Here is a workaround.
Don't just use add.
So it is going to make a copy in memory but this is a lot of time-consuming.
What if I just want to iterate on the content and print it.
That's it.
So here is where the iterators come to the scene.
Iterator is an object, Mainly has a class
but you can think of it like a position in an array.
OK?
Whenever we mean the class, We mean the struct like think of them as the same thing.
So the interesting about iterators, It has some begin, Which is the beginning of the dequeue
for example, and it has an end after the dequeue so think of it as a position.
If you did position plus-plus, you move forward. Position minus-minus, You move backward.
What if I would like to get the current element?  We use asterisk-position.
Probably, This is the most new thing for you.
If you have this asterisk position, You can start to change and print the value.
So thinking about iterating on that, You start on the beginning,
You move, You move, You move
as long as you aren't equal to the end.
Once you are equal to the end, You know that you are done with printing.
Let's see some code for that.
So we have here a function printing for the dequeue so the way that we get an iterator that can iterate
on this dequeue is as following:
You get your data structure like the dequeue integer here then you write colon, colon, iterator.
So Iterator is a class inside this dequeue so now you can get an object for yourself. If you see
q dot begin, It returns an object looking into the beginning of the array.
Now I would like to print it.
You say as follow: while iterator not equal
queue dot end (Remember the end is after the array) so now iterator here we say plus-plus it, It keeps moving to the
next element, to the next element, to the next element.
The way to get the value of the current position is using asterisk-it.
This is a new operator for you.
It is named dereference operator.
We will later learn more about references and dereferences.
So this is how we mainly can iterate on that.
...
This is very fundamental for the remaining of the section.
I would like you to read this code to make sure that you are familiar with it.
We have queue dot begin is looking to the begin.
We keep going till we are in the end. We can use plus-plus it to move forward and asterisk-it to
get the current value.
So this one is going to print to the five values.
Now, let's do something a bit interesting, We can also print  the queue in the reverse order in a very
similar way.
So we would like to implement the print back for example.
So the way to do that is another type of iterator.
It's name the reverse iterator.
So to get it, You say queue dot r begin this return a reverse iterator object, adds to it and you keep
going till you queue dot r end.
And again, asterisk-it to print
but wait this is also plus-plus it, You might think OK, I'm stopping at the end, and then we are returning backward
so my it minus-minus? No. You can think of it as the content of the queue has been reversed for you and you
have again begin and end for it.
So the way you print it is again you get the start in the end and you keep going till you reach
its end.
OK!. So practically speaking, Rbegin adds the last element, Rend is before the first element.
So this is how the iterating is working.
It is another way to write the same idea but more fancy way like using auto, You can just save your time
instead of writing all of this big expression here in C++11.
So you just write auto and just put all of them together here with the for loop, It just making your life much
nicer.
Again, Make sure you are familiar with that.
An interesting thing here about the iterator is you can do some arithmetic on it.
What does this mean?
So think of it again like a position. Here we say q dot begin is looking to the first element.
If I added plus 3, I'm jumping to the fourth element.
So now this iterator is looking to the forth element.
If we printed it, We get four.
Now, I can also say iterator minus-minus. If you did an asterisk here
(Remember the rules of the minus-minus operator this way,
The postfix) then it is going to print the current value then move one step backward.
So asterisk-it minus-minus (We are at the four), we're going to print it then we're going to move to the backward
for printing
The current iterator or current position, We have three. Try to think all the time like we are dealing
with an array and it is more of like a position on it. Here we say minus-minus iterator
so we are jumping one step to the back first, then we are printing.
So this is now 2. Again,
If we printed here we are at the 2. We can also say like iterator plus three,
If this is the position then position plus three is now at the fifth.
We are at second. With three, We are at the fifth.
So with asterisk-it, We can just directly get the value.
So again, Think of that.
Think of asterisk like you are accessing using an array and then you are saying array of current position plus
3. We can also say position plus equals 3,
This is jumping 3 positions, asterisk-it, and so on. You can change the whole value of the vector
by the way, You can start on the beginning till the end,
Keep going
and asterisk it equal ten.
So again, Think of that as an asterisk as like accessing the array in the current moment.
So this is how we can do some arithmetic with iterators.
There's also another interesting thing,
The const iterator. the const iterator is the same concept as the main iterator but you write cbegin,
cend and it is const iterator. the only difference here is that you cannot change the iterator
during the iteration.
It's same performance, same everything,
You just can not change it.
It is more if you are communicating intention to others
like there is no intention to change the content of this dequeue, for example.
In fact, we're here seeing the dequeue, You can have iterators on many, many data structures.
some of them you cannot, like the stack, queue, and priority queue. If you have to print them, They will get empty.
But most of the other things they are
OK. So here is an example of printing string.
We have a string function that counts the number of lower characters so I can again make an iterator
in the beginning of the string,
Keep going till the end.
Asterisk-it here would be an index in the str so it would be now a character. you can count plus
equal is lower or not
then this will tell us the number of lower characters. Remember, is-lower returns zero or a big value
so it's better to put here greater than zero to make a comparison.
The auto it here is of type string,
Colon, colon iterator.
In the next videos, We will learn more about other data structures and they all support the iterators
You will see in the next videos operations on these containers, for example, We will start to erase elements
or insert a bunch of elements using iterators, We will see algorithms that take the beginning and the end
of iterators.
So more when you come to study, You will see that you can define a vector of integer iterator, set of
integer iterator, map of integer and string iterator, and so on.
So there are more iterators that are coming in the next videos. That's it.