Today, we will discuss about the character array.
But let's first refresh more about the characters, remember, we once said that every character is
eventually Internally is just a number.
We already did this conversion before and we saw that the letter A is at the range of 56.
And the small letter a is at the range of 79.
We can notice also that
ABC they are it seems here also consecutive.
Now this is a bit interesting that we can, given that, from A to Z are just consecutive,
We can if we have the letter A here and we increment it 26 - 1, we're going to get also
90 by ourselves.
So this means a very interesting fact that we can just put character here with 90 and just print it,
it is going to be Z. so we can play with math,
when it comes to characters.
The same conclusions comes here.
How is that useful?
This is very useful, for example, in conversions between uppercase and lowercase.
Let's see how, first of all, this program is going to read here a character and doublecheck,
if this is an upper letter or not?
Given the math, we know that letters from A to Z are just consecutive, so we can double-check
if ch1 is >= A or less than or Z.
If this is the case, then this is an upper letter.
Now here is more interesting thing,
We can convert it to a lowercase, how? if you subtracted - A from it, it now becomes zero.
If you added 'a' for it, it now becomes 'a', what if this is D, D - A, it is going to be
I think 4, when you add the small 'a', is going to convert it to 'd' small.
So this is how you convert an uppercase to lowercase, in the same way you can convert the lowercase
to uppercase.
If you'd like to double-check if it's lower case, in a very similar case, we should say if ch1
is greater than or equal 'a' I'm sorry, this is 'a' small, up to character 'z'.  else here, if you'd like
to check if it's digit, also, digit, but digit as a character, you can say if it is '0' here up to
'9' here.
So the moral of that is, given that C++ implemented the characters as integers and they are also consecutive,
this means we can easily double-check the type of the character and we can also do conversion between
some of the types.
Please make sure that you understand what I said here.
Let's go back to to arrays and strings.
Remember, we did before something we called string name, like string name = "Hany" or "John" or whatever.
Now look to this very interesting access,
I'm saying name.size() and these two parentheses,
This is our first time to use
this style.
This is called a method or a member function.
And it's going to return for you the size of this array, which is here 4. we experienced before
the name here.
And I just would like you to memorize this syntax here for now.
You put the dot "." without spaces, then size, then these two parenthesis.
Now, if we know that this array is 4.
Check out this interesting syntax.
We say "for (int i = 0; i < sz; ++i).
cout << name[i];".
This is also going to print to the same one here, but is printing it letter by letter.
What is very interesting here for us is that we can deal with the string name as an array.
Why?
Because internally it is an array,
it is just a sequence of characters.
It is just a char array.
That's it.
And today it's a good chance to know how actually this string is represented internally.
This is mainly coming from C..
I would like here to represent array of integer.
We just do it this way,
Integer numbers of five "int numbers [5]", which means five numbers.
If we would like to create a double array, we create a double array.
What about character array?
It's also the same logic, we say char name1[5] =  Heni, wait a second, Hani
Here is 4 letters.
Why do we put 5?
We will know after a minute,
OK. but just keep in mind that, the length must be 1 + your expected size.
We can also use name3, all of them when printed would be just Hani,
OK. but this is more of C style and this is C++ style.
So let's go back to the story of the extra position, when we define character name1[4], C++
would like to give us this nice functionality of printing name1, when we were dealing with integer arrays, we never
did something like cout an array.
C++ wanted to give us a very conventional method to just cout a character name.
This is very interesting,
But where is the problem?
The problem is internally, C++ doesn't know actually the size of this array.
This has been reserved by the compiler in a way or another.
When we put the word Hani, and we try to output it, you see here, this means garbage
here.
Something wrong in the memory.
So C++ wanted us to tell the compiler when the string really ends, so this is where the null character
comes.
That's why we have 5 here not just 4, and we put here the backslash zero '\0'.
This is called the null character.
And this backslash, it is something called escape character,
We will know about it.
So now here you notice,
when we wanted to create 4 elements,
We needed to 5 elements.
we needed 5, and we needed to mark the null character here.
Let's make it more clear,
When the C++ compiler sees the null character in the runtime, it just stops printing.
For example, if someone came here at name1 and put this second letter with '\0', which
is a null character.
If we try to print name1, it is going to print only 'H' because the compiler at runtime will stop once it
saw the '\0'. so '\0' or the null character, its main purpose is being a Terminator.
It tells where to stop and when to stop.
That's it for today.