Homework set number two, in the first one very relevant to the previous problem, you will read a string
and compress it as following, you will compress each group to something like, let's say you have four "C"s,
then you compress to "c4".
And between different groups use underscore, for example, here we have four "C"s so write C4, three "D"s,
so write D3.
a lot of "X"s, X8, and one E, e1.
And we put exit,
we would underscore in the middle, here we have a lot of "X"s, so it's x8. In the second problem you
would like to read and compare two strings and you should develop that by yourself.
you will not use a < operator between two strings,
so you will read two strings, but you will do the comparison by yourself and follow
follow the way that we learned about how to compare two strings.
In this problem, you will read a very long string, but it would be at least of six digits and you would
like to add the number five five five to it.
You shouldn't try to convert it,
it is very, very, very long string to integer because it will exceed the maximum limit.
For example, if the input is like this number and you added the four fives, it should be like that
one.
So try to develop an algorithm that correctly handled this problem.
That's all.