Let's solve homework set number 2. The first one is compressing; the core of the idea is very, very
close to the grouping idea, but the code might be a bit problematic for you.
I'm writing it here in this way, which you might be a little more.
You probably can write it in less code, but maybe this is more organized.
Maybe.
The first trick here that I would like to teach is: sometimes we can alter the input to make our
life much easier.
When you try to develop this code, this problem, you would need that observe....
You might need extra handling for the last group in the input, if we would like our code to
be handling everything and we don't have to do something after the last inputs
here to verify one more last group.
This is a very nice idea to add an artificial thing to your string that can help you to make
sure that your same code is doing the same handling. Observe here in this problem,
the input is only letters.
So I can add this letter safely.
You have to make sure that you are not adding something that can be part of the input itself.
After that, I started to turn it on the string, but I started from one because this time you are not printing
letter by letter, we would print group by group.
So instead of keeping comparing if "i" not equal zero, we don't need that now.
So I started my first group with size one and then I started here from one.
And then you can keep going here.
Similar to the previous time.
If they are in equal letters then we have a new group.
Now we would like to separate the groups by underscore.
To do that I use the here this symbol letter;
If is_first_ group or not.
Very simple boolean.
If it's not the first group, we can always print the underscore.
Otherwise, if it's first time, we don't and we keep assigning this here to be zero to indicate it
isn't a first group anymore.
This way I handled the underscore between the groups in an easy way.
The remaining thing is just to print the current group, which is the previous character and the size
of it.
And remember that "i" is starting from one.
So "i" minus one would be a valid indexing.
Again, you might be able to write that in an easier way, but maybe this is clear enough.
Hopefully.
Yeah, let's stop here.