In this problem, we would like to convert 2 strings, which might be a bit problematic, maybe so
anyway, for me, first of all, I needed to initialize a variable size to be the smallest of the two
strings, the a and the b.
So I started with taking the size of a and if size is less than b, I take it from b. Now,
size is like the minimum between the a.size and b.size.
And there are two cases for me that I can differentiate.
I'm using "smaller" as a variable.
Maybe "smaller" isn't a good name.
Maybe good name. "smaller" here
if zero, it means it is really a[i] smaller. One, it means it's bigger.
If -1 , it means we are unsure.
I keep going over the string and compare letter by letter.
If they are not equal then we can compare.
If the first one is less then it,  we need to put smaller equals zero.
Otherwise, we got smaller equal one.
Maybe we can do this in a similar way and say if less than, put zero, otherwise,
put one. And this condition will help us to break once we have to break so that we don't keep going forever.
After that, there are one of three cases, either smaller is zero, which is done. smaller is one, which is done.
or smaller is still minus one, which means there is a complete match for the two strings together.
So the one that will be actually smaller is the one who is smaller in the length.
That's why I here after that I start to compare if the length of the first is a smaller then put it with
zero.
So it means the first one otherwise got the first one.
Finally, we print if smaller == zero, then the first one is  smaller, otherwise,
the second one. The big picture of the solution is to compare letter by letter until you are done or
you find the difference.
And after that handled the case of two strings with one of them completely equal prefix from the second
string.