This problem is just the stress on the addition of two numbers, having a carry, moving it from a number
to another and so on.
This is mainly the purpose of it.
To solve the problem, I started by reading the string, and to add the number to a second number, you
have to add from the right side of it.
That's why we will start to iterate.
But every time we get the digit from the end of it, "sz-1-i" is mainly the digit.
Removing minus zero is getting the actual data.
In the first of four iterations we can add the five because we have number that's five five five five.
So in the first four times we add the five.
So we think the digit let's say it is two and then we have the digit.
We add five to the digit.
Now it's seven.
But what if it was, for example, nine and you have a digit, for example, that's another eight?
For example, this is now 17.
So in math, we have to write seven and have a carry of one.
That's why we have here the carry initially zero.
But if the digit is greater than or equal 10 in math, we remove a ten and make it like a one carry.
To be added with us, otherwise, the carry is zero. At this moment, the is again, value from zero to nine.
So we get it back here to the array again and we keep going.
So the idea is get the next digit, add for over it five.
If there is a carry from the previous time, just add it and then we have here handling for the
new carry for us. The carry after every time we either would be one or would be just zero.
That's all mainly implementation and some math from the elementary school.
This code isn't very efficient
if the string is very huge like you can expect, for example, that you don't need to go maybe
more than maybe five or six iterations because at some point of time there are no more carry any more
and there is no more iterations anymore.
But I like to keep it simple to this point.