In this homework, we will develop an application for an employee system,
we have a factory of several employees that we would like to manage and we would like to have the following
ability: to add a new employee, print all of them,
delete someone by the age range, or update salary by given name, this program will keep running forever
and then the user take a choice from one to four to do these choices.
So let's let's get in more details for choice
number one, we would like to allow the manager to enter information of an employee.
The information is name, age, salary and gender letter, add the information to your
database, which is your internal memory for now.
printing all of them or, in the choice number three, you will take a start range and end range and remove
all of the employees that has this, that the age is within the start and the end.
in the fourth choice, the user enters a name, then salary, and then you update the salary of a person
of his name.
We are assuming here that names are symbols.
Let's see some screenshots, here
we have the menu of four choices.
The user entered one that I enter the name Mustafa age 3 blah blah blah and gender M, for
simplicity I use the names without spaces.
And then I added another name and then I asked for two, which is printing all of them please.
So two employees would be printed.
After that, we asked for four, which is updating salary by name.
You would enter a name which again doesn't have spaces and a salary.
If after that you try to print them, you will notice that the salary of Mustafa here changed
from thirty-three... from one, two, three, four, five to five hundred and five.
Finally, we would like to do a deletion by age so we enter a start and end the age
Then all of the employees in this range would be removed.
Observe here, Mona here within the range so it would be deleted, but Mustafa will remain for
us.
That's all the program is.
simple requirements do not complicate things for yourself and try to make it just that simple.