Let's see how to solve the employee application, which is a simple application at this stage.
First of all, we need some storage for our data.
We have names, ages and salaries.
So I created 4 arrays that correspond to our needs, and I use some artificial maximum here of 10000.
And I have a variable here to refer to the number of added employees so far. Like any program that
needs to keep printing forever and also have a menu, I have a while loop here working forever.
And I have a list here of four choices presented to the user and a choice that we read from the user.
In the future, we will learn how to handle in a proper way the failure in the inputs; the user  might input string
for you might input something that's completely invalid.
How to handle that? in the future
we'll learn about that. Now for a basic verification,
I'm just checking if the choice is between one and four or not. Observing here the syntax;
this is the target condition.
Like I need to make sure that the choice is greater than one or equal to it and less than equal four. After that,
I'm just putting a note here to not all of this expression.
This expression can be not by also noting this one by itself
and noting this one by itself
and switching the and to or, this is how we can flip a complete expression.
After that, we just go if it's choice number one, we started to read the name and the age and the
salary and gender, we read them directly in the array depending on the counter.
But after that, we have to increment the counter here.
If the choice is 2, we just iterate and start to print the data that we have.
And observe here I have an if condition that say if age doesn't equal minus one, what
happened is we will have a delete operation from here.
And I don't want to mess up with the array at the moment.
So I will just mark some elements with minus one as a deleted.
So we call that lazy delete.
Lazy delete means that you can actually make a delete operation
you just like make it in a very lazy way.
Lazy initialization and lazy deleting are something very common in the industry.
So if it exists, we will just print it.
And here is the third
choice, if the user would like to remove an age based on a range came to print the start
and end.For simplicity,
I assume the user would be a good one, just entering a small start after it can end one and start to less than
small.
Then I iterate over all of the employees and if his age is between this range, I mark it with minus
one, which is a marking for a removal of this person.
And finally, if we'd like to make an update based on name and salary, then I read the name and salary
and then I iterate and try to find him.
If the person isn't removed and there is a match for the name we mark that we found him, update the salary
and break. If not found, we just give a message that not found.
I hope overall that was a fair example for you.
The more we go in the course, you will have more of like harder programs and many other
courses we call such a simple program like a project
but this is actually a mini assignment.
I would like you to be familiar with that because the project, the course will end up with codes up
to like...,  in an optimal way.
The last project is like a one thousand two hundred lines of code.
You probably will write it in two or three thousand lines of code.
And this is a lot, but it would be a very decent teaching experience for you.