Let's discuss more points about the char array.
The first is reading, we used to read the string array, the string here, and we used to read it without
spaces.
Now, an interesting thing, what if I would like to input something like I am Mostafa, this is
a string that has spaces.
If we use the normal cin and we have to read three different words, what if I would like to read
all of it. C++ introduces the "reading line" idea.
So you do that using something called "getline".
But if you're reading the string, it is different from using a character array. in a string, you just say
"getline(cin, name1)" and then just "cout << name1"
that's it. Here,
In our case, it just be "cin.getline(name2, 50)", and you have to give it a specific length and
define the length
here, you can even give less than that.
So this is how you can read a line in C++.
Yeah, what about creating array of strings ? this is now going to be little more, like, complex,
like we saw an array of integers, array of characters and we can even create array of strings.
So this now, like "Mostafa Saad", "Never Ever", "Hello world", these are three different statements.
Every one of them is in a statement by itself.
If we try to print them, we can print them.
So I would like you here to notice something,
We have an array of 5 items,
Every one of them is an array.
This looks like an array of arrays.
And we will introduce later something interesting, called multidimensional arrays.
OK, in a similar way, we can read array of strings, like we have a string name[2],
We have two numbers,
We can just cin>>names[i].
What else, the escape characters, yeah, we saw this \0 and we named it.
We named it the null character.
This is part of something big called "the escape characters" here are some of the interesting escape characters.
We also know the \n, which is just new line, there is something called \t, which is tab
like if you said "hello \t world", it is going to print a tab.
Tab is a bunch of spaces defined in the tool.
Also what if you would like to print a double quote "" in the string.
You cannot do that without a \, so the compiler can differentiate if this is the ending double quote
or not.
Character VS string.
The character array is more of a C style.
You need to carefully handle the null and other things.
The string, the string isn't a primitive.
The string is a class.
This is something that we will study later, is more of C++ side.
Like we say, string name , notice here
I didn't put the equal.
This is the C++ initialization style.
It's part of something called stl library.
We are going to learn it later, and we'll learn more C++ capabilities like it supports, for example
Addition, comparisons.
We already did that, so please use it.
You will rarely need to use the C-style-character-array, but we need to introduce it.
I would like you to go and practice what we just said, and be careful with the (getline).
For example, when you getline a line, you're reading some characters, but you are stopped before
\n.
If you wanted to read two getline after each other, then you probably would need to read and empty another
getline to read the \n. go ahead and play with it, before ending.
I would like to introduce some concepts that we use when it comes to strings, something called the
prefix and suffix, substring and sub-sequence, a prefix is any string that starts from the first
characters.
For example, if you have, let's say this string: "aaa...blabla", the 'a' here is a prefix, 'aa'
is a prefix, 'aaa' is a prefix,
'aaab' is a prefix, any string
that starts from the beginning and ends somewhere is called a prefix.
The suffix is the other side, it is the ending.
So here with 'g' is a suffix, 'gg' is suffix, 'fgg' is a suffix, 'efgg' is another suffix and so on.
A sub-string is like the sub-array,
It should be consecutive.
So for example we can say 'aab' this is a sub-string or a sub-array.
The last one is a sub-sequence.
Sub-sequence isn't consecutive but must be in order.
For example, the next letter must have a bigger index.
An example of that might be, take this 'A' with this 'B' with this 'F' and this 'G'.
So this way, it is a sub-sequence.
These are 4 definitions that we use in our discussions.
Finally, practicing a character array is exactly the same as practicing an array.
We didn't introduce a new thing.
We really needed to introduce the null character and the difference between it and the string array.
For example, you can reverse a string, you can say if a string is palindrome or not and so on. it just
you might need some conversion between characters or so. That's it.