Let's do some practice on the character arrays.
The first one is a concatenation task.
You are going to read two different strings and concatenate them, but in a bit a special way.
Here is an example,
Let's say you are reading something like "AM CICBC", you take the first letter from this one, then
the first letter from this one, and then the second letter from this one, then the second letter from
this one and so on.
If one of them is done, then you just add the remaining of the string.
Don't create new strings, don't change the input content, maybe just like a printing or so.
Here is how to do that,
We first need to figure out the length of the two strings, which one is like the max size that we have.
now here we keep the maximum size between the first string and the second string, notice
here we use the .size function.
Now iterate over whole max length.
We know in the best case there would be some letter from the first and some letter in the second.
If there is more letters here from the first, print it, of there is more letters here from the second, just to print it.
This way, you can concatenate them step by step.
And this way you can handle easily the difference in sizes.
Another problem is the frequency of a string, you are to read the string that will have different letters
of upper and lower, ignore that, the fact that they are upper letters and compute the frequency of lower letters.
So, for example, reading this string, then we are ignoring the three capital letters here,
and computing the frequency of the remaining of the letters.
So 'a' appeared three times, 'b' once and 'z' two times, stop the video and try to create it by yourself
remember the frequency array, so we can make our life easier by creating a frequency array big enough
to cover the small and capital letters, initialize all of them to zeros, iterate over the string and
just compute the frequency, come to the character [i] and just increment to the frequency of it.
By the end of that, we have the frequency actually of the whole string, even lower and
upper cases. after that we want to print only the lower cases.
So one easy trick is just to iterate from the letter 'a' to the letter 'z' if there is some frequency here
just print character i and print the frequency [i], notice here I casted the integer i
to character to be printed like a character.
This program can be done in several ways, but I think this is one of the easy ways to do that.
A special mapper, or like people doing encoding and decoding, you are to read the string and you are to
do the following conversions, if this is an upper letter, don't change it, if it is a lower letter you are
to use the following map,
These are the lower letters and this is a conversion map.
So we are converting letter 'a' to letter 'Y', letter 'b' to letter 'Z', letter 'z' to letter 'L' capital, and so
on.
So this is your conversion,
whenever you find a small letter, you convert based on the corresponding one. in a similar way,
if you found some digits from 0 to 9, you are to use this conversion to convert it.
So if this is the input, we are going for letter-by-letter to do conversions except the capital letters
'M' and 'N'.
here, they are the same here. again,
Think about that.
OK, here is one very nice way to do that.
First of all, I started with putting all the lower letters and in another string, the corresponding
one, and then the digits and their corresponding one, I created - let's call it a map here -, I'm
creating a map and I'm iterating on the (from) and from every letter in the (from) I'm saying
What should we map to it?
For example, I'm saying here, letter map of 'a' -small 'a'- to 'Y' capital, letter map of '9' to the closing
parenthesis ')'.
So by the end of that, letter map can help me easily to convert from a letter to another.
After that we would iterate on the whole input string,
If it's a capital letter just ignore it, otherwise change it from the map.
I expect you that you try to iterate in this string and find the corresponding one
and do it,
This is good.
But as you see here, this trick is just saving us a lot of computations.
It takes time to learn how to come up with smart and nice ideas.
That's it.