Homework set number one for the character arrays, in the first problem we would like to check if two
strings are prefix or not.
Remember, when something is prefix, it should be coming here as an early character of it,
so for example, ABCDE is prefix of an ABCDE, on the other side EFG isn't prefix of ABCDE.
In the second one, the opposite,
we would like it to be suffix, to check if it is suffix or not,
so ACD does it end here?
No.
Does ABCDEF end here?
Does this string end with EFG?
Yes.
So this is a suffix for it.
So suffix means ending with this string.
the "Is substring" means it's somewhere in the middle and this means that it could be prefix or suffix
or something in the middle, which make it more yeses here.
Now looking to that ABCD is a prefix, ABCDEF  is another prefix, EFG is a suffix,
so good to, DEFG is something also suffix BCD is here, a substring and so on.
The last one is a subsequence and subsequence is like a bigger scope than all of them.
So all of them now are subsequence,
which you mean the letters should exist in the same order as here, for example.
A, C, E, G.
All of them are in order, here for example the GD aren't suffix because they doesn't follow order, G
is in ending and B is in the beginning.
...in the middle,
so it doesn't work this way,
converting a number you would read a string of six letters maximum convert it to integer, then print
two things, the number and the number multiplied by three.
For example, if the input of a string hundred you need to print hundred and three hundred.
If the string is zero, two hundred, you need to print 200 and 600, so mainly convert string to integer
and then print it, you have to do the conversion by yourself.
Grouping, you will read N string, then divided to consecutive groups of the same letter and
then each group, for example, here you'll notice the first three characters are same one one, one,
then three, two, two, two, two "A"s, three "B"s, here
all of them are of the same group,
so: read, divided, print them
separated. That's all.