Let's see how to implement the codes for the homework.
Number one here, the Is Prefix  method.
Our first function, the idea is pretty simple.
I would like, first of all, to get rid of an annoying test case when the "small_str" is bigger
than the "big_str".
And you should develop such test case by yourself to make sure that it is valid like most of my test
cases provided in the file.
The big_str was really the big.
But what if the small is big?
You should make sure that your code doesn't fail. To get rid of,
this test case here,
We are just handling it first.
Now, from now on, we are assuming that the small_str or the prefix is really the smaller one.
To make the check, all what we need is to iterate from the beginning on the small one and keep comparing
with the big one.
If it happens that at any point of time it doesn't match, then we just say "NO", it doesn't match
and return here.
Otherwise. if we reach this line of code, it makes that all of the current matches are correct.
So also so now we print the "YES".  Another hidden test case that you will not be able to test easily;
What if the two strings are empty strings?
The answer should be yes.
And all of the four problems, the prefix, suffix, and so on. So also make sure that your code seems
working while for these test cases.
For example, you can assign both of them for empty strings and make sure that they are working
well.
So this is for the first problem.
The second problem would like to test the suffix, which is the opposite of it.
So this is the suffix,
We need very similar logic.
Handling the big test case first and then we need to compare from the end.
It might end up from you couldn't get in an ugly way.
So I tried here to make as much as I could something that is well reading; well readable.
Remember that your colleagues will need to read your code and understand it in the company.
So try to make sure that your code is readable, is really easy to read.
So what I did here is I created two integers:
big_end and small_end, pointing to the last element in the array of both of them.
And then by iterating with the length of the small size, I'm comparing the end of the guy with
the end of the guy and this variable is decreasing and this variable is decreasing in the same time.
So very peaceful way.
Yeah.
So this is a nice way to do it.