The third problem in that is Substring problem, which might be a bit harder than the first and the
second. The problem in the substring problem, we can have a match anywhere in the string.
So we need to know to do like a brute force.
We need to try every possible thing.
That's why I'm starting here, to try every possible position in big_str,
so "i" is every possible string.
And then for the small string, we will iterate on j with the small string.
And I start to compare the big to the small one, for example, let's say that the
big one is aabcd and the small one is for example abc.
Now I need to try the aab with abc and then try abc with abc, then try bcd
with abc.
So that's what I mean by trying every possible position.  Observe that the last
possible position to try is from bcd
doesn't make any sense to convert from c because cd would be only two letters and this guy is three
letters.
That's why here I am actually trying to decide what is the last position to stop.
And this is simply we need to stop....; we do need to iterate more
if the length of the end of the string is less than this one,
we do need to keep going.
So I'm here subtracting the length of the small_str
from the big_str to count for that. Observer that this is one-based string and this
is one-based size, one-based minus one-based would be zero-based that's why I'm adding here
a +1 make sure it is valid.
If you would like to think in terms of low boundary, think that this is one letter and this is one
letter.
So one minus one is zero, plus one is very important to iterate at least one step.
Also, if the two strings are empty, this would be zero and zero then plus one would
also get inside but still would be valid.
It is very important when you are dealing with the size to cast two integers. Somewhere in the course,
I will tell, I will let you know what's happening
if you didn't cast this integer with an empty string, it will work for infinity.
So always cast for now, this integer here at avoid problems.
Now let's say that we have this position
"i" and I would like to match the internal substring with it.
I'm just going to iterate over the small_str and compare the current small_str with the
big_str. If it doesn't match, our marking is matched with false.
If it happen that one string is done correctly,
once everything is done correctly then we have in his match with True. we see out "YES" and just return.
That's all about this one.