For the Is Subsequence problem, it can be solved in a nice way.
I hope it wasn't so hard for you.
The idea is based on matching.
Let's say let's say we have here a string like aaabcd
Let's say the target string is, for example, it is only b, and d. it seems we would like this b to be
matched with this b and this d needs to be matched with this d so the idea you start from the a and
check if it matched with b or not, if it matches, you mark that you match at the first letter, second
letter and so on.
So here does a match the first? No.  Does a match? No. does a match? No.  Does B match?
Yes.
Then now we are here would like to match with the d. Does c match? No. Does d match?
Yes we are here so we are done with the string.
So the idea is to iterate on the big string and try to keep matching with the small one.
So here is the next to_match here.
The next match position in the small_str
is zero. I am iterating on the big one and then I'm comparing if the current big match the current
small if it matched a current letter, we increase the match.
If it happens that we are done with the whole small string, then we will have completely found a subsequent
otherwise,
the case is no, there are different cases here.
You might, for example, match all of these small substring, but still more letters to match.
So it will end up here and so on.
So, yeah, I hope you understood this.
Nice idea.