To convert a string to a number, we will just go in a very, very, very simple way and we will just
iterate on the string and convert it to integer.
To do that, let's refresh something.
If you have five digits, like one, two, three, four, five. I would like to convert 12345
The way to do that in math is to keep multiplying with 10 and adding a digit, for example, starting with
one. One times 10 is 20, add the next digit 2.
Now we have 12, 12 times 10 is one hundred and twenty adds the plus.
It is what now?
123 multiplied by ten and add four. it's now
1234 multiplied by ten, add five.
It's 12345.
So we actually all what we need is to keep iterating five steps. In every step,
we take the current number, multiply it by ten and add the current digit.
The digit is in a string format.
If you would like to extract the corresponding integer of it, we can just subtract a zero digit from
it because the digits...,  the characters are from zero to nine matches the character from zero to 90 integers.
Just we need to remove this zero because it will have some value let's say maybe 50.
I forget the actual number.
So this is how we convert a character digit to an integer digit and then we keep adding it.
Once we are done with that.
Once we are done with that, then the one number would be converted.
And the second problem would like to do the grouping
of the numbers here. To do that, we will simply iterate on the string, and whenever the current letter
doesn't match the previous letter, we know we have a new group.
But be careful if you are at "i" equal to zero, then there are no groups at the moment.
So if this is the case, we separate them by spaces, otherwise we just print the current letter.
So this how we can split the groups with the spaces in an easy way.