We learned the pointers in C++, which allow us for a direct management, for the memory, like educating
and educating is very strong, but also very dangerous.
Remember the initialised memory, the memory leaks and the dangling pointers, a lot of issues.
I try to help you with the simple rule and educational rule.
I say like who creates a memory deleted something like if you are inside the class, you created a memory,
then use that structure to delete it.
If you are outside the class and some function and you created a memory, try to delete it.
However, this is still very problematic.
For example, what if a function is returning some pointer?
Who is supposed to delete that?
What if there is an exception in the middle of some competitions?
Are we sure that everything is released or not?
So there is a lot of good here to handle the the issues of the role pointers and a lot of issues that
could just go out of the hand, out of the control.
C++ in the modern sense, C++ 11 and then enhance it in 14 and 17 is providing us with what we call
these multiple pointers in languages like Java.
And they have a very strong mechanism called garbage collector.
And in these languages, programmers totally don't care about the memory leaks and dangling pointers
to a large extent, like everything is well handled in this language.
C++ try to like provide a mechanism to do this garbage collection style, what we call the smart goiters
smart appointers.
All of it is about providing smart and automatic memory management.
For your point that, for example, if your pointer is now out of its scope, we are just also deleting
it.
So again, why smart pointers to automatically delete the pointers?
So you are creating pointers, but you don't delete them.
It is a lot of debates about these portable as a garbage collector collection.
The relationships on all of that, this out of scope for now.
I would like you in the far future to come back and read a little about that in C++.
There are three smart pointers.
Share the pointers since C++ even and weak pointers since C++ even ubiquitous also since C++.
But there are some enhancements in for team.
There is also in the best what is good or 2.0.
But this is now removed in 2017.
You don't need to study it at all.
So let's learn about that.