Let's start with the pointer.
Let's, first of all, share some of the information about all of this, might some pointers?
First of all, every smart pointer is a class that is managing a pointer.
You can imagine it like that.
There is some class that is named the Unique Pointer.
And here is our internal data that we would like to create, but we don't want to delete any more by
ourself.
So we have some class unique pointers that have this data inside it and it has a structure to delete
it.
So when I say a smart pointer, unique pointer, the pointer, I mean, it's actually a pointer.
The class name is Pointer.
OK, so don't confuse a smart pointer.
Is it a pointer is actually an object that has a pointer data inside it and remember and a smart appointers,
you create them but you do not delete them.
The usage of the pointers are very close to the rule pointers like using the asterisk or the the the
arrow greater than a symbol.
I forget the name of that symbol.
So more about the the the unique pointers so that this will be an cheat.
The word unique here means it is one.
There is only one owner.
For one, it points to it.
So we have here the internal data integral pointer and there are no other pointers who can see and accept
this data in a direct way.
They cannot.
So to try to get the intuition behind that, if we have a pointer that only a single object is managing
it, we are avoiding a lot of trouble about the destruction of the multi threading axis, about exceptions,
about a lot of things.
So this is the moral of the word unique.
There is only one ownership to to to achieve that.
We cannot allow the assigning or copying of the pointer of the object here, this much weaker object.
So there is no implicit constructor, there is no copy constructor, there is no operator assignment
equal.
All of that is done to cancel the ability to steal or to exit this internal pointer internally.
The unique pointer is implemented in a very efficient way and in the market.
This is a pointer that you should try to use like 80 or 90 percent of your time.
It is very safe.
It avoids you a lot of trouble.
So let's see some creation example here.
We need to include memory to get the smart pointer.
So the first way here, I'm here creating new integer array using some direct initialization here.
And then you say unique pointer integer.
So it's like you are saying, well, I would like a unique pointer of time into it and that's it.
So what, what do we have here?
We have an object, not a pointer named to be one of type unique pointer which is the end, and its
internal data is now a new integer array here.
And you integer value, you integrate pointer value.
So we have an object that is managing this integrator.
Now, when we see the following, you cannot do something like a unique pointer.
B one equals you end twenty.
These two things are different.
The new end is type and the unique pointer is another time for that to be allowed.
You need an implicit constructor that allows something like that.
But internally, only explicit constructor is used in pointer and pointer to disallow this usage of
this.
So now we created the B1 pointer.
We can like the very normal robo inter.
We can say, oh, it has to be one which will bring the twenty.
I can say astrobee one equal fifty, which is going to do just printed.
Now, here, let's say, I would like to reset the pointer, like changing it to point to something
else, not this new 20 something totally complete, one might say, okay, let's do be one equal at
30.
This is a new pointer.
Now, the unique pointer doesn't allow the ability for equal assignment.
It doesn't allow to assign it.
If you would like to do that, you have to call the reset function.
That is a function internally is going to delete the current pointer and use a new pointer.
So, again, now you can use a new pointer.
What's going to happen in this code once this function go out of the school, be one internally will
destroy its new integer here, the thirty one.
So as you see here, we created the pointer, but we didn't delete it.
And this is a great advantage of the smart pointer you create.
But you didn't leave the syntax a little bit verbose.
Might be a little bit annoying, but otherwise it just handed the deletion for you could be constructed
in a very similar way.
You cannot use a copy constructor.
So let's say that we have here the unique pointer.
Be one of you.
And twenty one might say, OK, let's create another pointer.
B two of B one.
This is a copy constructor.
Again, the copy constructor isn't allowed.
So there are three things that are allowed.
You can use it, use an implicit constructor, you can use that.
You cannot use the copy constructor, you cannot use the assignment operator.
All of that is done to protect as much as possible the internals of the unique pointer.
OK, what if I would like to really give my content to someone else?
Now you have to use some of semantics.
So if you did something like unique points of P2, equal move would be one.
What's going to happen is the C++ is going to move the internal array of B1 to be two in a very efficient
way.
But notes that once we are done with this line and line 15 B.
B.
So this is byone don't use BE1 anymore because BE1 is now is in the value of Bittu.
OK, so B one is gun, like you cannot use it anymore.
So the move semanticist move the content from here to B to.
You can if you try to doublecheck here, if you want equity control pointer, we can do the comparison.
Normally the answer would be, yeah, it is, it's now nailbiter.
That's why we shouldn't use it, because we moved it to content to be to what if I would like to force
a delete.
You can say here equal Boynton's is the only case when you can assign something.
So it's kind of an exception and more popular is to use the reset function like that.
But again, you don't have to do this delete.
It is going to be done automatically
to stress on the idea that the unique pointer is actually an object.
I would like to remember if it's an object and it has its own address.
But remember, inside it there is a pointer.
And from the pointer, you know, there are two addresses.
There is an address for the pointer itself and there is an address for the where where the winter is
looking.
This means that we have three addresses I'm just showing you here.
So how to get that?
The C++ allows you to call it to get function to get the pointer.
Typically, you should avoid doing that.
You should avoid that.
I would like to see that when we needed to get we didn't use the arrow.
We use the dot function here.
OK, so now we have three addresses.
The row pointer itself has its value and address one another.
So as we used to that the object itself B has also its own address.
You can also call the function at this of B if you would like to give the the address.
So as I said, that unique point, that is an object.
It has its own address.
So that makes its word with a pointer like it's a pointer.
Actually, it isn't just an object.
That's it.