Let's continue more on unique pointers.
We would like to see some cases where we are trying to pass a unique pointer to a function the first
way, as you know, we have several ways to get something very valuable, a reference by the semantic
and so on.
So the first one here is passing by a unique point.
If we'd like to best buy value so you can hear to hear some reference.
Now, there's an issue here, how to Bashira unique pointer.
And we said that there should be only one pointer who is handling the Internet data.
Then this again would need a would need a move semantic notice here and all of the function and trying
to verify that the B is a null pointer.
So be careful from that.
In the second case, we have here, the difference of B now, this is very this is very normal, like
it's OK to pass the unique pointer here by reference.
Notice that one might say, oh, but this now means that there are two pointers who are looking to the
Internet data.
No, this isn't true.
The Internet data is looking by the same object we have in here, an alias for it.
So B here is the same as a caller.
We are looking to the same thing.
What are the consequences of providing a function with a reference?
It means that someone might destroy our data.
So when you are using such a function, do you really mean it to be very careful if you intend to do
that later, because you are passing also by reference, but you are using this time.
So as we are using colourist here, we we cannot we can definitely again, still believe with the pointer
value here, but we cannot assign it to a different value.
We cannot reset it.
So they could hear about this case that no one can store or play with the actual pointer itself of the
object, but they can play with the internals, like changing its value in a similar way.
We can use the best thing, like our value reference, like the semantic and as we know, this would
allow you to best buy a temporary value or to use movimiento everybody like here.
So let's see A uses you for that.
These are the three functions we discussed I had define the B1 normal way.
I also hear took a difference of B2 over B1.
This is okay this is just LSP one B two are the same thing.
Now if I tried to call Brint one of B2 with this function is going to give compiler error.
Why would this now involve a copy constructor.
You are trying to copy this to, to the B is going to combine because we are just allowing the copy
constructor.
The way here is to move the B2 from here to this guy.
But be careful once the this function is done B to here is garbage.
OK, let's reset it now because we did hear a remove here.
I can now kolby to to this guy.
This is working very well.
Why.
Because B here is by reference, so no problem at all.
But notice that I cannot call Brint.
It was a move.
There is no need to do that.
But in case y because the function here Brinda two is using reference but is incorrect.
And as I said, if there is a temporary variable like the one coming, remove this one need to be reference.
I need to be honest.
That's why the case of Brinda three is going to work very well for you.
Returning from a function is a bit special case like thinking here about the good pointer.
You are returning it from the function to taking it here.
It means, practically speaking, two things are looking to the two things are looking to the to the
data now.
But but in C++, we know that this one is going to really be destructed.
So with some moving here sematic, we can just get me out of here and put it here.
So it's OK to return any pointer.
The right way to use unique pointers isn't to create them in the in the way like it in as we did C++
encourage you and we will refer to that more later.
Do you something we called Make Unique, Make Unique is a helper function that helps you to create a
unique object.
So how to how to do that?
You define this part, you use equal or maybe précis, and then you call the mechanic and then you are
using here the same template as the object here and here embraces.
You are going to you are going broke is here.
You are going to use that the parameters to initialize something.
For example, if it is an integer, you say now here like a constructor aside and give it to any.
In a if you would like to make a shorter sentence, you can use the altar now because this function
knew about the data type.
So can you just use it to be three make unique of 20?
This is actually how we do it all the time in the in the market.
Now, I would like to to to stress the meaning.
I would like to show you how to do it with a class.
Let's say we have a class embley that have two parameters.
Now I would like to call the Mikuni if I would like to do it in the normal way, I'm going to create
a unique pointer over amply and then here create an object of ability and the values for it.
I would like to make unique that I'm going to make unique, use the same template and then open the
braces and start to give it the parameters.
So think of the parameters here of the make unique function as the same parameters as your object.
Now again, notice number here is a pointer.
If you would like to access it, then you have to deal it with the pointer.
So for example, you say here brain is going to print, but if you would like to access the functionality
of a unique pointer itself, then you have to use the douget.
So the arrow is handling what you are pointing to it, but the DOT is handling the object of your pointer.
It's up from now on.
I would like you to get use of the make unique function that it.