Let's continue our talk about unique pointers.
We would like to see how to make a point to energy, for example, when you can use a unique pointer
and here in the template we give it integer array.
Then we say B1 Iqua, new interval or you end of end with the parameters.
Or we can use a unique function and this is how we should use it.
Now, there is a question here.
Are these the same like are you want me to be three or three reasons?
It does not exactly be one here is creating a memory and it didn't initialize it.
So in fact, Fuster one, both B2 and B3 are initializing the whole array with some value.
Typically zero here in practice, by the way, is the L would be enough like you need to use unique
pointer over integrate.
In my opinion, you need to do that.
But just in some cases and some like memory management cases or also because the vector is a bit slow,
people don't use the vector, they use the report.
But but typically you do need to make a unique pointer overlay, if you would like now to iterate to
initialize this array to a value you can just say for integrase visit and then just about the value.
I would like you to be careful from defining it this way.
If you decided to define it like you return it to a new integer five, but you are having you just end
this integral pointer, but this integrated array, so this would have undefined behavior, probably
would cause a memory leak.
So this is integer, this is just integer, but this entire array is integral.
I would like to go back to this initialization track.
Let's say that you really have a big array and you have to use a new pointer over this array and you
would like to avoid the default initialization because the Beslow.
So you now define to be one in this way.
New end is just creating the memory and use it.
Now, let's say that you would like to initializes very fast this something I didn't talk about it before
the meme said memes, it is a function in coming from the C language that is very fast initialization
intellectualise, character by character internee.
Look here at line line thirty eight, if you have a character is to r you can say meme's it is to R
later t size of this is going to initially initialize every assign every letter here to character in
a very fast way.
We can do the same thing with integrity types only for two values, zero at one.
And please notice the syntax you use.
First of all, we got here the rule pointer so that because we would like to initialize it, I say it,
meme's it, give it the pointer, give it the value which could be zero or sorry, this is minus one,
zero is minus one.
And now I'm saying in times of integer, I'm thinking here the the the number of memory items that it's
going to assign.
So I'm standing here, get the size of interent multiplied within.
When we do that, it's going to assign initialize aside the overlay to minus value, minus one value.
So the moral of that is it's in some in some cases, if someone would like to the very first initialization
for specific cases, he can get the pointer and just use Mxit.
If you get confused from the set and its usage, just skip it for now.
I know that you will not be able y to know why.
Just zero minutes.
What are the valid values at the moment?
Also using a unique pointer, which is the L is a bit problematic.
So be careful.
Let's say that we have a vector of unique pointers.
We can push back on the fly, something like make unique of seven.
Now the move semantic is going to handle that.
But if you have a pointer B what?
You can just push it here because it's going to take a Kobie using constructor, which isn't a zero.
You have to use a B one by yourself with the move function.
Let's use another example here.
There is something in C++ that is named Ambanis back, which is doing something in place, construction.
Even without the move, it's very efficient.
Something good, new placement.
You can also you can also use Imbursement back with moving or with the normal way.
The more of that just seamless back is more efficient than the wish back.
There is something interesting in C++ 17, when you push back some pointer, you can take a reference
over it in the same time.
This is just that.
Use one line of code.
Don't do that in C++.
Fourteen, it will not work.
It gives you would like to iterate on a vector of unique pointers.
You have to use the difference.
You cannot move it, remove it because it's going to make a copy and which isn't allowed.
So iterating on a vector, you have to use the reference.
There is a memory leak here, so be careful from from that.
Now, you shouldn't use that, but I'm just telling you about it, the release function in the winter
is releasing the pointer for you and giving you the responsibility to remove it.
So if you could release is going to give you the internal pointer.
Now, be one is null pointer.
So now you have to remove the bee by yourself.
You should then use the release function.
I'm just warning you, in case you just by mistake use it or you have very, very specific scenario.
This is the only case when you have to delete the pointer.
Borshoff also be careful from the situation we have here, Integral Pointer Bee and we give it to to
two unique pointers.
You can do that.
But notice this is a is going to be a dangling pointer.
The first pointer would remove Bee is OK.
The second one would cause a runtime error.
So as you see, we can do a lot of problems still with smart pointers.
Just look at the scene, and I already say that before the behind the scene, the smart operators are
just grabbing for the internal data in this way once you go to that school.
This one is going to destructed object.
This mechanism is known as R Eye, and the model of it is just grabbing the resource by this way to
reduce the hassle of destroying it, even feel free to think about.
Let's implement my own unique pointer class and do this stuff by yourself.
That's it.