Another interesting type of pointers is this should the pointer remember in the unique pointer, we
have only one object, that manager and the control the object and never, ever provided to others in
a straightforward way in the short pointers, we can now have actually multiple references pointing
to the same object and implementation wise.
This means that the copy constructor, seven operators are going to be enabled.
Now, how is that is is managed in the memory with with with every reference that is pointing to the
object is going out of the school, the pointer is going to be deleted.
This is something that's happening behind the scene, but still good to know about it.
The mechanism in the C++ is named as reference accounting.
The idea is very simple.
You're sure the pointer has an internal counter?
Initially with zero when you create an object is no one with every object that Tica could be using to
reconstruct assignment operator, the counter is going to be incremented plus plus.
And with every object go out of the school or deleted, the counter goes minus minus behind the scene.
Once the compiler runtime figured out that the object, the counter becomes zero, this means that there
is no object at all pointing to this object.
So now we can simply automatically remove the object over all the functionality of the pointer is very
close to the facilities of the unique pointer.
So what we learned would be valid.
I'm not going to duplicate all what we learned.
I just would like to highlight the differences here about the Jefferson County.
So terms of creation, it is very similar.
You have the original short pointer.
You again cannot use the equal here like the assignment or so, but you can use now here the copy constructor,
which would be OK if you have a pointer, you can use a seminal now.
So now looking to here we have one B to be three.
They are all share the pointers, share the pointer.
So if we try to assign the value one to five and we bring to the value of the three ones of here, then
all of them would have the value of five.
That's why they are all shared.
They are all looking to the same memory, similar to the unique make unique function that is also make
sure the function is used to make sure the function as much as possible.
This is, let's see, the should the count to be more familiar of this reference count idea.
Let's create here a pointer B one.
Now, if we try to say beyond don't just count, this would give you the total count.
So far that we have.
So this is going to be one.
Now I'm going to use a create another object B2 with constructor from B one.
This is going to if we try to to bring to the use count of both of them, it would be the same.
And both of them now two, because there are two objects who are looking to the object.
Let's get in the school year and create a third object, B three a.m. B, three to be two.
If we try to bring to the use count number to be three because B one and B to be three are all using
the object.
Now the could function one checking the function, given it is a function that is passing by value.
This means that the B one is going to be constructed using a copy constructor from B two, if we try
to bring it here as a use count, is going to be four because now there are three objects here and fourth
one here that has an object.
Once we return it from the function and we try to bring to the count is going to be three because this
object now is as went out of its school.
So this one doesn't exist.
That is the function again is three.
What about calling go to go to it function by reference.
So there is no copy here.
If you try to print it, it would be again three because we didn't create a new object here.
Once we go out of the scope here, B three is going to be destroyed.
So the counter is going to be reduced to two and two.
This would be one with null pointer.
Now we will be lost.
One more pointer.
So now the counter would be two is going to be one.
There's only one here wants to be to go out of the school.
Then the the the counter would be minus minus zero.
So overall it can be the allocated automatically from the memory.
The usage of the pointers was Vector's is very straightforward, not like the unique pointers we have
here.
OK, let's try to do a nice thing here.
There's something in C++ could type if you can bring any type that you would like, maybe like a big
statement and you say typedef this type to this name, it means every time you see this word, consider
it like that.
So I can say here are going to be one when you are just doing it for fun, like for you to just tell
you something else.
Here, the U.S. is one, if you push the three copies of that in vector, they use count is going to
be four, three and said the vector and one outside it.
If we clear to the victor, the count is going to back to one.
So the use of the victor with winter is very straightforward.
You can follow over it using the reference or you can look for it without the reference as you like.
Now, there's an interesting thing here to the casting as we started in the of inheritance polymorphism,
you might sometimes have to do that one casting from the from the base close to the beer and the glass.
So let's say we created here an object of type, Embley, but we put it in a shared object of type person.
So a person here has been in class with virtual function.
If you would like to do the down casting, you have to use something good dynamic pointer cost.
If you did this casting, you are going to take a child one of type embley here.
And if you try to to to bring to the count of both of them is going to show you two and two in a similar
way.
You can also use a static with cast, but in unique you cannot do that.
You cannot do the dynamic intercourse y because this means there will be two who have an object of your
of your class.
And the unique pointer doesn't allow that.
The only way to do around that is just look around like you bring the pointer from inside it with the
get and do the normal dynamic, just as we did in the past.
So this is definitely like you should avoid that is like that, but sometimes this isn't avoidable.
Notice that if you try to do the dynamic first with the shield, the pointer, the reference account
will be will not be incremented because you are now playing with your provider's.
Also, you shouldn't try to delete any of these guys because because they are eventually handled internally.
Remember, we only use the delete once when we have to do.
Is that the release function?
I would like to highlight something about the concurrency.
We didn't study concurrency and it's an advanced topic, but I want it in this place to.
But for the sake of completeness, something about it, if you didn't get it, this is totally, completely
OK.
The moral of the concurrency is that the same code is is in a, in a, in a in the same time was more
than one thing in the same program.
OK, this is a bit puzzling for you, so please escape if you couldn't get me.
Generally speaking, shearwaters are safe as long as you're using the value could be a move.
But once you started to use the reference is going to make problems and unsafe.
So you have to be very careful about Bessin.
You're sure the pointer would reference Y.
Remember when users shared the pointer with reference, the count is increased.
So imagine the following.
We have some function that the pointer and it's doing something with it.
In parallel, someone is playing with your code in the same runtime and then the object has been freed.
Now the difference becomes zero and the object is removed from the, from the, from the like the processing.
And you don't see it anymore.
But this function is still playing with your pointer.
I know that you couldn't get that because you don't know concurrency.
But just in the future, when you learn concurrency, please come back to this slide.
A few things to keep in mind.
Please keep using the makeshift and make unique functions behind the scene.
These two functions are doing one thing in memory allocation to where is the tool?
When I say like I make a short pointer of new integer of twenty, then you end is a pointer created
memory and the victory and the object itself.
This is another creation.
So the classical way to create a shared or unique pointer is due to memory creation using the make unique
and make sure there is a new placement, a strategy internally that is creating only a single one memory.
If you couldn't get that, that's OK for having to go ahead of it.
Also, in some some cases they make sure that Mikuni can help you avoid some of the memory leaks that
might happen, do some of the exceptions to read here.
But the moral of that using make sure that Mikuni is very important and interesting question here now,
which one should they use?
Children unique.
It mainly depends on the context as much as you could try to make use of the unique ones, because if
you remember what I said here, the the there are issues about the shared point that it can really cause
problems.
Also, should the point is a bit slower, there is a chance that others will correct your data issues
with threading.
So sometimes guys just might use a pointer.
And if it happens that they need some some relaxation, they just get the pointer and just use it this
one way in the in the market to avoid the should the pointers.
So the overall should be I am avoiding the should the pointers as much as I need.
And if I use them, I have to be careful.
What about smart operators versus rule breakers?
As we know, reporters really are very problematic.
The bad part is they are a bit verbose, but they also less prone when it comes to the good over.
We use like the smart pointers.
You will start to get used to them.
So it will not be a problem if it is in.
Very good.
The rule is you have to be smart when you are using smart pointers, remember, more than once we highlighted
a situation where the smart waiters can cause a problem and this is one of them.
This is your turn.
I would like to read you this, will.
Good.
I would like to trace it then and comment line in 24 36 again, run my good combatted and think about
the reason behind the performance and then which of the next picture.
That's it.