The last time appointers is a week is a week pointer.
So when we shoot this good last time when we try to trace it, you probably would notice the problem.
There is a circular reference here.
The Embley object is needing the department object to pointer and the department is needing the Embley
pointer.
It has a vector of at least pointers.
So when you go with the code and you try to do, let's say here we are creating the Embley and then
we creating the department, we put the department at the embassy and we put that embley at the department.
Now the employee has a department which has Embley.
This is a cycle.
And if you try to bring to the use count of most of them, it would be two before the end of the code.
What's what's the problem here?
We we have e waiting for the destruction to be released and we have the waiting for e destruction to
be released.
This is what we call a cycle, a circular reference.
And as a reference account, we remain with zero.
This is going to be a memory leak.
So this is a problem with that code.
And that's why, again, sure, the pointer is a bit problematic.
The C++ tries to relax of this problem, using something we call a pointer.
The weak pointer is a pointer to a pointer.
Let's let's first tease this picture.
This is a problem that we haven't yet have here, A and B, this is looking to this guy.
This is looking to this guy.
They are waiting for each other to be released.
And this would never happen.
The C++ come with the weak points following the B has a shield pointer over it, but it has a weak pointer.
Overbey weak pointer doesn't incremented the reference account.
So if this guy has a reference count from here, this guy doesn't have a reference account to over here.
And this way the cycle has been terminated.
So the moral of the weak pointer is that although it can see the the other pointer, it doesn't increment
the counter because as we see here, the more of that the counter is incremented.
And this was going to be a bigger cycle that we cannot release.
But here now, if it has a pointer weak Overbey and it does it incremented the counter the now B, when
it go out of the scope, it doesn't find anything.
Look into it so we can simply be removed, then it can simply be removed.
This is a model of that.
But be careful.
The cycle sometimes can be careful.
We can have four classes, ABCDE and they are cycling around each other.
Let's go and see how issued a three pointer can be created.
There are two steps to create a three pointer, your first must have assured the pointer, then you
create a weak pointer from the Shield, the pointer.
That's why we call it a pointer to pointer.
So weak pointer is a pointer looking to the shield pointer.
The next finger will clarify that more that we have here, the Embley clause and the department clause.
One question here.
Which one of them to make it the weak pointer, is it the department or the employee?
Personally, I thought like that the department should be the stronger side.
Like I have employees for the purpose of the pointer back from the employee to the department is to
know who is holding me.
So the actual owner here is a department.
That's why I decided the department has a shield of employees, but the employee has a weak point of
department.
Now, here in Good, you are going to create the employee.
Normally you also are going to create normally the department, but you are going to assign these to
this department.
What is the type of this department is weak pointer.
So we are actually assigning share the pointer to weak point.
You can also make it with creation, like you say, e department equal weak pointer of the site, creating
it of should the pointer.
The moral of this three lines here.
You must have assured the pointer first, then assigned or constructed to a weak pointer then now do
the same logic.
If you run the school you will notice is working normally.
This guy is going to be destroyed and this guy is going to be destroyed because the weak pointer here
created doesn't affect the difference account.
But make sure you can trace this code now to visualize it a little more.
This is the pointer that we have.
This is a shared the pointer that is managing the pointer, but the pointer is just pointing to the
straight pointer.
That's why we say it's a pointer to a pointer.
This means that the pointer can can talk to the shield, the pointer, but it cannot talk directly to
the pointer.
OK, but then I would like to access the pointer.
The symbols provide you with the function name the lock.
The word lock is again coming from the concurrency world when we look at object, which means that no
one should destroy this object or play with it or right over its content and in a way that corrupted
till we are done with it.
So when we when you say look here is going to return the the pointer that has been used to create the
weak pointer, now we think the pointer play with it.
And once you are done and go out of the scope, this object now can keep going and maybe can be released.
Also, once you take a look over this pointer, it will not be released from the memory.
So it's safe here.
There is another function here that's more interesting expert function.
What if I have a weak pointer over this?
Should the pointer?
But then at some point someone deleted this pointer and now I came to use the pointer.
I found it.
If it is gone, if you didn't if the C++ doesn't help, that will help us with that.
We are going to fix the dangling pointer for C++ to prevent that.
It provides us with is expired the function, which is simply tell us if this pointer is still alive
or not because the weak pointer doesn't increment the reference count here.
So this guy can now is need an extra mechanism to know if this guy is alive or not.
Let's see some good to the lock and expiring.
We have here a function that's good bread inside this guy.
And I just would like to bring to the number of employees in the department as a side note.
Remember that this print function cannot define itself here because it's incomplete.
You have to take it outside.
You have to split the implementation, the declaration from the definition.
Anyway, we right now writing our printer function, you cannot access directly from the department,
which is a weak pointer, the employee, why it doesn't see it.
Remember here the weak pointer doesn't see the data.
It just see the share the so snow here.
You cannot do that.
You cannot access it.
You have first to get a look over it.
So let's see some logic that some people do in the market, which is wrong all about it right now.
You're seeing as following you, seeing if not department expired.
You are saying if this object isn't removed so far, then you are calling the look function.
The look function is going to return Asgeir the pointer object to here, then you are using it.
So let's see here two scenarios.
In the first scenario I submitted my data and the called the function print so it come here is expired
to get an object, get it printed.
This is done now here.
I'm saying the external pointer now that is gone.
What I say print again it goes here is expired.
Yes.
This one is going to expire.
So the more of that remember the weak pointer cannot access the data directly.
And have to verify if the object is alive or not and have to call the look function to get the actual
object appetizer.
I know, but in a way.
I would like to take this one more step again about the conspiracy, which I do not agree here, like
a lot, of course, is skip this, but I felt for the sake of completeness, I should put it here,
come back in the future to understand it in multithreaded.
As I said, there can be more than a line of code that is working in the same time.
So here is how this could the previous could Israel you here say, is it not expired?
It's it.
Oh, it's alive.
Now you want to go to line twenty two between line to any online line to some good.
But the D was not going to imagine that this is another could that is now corrupting your could now
you got the object to from here which return it an object.
But the object is internally is not a pointer then used it but it's not a pointer a give it you runtime
error.
So the moral of that in a different set of this good is wrong because the look function might return
an object that is actually not a pointer if it was good with an object that has gone.
So be careful even just checking if it's expired or not in the earlier of the code isn't is improper.
OK, let's fix this little more.
The right way actually is after you get an object from the lock function, you are going to verify it
is not.
If it is a null you are using it.
If it is not, then it's actually expired.
So there are two cases here.
Is it early expired or not not expired and were done if not expired.
While we are going inside the function, it could be it expired.
So again, double check again.
If you thought about that for a while, then the expired function doesn't have a need.
We can actually make it much more simpler.
We can do something like that if or two department original equals Department of Luck, which means
bring for me an object from this guy and a check.
If it is not or not, then just use it.
Regards if you understood what I said about the concurrency or not, this is how you should use a weak
pointer.
You should call that lock verify condition.
So if you if you could if you didn't get what I'm saying about the Cucaracha, totally OK.
Just make sure you are using it exactly this way.
Now, this is of a question.
So what is the value of this about?
The function fixed by the function is the purpose of it is more of the cleaner.
It can tell us if the pointer is is alive or not.
So, for example, imagine that you have a queue of weak pointers and every time you are checking if
some of some if some pointer is good, then just remove it from the queue so that the purpose of expire
is just to check if it exists or not without having to return an object instance of it.
Sometimes even there might be intended design to use a weak pointer, although there is no, although
there is no,
although there is no cycles like it's intended.
Now, let's say you have somebody sort of like a DBRS and then you you would like to give this database
to some other classes who would be using it.
But the logic is, if the database got closed again, then whoever is using the database now should
stop using it.
So sometimes this is a bit intended.
In this case, you also go and design the other dependent objects to be weak pointers and then they
are checking if the object exists or not.
If not exists, then they stop using it.
Anyway, also, if you didn't get about this scenario for now, throw it behind your back, it isn't
easy to imagine the moral of what I want to say here.
This is how you should be using the object here.
That's it.