In the last time we learned how to do the custom, the letter for the shirt, the printer, sadly,
when it comes to the unique printer, the syntax is a bit different.
I would like also to take the chance while teaching you the custom editor for a unique printer to introduce
you to a bunch of modern features, just about everything of them, like function, declension, time
and using the syntax of today will look like weird.
This is very normal.
The way to be very familiar with it is mainly to write it many, many times.
So let's first know about function.
This is a bit introduced in C++.
Then let's say you have some some function here.
Here Square.
We can describe this function as its function.
The ticker parameter written, the the competition itself is just multiplying the number itself in C++
lipin you can define a function as following.
Remember we say integrate X equals 10.
I'm not defining a function.
So I'm going to say here we have a function temblors function and it's a type is a function that is
returning an integer and it's taking an integer.
If you define something like that you can say here equals square.
So one of the interesting things of of of the modern C++ syntax, your flexibility, investing function
and defining function this way, this is very strong.
It's merely existing in other in other programming language like Python and so on.
So you can call F or five to twenty five exactly like Askwith.
So this is how we are defining some function in the function is very, very strong and can be used in
very complicated scenario.
But for now I'd like to make it simpler like that.
So let's learn about the custom that Easter, the custom, the letter is following with the with the,
with the short pointer, with a unique pointer.
So here is our dilator, very normal.
And here is also our parameter polynomial.
The extra thing is a unique pointer.
You have to best for him also another parameter which corresponds to the reader.
So are giving him details exactly about your letter.
So you are telling him, hey, you have a function that this Deeter function is a function, that its
return is void and it's apparently an integral point.
So this is a letter, if you think about it, it is a returning void.
So you would the void here and it's sticking into your pointer, so you would integrate with The View.
So the extra the extra about the should, about the custom, the letter you have to provide a second,
the template parameter that is describing your delete the function.
At that moment, the custom director for the new player is done.
The remaining of of decision.
I'm just teaching you more modern syntax, C++ to do that.
OK, so the first one is a declaration type, so let's let's learn something about it, let's say that
we have a function F and I say all to be equal.
One point five, C++ is going to resolve this all to two double because this value is double.
So when you are returning B, we know the B is is double parameter.
OK, this is very good.
One of the good C++ features because it might help us to make our code more readable or more generic
and so on.
Now let's see the function.
This one here I'm declaring a parameter I, which is ten point two.
It's double another double digit one.
It's three times two.
So items to is twenty point four and so on.
There is another way to define the double variable here.
Let's let's let's see.
I'm doing here.
I'm saying here what instead of the position of the double Arabised, it was declaration type based
on I am quoting here that the type that we are going to put here is exactly the type of guy.
So what is it?
I just double.
So practically speaking, this line is like double G two times two, which is twenty four.
So the moral of that is the declaration over here allowed us to remove the declaration time exactly.
Two and and link it based on something.
So please familiarize yourself with line 15.
There is another way that we are also using the declaration time you are seeing here declaration type
and you are giving it F with that function call operators.
So F is a function and this is a code for the function.
So we really care about its return type.
What is the return type of double if it is double?
So again, this this part is going to be resolved to double.
So this is another way to make use of the declaration time.
So again, it could look more generic, like we are saying, hey, you know what, J3 type is the same
as the return of F, but remember, we're using here the parenthesis here is a third way.
You know, we can define a function, as you said, like that, we can say that we would like to define
some function which of type global and doesn't take parameters like we did in the a few slides ago.
Now, I can do that in a different way.
I can say here that the F2 is the type of it is is the reference F reference, if it is referring to
the will function as a return type and as parameters.
So again, this one is going to be resolved as a function of double with our parameters.
Now I can call F2 normally and get some value here.
So as you see the declaration, Tyvon, all two are very, very, very, very well connected.
They are tools that can help us make our good little more generic.
Now, let's see, how can we help with that in the function pointers, remember?
And a few slides ago, we we here have a will.
We say here is a director and we say this is a function of void of integral pointer.
But what if we know that we care about that?
What would that the nature of this function?
We can just use here a declaration type to say, hey, you know, this Drita function that we're giving
it, but consider it to type here.
This way, you don't have it now to think about what are the parameters that are here.
You don't even have to think about that.
So again, C++ made it a bit simpler for you when you did such a good.
You understand that this is going to be replaced by function of void integral pointer.
So this is a model of that.
Let's use something else.
If you if you if you look to the syntax, the idea that you are using here, something like that with
two parameters here, looks like ugly like let's say in your code, you have to use a lot of a lot of
unique pointers.
The code would be very ugly.
So something like TYPEDEF can help us to simplify the code.
I'm not going to back to the old syntax or even the declaration as you like.
And I'm saying typedef all of this type to this name.
Remember we said before when typedef you can define it with something and then you give it any.
So far so good.
So now in the old way I can make a unique pointer of these two things, but now I can replace all of
these big name with, with this, just the name that they just used.
So the model that we made the code like looks smaller and now it looks like you like a little type.
So you don't think of it here.
It was very inconvenient to have to pass another parameter, but now just one name.
OK, but this is a problem here in the school.
What if I would like to make this go generic, like I'm not defining this, this time for an integrated
after time, maybe for double.
This doesn't make sense.
So let's make it more generic.
We cannot in C++ introduce something good that they're using.
They using is just a generalization of typedef that allow using templates.
So how would you use it?
This is a new syntax for you.
You define it as following, you define your template and so you get you say using, you give the name
that you would like to use equal and then define the type.
So now here you see it is a symbol like syntax, but we have here this time T and the T. So now we we
are now defining this time in a unique way.
Now, if it would like to and also define here my little function in the template way, if I would like
now to define a unique point of integration, give it here the template and delete the little one was
integer.
So it's OK, let's say here a unique double or unique pointer of double.
You give a double pointer and you say delete or two of by double.
So now the model of that is you, you give it my name here.
You made it more generic.
This with the purpose of that.
There is concern that I would like to discuss a bit interesting is there are many ways to define the
dilator.
Remember, it's expecting a function so we can use a function or a functor or a pointer to function
or or this function in the C++ or the declaration that there are a bunch of different ways.
Right.
Surprisingly, the memory size of the unique pointer in every one of them is different in memory.
So it is what you are defining.
Some Londa function, put it aside and we have to define a normal function at a function of a function.
So here this is a default default, a unique pointer.
If you try to tap into the size of that guys in the memory, it would be eight bytes if you decided
to use Functor.
It's also eight.
But if you decided to this declaration type of function, it's 16 by double.
Now, if you say the declaration type over anonymous function eight again, if it decided to use something
called function that we didn't take it so far, it's six years more for more of a time.
If you decided to use the function one, it could be from 40 to 60.
It depends like on your machine, something like that.
Maybe even bigger.
Depends if you if you noticed the here there are two things.
The first is the memory, different sizes, whatever approach is different.
The second is using using the function style is the most expensive one among them.
If you have interest to know why there are different sizes and memory, the end of this article has
a good has a good information about how the function is, how the pointer to the director is.
It is it is it is sieved internally.
The model of some of them.
For example, there are some mechanism in C++ model with MBT optimization that could allow us to not
put an extra size for some of these pointers.
So the moral of this is right, if it happened that you have a heavy and extensive usage of a unique
pointer with a editor, you have to avoid this function site.
And the best for you probably would be to just go with something like maybe the type a functor or maybe
a declaration type over over an anonymous function.
So this is a model that so that you could doesn't take a lot of memory that it.