One of the advanced topics in C++ is exception handling, and this is a mandatory topic in practice.
Sometimes when we develop our applications,
We may face conditions where we cannot complete the functions like a blocking issue.
You can think of a lot.
Let's say you are creating an array, but the system rejects creating the array and telling you that
there is no enough memory.
You are opening a file, and the system tells you that you cannot open this file due to some permissions issues.
Let's say you are making some remote call.
Let's say you are in a bank and making a remote call to some payment service or whatever service,
and then there is a network disconnection that happened during the call,
so the system suddenly cannot proceed anymore.
Sometimes thinks about more logic. Let's say you are in a payment system, so you are paying a bill for someone,
...
but the money value is negative,
It isn't just a low value,
It's negative value,
something is wrong with such a value, or you would like to compute the square root of X, but X is a negative value.
Sometimes you are making coding mistakes like let's say we accessing the array out of the boundary, or let's say we are
receiving a pointer to process, but the pointer is null.
So there are a lot of things that can stop us from continuing processing, and this happens a lot in practice
and we would like to communicate the problem, and we would like to handle it. In the industry,
there are two major approaches to solve this problem.
The first one is the error code approach,
and the idea here is to return something to the caller to tell him that there is a problem here.
One might say, OK, let's return a boolean success for true fail for false.
This is good, but very limited.
You need sometimes to communicate a reason.
A more flexible approach is to return an integer,
we call it an error code.
If it is zero, it means success,
Otherwise, like I was working in a company, for example, and we had a huge list of error codes for
all of the scenarios that we figured in the system.
So, when you return say error code 17, then we open our document and say, what is error 17?
error 17, oh, error 17 is permission issue with opening a file.
If you even noticed the function main is returning a zero.
The point behind that is an error code.
When you return a zero, it means that we are successful in return, and there are a few other returning values.
...
This is one approach and we are not going to use this approach, it is as simple as I said, the other
approach is throwing an exception, which is now a programming mechanism.
So the error code here is all about you and your team and what you define as error code and error scenarios.
Throwing an exception is a mechanism that you can terminate the current function completely. In the future,
I would like for you to try to read about the error code versus exceptions mechanism. So let's see
how to throw an exception in C++.
I have here a class bank account that has a value of 1000. Forget lines 7 and 8 for now.
...
So you have in your bank account 1000 money and would like to pay a bill of some value.
So the logic here is if the money is greater than the bill value, let's say you have in your bank
account 1000, but you would like to pay only something that is 100 values (100 dollars).
So you can just subtract it and return through which you mean we succeeded to do the task,
that we succeeded to pay the bill. On the other side,
Let's say that you don't have enough money in your bank account, then return false. Notice here,
returning false doesn't indicate there is an error or a blocking error.
This isn't the case here.
It just the logic of our code that we either can pay or can't.
So if we sent to pay 100, it's going to work well,
but if you want to pay 5000, it's going to not work well.
Now, let's sent a negative value here. If the bill's value is less than zero, a developer here would think that it
is very wrong
if someone is calling my function with a negative value and this worse like to
communicate to the caller that, hey, you shouldn't send such a value.
Something definitely is wrong on your site.
In other logic, someone would say, I just would like to return false for that, but I would like
to say this is an invalid situation and would like to terminate the processing to see what is wrong
in the system.
So here is what happened.
I'm calling word called throw, it is a reserved keyword to throw exceptions, and I'm throwing
something called invalid argument.
This is one of the structs in the system that is defined for you,
and I'm giving an initial message here.
So let's see what's going to happen here.
If you look to the terminal (the console here), you will notice here the word terminate throwing
an instance of invalid argument,
and there is a message forward the word
what, bill value can't be negative.
...
What happened is the program has been terminated completely. In line 8,
It is going to go back to line 20 and then terminate the program.
This line in line 21 will not be processed.
The program will terminate completely.
So as you see now, the throw statement helped us to terminate the whole program.
C++ defined a bunch of structs or classes for you that you can use and will come back later to their
different types.
Let me show you something interesting.
If you tried to use a vector of integer V, there are two ways to get the value of an index.
You can see V of 25, and you can see V dot at 25.
Now, what is the difference? this vector of length 10 only so these two are actually accessing out of
the boundary.
The V with the subscript operator,
it doesn't do any index verification, it just returns it.
So probably something like 25,
It may not crush the application because it is very small value.
So you just reading or writing so you will not corrupt a memory.
So this T would actually print something maybe zero, some garbage value.
But now, when you come to line 13, the dot_at function is going to validate and is going to throw an exception
if you are in the wrong position.
So you see here what happened.
The program terminated with a function called range check, which is telling you that N, which is
25 here, is greater than size, which is 10.
So the difference between them that this one will throw an error that can terminate your whole application.
The error name is out of range exception.
Let's say get inside the member function of at. Open the STL function itself.
You will notice the at function in the following: first column is some function called range
check and then returning asterisk this,
which is a class, the vector here is returning the position
underscore, underscore n.
Here is the range check function, they say if the underscore, underscore n, which is 25, greater
than or equals 10, throw this exception and tell him that this is wrong.
Now, you see what happened
actually inside the function is: there is a call that might throw an exception,
and then the normal access of the array.
If this function throws an exception, then this line will not be processed.
The whole stack would be terminated.
Now, it's a good time to know about what we call exceptional propagation...
...
Yes, sorry.
So, starting from the range check, the range check is going to throw an exception.
It's going to stop the range check and jump back to the AT function, which is going to jump back to the
main function, which is going to jump it back to the process OS (the one that called all of us).
So you see here: there is propagation to the error terminating every function.
The same case in the pay bill function, the pay bill is going to throw an exception, go back to the
main, go back to the OS, terminate everything. We will come back later to this topic,
It's called stack unwinding.
Let's now introduce what we call catching the exception...
Normally, we don't want to really just terminate our whole program,
we would like actually to know there is a problem.
So the C++ introduced what we call the try catch.
It's very common in programming languages.
So you do try here,
Open a brace and close it, and you put here a scope of a bunch of statements,
and there is a catch statement that has an object type reference of e of some object that's going
to capture. What's going to happen
is as following: this code is going to be processed.
Does it through an exception? no. Does it through an exception? no.
This is an exception? yes.
Once it has happened, it jumps to the line 23.
Before that, it used to terminate the whole function and jump back to the caller.
But now, it is jumping to the catch, and checking is the exception of time invalid argument?
If yes, get inside here.
Now, notice that the program now didn't terminate.
This cout Bye would be actually printed.
So the purpose of try-catch is to catch the throwing errors and try to do something with it, which
even you might try to throw something here again.
Let's see this here.
Now here the same logic,
but I also after I looked it, I decided that maybe we should throw it again to the caller, and we
throw it again.
Now, you see the program again come back to be terminated, and this cout Bye would not be printed.
So the logic is as following: if you found something that's really broken, you
call a throw to stop every processing and propagates up to the caller one by one.
...
The Try is going to try to catch something here and send it to the catch operator.
You can think like if our system database cannot be reached, probably would like to try and stop this
error and send some SMS messages to maybe the administrator.
The catch is going to probably try to stop the error.
Practically speaking, if you have a big system say low layers like function calling function,
calling function, calling function, probably the low function will keep just throwing the error as it is,
but the high functions probably have more logic to try to stop the error and make some judgment
over it.
These are the three components.
Please, play with the code before moving to the next sessions.
This is useful and future reading after you finish the exception handling topic.
That's it.