Sometimes you would like to throw some types of exceptions and also to try to catch them.
Let's see this function.
Let's say we are trying to create an array, a function that returns an integer pointer for create an array,
but we are in memory, so we have limited memory here.
So the first thing is, what if someone sent for us an array length that is negative, for example, this should
be an invalid argument.
No one should ask us for that.
So if this happened, throw an invalid argument and say that the array's length is very big. On the other
type, if the array is greater than 10000, let's say that this is a limitation in our application, and
we don't like to reserve such a big memory.
So now, we throw another type of exception called runtime error and say that this is too big, otherwise
we will create a new int length.
By the way, C++ can throw an exception from this call.
That's called bad_aloc if even the system memory doesn't have such a memory.
So this function can return three different types of exceptions.
Now, let's see the function that is calling this function.
So we have here a try-catch with integer pointer creating an array, and we sent -10,
but when you run this program, you will notice that the system will actually crash and we want to
try-catch to not crash it,
but the problem is here, you are catching the wrong exception.
So we now, here going back one step. We know it is a negative value, it will throw something called
invalid argument.
But here we are trying to catch the runtime error. So what happened in the catch statement is that the catch
statement is going to match the type with the type.
So does this an invalid argument type?
No.
So this will not be entered.
So this catch statement will not be activated because it doesn't match the type of this error that
we have.
So how to solve this problem?
We solve it with multiple catch statements.
So here is what I'm doing.
I'm saying if the called exception was of time invalid argument, do that.
You think of it like an if-else.
Otherwise, if the called exception of runtime error, do that, it's going to do it.
Otherwise, three dots here means that
you can catch anything that we couldn't call in the previous statements.
So let's now try to trace. If you give -10, it is going to jump to an invalid argument, which is here
I print it. Now, the program didn't crash with throw an exception, and we caught it also. The dot-dot here should be in
the end of the processing and it isn't so welcomed unless in the very very high level of the application.
You would not like it.
You aren't sure of anything, code goes out of your control, then you put three dots just in case.
But the default is you should handle the different types of errors.
Let's see another type of throwing, you can also throw other data types, not just the class here.
so I can throw something like 17, for example, and this for now, let's say an error code.
Now, if we try again this code, this code is going to again fail because you are throwing an integer.
Is this an integer?
No. Sorry, it will not fail. The integer here will not match the runtime error.
It is going to go to the dot-dot-dot
so it will print caught unknown exception.
Notice here printing the p here.
I'm saying if it's not a null pointer, then it has been created, then just delete
it here.
Now let's catch the integer itself.
I can come here and say if you caught an integer error code, then print
the error code. if it isn't an error code, runtime error, print runtime error. Otherwise, dot-dot-dot.
So you see now we caught here the error code.
If we tried to return a double from here, then the double would not be casted to an integer.
It would be caught.
in the dot-dot-dot. So again, you have to catch a double variable. So you can throw different things, but you have
to catch them.
Otherwise, they will not be caught.
We highlighted that there are different types of classes, they are actually something called inheritance,
and when we come back to the inheritance topic, we will come back again to these different types so
that we know exactly how to use them in a proper way.
At the last thing, which is very intuitive.
You can have like nested loops, nested if conditions, you can have normally nested
try-catch, nothing wrong about that.
So here I have a big try-catch of type int, and inside it, I have try-catch which throwing int and this
guy prints something
then throw it again.
This throw jumps to this catch. Very normally, you can have like if you have a lot of function and every
one of them is having some try-catch-throw then actually have a lot of nested try-catch functionalities.
That's all.