Stack unwinding is a process that happens behind the scene when there is an exception that has been
thrown in your code. I guess so far, you can already guess what's happening behind the scene.
If we have some function1 calling function2 and function2 having to throw an exception, then
the logic is: does it have any try-catch around this line of code that throws the exception?
If the answer is no, then the current function would be terminated, and it would be removed from the
stack and all of its local variables, as we learned in the stack and heap video before.
Now on the other side, if it happened that the function has a try-catch with a matching type, if
it doesn't have a matching type, then it doesn't have an effect.
So again, it will terminate removed from the stack, and all of its local variables would be destroyed.
But if it has a matching type, like let's say we have thrown a remote runtime exception and we caught a runtime
exception, then we go to the catch block to handle it, which may have to throw again. If it happened
to throw again, then the same logic starts to apply, and so on. After function1, the function2
may receive a throw exception from function1 to start to do the same
logic.
If it happened that the main itself received the exception and there is no try-catch for it, then the whole
program will crash.
Let's do a little simulation to make sure that we understand that. Here is some class employee
with just an id and destructure that destroy
an employee. Take a minute, stop this video and try to simulate all of the function calls from here.
Let's do a tracing. The function main is calling function f1. F1 will print start f1.
So we print here f1, and then it's calling f2 which is surrounded with a try-catch of type integer.
Now F2 will start to print F2, F2 is again calling F3 but has a try-catch of type runtime error.
...
Now, F3 is writing f3...
First, creating an object
p and assigning id 3.
Now, where is this object created? the employee object is created on the stack.
So if it happened when this function is destroyed, this variable should be destroyed.
Calling f4 will print start f4. We are defining a new object here, but we are defining it on
the heap.
It is dynamic memory that should be released.
Now, it happened here that we are throwing one, so we are throwing an integer.
So the stack unwinding process starts and says, do we have a try-catch here?
...
The answer is no.
So the function will directly terminate and throw back the exception to this line of code here.
Now, one clear problem here is there is a memory leak here because this object is dynamic and need
to be free and clean, but this line will never be executed.
So this is the first memory that we have.
So the first lesson here to learn is you need to be careful with dynamic pointers like that because
if there is anything that has been thrown here, your code will have a memory leak.
You might think like I'm not going to code in this ugly way, but you can have some calling to
some functions in some library and you don't notice that this function is going to throw an exception.
So you end up that you really have a memory leak.
So anyway, this line will not be executed, end f4 will not be executed.
Now, the exception come here to the line f4.
Does it have a try-catch? the answer is no.
So again, this function will terminate,
but there is a difference here.
This object now is in the local stack, as we are terminating F4, we are destroying all of the local variables
in the stack unwinding process.
So that's why we see here a destroy employee 3.
Now, f4 is jumping back to here at line 31. F3, it happened to have a try-catch,
so the exception with a check first, if it's matching or not. We have here a runtime
error exception, but we actually throw an integer exception
so this guy doesn't have an effect, doesn't have a matching.
This message would not be printed, and this message would not be printed.
Now, the exception is going to free local variables, jump again to line 42.
In line 42, we have a try-catch of a matching type.
Now, the exception stops here and jumps to this line of code, writing error code 1,
and then there is no more throwing of the exception here.
So the end f1 would be written, and we go back to f1.  If it happened that even this guy doesn't have
a matching try-catch and this guy doesn't have a matching
try-catch, the program crashes.
This is all about the stack unwinding process, which would have some specific handling behind the scene
for the local variables and the destroying of them.
This is another code here.
We are creating an object, and it happened that we are throwing an exception in the constructor,
and one of the interesting things about constructors is that the constructor is a function that doesn't
have a return type.
So you cannot say that the constructor field. Throwing an exception is one of the best ways to say that
the constructor failed to initialize my variables in a way runnable.
But again, we are failing here
in a memory leak. This destructure will never be called even if you are creating a normal object
in the stack like that.
Why?
Because the object didn't complete.
There is no complete object that has been created here.
So this is one lesson that you have to be very careful. On the other side,
you should never try to throw an exception inside a destructure.
This is very problematic.
Imagine that there is an exception that the stack unwinding is handling,
and suddenly in the middle of that, your destructure also throws an exception.
This would be very problematic and might end up with some undefined behavior.
The last track that I would like you to be aware of is a very wrong assumption between guys and the
difference between throw e and throw.
We know that when we catch an error, we can throw it again.
OK, so here, f3 is throwing runtime error, and now I have a try-catch here of runtime error,
and then in the try-catch, I am printing the error address, and throwing e again.
Now, the guys think that this is as a reference e and this is as a reference e and this as a reference e,
they think that all of these e's would be one. This will not be true. The E only would be once in
terms of whatever receiving.
When you try here through E, E is creating a new copy. You will notice every time we have a different
address and this means we are creating copies of it, although 99 percent, this will not be actually the
intentions. You actually don't need to make a copy. If this is a very heavy object,
this might slow the performance of the system.
Now, another way is just to try throw without through E.
When you do that, the compiler does some magic behind the scene and keep throwing the same error exactly.
...
So you notice that throw E everywhere is actually having the same address.
This is very important,
and even later when we will learn the OOP, you will know about the inheritance hierarchy.
You will know that this is very, very, very useful because it gives the child and parent information
throwing
exactly.
So the moral of that stick to throw only unless there is an important reason.
I would like really to make a copy of the error itself. That's all.