In modern C++, we have a new specifier that is saying no_except. the specifier is an abbreviation, and
it indicates me as a developer, I'm sure that this function doesn't throw an exception.
So, what is the point of saying that? When you give such a specifier, the compiler is going to do better
in different handling for your functions.
Specifically, it will have some details about the unwinding that is going to skip behind the scene.
So this ends up with good optimizations for the compiler itself,
but where is the problem? the problem happens if you say that your function doesn't throw an exception,
however, it actually through one. This is a nice code, you have just a function that computes the absolute,
just doing some checks and returning the variable,
there is nothing wrong here,
and the computed variable here is X, it is just a primitive.
So we are fair enough.
But if this function, for example, is creating an object with a new, it might fail, for example,
due to some memory allocation problems.
So for now, this is a good function.
This one also is a good function.
So everyone is happy.
But what if you was wrong?
You say nothing here,
so you didn't say that this function doesn't throw exceptions.
This is a good function,
but this function, we say no exception or no_exception of true.
It is the same.
Now, this is very wrong.
The compiler will skip some important details behind the scene, but actually, your code throws
an error.
So what happened is undefined behavior, and typically your program may crashs for that.
So this is the whole story.
It is good to write no_except,
but, if you have to throw an exception, your program would terminate probably.
On the other side, the no_except can also be used as an operator as following: let's say you have
a function
My_apps, you can say no_except (this is like an object here), and you are passing parameters to be this
function,
and passing some parameters for it. This function here, as an operator, will tell you that this function...
has a no_except or not.
So here, it would be false because this function doesn't have no_except. If you tried to call my_abs_div,
so now my_abs_div is doing something very interesting,
It saying here we can write nothing or can write true or false.
So instead of writing here, true or false, if you are dependent on function like say my_abs,
you can say no_except of my_abs of y.
Now, this is very similar to that guy, so that this guy is going to compute that if this guy has a no_exception or not.
It doesn't have an exception.
So this guy will be false.
So it would be now no
except or false.
So think of this as a function that's computing for you an expression computing for you if it's
true or false.
In a similar way, we can say here no_except over this function that has a template.
Now, this function is is just making a copy of this object.
So it's calling the copy constructor.
You can, again, do it like following: no_except of
and you are computing here a true or false. For T of source, you are calling
the copy constructor of this guy.
You are telling him what does the copy constructor of this guy return?
So let's say the function returned true, then you are  no_except of true,
but if this function call or operator call returned false, then you are false.
The moral of that is you can sometimes depend on one of the functions or build a simple expression
if it's possible.
Now, your turn, I would like you to read this nice program, understand it, and guess what is the output of it?
...
You probably thought this is going to divide by zero, so it is going to generate an exception and then
we are catching everything.
So we're going to catch the exception here,
but this will not happen.
Catching by by zero can be caught. The low level
events like arithmetic events overflows, and division by zero are considered to be handled by low
level mechanisms rather than exceptions.
So there is no one who is generating behind the scene an exception for the division for you.
This is going to be directly computed by, say, your hardware and returned eventually for you.
If it is impossible, your program actually crashes.
The right way to handle division by zero is by checking if the Y is zero or not, not by depeding on
try-catch, and this is an important thing to understand.
There is a difference between exceptions that we prepare and throw as an object and between the
low-level mechanism that happened here behind the scene.
The final thing a little of topic is a keyword no_throw. It is a constant. Let's say we
are creating an object using some new, or primitives, or whatever.
One thing to know is if the size of what you are allocating is bigger than your physical memory,
then the computer definitely will fail to create it.
So actually, there is an exception here that would be thrown.
It's called
bad_alloc.
So we failed to allocate memory for you.
So normally, if you would like to allocate an array, you can do try-catch and catch here bad_aloc
and try to create. Every time that you create,
this is good, otherwise no problem.
Now, there is another way to do that
if you would like to avoid the try-catch. You come here and put the word no_throw. This function now
is as following:
If it fails to create a pointer or new memory here, it is going to return a null.
So you can check first it is null or not. If it's null, don't use it. Otherwise, you just use
it.
So the moral of that is there is a way to use it to create a memory using try-cash, and thre is another
way to avoid the try-catch.
So those are the two different ways.
Finally, it's good to know that all destructures are implicit with the word no_except so there
is an assumption that you will not throw an exception during the destruction.
So you don't need to put the word no_except besides destructures,
and you shouldn't try to throw an exception during a destructure,
and as we said before, it's good and OK to have a throw inside a constructor.
Remember, as we said during today session, don't wrongly use the no_except keyword specifier.
...
If you used it, you have to be very sure that there will be no exception from your function.
What is really more important are the exceptions that might happen in an implicit way and you don't
notice them,
for example, you are catching a function that actually throwing an exception, or you are calling a constructor
that actually can catch an exception, or you are calling a function that actually catches an exception.
So this is really tricky.
You have to put an effort to make sure that there are no exceptions that might be thrown somewhere.
The word throw can be used as specifier
exactly in place of no_except keyword,
but this is now would be deprecated, so don't use it.
Also, the Microsoft compiler, I notice they have some different changes from the standard,
but it will not affect you a lot. In the future,
there is something called
move_if_noexcept, you will later study what we call a move semantic.
So it might be a good time then to come back to this function and see what does it mean. That's all.