In this video, we will highlight some of the common mistakes when it comes to exceptions to keep in
mind. The first thing is, as we said, there is an approach for using error codes and there is another
approach for exception handling. Some guys would tell you don't use exception handling because it's
very expensive (resources wise
I mean), but however, this isn't a proper advice.
The current model implementation of exception handling is very efficient,
and the exception handling, in the opinion of many guys, is a very strong mechanism to deal with
exceptions.
So this isn't a reason or an excuse to avoid exception handling.
The second rule is: some guys might try to do some mixing for the exception handling with the error codes.
Probably, this might not be a good idea.
It's good to stick to one approach to avoid issues in your software.
The third advice here is to avoid using exceptions for normal code flow.
Remember, the exception is an indicator that something is really broken, something is really invalid.
If your function can handle wrong parameters, for example, in a meaningful way, then
do it.
So the exception is something that might terminate your program,
there is some missing handling. So do not use an exception for no reason, use it because
there is a good reason, and there is something, for example, blocking for us.
Also, one advice is don't throw an exception for a constructor.
This is a common mistake.
It's OK to throw an exception from a constructor.
Nothing wrong about that actually is a good idea because constructor cannot return a value.
Some guys may say that it's also OK to throw an exception in destructures,
and this isn't OK.
your stack unwinding may fail to handle the different exceptions that are throwing together
this way.
Some guys throw an exception by value, not by reference.
So there is a big difference between throwing by value and throwing by reference.
Remember, if it's a pointer, for example, to some local variable and you try to return to some reference
for it,
this reference is going to be destroyed,
and if you tried to throw a dynamic memory, for example, then this is also a problem.
Why?
For two reasons:
Let's say you are trying to return some pointer to the error itself.
Scenario number one is: if you are actually failing in a bad_alloc scenario like you tried to create
something as a bad_alloc, and now while you are throwing it, you are trying to create new memories and
you already are suffering from a new memory issue.
So this is one issue in throwing pointers.
Another issue is: when you throw created dynamically pointer,
then the caller has to remove it, and this is still now confusing about the responsibility of freeing
a pointer.
So be careful about that.
So always through by value.
This is the moral of the advice here.
The second idea here about the catching itself. When you try to catch, it is a good idea to catch by reference,
because if you didn't try to catch by reference, you will end up copying the object itself
twice, which is problematic. There is also in the future
something called object slicing problem.
I would like you after reading OOP to come back and read about it.
Another issue is: if you are marking the function with no_except, although you didn't do enough effort,
verify that there were no exceptions that would be thrown from this function.
A common issue is to swallow an exception like you are hiding the exception. You are doing some
try-catch that catch anything, and then you are just blocking it, and you let your program keep going,
but there is an exception.
There is something wrong in the flow.
We should handle exceptions.
Can you handle it?
Handle it. Can you can't handle it?
You throw it back to the caller and so on.
Finally, as we learned, there is a big difference between when you say throw and throw e.
The throw doesn't create copies, which is good.
So as you see, we have here a few relevant things like - Are you going to throw by value or throwing from
reference?
Are you going to catch by value or by reference?
Are you going to throw E or throw?
All of them are relevant to the memory and what's happening behind the scene. That's it.