One of the most interesting features in the modern C++ is what we call the lambda exhibition's, the
lambda expressions is an anonymous function or Unnim to function.
So this is unnamed.
This idea is very popular in other programming languages like Java and Python.
The idea that you can write a function on the fly without having a name for it, make the code very,
very flexible in many cases.
So whenever you need to create a function you just created where you would like to use it.
That is does.
It could make things much more simpler.
It started in C++ for living and enhance it in C++ for team.
Looking here to a function, if for some the function, if someone is taking into your X, Y, just
serving them and turning them back and defining a function, it's an anonymous function, but it has
a name at the moment.
So look to this index and try to familiarize yourself with of the video for a minute and compare the
Syntex with this index.
Look into it.
You notice the following starting from this Brontë's, that this tell this place it's very, very exact.
Now we have a year or two if for some two.
So if some two here is the same function name as if someone and also here is the time of this if for
some to so think of it like integer e so the the variable name here, it looks like this is acting like
a variable name.
And also here is more like the specific function definition.
Here they are saving our time from defining explicitly how to represent a function.
And then we are seeing this function is equal, this separation, and now this.
This line is now like an exhibition.
It needs a semicolon in its end.
This is a very common mistake for a for beginners.
They they just forget this semicolon.
Now, once you define the function this way, you can use it exactly like if someone here so we can
say if someone three and six to get nine, we can also call if if some two, three and six and get nine.
So this is how we define an anonymous function.
But give it name for now.
Remember, anonymous function is like all the exhibition is something that doesn't have a name, but
we can.
I started with an invitation to make it simpler for you.
So please make sure you can you can match the connection between these two cases.
Now, sometimes you would like to develop a function, but it has different return types.
So overall, the compiler will get confused.
For example, let's say your function have somewhere aligned that return to point five and another point
that then explains why you chose to integrate.
So now the compiler would like to generate the function for you, but he is confused about what is the
return for it.
It cannot like here when we say the dysfunction, the compiler can do this into an integer.
So this is an integer.
So we it can we call this operation deducing?
Well, the compiler did use the data type.
So here in our case, this is confusing for the compiler.
It will not be able to figure it out.
So the way to do that is to use this syntax to both here all int to say, hey, you know what, this
function will be integer.
You need to to try to guess the output by.
So if if the if the overall of the function is confusing for the compiler, it will generate an error
and in this case you have to go and modify the function and add something that force the return type
of dysfunction.
However, there are some things that are invalid as a return.
For example, you cannot return an initialization list with this way, the compiler will fail to create
a function for that.
This way.
Let's go more.
This is a function is odd one, just verifying if a number is good.
Not now.
We have a vector here of five numbers and now the finding a very similar function to this function.
But this one now is more of an anonymous function.
So I'm seeing here, as you see, starting from this parenthesis to this place, it's exactly the same
function I'm giving here, or to giving the function name and equal assigning it to this expression.
So think of starting from this bracket to this.
But this is what we call lambda expression in the algorithms headers.
There is a function named count.
If the count in the algorithms, the function, the take a start and take an end and take a function,
function or take along like you can give it is one which is the pointer function.
We can give it anonymous function here and so on.
Now it's going to iterate over every element in the vector or whatever in the container here and evaluate
is odd and evaluate this function.
So this function is just as checking if the number is not so is one.
Odiase two know three four five.
Yes.
So we have the answer is three.
So counting is an algorithm that starts from start to end and apply the function and count.
How many times of this function is going to return to this function is tied to that have boolean study.
We call it predicate.
It's going to indicate true or false.
Now, so far, so good, we are defining the Alamdar function, we are running the exhibition and we
are using it now.
Let's go one more step briefly to anonymous function, really are going to write the same line as line
13.
But this time we are going to remove the what is two and directly write what it equals.
So it equals here, starting from this bracket.
This is what it did to this great race.
We are going to just copy paste it here and put it here.
So I would like you to always deal with this part of the exhibition as just like any expression, like
two times a three plus one.
It's an expression.
So instead of passing the function, we are passing the exhibition.
We are passing the exhibition directly here.
Now, this is really what we call the exhibition.
It is anonymous.
There's no name here.
This is your first time to see such a syntax.
You are seeing that we are passing a function in this way or a passing exhibition this way.
We can also use it in different ways.
Like, for example, I can I can call is old one with eleven, which is a chicken is eleven is although
not now in a very similar way.
Remove the word is good one and take the expression from starting from the breakfast table here.
Take it as it is then.
Now call the function.
So remember once you put this expression it just means a function.
OK, so you have to evaluate it.
So every time you see a lambda function starting from here to here, just imagine that this is some
function name like let's call it EF1.
So we are calling if one of value 11.
So looking here to this index, what does the syntax mean?
It looks weird.
I know that.
So we have here from this bracket still here, imagine that it's just some function that the word anonymise
and then when you put these two branches, you are actually evaluating it.
So this line of code here is going to write the word anonymous.
One of the very common mistakes with no is to forget to to forget the function call operator here.
So you are defining the roundabout.
You are not using it.
So here is another function, the function that we give it, the sort of function I would like to call
a sort, I would like to give it begin and end, and I would like to give it some comparator to sort
of the numbers for me from small to large.
So I'm calling the function sort and they're asking for eight anonymous expression or lambda expression
that is going to take two numbers and compare them from greater to smaller.
So once we get that, the vector is going to be sorted from large to small.
So remember, in the best we either you sort of begin to end or we used to assembly function or a function.
Now we are passing along the expression also.
Also, in the modern C++, we have this two function begin and end, which can help you to correspond
to the vector, end and vector to begin, but it also works on arrays.
So this is like it helps you to be more generic function in a way.
So this is now the the core of the exhibition, we're going to work more on this idea, but I need you
to be very familiar with the new syntax of creating a function this way.
So make sure you are familiar with that.
Let's proceed more, you see here we are defining a normal function take to a number and some of them
you can also go morganatic you can say here also X and Ottavi.
So in the generalized lameduck solutions, we can also define this kind of very general, complex simulation.
So you can now call it once with the integers, for example, and you can also call it with the like
say here a double value, an integer value.
So this is going to be they have some conversion here.
Now, the compiler can make automatic calls for this one and decide everything that's going to happen
for you if it's possible for it.
Again, if it happens that there is some confusion, then you force a return, a specific return.
So if you have two, you can also provide a note except here keyword to indicate that this function
isn't going to throw an exception.
Let's see one more complicated case to to try to get more sense of what London can do for you.
So let's say that we have a function here.
We named it for each.
And this function is taking a picture of each year and taking a template.
We named your function and we name we give it the name operation.
So I'm not iterating on every item and applying this operation on the item.
This also looks like a new syntax for you.
But remember a few minutes ago we showed the for each function, the a function which is iterating from
the beginning to end.
So and we were basing in the function that we are doing something very similar to its internal implementation.
We are basing a function or it could be a functional equivalent, the and it could be a function.
We are basing it here and we are using here in the function.
So if this is for example, here are to here, I'm actually showing you the three cases that could have
in for example, I'm sorry, I'm saying here, a square function that Bio-Reference X and just to square
it.
So now if we based here the square function.
So imagine now this is like square x square item.
So the item is going to be square and also creating a function with the operator function called giving
it to X and incrementing it with one rootsier we cannot here just to use, we can use it, but here
we can normally use it.
I'm also having a third case.
I'm using a lambda expression, the squid print and it's going to take some X with also and is going
to just print it.
So it seems that we have three cases here.
The pointer to function or just what you used to say, a function.
And we have the add one struct and we have the brain to function.
Now let's make a use of them here.
I have a vector of five numbers.
I'm now calling the for each function and they're saying the function of add one but with the function
call here function collaborator.
So this is more like we are passing something that can be applied on the function here and then I'm
calling it again bombastically function in here.
And I'm also calling it here with a function that is going subtraction to the number here where the
expression just does take a number and subtract it.
And I'm also now quoting the function of it with a print.
So every element is going to be printed.
When you apply this function.
We are adding one and then squaring and then subtracting, for example, for three.
We adding one right now for we are squaring it now 16 who are subtracting it's now 50.
So as you see here with the expression a similar to thing, the function function better.
We can now base the lump acceleration in different ways.
That's it.
Please make sure you are familiar with the Land Exhibition Center's.