Let's continue our talk about the anonymous function, what we call a capture close, you see this practice
that we used to write in the syntax of the expression, this is good, the capture glass.
And inside it, we can do a lot of things.
We can be specific or all variables by value or by reference.
We can best this of class by reference and so on.
So the purpose of this guy is bashing something.
So let's see, how can we do that?
And who would like to buy something with a value here?
We have a victor and we have here two values, two variables.
Now I'm defining here an anonymous function, the anonymous function.
Let's let's see from the branches here.
It's taking the branches here.
And it would like to iterate over the vector elements that we are providing or whatever container.
And then it's doing something like it's saying item plus equal factor.
But what is factor factor is a local variable here.
So it could happen that you would like to define your function somewhere here at 12 and you would like
to pass some of the local variables around the function.
So if you would like to pass the variable factor, you can reset it to here in the parameters.
You just put it here, then you can use it internally.
But now this is best by Kanishka, by value.
This means two things.
First, it means that the value itself is is constant.
So factor internally can just be used.
It cannot be incremented this way.
You think of it like you have a function that have a keyword inside the class.
You can adjust the element to the factory.
It is going to give you a comparison here, which is the only variable.
So when you buy something this way, you are basing it by course, by value, so you can use it internally,
but you cannot play with it.
Now, remember who we after we define a function, we need to apply it.
So here I am applying it on the vector to get an increment of two for every element in the vector.
So they are going to be three, four, five, six.
What I would like a little more flexibility.
I would like to best buy value, but I can I can change it internally.
So now you can work toward the key, the key word here, multiple mutable.
And then now you can change the world, the vector inside the function.
However, if you try to bring to the factor here, the value would be the same as here.
It would be the the same local variable.
So think of this like you are sending it a value, passing by values.
They can play with it, they can change it, but it doesn't affect us.
So the model of the capture clause is to bear some variable.
And here we learned how to best buy value and either like a to value or just to value.
If you would like to best by reference, you can pass the ampersand operator here.
Let's say you have a victory and you would like to summit and you have the same as a local variable
here, so you would like to iterate over the vector and some it's a value here.
So this is local variable that we need it to be updated of the code.
So we know we started to give it here, the parameter here, and then we can apply the function code.
What if I would like to define a function that has a taking something by value on something by reference
for what you would like to think, by referencing the value here, but the end here and for the best
value, just don't put it this way.
You are defining a function that takes the, uh, the the very the variables with different modes.
If you started to think about this example, you will start to see why, why I don't know or a of exhibition
are very, very powerful in a different in a different scenario, you would have to define a complete
function that the vector and you either want this parameter by reference or return it from the function
and so on.
Now this function is doing all of that here.
And the more we go in the exhibition, you will notice is making our life easier.
And and we didn't like we didn't add in the global space, the global scale, one more function with
the same name that might create conflicts with others.
What if I would like to base all the variables by value over reference the equal means bas all the variables
by value to value the end here means obsess over the variable by difference.
So this function now can see the factor and can see even the vector and this function can see the sum
and can see the factor.
But you see them, all of them by by reference.
Generally speaking, this is a bit risky, but you should know just about its availability as a feature.
But but having a complete visibility to your school might not be the best way, especially with the
end year.
OK, this is the very still same here, betting everything by value.
And B, I'm here messing about.
So this was the value.
I'm here basing by value only.
I'm here passing by reference for all the variables.
So every like this function and dysfunction doesn't affect the doesn't affect our outputs.
So far, one and B here would be still one in five.
Once you come back here incremented them again, that would be really two and six because this one is
the one by difference.
What if I would like to assess all the variables by, say, value, except something by reference here
you can start to specify like saying equal.
It means I'm basing all the variables by going to that.
And here you are saying, but you know what, I'm bursting the see as the difference, so if you try
to change the sea, it would be change it in a similar way.
I can say embarrassing everything by reference except to be messing it by value.
So if you try to incrementally be here, then the beast will remain by will remain five as old value.
So we have more flexibility in what Thabazimbi value and busway reference.
One more interesting scenario.
If I say the class and I have my, I would like to define a function and lambda expression that can
access the member variables of of the this and it can change it.
So, you know, you can come here and say, hey, best thing also that this so in this function F and
the ABI reference I'm basing this, would this basically be by about value?
It seems in some compilers you can see the asterisk this and in this case it would be best that this
very valuable reference book.
But it didn't work with me with the GC compare.
Another case is about the static variables we know if we would like to bust the local variables, we
have to put them here.
The only variable that you can see from outside around your scope, and it's still accessible and you
don't need to mess it is the static variable.
So basically variable is defined and visible from inside the function.
That's it.