The term with some minor improvements, so specifically, let's say you have you would like to create
or you would like to initialize some, he would like to return initialize some variable in the capture
clause itself.
So let's say that you have here.
Here.
Let's say you are defining some out of history over some file here, you would like to create some.
Lambda expression, you cannot simply because of us here, definitely because you cannot copy the theory.
Otherwise, it would be two extremes working with the same file in the same way.
So this is prevented.
OK, so I can pass it by reference, this is no OK, if you best it by reference, you can use it.
This is totally OK.
There is one issue here.
The the issue here is when you buy this object to the function, there are now two things that are working
on the object, one inside the function.
And maybe something after this might cause like some trouble in reading, writing, maybe because some
issue about that.
So what if you would like to basser object to the function and you just get rid of it?
There are two things that we can do here.
The first from the expression.
We can create a variable here and assign it to a value.
So this is the first thing about the Jerusalem exhibition.
The second thing coming from the semantic move you are moving this object to inside this function,
once you are done with that, this function is taking you or if this object and you cannot use it any
more after it.
So this is over all of the exhibition, your ability to pass a variable and just adjust the move here.
I'm just showing you the actual uses for that.
Otherwise, you might say a defining somebody here.
I can say here X equals 10.
This is a creation initialization for a variable.
But but but the real scenarios for using the lambda expression, you have some object and you really
want to base it and you want to get rid of it.
You don't you don't use any more after the function.
I would like to show you another example.
It is from the unique pointers or from smart pointers, but you are going to study that in the next
chapter.
Please come back to this is like the vector.
So now here, as you see, this is another function code named I'm I have here some local variable to
convert m creating a variable, initializing it X with.
This is from the generalized lambda.
I'm creating another one with Y just for no.
I'm also having here a unique pointer and later we know also you cannot pass by value a pointer.
So the best way to here.
Here you are going to base it with a move so the move is going to move it from here.
And again, you cannot use the DB here.
By the way, when you see the syntax like like it seems like there is an error here.
It is just a collapse.
Doesn't figure out some of the modern C++ syntax, that's all.
So this is all about the one part of the Jerusalem, the expression, your ability to create and initialize
variables, but a series of the stronger cases when you would like to move some object from your local
school to that exhibition function.
So that's what I would like to highlight a couple of other relevant issues.
The first one is this a blunder very, very, very similar to nested if conditions instead do conditions.
There is no new syntax, just units to things inside each other.
So here's a function that is anonymous and it is its breece, and this is a calling for it.
Inside it, I'm defining another function, another exhibition, and using it in a similar way instead
of defining it inside the function.
This way I can even define and use it on the fly this way.
So it looks like from the exhibition inside the exhibition, this is in a new C++ syntax, just utilizing
what what exists.
In line 19 here, I am quoting the function with the so there are two mistakes that could have here,
some some guys in general might forget to call the function.
I said that before.
So it just nothing worked.
The function is in code.
The other thing is you forgot to bust the V, which is a function is expecting here.
So if you didn't forget that, unfortunately, you would get an error.
The error would be something maybe like that.
Generally speaking, with modern syntax, the error message sometimes are very hard to understand.
The last thing that I would like to talk about is what is happening behind the scene, like how the
lambda function are handled by the compiler.
What happens is as follows.
We need to find out the function like that.
The compiler generate two things for you.
If you if you call it the first thing.
And this important part is going to define a struct with a function, operator code is going to give
it a very specific, unique name and it's going to give it like a function call.
And here is the parameter that you use with this parameter.
Now, notice here, the default one will generate something we are passing here by value, by the value.
So it's going to want to hear the word, because if you use the word immutable here, it's going to
remove the word chorused.
If you have more parameter in the capture clause, it will be more of class members variables here.
So the moral of that is the behind the scene.
The compiler will need to see the long expression it just struck with the operator and with whatever
necessary function members and definition keywords and whatever class members that you need to do that.
If you want to call this function, it's also going to create an object for you from this class and
just couldn't get for you.
So the more of that that said, this is what happened behind the scene.
The exhibition is just a struggle with the ability to function.
That's it.