Using lambda expression with their food is very straightforward, but I thought it's good also to see
some good snap, it's free.
So remember, if we would like to use the full expression, we really have to use the ads and we need
to use the three dots.
And practically speaking, the generation time would be the first element.
And this guy is going to be expanded over time.
So I would like to print a bunch of numbers sent to a print function.
We can use here an expression to print and then comma the three dots.
So the expression we are doing here, we are putting here at around Brahms's, OK, or even in this
like a function that we have now, the function, the expression here is just the printing, the Addicks
first column and then some space that's very close to the Bush example that we used before and before
the expression we would like now to use the lambda function.
So let's say I would like to make a decorator function here some function print element.
This is a very straightforward lambda function that is taking some output and putting something before
an object in some ways.
And just you put it here and it always says that's some logic to decorate something maybe similar as
you like.
Now in a very similar way to the applying function, we can call now the print element ARGs and the
three daughters.
So now the whole expression is going to use this function.
That is an advantage here compared to using a normal function like by parameter to the print.
One might say, OK, let's let's send the function to print the element and use it here.
You're going to face difficulties and the easiest way is to make it all of them of the same parameter,
like your printing bunch of integers, bunch of doubles and so on.
But if you'd like to print a bunch of different things are going to give you a hard time with no expression.
It's very easy because you can internally define it so you don't care about the type and just using
it.
So actually the expression make your life easier if you would like to print a bunch of numbers, a bunch
of different data types using for the expression, let's see another example.
What if I would like to have a function lambda that kibitzer and it allows the arguments as simple as
you come here in the clouds and just say ARC's the notice, the three dots are after the arcs, not
before it.
So this is how you can use it and you can now have like maybe the size of as you like, maybe another
scenario if you have in the main, I would like to just develop your own two fold expression directly
as a as a lambda function.
So you define Lunga and you just give it the normal parameter back and then you start use it.
Normally, as you see, using the expression with fold is very straightforward, but sometimes the guy
is like, good, confused.
Oh, is it possible how to use it and so on it.