So far, we were reading and a black screen, but if you would like to take one step more toward complicated
things, we can read and write two files.
So let's introduce the idea of the stream.
So the console, as you know, is just this black screen and we used it and our IO stream was linked
to the keyboard.
So when you try to input something from the keyboard, we read it.
If you wrote it, we see it on the screen.
And as you know, definitely this isn't the most flexible way.
Like in real life, we would like to have files or data disk and so on.
So you can think of the stream as some path where input and some input and something is moving into the
direction here.
So we this is a keyboard and you enter something is going to be free to your program.
This is the meaning of the stream.
Think of it as a stream of something, a stream of water, or whatever.
So it's here, a stream of characters going to the console.
Now let's go to reading and writing in C++.
I would like to show you first one thing that you shouldn't do in any professional project, but it
is for fun.
It can switch in a very easy way.
You will see your reading from a console to reading to a file without adding more than a couple of
lines.
So this happened through something is called free, open, small C style.
So if you put here this line "freopen" and use "stdin" application for standard input and used
here the file path and use here, "rt", then every c.in would go and read from this file in a
similar way.
If you use this file name for the out with "wt". and "stdout", then every std output, would then
then see how it was actually read the right to file.
So this is the easiest way to switch any program to read and write from files with
just a couple of lines.
OK, yeah.
So if you have here some file has some numbers you put this "freeopen" to read from it X and Y if you see
cin X and Y is going to read from the file here 3 and 6 and then you can sell them to the console
because this cout isn't oriented.
How does freopen work.
Let's put it now as out of the scope.
So this is the easiest way, but this isn't how you can do it, how you should it in a real big project.
This is just how can you switch on the program to read and write from files?
OK, let's see this the right C++ way.
This hash include fstream.
It has two things Ifstream I for input and ofstream for output.
So you need to define an object.
ifstream fin this is very close to the struct and then you say here, read, underscore, file
dot text.
So this is how you define an object that you go to read.
Skip this logic here and jump here.
Now you see here we say fin greater than  X and greater than Y notice here the style is very similar
to cin and in fact cin was defined this way.
is an object like fin here but defined already for you and was ready to read and write fromcin
the console.
That's why if we wanted to read and write from a file, which is similar one but of type ifstream
which is mean reading from a file this file name, once you're done with that, you start to read and
write with it in a very normal way.
Now there is two missing things here.
The first is we would like to check if the file exists or not, or can we open it or not.
Could be like, for example, permission issues.
So we say here, fin.fail.
If we couldn't read that, then we cannot open this file.
Otherwise we can use it, notice here.
We use this cout in the normal way.
The second thing is you have to close it by the end.
This is very, very, very important.
So we have one line to create it and want to check about working, then use it, then close it.
This is how you can read from a file.
And remember, fin here object is very similar to the CIn that we were using to read in a similar
way.
We can use the printing one.
So let's add here an ofstream Fout on this file.
So again, this how we can write to a file.
We can also check here if the file is ready or not and use it exactly as we use the cout.
Once we are done, we again importantly to close the pipe.
That's it.