This video will be like a demo for how to read from a file in eclipse.
So here we wrote our code that's going to read from this file.
So let's take it here and let's create a file right-click here on the project.
new and then you select the file.
You give it a name and.
That's it going for you.
Let's try 10, 20 now.
Our code is ready to read in this file and write in this file, which doesn't exist at the moment.
So let's just run this code.
After we run it, the file is created here, but you may not see it, so you come here maybe and
refresh the project you see now here my output file is 30.
Sometimes you see the output file is empty.
If this is the case, you need to add the word of flush, which you will learn more about it in the
more fundamental topics.
It's force the output here to come.
So if you don't see the output in the file, you just need to write the flush here in the file.
I'm not sure why.
It's why is it sad, oh, there's a missing come.
Yeah.
That set about creating file an eclipse.