And this video will learn how to read a file from a file using code looks.
First, we need to create a file.
Let's create a file with this name.
So you come here and say file new empty file and then ask you to add to that active project.
Yes.
Give it a name put the name here saving it in our project.
Hello world and save.
Yes.
to the Debug and release yes
Add to both of them.
Now let's put your numbers like 10 20, save the file.
And now let's try to run this file.
You see here in the others.
You see the file here.
And yeah, if you go to browsing the project, you will see now the read file is here.
Let's run this guy.
OK, so we are going to go back to the files here, we see we have now here something called my output
file, but we would like maybe to add it to our project itself.
Like if you came here, you will not see it.
This is your what you see in your project.
This is your actual hard disk.
Now, I can come here and say add active project to both of them.
Yes, yes.
Now, if you come here, you see my output file here see if you would like to remove a file from the
code blocks.
You should differentiate between removing from the eclipse itself and removing from the hard disk.
For example, if I came, I just here and say remove the file from the project.
Now go to what?
What is still on the hard disk.
This is what set on the hard disk the file still on the hard disk it is not removed it only removed from your
workspace if you would like to remove the file from even the hard disk.
You need to come and remove from here.
delete, and then, yes, so now they aren't in the hard disk anymore, but they might visible from here see it move
them from here else.
Yes, I typically, especially for cp file is good, maybe to remove them from the room from here
and from here.
That's it.