Let's learn a little more about the Files and Streams.
There is a way, if you would like your object, to read and write in the same time.
here there is something good.
ios. you first
Need to build some flag with it.
OK, so this flag here, I would like you to just use it as it is for now.
The default is in, out, app means append.
So this means we are reading and writing to the file.
But when it comes to writing, we append to the file.
What does this mean?
Let's say there is a file of hundred lines and you would like to write it.
There is a question here.
Do you like to add a line after the hundred lines or do you like to remove the current file and start
from the beginning?
OK, so that the default mode of the append(app) here, if you used it, is going to add an extra line to the
end of the file, if you would like, on the other side to remove the old file and start from scratch
on it.
So you are overwriting it use here ios::trunc
So these two lines here that you either decide to read or write, to write in these two modes and we are reading
also in this way.
So to define something that is read and write at the same time, use the fstream directly.
So it isn't just ifstream, it is fstream and then you pass here this status.
So we give it path and we also give it status.
And then as usual, you check if it's open or not.
And you also close it here, in the middle.
You can use it to read and also to write.
OK.
Overall, I don't like it.
Like I typically don't read and write in a similar way.
I typically just read or write or maybe in two rounds, like a one round.
I'm using it for a complete reading.
And after that, I started to write like I typically don't mix reading and writing in the same
way, like reading and writing then reading and writing
This could be confusing.
But anyway, if you just used fstream and provided a status for it, it's going to do fine if you are
going to read or write or what.
Let's see.
Another example here I would like to show you that how could I read the whole input file?
So I defined fstream and use the path.
This is just the default.
So it's going to read and write.
And then I checked if it's open or not.
And here I closed here I defined the while loop to get line.
Remember, Getline was taking cin, and line now we are going to give it the file handler.
So which is defined here.
So while Getline file handler and line, it's going to read all of your file content, which is very useful
during coding.
that's it.