Another interesting kind of stream is a string stream, the string dream act in a very temporary way.
you hash include this sstream and you can use the iStringstream.
So what does this mean exactly?
We are instead of reading from the console or reading from a file.
We are reading from a string that we have.
So let's say you have string str, which is "Mustafa 23 years", and you would like to parse it,
to extract the word Mostafa and the age here, for example.
So one way is to take the string and try to cut it and find twenty-three and so on.
This is a lot of logic.
What if we are dealing with this input as if it's coming from the console or from a file.
So here is how we do that.
We define istringstream, let's name it iss.
And then you provided with this is str now you start to act with ISS as if you are reading from,
say, a console.
You say here, ISS name age.
If you try to see what age it would be.
Twenty three.
So, again you have a string, you are dealing with it as a stream, like a console stream or a
file stream.
And then you are reading from it very normally as you see it was like very trivial to get the twenty
three using this way, otherwise you have to split the string and try to identify the number in a similar
way.
The ostringstream allows you to deal with the string as an output destination.
So let's say I would like to create a string and I would like to print Mostafa Space 50 years old.
So the way to do that is to define ostringstream "oss" and then write Mostafa space, 50, space years old.
If you did oss.str, it will give you Mostafa, 50 years old.
This is very nice way.
If you would like to construct a string in a complex way that involves a lot of things that you can
also define astringstream.
Can you read and write in the same way?
But I usually use i string stream and o string stream in a separate way.
So these two string streams provide very conventional functionalities that it.