In this section, we will start to discuss a lot of syntex details in C++ relevant to classes that allow
us to build more of OOP projects.
It isn't about the core OOP's concepts but think of it like more of the utilities.
The first thing is a constructor.
We already saw the constructor when we studied the struct.
We know that the constructor can give us an automatic way to assign initial values for your object.
We saw before the default constructor where there are no arguments and also we saw the parameterize
constructor where you can have multiple constructors.
The constructor is eventually a member function,
but it's kind of a special member function, for example, it must have the same name as the class and
also, it doesn't have a return to type here. In C++ 11, the recommended way to initialize C++
is the initializer list.
This is how you initialize using the initializer list. You see here
after defining the function of the constructor you put colon,
then you start to put width, width, height, height, or whatever.
These are recent parameter.
As you see one advantage here, you don't care if the parameters of the constructor name are the same
as a member function,
but going back one step here, you have to make the difference, like, say, here width underscore and
width to be able to assign it.
So this is one intuitive way about the member initializer list.
So you define it this way.
If you also have here like one parameter also, then you can say define that guy and then define
that guy with initial values zero.
Remember, when you have different functions with the same name, but different parameters,
we call it function overloading.
There is also an interesting thing,
we call it delegating.
So if you have a constructor that is empty, you can set the width and height with zero,
but a better way to minimize the code is just to do something like rectangle zero and zero.
This one is going to call the constructor here.
So this is like a function calling a function.
So the empty constructor is calling another constructor.
So the whole initializer list is about having a colon here.
...
The way that the initializer list works is actually very interesting because it works before the
actual processing in the constructor itself.
That's why there are some things that cannot be initialized in another way,
for example, if you have here a const variable or a reference variable, you cannot get inside here
and just initialize it.
It doesn't go this way.
You have to initialize it in the initializer list, and there are actually a lot of other
reasons.
So the recommended way from now follow is to initialize using the member initializer list
unless there is some reason to don't do that.
When a constructor calls another constructor, we call it delegating constructor.
When you are in a company, you would hear something like the power of delegation,
your team lead is delegating tasks for you,
so delegation is an important concept in practical life.
The default constructor, as you know, is a constructor that doesn't have any parameters or there are
parameters, but they have initial values, notice that these two functions now are the same
because they are actually both of them allow empty constructor,
so this will actually will not compile.
OK, you have only to make one of them.
OK, so what if we don't provide a default constructor to the rectangle?
What happens actually that the compiler will generate a constructor for you, and it's going to take these
parameters and going to assign some initialized values for them.
In our case, they will be assigned the default values of 10 and 20, but otherwise, they will be assigned
some default values like zero and zero,
for example, here. Don't use the default initialization,
It's much better to define your own constructor and initialize your own variables.
Yeah, read this code, this code will not compile,
Why?
There is a restriction in the constructor if you provided a constructor that takes parameters,
you cannot call the default constructor, so you have to provide it.
This is one of the tricky compile errors, that you still to see and get puzzled about what is a problem.
If you provided the constructor with arguments, it's OK as long as you are using this constructor,
but if you tried to use the default constructor, it is going to do a compilation error. As a tip, always provide
a default constructor, it will make your life easier.
A destructor is a bit the opposite definition of the constructor, when your object is going out of the
scope, it's going to be destructed automatically.
So sometimes we need to provide a destructor function.
It could be only one destructor function.
You first use this symbol on your keyboard and put the class name and start to
do ...
some destructor's logic here. If you are defining it outside the class, like defining it,
use the scope resolution operator then the destructor's name similar to any function name.
So this all of it is a function name for the destructor. If you have an object written with a pointer
and then you deleted it directly, then this guy is going to call the destructor.
If it just went out of the scope of some if's conditions or so, it is going to call the destructor.
If the whole program ended then anything that not be destructed will also call the destructor.
So constructor builds, destructor finishes.
But why do we need the destructor? mainly to deallocate memory
If you have pointer data created inside your class, if you didn't remove
them in the destructor, this will create something we call a memory leak.
A memory leak happens when the program has data that no one deleted. As a rule,
Keep it in mind, whoever created some pointer in the memory, must be deleted.
For example, if inside the class you created a memory,
then you have to delete the memory inside the class from the destructor.
If you created an object with a pointer in the main, for example, you have to remove it in the main.
If you didn't do that, there would be a memory leak.
OK, so a destructor must have logic to destroy the data by itself.
Let's see an example here.
This is our own class,
It's called my vector,
It has internally a pointer array and an initial length of 100,
and this is one constructor that has length and some default value. In the creation,
we assign the length, and also we create a new array, and we start to assign for it the default value.
We here create the vector and then after the main, the vector will be destroyed.
Here in the destructor, I say delete array arr, that is it.
This way the memory is released.
Notice if you forgot to put the brackets of the array, this would be a memory leak.
So there are two cases for the memory leak. The first that you forget to make a destructor, or make an empty destructor,
or make a delete without delete the array.
You have to be careful with pointers in C++.
Finally, there is something called this pointer, when you create an object from outside, there
is actually a pointer
looking at it.
We inside the class, have the chance to access this implicit pointer for us.
It's named this.
OK, so it's a pointer.
That's why we use arrow here.
You can use it any time, you can say this arrow length,
so this is the length here.
We don't need it unless there are some reasons.
As you see, most of the time we can refer to variables directly,
but later, you will see some use cases for this THIS pointer.
That's it.