Another interesting thing about the class is the friend class. A friend class is a class that
we define it as our friend and we mean by that
this class has the permission to access our private data.
Looking here, we have Class A defined with its own private and public, there is also class B here that has
functionality with Class A, so class B here is declaring that friend class B, it means that there
will be some class named B, and this class is a friend to us.
It means it can access our own private data and private functions.
So here the class B have an object of Type A,
so it now accessing its private functions and also accessing its private data.
So this is what is a private class. By the way, class A when I refer to Class B, but class B when I
refer to class A.
This is a cycle.
Sometimes our classes are cycling this way.
If you looked here, we just are declaring the class without defining it.
This is how we break the cycle.
So now A knows that if something is B but no details and B knows A and has no problems.
In addition, there is a friend member function.
What if you would like to give access to a specific member function in another class, only
a single function, then you can only make only this function
a friend, for example,
let's say that B has function access1 and access2, but you would like to only declare function accessA1
to be a private function so that it can access our data and our member functions.
You say here, you write the function, but you use the colon operator of the B class,
so now this is a friend member function.
In a more global case, you can define any function in the system as a friend function.
So if there is some function named printA, you can declare it here as...
as a friend function, then this function can also access our private data.
That's all about the friend function. In C++,
It isn't healthy to use it a lot.
We will see in the homework what example for that.
But be careful.