In our first homework set number one on the last three concepts about static, friend, and const.
First of all, why do you think that C++ doesn't allow us to create a const static member function?
If you tried also to use this pointer inside...
..., sorry, C++ doesn't allow using this pointer to access a static member
data.
Why do you think so?
Read this program,
guess what is the output and why.
This assignment is about the configuration manager, section about some ideas behind it relevant
to design patterns.
So a configuration manager might have different meanings in industry, but one meaning is something
that's loading a lot of configuration that we have,
and typically this configuration is just static and it's typically involved servers IPs,
databases paths and so on, and typically also might be heavy
So it's a good idea to cash them for frequent requests. After you developed it,
you notice that there are several code parts that create a separate object, where is the problem?
The problem is it's actually loading the same things, but every time it takes like 30 minutes to load
the data from the memory.
So your team lead suggests the following: change the class to allow only one instance to be created.
In other words, no way for others to make 2 different objects in memory.
This way you are forcing everyone to use the same object, so it would be loaded once, cashed once,
and no one can use 2 object of it, so it load once,
and that's it.
Here is the current
code, it has some configuration, a boolean if it is loaded so far or not. We create an object, and then
we call load function to load it.
If it is loaded then that's all.
If not loaded,
we loaded and mark loaded with true. This code by the way, like kind of lazy loading. You load things only when you would
like to load them.
Anyway this is a current configuration manager.
There is some function right now that creates the manager, another function that creates the manager.
Notice every one of them is doing some lazy loading.
So every one of them is taking like 30 minutes, we would like to solve this problem. Code review:
We have a project with the following requirements.
It is for classes
so there is a class for a student and his grade per course. Grade can be a maximum of 100 at least now,
and this is the current grade, for example, for one course. You should provide functionalities
for printing or retrieving.
Also, you need to track how many times the printing function is called.
It's important to keep statistics sometimes about the different functionalities.
So the developer coded it actually the following that you are going to review. This is a global static
total prints variable.
Here are some ID, grades vector and course name vector.
There are some constructors here, adjust_grade is trying to be careful with negative values or wrong values.
There is a function that adds grades, it takes a grade and the course name.
If the course's name already exists, it just ignore it,
It doesn't update the current grade.
This is the print
all courses function.
It's incrementing this global variable and then printing all the current data.
Some getters here, totoal_grade_sum is just summing the total grade of the student and just returning
it.
Please read the code very carefully.
This is an example of creating an object, adding three subjects, printing it. Now after reading the code
very carefully and understand it, figure out 2 coding bugs.
There are several OOP violations or design issues in this code.
What are they?
Figure out something
if we need to change it in the code, then there would be a lot of changes in the code, and how to fix that.
There are some naming inconsistency,
figure that out.
Also, suggest two better variable naming to some of the functions. For the function
get_courses of student info, integer position, maybe suggest also a better declaration, like a different way
to declare this function.
That's it.