For the second set of homework, which involves some like, might be a bit hard for you. The first
one is black box testing.
Testing is a very critical part of any software engineering process, like the very popular unit testing.
A black box
testing is a black box that focus on what, not how.
What does it mean?
It cares about the public functions only of the class and doesn't care about how does it work or any Internenal
of it.
So if the class has a few functionalities, you provide them. You can think of it like the following:
You have some class named black box tester, test_all function, you call it. The test_all function
start to test one by one internal functionality,
every functionality here is testing something of the public interface. You might expect if a class
has five public functions, you might, for example, have here five or more just functionalities.
So think of it as a tester, you are testing the WHAT logic of the other class.
The white box testing is a bit different.
You now care about the internals.
This means you care about the private variables, and you care about internal updates.
This isn't the standard the way that we do in it in the market, but it's a good approach to know.
So the question is how to test a class from outside,
and you still know about its inner details?
There are several approaches for that.
Feel free to make it like a future
reading. The one that I would like you to follow is: define a friend class inside the students
grades info as a friend class. Now, the friend
the class can access all the internal functions and external functions,
and now please start to do testing for the class in terms of white box testing to make
sure that everything is OK. About testing and using a friend,
this is a future reading for you after the course.
Code extension, the previous code (we are actually referring here to the code from
last homework, OK) has 2 limitations. The printing functionality is just printing to console and printing
all content,
but this isn't flexible, so we would like more flexibility.
For some reasons,
we cannot change the old code,
and this is a case always in the industry that you shouldn't, in most of the cases, touch others code, but you
should try to extend them.
There is something that we call closed and extension.
So by close, we mean it cannot be changed for a reason or another and extension,
we just is extending with more functionality.
Here is the idea from your team lead.
You are to develop a class that mainly works on an object from a student_grades_info.
So our class would be composed of one object here,
and then it satisfies two critical functionalities for iterating on a student_grades_info. Function
name has_next
tell us if there are more items to retrieve, and a function named get_next that returns
the actual object to read. With these two functions, has_next and get_next,
we are providing more flexible functions to return the items and print them in whatever way you
like.
There is also a function called reset that can reset printing from the beginning. Develop a class to satisfy
that. Here is the main function.
Now, we have here a student grades info as we did, and we have a new class of info printer that takes
an object from the class that we defined.
We can now add grades info as we would like.
No problem here.
So we are adding to the original object,
but when comes to printing, we use our info printer object.
So here are the has_info, has_next, and get_next behavior.
Let's say we want to print a maximum of three courses only.
So we say while limit minus minus
as long as we have a limit, check with the printer if it has next or not.
If it has nixed, then you are getting the text and printing it.
Now let's say we are added other couple of courses,
so in total now we have 4, and still
the limit is 3,
Reset the iterator, and now again using has_next and get_next, print the courses up to three which happened here.
So as you see, the printer has an object of st1 and providing has next, get next, and reset iterator
to provide a more flexible iterating on a class that we cannot change. Wrapper,
wrapper is a very common idea in industry.
Let's say that the student grades info is a class from the open-source. In industry,
if there is something good available from open source, and it has a good license, we might use it to save
our time,
but there is always a concern
what if there are hidden bugs in the future, and no one is planning to maintain them and solve them?
Let's say we have 20 classes using this grades info. If you decide for some reason to replace this
open-source project using your own project, all of your code is going to be changed.
Now, we don't want to face such an issue.
So here is
what your team lead is suggesting.
You are to build a class and name it wrapper.
The wrapper class will provide the same public functionalities as the student gades info,
It will have an internal object of type student_grades_info. Every call to the wrapper
is just delegating the call to the local object that it had inside it.
Now, let all your code depend on this wrapper, not on this open source code.
If in the future you decided to remove the open-source code, you are only changing the implementation
of the wrapper.
So you change only one class and nothing else in your system. You are also to extend your current functionalities
with two public methods to help us to maintain, to count the total number of prints for the user prints
and to the total number of created student info.
Let's see an example.
We are here creating info_wrapper, as you see is just acting here now
add_grade, add_grade, add_grade.
It's acting exactly like the old object from the student
grades info. When you call add_grade here, it is going internally to call add_grade
In student_grade_info, printing is going to printing, and so on.
You are doing here some logic, then you can call these two static functions to do the printing for you.
So this is the overall logic that we would like to see. Future features, you are a team lead
and you have a discussion with your team member.
He told you that in an informal discussion with the customer, he was told that in six months, there
will be a need to do print for different things like printing to file and console, and maintaining statistics
about every used function.
He suggested implementing all of these extensions now to save our time
in the future to do other work. As a leader,
do you accept or reject that?
Do you have other suggestions?
Why?
We have a class that has answer text, and you are debating with some fresh software engineer about
which style to use among all of these guys.
I would like you to discuss the differences in providing the function in this way.
That's it.