For the homework of the constructor and the destructor, we learned that the initializer list is the
recommended way for constructors. Let's say that we have a class that have three variables A, B,
C in order, but the initializer list used the order B, A, C. So the question here, will the constructor
initialize them based on class order or initializer-list order?
and what is the order of the destructor? In general,
you are preferred to learn the answer to such a question by reading actually a book or reference,
but I would like you to write a program that can tell us the answer to these two questions.
You are to read this code and first of all, you are to tell us different ways how to finish the
constructor of class C here.
So we have here something with reference and something with const. How to finish this constructor? is there
more than a way?
And for the class A constructor, how many times would it be called and why do you think so?
and give a tip for the coder who wrote this class.
In this program, let's say that there is a code review for class D here, but the senior team leader
told you that it's better to use const and  reference in the constructor objects this way or function
calls.
Why do you think so?
Validations, figure out one bug in this code, fix it, and provide a tip for the coder who wrote such a
code. Figure out another potential bug, and also provide a tip for the coder.
In this time class, identify two changes that would make the code readable much more, identify also
a bug and two code duplications.
There is a missing input validation here for some potential user mistake,
What is it?
We would like to change our class to support this kind of fancy usage, you will see it a lot in practice.
So what exactly to change the code to allow that.
There is a code change request that came to this class and code change is something that happens
all the time in industry.
A good class and a good OOP project is a project that tries to minimize the code changes.
One important difference between moving from normal programming to OOP: we think a lot
about the code, the code design, the code quality.
It isn't just about let's program the idea.
It is more about the project, the functionality, the clarity, the readability, and so on.
So anyway, the request is that this class has three variables, hours, minutes, seconds.
We would like to change it to only have one variable integer total_seconds. Do necessary changes to support
the new class. Identify one good coding tip
if it was applied from the beginning in this project, the code change that we will do would be much less
compared to the one that we will do for this class.
This code is working well.
I would like you to read it.
We have some car specs here, like some functionalities of a car with some getters and setters,
and this is an AutoTrader that gets a request to search for a query with the following matching and then
it keeps going searching in the cars comparing one by one to check if we have such
specs or not.
This code is working well, but it is badly designed.
As I said, starting from OOP,
you start to think a lot about the design.
How good is a design?
One important thing in the homework in this course emphasizes designing skills.
So think what is wrong in this design?
Thinking deeply.
What is the output of this program?
This is one question, and there are two memory leaks in this program.
Figure out them.
That's it.