C++ provides us with the copy constructor to help us in some situations related to the use of pointers.
Here in this example, we have a class my number that has a pointer data type of integer and another
just normal integer. In the constructor, the val1 is initialized with a new integer memory, and then
it puts the value of X and val2 just for y. There is here a destructor that we did nothing at the moment,
and we are printing the address of val (the pointer) and also the address of the second integer val.
Here we define two objects, A and B. A is using the default values, B is 10 and 20, and we start to print
the value and address of A and B.
So we notice A is 3 and 5, and these are the two addresses.
B is 10 and 20, and these are the two addresses.
So far, so good.
We now are trying to assign A to B, so B equals A. What happens in assigning objects this way?
The compiler is going to copy member by member the values.
OK, so let's print B right now after this assigning. We notice here that the value of B
became like the value of A. This is good so far,
but let's look at the memory itself.
We notice here that the val2's address is still as it is,
this is normal, but the value of the address for the pointer is the same as the value of A.
So what happened here?
Where is the address of myself?
My address is just gone.
So the address of B of va1
is gone.
Now the B pointer is looking at the A pointer.
So first of all, there is a memory leak here because the B pointer is just gone without deleting it.
The second problem that we are going to face is here in line 17.
If we tried to delete it here, there is a problem that's going to happen.
Think about it.
This takes us to the problem of the shallow copy and deep copy. When we just assign two objects to itself,
we are just going to take your pointer as it is,
but my intention wasn't to take your pointer.
Your pointer is your own.
You created it and you should delete it,
and I have my own pointer,
I should delete it.
Now, this wasn't the intention.
So this takes us to what we call the deep copy. In a deep copy,
we just don't go and take the pointer copy to us.
We go actually to the value of the pointer and start to make a copy from it to us instead of just
taking your pointer.
So this takes us to what we call the copy constructor.
The copy constructor is a special constructor,
It has like four different ways when to be called, and is going to help us to make a deep copy.
There are two cases when you are initializing from another object and a case for passing objects that
doesn't have a reference and fourth case when you are returning from an object.
If you didn't provide a copy constructor, it is going to make a default one
that just make a shallow copy, which you will take the pointer of the other class as it is. Later we will learn
about something named Move constructor that is very related to it.
So let's see where is the copy constructor. Here when we say A and B, we are actually having
two normal constructors.
If I started to say defined my number C of B, B is actually another object of my type.
So this has to call the constructor to build C from B, or if you just did D equal B is also coping
constructor from one object to another. Fun1 of C is a function that is taking an object and doesn't have any references
here,
so this is calling using copy constructor, and Fun2 is returning an object here, which I'm taking here,
it is another copy constructor. These are the four cases of the copy constructor. Notice here,
I started to say A equals B. This is an assignment, not a copy constructor.
So what's the difference between line 43, a line 38? that here you are creating a new
object.
So it's using a constructor, but here just assigning it.
If you started to print the addresses of A, B, C, D, you will notice all of them are looking at the pointer
of A which means we lost the pointer B and C and D, they are all gone because of this shadow
copy that just to take the copy of pointer A to myVal. The way to implement a deep copy is using a copy
constructor that goes as following:
You define a new constructor,
so my number here, and you give it an object of the type my number also,
but you have to put a reference here and preferred also to put a const here.
Now, the logic of this constructor is as follows: you are giving another object that already
exists, please make a copy from it.
So the way to make it a deep copy is you go inside it, you create your own value,
and start to copy the other one value in your val and whatever other logic. When you think about
that logic here, here we define A and B and printing A and B, you will notice they would have different
addresses.
Why?
Because we don't anymore take just its pointer to my pointer.
I'm defining my own pointer and taking my value from its value, not putting my pointer with its pointer
one.
So in the first case, it would be like val1 equals another dot val1. That's it.
But here I have my own pointer, I'm taking my copy by myself.
The reference is mandatory to be used, const is optional but highly preferred.
So this is all about the copy constructor.
Let me highlight one more thing that a bit related to the copy constructor, which we call the temporary
object. An object that doesn't have a name is named a temporary object.
So the main rule, for now, is it cannot be bound to a non-const reference.
So what does this mean?
If you have a reference, then it have to be const.
Later, we will learn about something more complicated in C++ 11 named move semantic,
It use this double reference or
double ampersand. Let's see these three functions here.
We have a function that takes an object A,
no references.
So is this a reference? no.
This is OK now. Play number two,
is this a reference?
Yes.
Is it const? No.
And here is this reference?
Yes.
Is it const? No
So if you here tried to call play one with my number brackets.
Now, is this a temporary object?
The answer is yes.
Why?
There is no name for this object.
So the rule is, are you sending for a reference?
No, this isn't a reference,
then this is OK.
Now here in play two, you are sending also a temporary object.
Is this a reference?
Yes, it has to be const.
Is it const? No, then compilation error. Play number three is calling something.
Is it temporary?
Yes.
Is it a reference?
Is it const?
Yes, this is OK.
So the rule here is if it's a temporary object, which means it doesn't have a name, then if you are
passing to something that isn't reference, this is OK.
If it is a reference, it must be const.
So here in this case we have a reference then paly two cannot accept temporary objects.
Paly three can accept temporary objects, Play one can accept temporary objects.
In play-four, we are here returning an object from this function.
This is OK, but remember, the returned here is a temporary object because ...
this object
here is X, but X is going to be destroyed.
Something in memory is going to be sent back by play4.
So if I called here paly4, the eventually what is here is a temporary object.
So again, you cannot pass it to play2 because it has a reference, but without a const. Notice that sometimes
the copy constructor will not be called.
So while here, we are expecting a return of object that is going to be called, but C++ has a lot of optimization,
like something called return value optimization, is going to somehow do a lot of magic and internally
in memory,
It will handle it in a different way.
Sometimes you will wait for the copy constructor to print a message that some construction happen,
but sometimes it isn't printed, not because the constructor wasn't called, but more than C++ found a way
to make the same thing in a more efficient way.
So anyway, this is how the copy constructor is related to this story. That it.