Let's take the homework for the copy constructor.
The first one is in the copy constructor itself,
remember, it was like the argument const, my number, reference another.
So one question is, in general speaking, what would happen if we moved the constructor to the
private section of a class, and what would happen if we moved the copy constructor to the private section?
Another concern is C++ won't allow you to use a copy constructor without the reference, why? and also
C++ doesn't force you to use const, but still a very good practice to use it,
Why? think about that.
When we presented this my number class, we commented line 17.
Why do you think so?
So try to guess what's going to happen.
One of the coders wrote for us this code, I would like to read it carefully, think about what will happen
when we run this code,
why so?
Think about how to change it to prevent the user from such a wrong usage,
and also provide some tips to the coder who wrote this code.
By the way, here in 1995,
whenever we delete a pointer, it's much good to put a null or even better not_pointer.
We already coded this class before in one of the previous sessions.
I would like you to enhance it, provide a copy constructor. In the get method, I would like you to make
sure that we respect the boundaries, provide a method to change the content of the vector, and provide a method
to get the array's length.
So read it and do that. In a similar way,
about this my vector class,
one of the developers provided the get_length function as following: integer reference that returns the length.
So this is a return by reference.
Question number one, which OOP concept is violated this way.
Also, develop a main and show how a user can abuse our class with such a mistake.
I would like you to read this code and think of the following: which line of this code won't compile
and which lines of this code will make a runtime error?
So think about that.
Finally, let's say you have a coding project, you're on it, and let's say that there is a serious
memory leak in the code.
A serious memory leak is someone that is that like has a lot of memory not released in this memory leak.
Let's say a big array.
So if you're running the program a lot, the whole memory machine will be consumed.
I would like you to think, how can we know that
this code has a memory leak without reading the code itself.
You can just only run a code as much as you want.
So think about an answer and then check out this link.
That's it.