One of the important things in modern C++ is the std initializer list. Today, we would like to see
it more with classes, you probably saw before in the STL syntax like you're creating
an object with the uniform initialization style, which is throwing in a bunch of numbers.
So this probably might match what we call an initializer list.
We have here a class named adder
with a simple variable and an empty constructor and another constructor that takes an initializer
list.
You can think of the initializer list here, as just a vector of numbers or a set of numbers typically.
Now, this constructor is receiving this initialization style is receiving it in an initializer list.
We have here another function that we are calling with this list, and then we are iterating on
this list and just summing all of its values together and doing some logic here.
So this is one way to initialize your object and this would fit now with your uniform initialization style
when you use this kind of braces. You can also call the like, let's say add 3, 4,
which is calling normal function or calling with
initialization list on the fly in this way.
This list is typically of type constant, and behind the scene
it is implemented in a specific way, and it is very lightweight and very memory efficient,
and you will find a lot of things in STL with the support to the initializer list.
Now, I would like to take you one step bigger to realize that there are different situations where
you are passing this guy, but there are actually meaning different things.
In the first case here, we have a struct A which is very basic, has just primitive variables,
It doesn't have a constructor.
Remember, we mentioned before that there is a case where the struct or a class is called an aggregate.
So if you have a class that satisfies the aggregate conditions and we are defining A
of 1 and 3, then automatically 1 would be set to the X, and 3 will be set to the y.
...
So this is an aggregate initialization.
The other case is you have a constructor here that take two variables and assigning them internal
with the member initializer list.
This is called a member initialization list or member list initialization,
and then when you define here B of 2 and 9, then the 2 will be also assigned to the X and the 9
will be assigned to the y.
So, again, this isn't directly the std initializer list.
In the third case here, we have a Class C1 and class c1 is supporting constructor with two
variables and also supporting constructor with the initializer list.
Now, if you tried to clone the 3 and 7, would it be matched with the X and Y?
The answer is no.
The initializer list constructor will always have a higher priority.
So if it is something like C1 of 3 and 7, 3 and 7 will be sent as an initializer list
here to be assigned here, so you can access the initializer list within begin,
so the first element is begin and the second element is begin plus one.
So the moral of that is if it happened that we have all of these guys, then the priority is first for
the initializer list, second for the regular constructor, and third for the aggregate and notice here,
and this is a bit a bad thing, that the syntax here and the syntax here are very close,
just this is braces and this is parenthesis.
You have still to be very careful so that you don't call the wrong constructor.
If it happened that you have a template, say a bunch of numbers, you cannot send directly initializer
list this way, it might be hard to deduce its type.
You can send it in an explicit way like say, initializer list of integer or you are sending something
else like vector of integer,
but this why this one is more lightweight in terms of memory.
Let's see the initializer list with the STL.
If you defined an initializer list like 5 and 10 here or use the parenthesis and use 5 and 10, one
of the bad things, they are different, as we just have seen from a few slides.
If you tried here to call with these braces, this will call a constructor that will just take two values
and put them in a vector.
So if you tried to print the vector, it would be five and ten,
but if you tried to call these two numbers with parenthesis, this is calling another constructor, which
will just create five copies of value 10 and put them in a vector.
So the problem here is that this guy now matched two different things.
It matches two different things.
This is the type of constructor, but this is completely another type of constructor.
So be very careful about that.
What else here, the multi-map, if you have a multi-map, in C++, we used to insert it this
way,
we used to insert a pair of an integer with 1 and 40, another pair of integer and an integer, and so on.
...
With the initializer list in the C++, you can write as simple as 1, 40 and 1, 50.
So now it just constructs them for you in a very beautiful way.
Let's print all the multi-map elements that have the key of one, which would
be a 40 and 50.
So you can do that as following:
You can call the function name equals range with value 1 which you will return for you a range
with first and begin.
This is a pair of first and second, which now can iterate on the range that
is starting with the value of 1.
So now you can iterate normally and print the value of the iterator.
So the iterator_begin is the first one with 1, 40 and the last one will be 1, 50,
and you are iterating in between here.
The last thing to notice also with the initializer-list problems is when it comes to the
auto.
If you used auto X1 and you used the equal, which is doing copy initialization with one and two here is
going to be like an initializer list.
If you tried to do an auto with something that makes data types, it will fail for a compilation error.
It cannot deduce that this is integer.
Jump to line 12, x4 with a single element with equal would be an initializer list
Here the tricky one, x5 without the equal direct initialization is an integer.
So line 12 and 13 are very problematic.
Line 12 is creating it as an initializer list
if you used the equal. Line 13 without equal is going to create an integer.
That's why line 11 is given a compilation error.
Assume it's a single element, not just a list of elements.
So this is one place where using the initializer list will create a problem.
Still, C++ is very problematic when it comes to initialization.
That's it.