One of the interesting features in C++ 11 is the default keyword. Let's read this code.
You have here a class employee with a single parametrized employee class that has a salary and has a string name.
As we know, if we tried to create an object without parameters here like that, which
is trying to call the copy constructor, the compiler would generate an error.
You cannot call the default constructor if you didn't provide it,
and meanwhile, there is a parameterized constructor, as we learned before.
So this case is a compilation error.
The main way to be able to call this code is to come here and provide some employee with an empty body. In C++11
...
there is a simplification for that.
You can come here to line 12 and just uncommented it, it says employee equals default. When the compiler
see this instruction, it is going to generate a default constructor for you.
So it just something that makes your life a bit easier
like - you can always if you don't have a problem with an empty constructor, you can just
provide it. This generated what is called defaulted default constructor.
So default constructor, it means it doesn't take parameters and it's generated by a compiler.
So if you uncommented line 12, it will compile. Now,
it seems like very easy,
everything is done. Not exactly,
there are now four cases for a default constructor that has an empty body.
The first case is you declared by yourself. You define a default constructor by yourself in an explicit
way.
The second way is you write nothing,
however, you do not have a parameterize constructor.
In this case, the compiler will generate a default constructor for you,
and with the third way that we just learned, we can declare and define the class with the keyword
default,
and this case also can be like switched also to declare in the class and have another dot_h file or
some separate definition where you are using the default.
So here, declare, define together in one statement like we did here, and here, declare in the class
and separate the definition in another file.
So in the separation, you just say constructor name equals default in that definition,
colon-colon constructor's name equals default.
So let's see the code of these four different cases. Here
you define the class, and you define the constructor and just an empty code here.
This is a default constructor.
In the second case here, you didn't define the default constructor, but there is also no
parametrized constructor so the compiler will generate one for you.
The third case you define the constructor with the key keyword default.
In the fourth case, you define the constructor,
and here in the definition, you declared here and in the definition,
you say the keyword default.
Now, we have four cases, but who cares, they are all anyway
default constructor,
and if you would like to get a sense of the differences, you might say, oh, this is the only one
that I generated, and B, C, and D are 3 generated cases, but still who cares about that.
So here is a point.
If I told you that the user defined constructor is behaving in some scenarios in a different way
than the generated constructors. What is your guess?
Your guess is now OK,
One here is my user provided constructor, B, C and D,
cases 2, 3, 4 are user defined constructor.
Sadly no,
and this is a bit very counterintuitive.
The B is actually Yes.
Isn't provided by you.
So this is very clear.
The C also isn't provided by you, but D is considered as a user-provided constructor.
Why?
Because you declared it here without any intentions, and later you decide that the definition is going
to be this way, or maybe later you can define it in a different way,
and the decision if it is a user-provided constructor or implicitly generated one, depends on the
declaration of the definition.
So the declaration here says default, but the definition declaration here doesn't say.
so the moral of that is the constructor of A and D are considered to be user-provided constructor and
constructors of B and C are considered to not be a user-provided constructor.
It is counterintuitive because you think here you didn't provide anything. Now still again, why there
is difference?
Anyway they are all four generated empty by the constructor.
Sadly, there is a difference. There is what we call a default initialization and what we call a value
initialization. Here in default initialization, we created A, B, C, D, and then as we didn't
initialize anything for the variable i in this constructor,
then when you try to output the value i of any of these objects, it's going to be garbage typically.
Don't be cheated
if the compiler printed zero. If you tried to print it many, many times, it is going to show you an actual
garbage.
So the default initialization here is just calling the empty constructor, which is doing nothing
for i.
So i is going to be garbage in the four cases.
Now, here is the difference.
What we call a value initialization.
When you use the braces or the uniform initialization this way, these braces without equal is calling
value initialization.
The value initialization has a different mechanism that goes directly to the values and does something
only if the constructor was automatically generated.
So as we said, the A and D are considered user-provided.
So even in A and D with value initialization, still your constructor, which is empty, would be called.
It would be still garbage.
Now in the case of B and C, they are compiler defined constructor, and the compiler will
not call the default constructor.
It will call another mechanism that does the two value initialization with the default values
for your variables.
So I here, in the case of B and C, will be initialized to zero again.
The constructor will not be called for the B and C, the empty constructor will not be called.
There will be a special initialization for the variables that happened.
So in the case of A and D, which are user-provided, the constructor will be called, and i will
be just said to garbage because no one handle it,
but in the case of B and C with using value initialization then  only B and C initialize member wise
in a special treatment.
Now, this is overall is very counterintuitive in everything,
and some people say, C++ initialization is just a nightmare,
and this is just one case of that.
You might know that a single integer can be declared and initialized in C++ like declared in 15 different
ways.
This is a hell,
this is a lot.
So if there is a tip I would like to give you here to avoid all of these issues, even if you didn't
know about them or you forgot about them or you cannot understand them is as follows:
First of all, always initialize your variables.
Don't let your variables here be left for the compiler or for some
guessing that is going to be initialized zero if I used the value initialization.
No, it will not happened, not necessary.
The second way, use this value initialization.
Don't leave it in the default initialization
this way, this guy is going to do more mechanism.
So you are by initializing your variables and using the braces style or the value initialization style, you are having
more chance of more robust code.
One more comment here about the variable S.
The variable S here, in all cases, will be initialized to an empty constructor.
Why?
Because this is an object, so it's going to call anyway
Its default constructor, which will be an empty case.
So it's a big deal here
in this string s because it has a proper constructor for it,
but i here is a primitive, there's no initialization that would happen here. That's all.