In modern C++, you can also easily delete a function from a class, you can read the copy
constructor, the assignment operator, some normal member function, and later we will learn also how to prevent
specific types of constructors.
Now, if you would like to delete some constructor, let's say, you have
here provided a class constructor for an employee with integer salary and name, but you want to avoid that
someone is calling with double, and there is an implicit conversion happening here.
You can come and say employee double salary, string name equals delete. When you see this keyword
this way, it is going to
disallow this guy to be called.
We can call with value 10, but you can't call with value
10.5. Another case
if you would like to delete the copy constructor, one might think, OK, let's put it in the private
section,
so it's now deleted.
Now, you can just put here the keyword delete, which is explicitly showing your attention that
this guy is deleted.
So now if you have E1, you cannot now copy constructor to E2, it will be prevented.
A third case is what we call the assignment operator.
We didn't again study the assignment operator so far,
we'll do that in the operator overloading.
You just come here and say write this statement, follow this structure for your class, and just say here
equal delete.
This is going to prevent an assignment statement,
and as we said before, the difference between this one and this one that this one involve E1 and
E2 with the creation of a new object,
but this one involves just assigning, there is no creation here.
You can also delete a specific function.
Let's say you have a hello, integer X, and double X, you wanna it to be called with integer, but not with double.
You can again put here the word delete so that the compiler doesn't allow this kind of call. Some tips,
I would like you always, as a beginner
that's all, to start with deleting your copy constructor and assignment operator.
This will warn you whenever you are trying to do the copy constructor and assignment operator, and you didn't notice that.
So it's just more for clarifying for you what's happening,
and you need that when you have internal pointers inside your class. At least if you
would like, you can provide the copy constructor, but you must disable the new assignment operator
if you have internal pointers. Later, when we learn the operator overloading, you will know how to
properly provide an assignment operator similar to the copy constructor.
Remember, this is very important when you have internal pointers.
That's it.