The keyword const with classes. One of the highly recommended things in the OOP programming
is to create as much as possible constant functions.
So what is a constant function, and how to do that? The constant function in a constant member function,
when you come inside the function and after the braces, you put the word const.
So what does it imply?
It means that the data members of this class will not be changed through
this function.
Thinking about compute_area, compute_area as a function is expected to just multiply width and height,
but not to change the width and height.
So if you tried here to change the width to one, the compiler will complain because this is a const function.
Getters are typically const functions,
no getters are expected to change the variable, but setters cannot be const function because they are expected
to change the value. Creating as much as possible const
functions will reduce the errors because if the developer decided to change
something that intention wasn't supposed to be changed, he would get a compilation error.
You can also definitely make your object to const,
but this is a different thing.
...
Oh, no, sorry,
there is an important trick here.
When you defined an object R1 here, you can call its own functions.
If you defined the object as const, you can only call the const functions, but you cannot
call the non-const functions.
So this is an important difference.
So const means internally you cannot change them,
and also you if the class is const, you cannot call function
that is not-const.
So set width, for example here, isn't function with const,
so you cannot call it because the object supposed to not be changed. In terms of pointers for the sake of
knowledge,
let's say...
there are three ways to define pointers here
to be careful with them.
You can say const rectangle pointer or rectangle pointer const or const rectangle pointer.
OK, let's think about this case here.
First R3, R3 is a variable,
its data type is a rectangle point const.
This is the data type variable.
So it means that the pointer is constant.
This means once you created the pointer, you cannot change the pointer
here, like put its referencing to one, but you can change the values of it, so the limitation
here is you cannot change the pointer itself,
but on the other side here, R2 itself is of type rectangle pointer, but R2 is const
This means what? this means that...( R2 itself is const)
you cannot change R2 itself, ok.
You cannot make a set width, for example, but you can assign it to another pointer.
OK, which is ok because the pointer itself is inconst. Here
in this case, both the pointer and the data are both, so you cannot change them.
You can always make a pointer const-const that restricted to look out to something,
but the opposite isn't true.
It has to be like I'm having here more, more, more restrictions.
If you have a const member variable, as we say before, you cannot use it inside the class this way.
It has to be inside the initializer list.
OK, the const variables like that are a bit slower, so they are not recommended unless there is
a reason for that.
Finally, there is something that we call the principle of least privilege, one way to think about const
functions is: you are giving less space for someone who is using something.
You know, when you install a program on your mobile, you are allowing only the program to access what
it needs to access.
So you are giving specific permissions.
If you installed a program that has a lot of permissions that it doesn't need, something is wrong.
So when we make a function const, we are limiting the scope that someone can do it.
So this like make the program much more stronger.
So please use const function as much as you could.
That's it.