One interesting feature is using a static with classes.
Remember, when we define a static variable, it is declared once, it is in memory till the program ends.
For example, this hello function has variables
i1 and i2, but i2 is a static. When we call hello
more than once, the variable i1 would be zero every time.
So every time you print it, it would remain zero. On the other side,
static int is a shared variable,
it exists once in memory.
So with every call when we come here, it will not be zero,
It would be the last
value. Initially was zero then 1, then 2.
So the static variable is defined once in memory and still till the program ends.
What about static
as a data member? If you declared a static data member, it is going
to be shared among all of the objects. Once created, it's there till the program ends.
A more interesting thing is that there could be a static variable, although there are no objects
so far. The initialization or definition of this variable is a bit weird.
You declare it here inside that static integer X, then you have to define it outside using the colon
colon operator.
So how you do it? you get it copy-paste, remove the word static,
put the class name, colon-colon before the variable name, then initialize it.
So here we can access it,
and although there are no objects so far, we are calling this function which is changing
it and so on.
Definitely we are accessing only because it just public variable.
So the point of static is being shared among all of the objects and in there till the program ends.
What about a static member function? A static member function is a shared function between all of the
static variables.
As a static variable, it cannot access the data members, Ok.
It can only access static variables.
That's it.
Let's put all of them together.
We would like to track how many employees have been created during this system.
We have here a class employee which has a name and a static integer employees count.
When you think about the count, it isn't about specific employee.
Every time we would like to call the constructor of the employee, we would like to increment this counter.
We also have a function that is of type static to return for us
how many static employee we have here?
We here created two objects now, so Mostafa will increment this variable then mona will increment
this variable.
We also here created a static object belal,
but this is just one static variable,
...
nothing about classes here,
It is just one variable that would be there till the program ends.
If we tried to print the count, it would be 3.
This is how you could have a static variable and a static function shared with all of the objects,
and this is how you declare and this is how you define it.
Let's highlight something special about C++ here.
Let's say that you have Class A and Class B, which have some functionality and public variable F, Class C
has several static variables.
For example, it has a static vector, static array, and object from A and object from B.
Now, as we define the static variable, as we declare them here, we have to define them outside.
So we here declared the variable V as just vector of an integer 20, we are defining array to
just be like global this way, and we are making an object of A and an object of B, A has a default constructor
no problem,
and B we are using the object B 1 and 2.
Now, here is a concern.
Let's go to line 27 here and comment it.
What's going to happen?
Look at line 30, the compiler is going to give an error because line 30 is trying to access B,
and B is declared here, but it isn't defined, so the compiler doesn't see it. Now, comment also
line 30.
The compiler will not give an error, although the variable B isn't also defined.
So the sad point is: In compilation, the variables that aren't initialized would
not be called unless they are used.
Only when you come to linking, you can figure out this kind of errors.
So the moral of that is if you are declaring a static variable, please remember to initialize it
to avoid problems. There are little more concerns here,
you can check out in the future. That's it.