In this video, we will introduce inheritance, one of the fundamental concepts in the OOP, so
when you think about what is coming and what is unique between the two things, like let's say you are
modeling a system for a teacher and then there are many classes such as student and teacher, what
is common ?
What is in common between them?
Give yourself a minute to think of some common data members and functionalities between them and some
unique member and functionalities between them.
What is the observation that we have? Let's try to give the thinking for a minute
If you thought about it, ...
Here is a basic class for a student that has name, email address, national ID and then some starting
year, total GPA, courses and also have some relevant functionality like is a valid email , add course grade and print grades.
thinking about the feature you start define as a human.
He has also a name, email address, and national ID, but has something that's more relevant to him.
Like when did he started working, what is the current salary and so on.
It has the functionality also to read the email but also has a function to add to the list of courses
that is going to teach.
So clearly the issue here is that there are some common functionalities that we are duplicating and common member
data that we are duplicating and definitely there are unique things that we don't care about them.
So this is actually what's the problem of inheritance?
The inheritance is a relationship
We discussed this before.
Student is a person, teacher is a person, Dean is a person.
This means there must be common variables and function between them and some unique variables and function between them.
in a similar way,
Circle is a shape,
Rectangle is a shape,
and triangle is a shape,
So there should be some common functionalities and the common data types, there could be functionalities
with different behaviors like we need to draw from all of them,
But the draw on the rectangle is different from the triangle, the computing area in the rectangle
is different than the computing area in the triangle.
You can also think in a hierarchy like a hierarchy of relationships.
So the person could be student or employee, the employee could be faculty or staff, the graduate could be
masters or doctoral or not degree and so on.
So back to the student and the teacher,
We know that the issue is duplication in code, but the question, how can we handle that?
This need some some some syntax mechanism and here the inheritance comes.
But let's first refresh something, the code reusability is our ability to reuse an existing code instead of
writing it from scratch.
If you have a good already existed, then probably it's written, tested, and bug fixed.
There's no sense in duplicating a lot of work about that this isn't easy - by the way - in practice.
But at least you should use .... C++ or OOP allows 2 reusable approaches that inheritance and composition.
We already saw the composition several times, like the class car has a class engine and victor of 4
wheels and so on.
Another type of reusability is inheritance.
If we can reuse the common features between the manager and the student, then we are saving our time.
So here is how the inheritance happened.
Let's define a class that represents the common logic between the persons.
Like we say, the student is a person, teacher is a person.
So let's define a class person.
What is common here?
It could have a name, it could have email, could have function that is validating the email and so on.
Now, if you did the following syntax, is class student : public person, then you are inheriting
this person.
What does it mean to inherit it?
It means that you see it's a public data members and it is  a public functions.
So now, although I have a GPA, I can also see the variable name and email.
And although I have the print grades and set GPA Functions, I can also see is this valid email format.
So inheritance is this fundamental syntax that allow a class to add for it the variables and functions
the public in another class. definitely
if they are private,
We will see nothing of that.
That's why I'm putting here in public. In a similar way
Let's see the mean of that.
So I'm defining here a student.
And then the student can set GPA, which is a function here, can also validate an email, which is a function
at the parent class and can print grades, which is a function here.
But notice, if you are a person, person isn't necessarily a student so the person can validate the
email.
But he knew nothing about the print grades.
So this is the functionalities that you get from the inheritance in C++.
This is code public inheritance.
There is other two types we will know later. Some terminology:
This class we call it
The parent class or the base class or the super class or general class, it depends on different
language, call a different things like C++ call it
more base, Java call it Super
But the class student we call it child or derived or subclass or a specific class.
Again, derived the name in C++ , subclass is the name in Java and so on.
That's it.