Let's continue about the inheritance.
One critical issue that happened in the last section is that we made the data in the person class public.
The problem that happened is we actually are broking the data hiding this way.
OK, so let's make them private.
If you made them private, you only see whatever in public section it's still OK.
But you don't see all of your variables in this way.
And you might even want to make more functions in private.
But we don't see them now.
So this is a bit tricky.
And this is why language is started to introduce a new access modifier the protected access modifier
The protected access modifier
is a special modifier.
where
If you are a parent and provided something private, no one see it as usual, if you provided something
public, anyone see it, if you provided something as protected, only your child can see it,
But outsiders doesn't.
OK, does this solve the OOP completely?
The answer is no.
It's still breaking the OOP, but it is somewhere meets a middle solution.
So let's see some diagram for that.
Here is some base class and here is some derived class
And this is an object using this class and this an object using this class and this class seeing this
class.
So as usual, the public can be seen by anyone, the private
No one is seeing it.
The protected is a bit tricky.
The protected of this class is invisible by outsiders, but only visible by your child class.
So this is how the access modifiers work.
So back to the student teacher class who started to create the person class and define the variables
here as protected.
So now I can see them, but outsiders cannot. In a similar way,
The teacher have his own private variables and can see the protected class here.
So if we had created a student class, we can set name, set GPA and print the grades.
So which are some of them from here and some of them are from the protected area here.
OK, can I say student "dot" name?
The answer is no.
Why?
Because the "dot" name is protected.
If it is protected, it means it is visible from inside the class, but it isn't visible for an outsider.
In a similar way we can define a teacher, we can call is valid email, which is a function here.
We can set the current salary, but we cannot access any protected data member or member function
here in the protected area from outside. we can only access from the inside of the class.
There is also what we call a multiple inheritance.
Let's say we have a teaching assistant and this teaching assistant is also is an employee in the university,
but also he is still a student like most master students in the universities.
So the way to do that is public student "comma"  public employee.
Now, what does this mean?
It means that the teaching assistant is seeing the protected section here and here and also in addition,
definitely the public section.
So now he is taking more features from here and more also features from here in addition to what he
already has.
So there is what we call a multilevel inheritance.
This is nothing more than just a class graduate is extending the public student class, and the student class
is extending the person class.
And so we are building like a chain of classes. That's it.