Homework set number one, I would like you to write some set of classes, no details no functions
just represent this inheritance hierarchy.
In a similar way, I would also like you to build  a set of classes that build this kind of inheritance hierarchy.
Design review, we have a class for wheels, class engine and class car is inheriting from
both of them.
This code is running well in bus system, everything is OK.
Meanwhile there is something wrong about it when it comes to design.
It's important to notice that your code can be working very well.
Meanwhile, it is a big problem in design and this mean in the near future is going to be problematic.
We have this design for mammals and we have here three members.
One question is, what does this design imply about the mammals?
Another question is, let's say the current system is really correct.
After a year, we had a need to add a new mammal to the system.
So it should inherit from here.
But the problem is it turned out, something was wrong with this design and now adding the new class
doesn't make sense enough.
So think and find.
What is this animal, if we add it to here, is going to fail.
So think about it and then try to Google, in were another to identify what might be a wrong mammal here ?
?
Let's say that we have 4 classes.
Each class has 20 functions.
We would like now to add a new class that has a relationship of "has-a" with the 4 classes.
But it is just to a good extent, not exactly has a relationship. So what is a problem that we will face?
to motivate you
more to answer this question,
Here is a scenario.
Let's say we have a class for a robot that just can drive, clean, and do funny moves.
Just a house robot.
Let's say we have another class for a real animal and this animal can go toilet or make sound and we have
a real cat and real dog.
Now, everything was going very well until a customer asked us to create a class for a robot dog.
A robot dog is like the robot so it can drive, clean, and do funny things.
But remember, it is an unreal dog so it can make sound, but it doesn't go to the toilet.
So back to the problem here.
What is a problem we will face if a "has-a" relationship, it just goes to some extent?
Finally, we would like to implement here all in one machine for printing, scanning and so on.
So let's say we would like to implement this system as it is.
What is a problem here in terms of inheritance and in terms of a better design?
What might be a better idea to make it more semantically valid and solve the problem here that we are
going to identify? That's it.