Let's introduce a new homework here, let me introduce some background about this homework first, something
from real industry.
Let's say we have some email service in our system, so it provides some standard features, like just
something normal, like email server so.
Now they could be extra features, very standard, very bittle.
that we add in systems like logging support. Logging support
You are logging a lot of info to some file about say you called a specific function.
You get specific results and so on.
Caching support.
The caching support mean that the information are in memory so that we can receive them in a bit faster
manner. A thread-Safe support is something that allow us to do parallel competitions and also to access shared
resources.
You didn't study threading so far.
OK, so these are three features in a system that we might add them to any system that we need.
There are also some guidelines in the company, for example, that you don't create a single class.
There is only one single reason to change a class, otherwise split the feature somehow.
For example, you didn't create a single class with logging, caching, thread-safe, which every one of
them would require a lot of code and a reason to change by itself.
So if you did a single class with all of that, you have now 4 reasons to make a change.
There is also another rule in the team or in the company that you shouldn't play with
other codes. play here
I mean to change it.
Consider it closed,
Closed means you don't change it, so you just reuse and extend it.
Remember, C++ has two mechanism for reusability, composition and inheritance.
Now let's go to the task.
When you joined a company that has an email service, they had code for the following.
A basic email service like here just send, receive very basic code to that, another extension from this code
that try and retry
retries means if you send an email,
But the email failed.
You try it again and again.
Let's say we are trying it 4 times.
So this is a feature by itself.
Also another module, the provider thread safe service.
So it is the email service, but with also thread-safe. A final module is a thread-safe email service with
the retries,
So this one is combining these two features together.
So now we have here 4 classes and there are different scenarios in the system that they are using the
different classes.
So some guys just need the very basics email service, some others needed the thread-safe, some other needed the
thread safe and retries idea.
So the 4 classes are in use in the system.
Now here's your task.
We would like to add a new module to the system.
It is a logger module, so we would like to add it to the overall system.
But notice that there were 4 classes before that didn't support the logger.
.
We still need them as they are like our ability to use any of them without the logging feature and also
add logging feature to them.
So, for example, the scenarios might be like someone in the team needs a service that is basic
and it has a retries, but it doesn't support the thread-safe, another team
member would like it to be basic + logging + retries +
+ thread-safe, someone else needs the logging, but he doesn't need the retries or thread-safe.
So we would like to change the class diagram to support the old 4 cases and also this new
cases, draw the UML by yourself.
Remember, you shouldn't modify the current system, just reuse them. After a few months
There is a need to support the caching feature.
Now, again, all the previous cases has some use in the system.
You need to keep them as they are and you also need to provide caching for every case.
So, for example, someone might say, I need the basic service, caching, retrials, but he doesn't
need logging or thread-safe.
So he needs the class to support that. Someone else needs the class that supports all of that, and so on.
So try to build on my solution for the previous homework.
This is Homework 2, not Homework 1, Sorry for that, Try
to identify the issue that happened through what we were explaining.
That's it.