Let's continue in inheritance, so far we have experienced that how different hierarchies can
be implemented in the inheritance, like the basic single one or even being multilevel.
We saw the multiple inheritance case we are inheriting from two cases we saw in the homework,
this hybrid inheritance case, which is calling the diamond problem. Class A now
is shared between class B and class C.
So it's visible from two sides.
We didn't see this one. It was just like a hierarchal case, we also see the high-class A is
a parent for two different classes.
Now, let's move to new issues.
What about the constructors? like we have here a class student who has some empty constructor
and constructor with name and some destructor.
I'm inheriting it.
How should I be initializing the data members of the above class?
So the right way is to use the initializer list and calling the constructor of the above class.
For example, if you have here a student GPA, you first would call the above constructor, let's say was
"Ali" as a name here and then you start to define your initializer list.
So this is the recommended way that
you should do it.
OK, you cannot use the initializer list to access the protected variable here.
For example, you can't here and just say :name hany.
You cannot do that, OK?
You can.
However, you can just initialize it inside the class as here.
Try to think why C++ doesn't allow that.
So again, the right way is just calling the constructor of the above class.
You can still change it here if it's definitely protected value.
Now, in terms of the order of constructor and destructor, ... , as you
see here, we are trying to create the constructor of the student, which first go and create
the constructor of the person and the person
Class isn't created unless we have this kind of job.
So the order is the parent
class is going to be constructed first, then the child class,
And this is very logical.
And in a similar way, the destructor would be the reverse of the order.
So the student would be destructed first, then the person class.
Please read these two numbers and do some simulation here to make sure like they make sense for you.
OK, so what if we have a function here like "GetStr" and a similar one here.
So this is could overriding.
So this two function are ... do you notice here get value and get value.
They are like the same number of data members and the arguments and the return type.
So if you define the class B and you say "B.getValue()", it will go first in the B and see
have "GetValue()"?
Yes.
So it will use this "GetValue()".
So it will not print 10. It will print 20. If you could "GetStr()" then is going to check
does this guy have "GetStr()" ? No. Does have it in public section?
Yes.
OK, so if so it is going to return it.
Remember if it was protected, will not be able to see it. In a similar way,
As you define objects you can also define pointer object and just use them with the arrow operator here.
Inheriting constructors, if the class A have a lot of constructors, by default you don't see them, you
have to write and support your own constructors.
What if I would like to use the above constructors as they are and I have some maybe some default initialization
to the constructors here.
C++ 11 provide us with nice feature, which is you
write using "A::A".
So "A::A"
This is the class name, and this is the constructor name.
This statement means you are inheriting also the constructors.
OK, definitely the public constructors.
So you can now see them here.
Now if you define here B(3) of this class, this guy doesn't have B(3), doesn't have an
integer, but this guy have and we are inheriting it.
So we use it.
What if I would like to prevent others from inheriting my class?
You can write here the word "final", if you put the word "final" here, you prevent others from inheriting your class.
OK, let's refresh the override and overload meaning, in case you forget about it, the overload
function happens within the same class.
It means that we have function with the same name, but different parameters.
Here's thinking about class A::f1
A::f1 here, these are three versions of it (f1, f2, f3 ) sorry, it is these three functions
here in class A.
They are all overloading cases, but overwriting is between classes.
So the two classes have the same function with the same parameters.
But in practice, which one is being called?
This is a question.
So if we define here a "B" one object, we calling f1(), f1(1), f1(1,2), we are calling
these functions.
OK, so override is when the two classes have the same function.
So overload is about a same class override about inheritance.
So far, we were learning what we call public inheritance, public inheritance actually is the most
common case, like 99 percent of the cases you're using public inheritance, but in a way there is
something could protected.
Inheritance and private inheritance.
What is a difference? In public inheritance
What is public on the parent class?
would be public on your side, what is protected in the parent class. .......
Let's say in a different way.
You have here something public it will remain public. You have here something protected
It will remain protected. In protected inheritance looking at X is public and Y is protected.
Both of them would be protected.
OK, so I'm inheriting your public and protected, but they will be protected on my side.
OK, what does it mean?
That they would be protected on my side?
It means if someone is using C, he will not be able to access them.
So X and Y now would be also externally look like a private values.
What about the private D
variable? the private
It means that the both X and Y will be private also.
So again, public A, this guy has X public, Y public,
Z public, try to think the visibility from inside the class?
If someone is inheriting from me and if someone is in the outside? so the public and protected would
remain in public inheritance, public and protected.
So the external guys are seeing the public and the guys who are inheriting for me, see my protected.
If I'm doing protected inheritance, the public and protected will both be protected.
This mean external guys doesn't see them.
But if you are inheriting from me, you see the X and Y, if you are doing private inheritance, X and
Y would be private on my visibility.
So even if you are inheriting from me, you don't see them.
This is mainly the difference between the three cases. Finally in UML we know the plus for private,
minus for public, the protected has the hash here.
So we use the hash variable here and the hash variable for protected.
Final note here is a nice note about eclipse.
If you have a class and did "ctrl + space", you would see different variables.
There are shapes besides these variables.
The rectangle is for private and the diamond for protected and the square for public, you can also
see them here in the outline.
So it's like nice when you click that, you can know what's public.
What's protected. That's it.