It is useful to refresh the inheritance when it comes with the exception, exception is one of the very
nice locations when inheritance comes in practice.
So the STL has an exception hierarchy.
Remember, the exceptions is a way to handle errors.
If there is something wrong in the classes, then we can throw an exception that just point out there
is something wrong in the system.
There are typically two ways for people to handle problems and code,
One way is to throw exceptions.
Another way is to return an error code.
they are both in industry.
It's important to know about the differences between them.
So I would like you to read carefully this hierarchy.
It is a hierarchy of three levels, in the top level:
We have an exception.
And the second level: we have some
bad_alloc this is if you are allocating a lot of memory, logic error, runtime error, and bad_casting if
you are casting something wrong.
So the logic errors like out of range error, for example, like you are good out of range from an array,
for example, overflow error if for example
Some numbers is exceeding some of the limits and so on.
So stop the video and familiarize yourself with the hierarchy elements.
Now let's refresh the following cases.
Here is a function that is dividing over X if X is zero.
This would be like division by zero.
The program is going to crash.
Whatever you are trying to do, even exception, nothing will stop it from crashing. Array X
this is a vector
And we are accessing it using the at position.
It has only 5 elements if you try to access with more, it will throw an out of range error, which
is actually a logical error.
Mysqrt function.
I'm saying here, if the number is less than zero, then just throw a domain error.
Otherwise compute the sqrt function.
My exponential function is taking X and computing it.
The C++ will return a HUGE_VAL.
this keyword, if the exponential value was too large.
So if this happened, I would throw out_of_range error saying that we cannot hold this value in double
for example.
Now, let's here create a test function.
It takes a double X, then the logic is line mysqrt(X), then myexp(X),then array_access(X).
So here is how C++ handle exceptions.
It will only execute lines 35, 36, 37.
If everything is OK, it just go outside them.
If there is a problem, it jumps to the first catch and say is the exception of the type of the domain
error.
If yes it enter here and then just
go to completely outside, if no it move to the second one.
Think of it like the if-else, it double-checks the if condition this then this condition, then this condition.
And if you caught it anywhere, you can print the e.what() to get the message.
Now the core message in this video is as following.
Let's put the hierarchy of classes here always like this is a child class, then parent
class.
What happens if you put here parent class after it
It's child class.
The parent class will definitely would be accessible,but the child
class will never be accessible, So the right order in try-catch should be some a child class,
then parent class.
If you put a parent class of someone, then one of the children, the child will never be called.
So this is the only thing that you have to be careful about.
And as we said, the division by zero will never be caught.
It's our responsibility to verify such arithmetic level.
The three dots here is catching whatever thing.
OK, so this is a very special syntax.
If no specific error here, it just would be caught from here.
OK, be careful from that because it might like swallow errors in your system.
You might catch it.
Then you look something, then you through it again.
In practice, what happened is we typically build our own exception hierarchy.
We build our own exception hierarchy.
So we start to define classes of specific reasons.
If you are building banking application, you might have some error, like, say, not paid exception,
things like that.
So here is a test, we testing test(10), test(-4), a big number, the test(10) will fail in the array access,
so it is giving this logical array vector access issue.
The -4 would fail in the square root.
So it's a domain error.
So you shouldn't. The domain means like expected for a square root number to be from zero to something positive if you enter minus,
then this is a wrong domain.
If you picked this very big value, this is a logical error or like a specifically out of range
for the exponential, test for zero will crash the whole program.
That's it.