In this video, I would like to share with you some notes from a practical perspective about inheritance
in the software engineering industry.
Sadly, many courses when the excellent inheritance they give the students and the impression that inheritance
is very deeply used in the industry.
But this isn't the case.
Going back to the past, inheritance was a major technique for reusability and extension's.
But after some time, a lot of projects would exploded because of the use of the inheritance, the unwise
use of inheritance.
So now there is a lot of careful since before using it in industry.
I suppose in from the homeworks you get a very strong message why inheritance could be problematic.
So an industry that is now a very common say, they tell you the prefer composition over inheritance.
So the idea is whenever you can do something with composition in a fair way, just go with composition
and avoid inheritance hierarchy.
So in industry, we actually avoid the inheritance as much as we could.
OK, what I would like to use inheritance.
It is still in use, but you have to provide strong justifications.
For example, it has to be really has a relationship as strong as a relationship.
The Berlanti class should be super close for all classes.
Remember the mammal case.
You should make sure that even in future the subclauses would still make sense for the superclass.
You should never, ever try to use inheritance only because you are trying to make a good use.
This would just corrupt the case.
Multiple inheritance is very problematic, so we avoid it as much, much as possible.
Like we see the diamond.
The problem it makes makes troubles.
So we prefer inheritance tree structure, like just the tree.
When you are trying to extend the class, you have to think twice if this class was designed for being
extended or not.
Like, for example, the Victor class isn't designed for extension.
Some language even doesn't support inheritance at all, like Java and shirt.
But they have something else named interfaces.
So the moral of that is inheritance is something that can be very helpful.
But also sometimes, or even in many cases, it can be very problematic in the polymorphism.
Listen, we would know exactly how inheritance can be used to allow behavior in a very strong way and
allow very strong compositional types, not this type of very deep multiple inheritance.
And then when chips, that makes a lot of troubles.
That's it.