The third homework set in the inheritance.
Remember, we said that C++ doesn't allow you to initialize inherited member variables in the initial
results?
Why you think so?
Think in some cases that the language designers considered for that in C++.
Also, friendship isn't inherited.
Why do you think so?
Comparing the set of objects of a class with its drive to classes?
Which one is bigger?
Like how many?
One of them is bigger.
So think, for example, in a working class and Honda, their child, the class which you base, which
class would have more instances created.
We know that we do not access private variables in.
But are they still inherited?
Finally, from a different perspective, think about providing protected variables or providing getters
and setters.
Which one would be a better approach?
So think like a subclass corruptibility class using the protected data.
Also the coupling.
If we allow the protected data, then they are visible.
To what degree?
There are more cabling and dependencies between the child and the the class.
OK, the package delivery service is as following.
You would like to design a set of classes.
You don't have to write a mean function for a package delivery service as follows.
We have something we call a standard package which has sender address, receiver address, and it has
written KG's and some price per kilogram.
So the total cost, the total cost is eight times the price per kilogram.
The address is just name city and the name, name and city.
Yeah, the string and the address of the street and some number, whatever.
Something similar to the package is a standard package with an added fixed fee for the total cost.
A heavy package is a standard package for heavy weights attached attached with extra weight.
So for example, if the weight is greater than 100 kilograms, then there is an extra piece of weight
minus 100 times that, the extra weight in kilograms.
OK, so what we have now here, this extra weight and we use it to add extra fees for the average.
There are also customers who create several shipments.
Each shipment has a set of packages of different types.
The total shipment price is the sum of the price of every package.
Each shipment has some information of card used for the payment.
This could be a debit card or credit card and the user might have many of them.
So try to design a set of glasses that express this kind of relationships.
Read this program and tell us what is the output of it.
And here, read this good and figure out some problems and why this problem happened, how could Syntex
using a Syntex to solve the problem?
I would like you to read this program very carefully investigated.
There's something interesting here in the mean.
Figure it out.
Also, what is expected out of this program, thinking about the data members X and Y and Z, think
about the visibility of each object.
Here we have more than object.
So think about the visibility of the member.
What's visible and what isn't in a similar way, the function here.
What which variable are visible or not?
That's it.