Homework set number four for the inheritance, the string, a class, as you know, is very powerful.
It has many constructors, operators and more functionalities.
We would like to introduce a new class that has all features of string across, but it has one new extra
functionality.
We will call it decorate.
If it take a string this year, it just give us this kind of concatenation to this thing so it is easy
for it.
You define a string, you say is to decorate.
If you try to print it, it is like that and you still can compare it and make use of all the previous
state functionalities.
So how to do that?
An image editor, your team leader, provided you with this diagram to to implement.
I would like you to read it very well and describe it.
Think about implementing it in any thoughts about implementation will later will implement this system
in the Bollywood film.
The third question and fourth one are less about inheritance, more implicit, but in a way.
So the homework three is a system design system design is is a key word that very close to the system
architecture.
And it haven't always on the very big picture of the system, when you have a big system of many components,
we need some people to think about the very big picture with the interfaces, integration between them,
reliability, security, a lot of things.
So and in companies like Google and Facebook, they typically have system design reviews for software
engineers, specialists in years.
Well, anyway, so let's say we are modeling the Medal of Honor game and there are millions of online
players.
We have some message to communicate to the players and now we have to design choices here.
Choice number one is each application vertically, like each mobile app, like your your personal mobile,
periodically contacts with the server to see if there are new notifications or not.
The game then the game has some provide provided some online API.
Anybody is a way to communicate with with some external party.
Here is a Medal of Honor game.
So each mobile just send and receive request and response from the notification that the other way is
looking from the other perspective.
So this is how the first case mobile is conducting the game.
The other way is the reverse.
Now the the the evry application register with the system and whenever the server has a new message,
it go and iterate over the different mobile or different devices and send the message in for every one
of them.
So the question for you is, should we go that the mobiles are bringing the game?
If they have messages that say every two minutes or the game iterate or all the mobile applications
and send them the updates, which one is better when discussing the two options and their implementation
implementations?
And you start of in every country, there are different banks where people just put their money and
there is also services where they want to be something using their money, like they say you would like
to pay your electricity bill, your mobile bill and so on.
So now with every new service today, let's say there is a new mobile network.
Each bank wants to support paying the best to this new service so that the customers be happy that the
they can use their own bank account to pay their bills for even a new mobile network service.
Thinking about implementing that, we have to have a team that implements something on the side of the
bank.
And we have also to go to the service site, which is now the new mobile network, and implement something
there.
So now we have new software at the bank site and new software at the service site.
We can communicate together as an entrepreneur.
Think about the current situation.
What what is wrong with it?
Like, for example, how many software programs are built for any banks and services?
Let's say you would like to introduce a startup proposal that offer an elegant solution to this problem
that you will figure out here how to solve it.
And these are some reading links about validating your business model and to a degree of sphere of success,
this is just for like for your personal benefit.
That's it.