In this section, we start to move to one of the very interesting and very important algorithm's topics.
This topic is the graph theory and graph theory is one of the topics that you can actually use in many
different ways, like you must understand the basics of graph theory.
We use some of it in many different fields, and there are some interaction to some extent in the industry
too.
So let's, first of all, motive that we can't see.
There are too many relationships everywhere.
Let's give a lot of examples.
But let me first say in a in a nutshell, what is a graph theory?
The graph theory is all about the following We can see that there are many things that involve some,
be it wise, relationships between objects.
So what is an object?
Anything can be an object.
I don't hear and I don't hear, mean, an object oriented programming.
I mean, the English keyword, for example, let's say we have a city and this city has six internet
airports.
And there are flights between them.
Let's, for example, no the airports from one to six.
Now this here is there is there is a diagram that we can draw by hand and we can easily understand.
So let's say this is a New York airport.
This is maybe New York Seattle airport, whatever.
Some six, some six airports here.
Now, as you see, there's some flight from Airport one to Edgewood five.
There is some flight also from airport one to airport two and so on.
So the airport here is what we call an object.
The Bitwise relationship is the connection between them.
So this is, in theory, a graph theory.
Let's go in and actual examples and go back to that.
So here is Google Maps and Google Maps.
You would like to go from a place to another.
There are a lot of data here, a lot of details, and there are even constraints like what time to do
the trip, what did what, what, what kind of transportation?
A lot of things you see.
We have locations.
We have some birth is between them, the social media.
When you think about the social media, there are a lot of people on social media.
The person here is the object himself.
And if you are a friend with someone, then this is a relationship.
There could be also some bridges that you like, some videos that you watch.
And all of such relationships and the media.
So you see objects.
Connections.
Even sometimes things could be very weird from your perspective, like thinking about circuit connections
here.
There are here boons and connections between them, grammar in English.
Even such a statement can be split into such a tree where we are building the expression values level
by level.
So it seems like, again, points connections between them.
And biology, the molecular, you can see also, it's eventually bunch of boys and connections between
them computer networks, it is very clear we have a network in our university.
There are a lot of machines.
They are connected together.
There is some direct connections.
I can reach this machine by going through maybe two or two other machines, but we are connected.
So the object here is the computer network and that links the the wire links are the connections, the
search engines.
When you access a webpage, this would be you could have links to other webpages.
That bridge rank is a very important algorithm used by search engines like Google.
So bridges here are connected with each other.
Let's move to a computer vision field in the computer vision field.
There is a problem with Google, but the booze estimation estimation.
So this is a person, and we would like to identify specific say it in joints that represented a person
like the head, the neck, the shoulders left and right, head left and right, and so on.
So when you think about this joints and the relationships, they actually represent objects, which
is here adjoint and the edges between them, the connections between them.
An object to tracking, which is also part of the computer vision field.
We have a video and there are a bunch of people in the video, so the same person, we see him in a
frame.
Then after a few seconds, we see him in another frame.
So we'd like to know, is this a bit implicit implicit relationship?
This person would be connected with the same person.
After a few frames, robotics also this joins can be represented as points and as connections.
See, transition diagrams, transition, Graham, describe the behavior of a system like, for example,
we have a process and this process with an event can move to another process and so on.
And this is a diagram that represent the people like you start as a board, as a child at this age,
you move to adult age, you move to that and so on.
So we can represented a different state so that we as a humans here, as an object, as a states.
And then we connected them based on some connection.
It's totally OK if you don't get most of these examples, that's totally OK.
I just wanted to highlight how graphs are everywhere.
And if you thought about what is common between all of these things, the government is we have objects
and we have relationships and social media or Facebook people would be the objects or even images in
internet work.
The computer would be the objects in a body person.
The joints would be the objects.
And there are relationships between beer of objects here.
So as you see, the relationships and graphs are everywhere.
If you try to draw your family like you, your beer and his beer and your grandparents, your child
and so on.
This represent such kind of objects and relationships.
Now, if I asked you that this problem or many other problems, you start to think, OK, we have a
network of six computers, 10 links, and it would like to know, for example, if this machine can
see this machine or not lakes through some some intermediate machines.
In practice, it isn't.
It isn't practical to keep working on every problem by itself.
We do what we call abstraction.
We think the problem itself convert converted to a bunch of objects and relationships.
We call this shape a graph.
We call all of these circles nodes or vertices.
We call the connections between them edges.
A graph is set of nodes and set of edges.
So all of the problems I have been explaining can be eventually abstracted to a graph.
The good news is I can develop the specific algorithm on graph theory and just the standard that is
ready in my library and whatever domain I converted to graph and use it.
So this is a concrete, real life example.
This is an abstract concept.
Graphic representation, as I said, all about objects and their relationships.
So when we abstract a domain, we we would try to count the number of objects.
These are my notes like here six airports are six nodes and then the relationships are between.
The objects are directly edges here.
Now I can work and do many algorithms on the graph.
For example, one might ask in how many ways I can go from node one to three.
Assuming Node one, for example, is a computer is another computer.
I can go in many ways.
I can go from computer one to computer to to computer three or one two five four three or one five four
three or one five two three.
This is pretty good.
Like, let's say the computer five got shut down for a reason or another.
We still can go to three through another computer.
But in practice, we implemented this as a a separate utility.
So this is one one question.
Another question might be what is the shortest Abarth?
From Node one to three, the shortest Abarth has many definition.
It should be shortest Abarth.
A one of them here could be in the number of edges to reach it and would, for example, the best one
five four three takes the three edges.
The best one five two three takes three edges.
The best one two three takes only two edges.
So this way I introduce for you two to three problems in graph theory.
How many baths is between two nodes?
What is the shortest bath between and then another?
And as I mentioned, eventually we abstracted the domain to the graph and do our algorithms on the graph
itself.
During the course, we would mainly focus on the graph path itself, but in real life, we have a domain
that we convert first to a graph like in Google Maps example.
That's all.