And the third problem I would like to try and other kind of domains that the graph domains or specifically
the grid domain.
And it's more or less implementation of skills.
And I think it's if you understood what is the what is the requirement?
It is just to be like a normal normal code.
So we are using here the adjacency list implementations, so this is could be best could be based the
code from our code.
Now let's see how to generate the graph.
First of all, as you know, if we have a matrix that is rows and columns, then we have rules, times,
columns, nodes.
So this is the first thing.
Here we are creating Rossum's columns, nodes.
The second thing we are generating the edges.
So we are, let's say, here the three times the four matrix.
Oh, yes, three times for amitriptyline by rule and also call them the white collar.
Now if I have this cell here, we can compute its index in a very easy way, which is row times columns
of let's see, we learned this kind of flirting Bittrex back in programming like how can you convert
index of Iron G in two index of just a flattened index, which either, by the way, is very but if
you are, if you are at some room here, then it means that you've finished all of this column like,
let's say you are to column the two and row two.
This means you already finished two rows and every row has three columns.
That's why you multiply through times of columns.
And now we have a column that isn't further so far.
So it's +I.
So if I told you row two and column two, so two rows are done, this is the route and the columns and
column two are still here.
So this is a missing column.
So this are the completed columns and this is the incomplete column.
This is already in a very simple way.
Now in the the problem, we know the neighbors are the top right bottom left.
So I start here to say, Hey, you know what?
My new rule is robust one my new column is as it is another one row minus one.
No changes here.
Another one.
The row is fixed plus one another one.
The rule is fix it.
And currently this one, this note of resentment for neighbors.
So now the original RNC is that is a is a from nood and their new new or new C is a new new this that
would represent them my direct edge.
So we go here after we after we completed them and say, add directed edge from this, from and from
this to.
So the moral of that is you, first of all, learn how to convert every cell IJI to a corresponding
index.
And the second thing you generate the four directions you converted to index, then you add an edge
for it.
The last thing here to be careful about the boundaries, the boundaries nodes will not have four indices.
So one of them will have you like an inverted index here.
So you need to verify the valid index or not.
So have you.
A very simple utility that takes the current to new row new column and the grid rows and columns.
If the new row is less than zero or greater than the rules or the new columns is greater than zero or
or the new Bekir.
You have this position, you need to make sure it doesn't go outside here or here or go outside here
or go outside here, so we have four directions for statements.
We go right this one in a single line of code, but just for for clarity.
This is merely how to reduce the problem of the image to the graph in the deepest section will learn
how to write this code in a more elegant way, and we'll learn more stuff about that.