And the next problem would like to recursively, Brent.
Brent assembly chin.
That's it.
So here is the right is British symbol.
After you reading the read the graph and the query.
So this is mainly the British chin function.
I'm just doing this exercise because later we will start to do more recursive, more recursive work
on the graphs.
So you have here.
Let's say we have not five go to zero, which you go to, for which you go to one, let's say what's
missing here.
Zero, one, two and three are missing.
Let's say this is three and we have two here.
And I'm asking you to bring to the chin from the from now we know we have one of two cases, every every
note.
This note have only a single with a single neighbor, and this one in the last note in the chain doesn't
have any neighbors.
So first of all, I ask here, does the just this has more neighbors or Iraq, which is usually one
or zero.
So if it has a neighbor, I get the neighbor which is at from you.
And then the curtain.
So this is a symbol of change.
So three has here, I think, a neighbor of value zero.
So I say grief of three and zero two zero recurso and three and zero and then zero check do have a neighbor
easier when a neighbor?
OK.
Graph of zero and one is four.
So Wilkerson four, then recurs on one.
Then we stop because no more alos, as you see overall, is pretty, uh, pretty simple and pretty straightforward.
The second home homework here is about printing every birth of two steps.
Also, this isn't hard.
Um, the idea is following we can make this in a very simple way.
We have we have nodes.
Right?
So I can.
This is an addition to this, so I can iterate on my nodes.
So let's say we have here node number three.
So I know for node number three now I get graph of OK.
So let's say graph of AI has um.
Not seven, not two, not five.
Now, this is my adjusting to this.
So so far, I have a single aged like three to seven, for example.
Now we go and see a graph of severe, let's say here down here, a group of seven has an edge to route
zero and had edgy to not fall.
So now we are here seven zero.
And then sevenfold.
So the moral of that is we simply need to reduce the three groups are enough to bring every edges,
the first to get this list, to hear the second look at this list here.
So this is now give me the fittest and the fittest edge.
Then using this one, we get.
It's also that it is two ages.
So this all three loops to bring to all of the edges of list of leads, say two, which is also three
new.
So when they say one five seven.
So this is merely has a five and seven.
This is merely like three values.
So I needed like this kind of three loops to bring three values which represent two edges.
I hope the idea is OK overall.