Homework number three, this homework is hard, and remember, I tried to challenge you during this
course, I can trivially give you like a bunch of easy problems.
You will finish the course you solve with all of them.
You are very happy with your progress and then you'll have to fight the story in the.
And that's it.
During the course, I will challenge you a lot and this is a good thing.
And remember, there will be a lot of moments of frustrations.
Also, remember that I asked you, there are two educational strategies here you can solve the first
the easy problems during the course in the medium, then the heart may be the first medium and later
the heart.
If you would like to try the hard, the earlier the course, that's totally OK.
Just understand that your skills are growing up so it will take time.
These two problems are the problems.
The logic behind them is an easy problem.
So take it easy.
Give a trial delay later, but then the to do list or check out the solution.
All of that.
Just be patient.
So in the first problem, we would like to find the thing in the quiz.
I told you something about that universal thing.
It should be fine.
They reverse the thing.
So they universities think is a vertex where it's in degree is in the minus one, and it's our degree
is zero.
In other words, every other node goes directly to this node and this node doesn't go anywhere.
So here node number three, it's our degrees zero.
It's in degree is all of them goes to it.
So it's in the minus one.
This is called a universal thing.
So the first thing I would like to use to prove that if there is a universal thing, there will be at
most one in the graph.
I already wrote the proof in the question.
So it's simple if you didn't read it or you would like to think about it, that's OK.
Now here is the challenge that I would like you to write an algorithm which would be open to find the
the thing the universe.
I think what's more, challenging this problem is you need try to to prove the correctness.
This is one of the problems.
If you try to be very informal, this is there is a good chance that you will miss some decent some
cases.
So this isn't an easy problem.
Maybe the lucky part is if you develop the good, the cases, you will find the failure points of your
algorithm.
This is a good thing about this problem.
So some problems, if you develop enough these two cases, you can figure out the mistakes in your idea.
Anyway, I would like you to try to develop an idea that is in and then prove the correctness believes
assumed that the graph that you are given to the here is an adjacent see matrix return, a zero based
index for the node, which is the the the thing over minus one if there is no such a thing.
I would like you to develop several cases.
OK.
For the program, this program will not read a graph, it will read multiple graphs, so you will read
first for artistic two cases, this is your first integer three mean three stick.
It is, and therefore it is the case.
You will have started to read the number of moods and edges and then read the edges.
So this is the guess.
What is the key statistic?
Three forever?
It is the case you would bring to their sink.
So for the first to graph, the thing is three for the second, the graph of the zinc is five.
For this graph, there is no theme I am providing you with two files.
One of them find the single edition, but the text for fun sync up with the text.
But it could be missed the content to test your program, but do that after developing your own test.
The case is an after verifying your code.
There is no problem on that.
On the internet.
I'm not aware of any of them.
So just see, I'm just trying to help.
I will not always provide them file, but this is a bit tricky problem.
So I wanted to give more help and advice when you are trying to solve hard problems.
Don't start thinking about finding the optimal solution.
This is a big mistake.
The first step in solving the problem is too far to think about the brute force.
Can we can we develop a brute force for this problem or not, for many problems?
There is an initial brute force idea the good thing about brute force.
It is easy to get an idea so your mind will start to flow in the problem.
And instead it is.
The second point is try to improve the brute force that is maybe like 70 percent the chance you can
improve your brute force, sometimes you know you cannot, you have to think in a different way.
So try to start writing a brute force version for this problem.
One good thing is you can define function.
Let's say, if a slow and this is a slow, stupid function that definitely will find the thing and then
develop your first version.
And now you would like to check the correctness of your first the every time you run your code or first.
Also, you write on slow and compared to Albert, for example, if you're a slow version, say the answer
is three.
But your first version, say this, it is minus one.
Then my good and fast is wrong.
So the good news you can use the brute force version to verify the correctness of your approach.
Yeah, that's hot here.
Now let's move to another problem, which also involves adjacency matrix, not A-list.
I would like you to assume we have a binary matrix binary adjacency matrix of directed, which is,
for example, matrix of AMG will have value one if there is at least age from AMG.
Now, let's say we computed the square of the matrix like M atoms m here.
The purpose of this assignment.
I would like to investigate what is this c in terms of the original graph.
So now we have the original matrix here M and then we square it and got a new Matrix C and we have some
graph.
So we know that M is adjacency matrix of this one.
But what is see here, what does it represent?
If you are done with this one and would like to go bigger than that, what does it mean to power the
matrix up to the power key?
You don't have to write a good year to compute the matrix about just go to any online calculator and
use it to compute.
The Matrix for this assignment isn't about coding, it's about investigating.
OK, so how to do analysis for such a problem and such a problem, you need to do two things together.
The first thing is to try to think in a logical way.
Like what, what is the matrix about?
What does it do, things something like that and try to find observation through that?
The second thing is to try to find patterns like you look to the concrete examples and try to find them.
Some people would just keep thinking in a logical way.
Some people would just keep thinking for the better.
I believe the two approaches together.
Do some thinking, do some concrete investigations?
Now, another tip when you are investigating a problem, never, ever start with the refugee example,
like you start, ask yourself, what does it mean to Baremetrics with the one?
This is a military vet.
What about two nodes?
What about three nodes?
So we know that the symbol is the graph.
A reasonable graph would be achieved.
So what about the chin?
What about three?
OK, so the point is start start smooth.
Don't just go very large, it would be very hard.
So for example, this is a fight with the opposite that she achieved.
So this is their adjacency matrix.
Now we bought it, which is a matrix times itself.
And this is the result.
So this is this is see what does a C represent in terms of that?
Yeah, that's all.