Let's all do the find universal.
I think a problem is are attached should be BGF that explain already the the solution in a formal way,
which I would like you to read it, but let me give a try to simplify things here as much as you can.
So first of all, it is good to understand the following.
Uh, let me yeah, I can confirm this, this idea here in the problem, when it comes to her, the problems,
the the usage of formal brews like administrate, its importance like you start to think from the very
different angles to make sure that the proof is really solid enough in easy problems.
It could be matter of one or two minutes to have like a proof, a sketch or an informal proof for the
problem.
But sometimes with hard things, this doesn't work well enough.
Anyway, let's go back to the problem.
One of the questions I ask it is Can we have a lake more than a universal thing?
Can we have two three university?
So this is easy to be proved by contradiction.
The idea is is following Let's claim that Vertex's zero is a inverse sink.
So here is the easiest way to draw an inverse.
I think a graph.
Let's let's say we have one to three this way.
Three.
But so let's say we have four or five moods in a graph and zero is a thing.
Now let's pretend that there is another note that is sync, but remember what is sync sync?
It doesn't go to any note and all of the other news, go to it.
Now, let's pretend that there is another note that is can be sync.
So let's say no, no, no one.
But for no no one to be sync, it cannot go to any other node.
But we already said that zero is sync.
So the universe and sync.
So one must go to it.
But now one one, I want to be another sync, but they go to another node already, which is invalid
and contradiction and also zero is a sync.
This means it doesn't go to anyone else.
So if it doesn't go to anyone else, this means no one else of the other notes can be a sync.
So by contradiction, we cannot have another synchronous.
So, yeah, that's the first part in the problem.
Now let's go to the problem and let's keep our life easy.
So we start with writing a very simple function that we call it is universal.
Think this universal thing is a brute force of function?
It take a good and verify, if not lie is a thing or not, which just applying the the logic, how the
function is saying it doesn't go to any other route, any other route comes to it.
So in a brute force, we can rat dysfunction and so to see the code here.
Is Universal think taking would I iterate on all of the graph graph nodes and if Graph I and G exist,
this means not I go to New G, which is invalid, then I is in sync return false.
The second thing is we found that no g doesn't go to Node I.
So also this invalid because we need all of them to go to me.
Just be careful.
You need to be like, Don't don't check against yourself.
So that's all, if we did these two things, we've verified that and would is think now this is a brute
force, nothing hard about that.
The second way is to write a slow version from the sink function.
How can we find the sink function in a brute force way?
Iterate on every note in the graph.
If it is sink or not.
If you found any of them, Sink returned to the other one returned minus work.
And remember, we cannot have more than a sink in the graph.
No, the challenge is how can we find that in all the only?
OK, so let's go back and think about it here.
We need to analyze more.
First of all, let's start with something assuming we have a graph of any notes and let's say we have
to do only I and G among the Indians.
Now we know that in terms of graph at IAG, we have four cases like either graph of IAG is true.
Let's use this or the graph of Asia is false and graph of China is false, which means none of them
go to each other or graph IAG is false.
But graph of IE is true.
And so on.
So we have four cases here.
So first one, I engine one of them go to each other.
Case two IAG.
Both of them go to each other.
Case three, I go to G.
Case for.
G, go to OK, now, what do you think about the first case?
I, Angie, can this be think?
No.
Because they are isolated.
Can this case be sink?
No, they go to each other.
Here I, Angie.
So who could be, I think, who may be?
I think Jim may be asking because it doesn't go to me and it I go to me.
And here I could be a cynic.
Because if he comes to I, so only these two cases, there is no sink.
I cannot be saying because you cannot be saying these two cases, Jim, maybe think I may be sick,
callous.
Maybe why?
Maybe because there are still others in the mine asteroids that we need to check them.
Now the major key here is to avoid duplicate processing, to be good and to develop an efficient algorithm.
Remember, when we were doing the sorting board we we met more than a problem.
We're making the algorithm more efficient is all about detecting what is doubly good, what is unnecessary
to do.
So let's simulate here.
Let's let's try to work.
Let's say that we started with Newton, but I am claiming that maybe it is a sink.
And then let's say we start to compare.
Note II equals zero, and let's say we have the other nodes Z like a one two, three four, for example,
and five.
So let's say we can build the I was equal one.
And so far, I may be a sink, which means node number one, go to zero.
And then we move to two and found also to go to zero.
So far, so good.
What does it mean if also three goes to zero six zero four two zero?
Five go to zero.
Now there is a very fundamental observation here.
If zero is so far, maybe a sink one to five cannot be a sink because they already come to me.
So if at any point of time zero failed to be a sink, you shouldn't try to check one two three four
five.
None of them can be a sink because they already go to zero.
And this is a great observation that would save your time.
So now let's say that when we comes to rule number six, we observed that node number six doesn't go
to zero.
And also zero doesn't go to six.
Now, what does this mean?
This means if, if if six, it doesn't go to zero zero, cannot anymore be a thing because one of the
nodes doesn't got it now for six itself.
If if if zero doesn't go to six, then even six itself, it cannot be sink if zero goes to six.
There may be six.
Now is a sink.
Did you get the idea?
So, so let's pretend does that zero actually go to node number six?
And yeah, and by the way, if the route already has a is a just since the format of the game, OK,
I think this was adjacency matrix in input, right?
Yeah, this was additions of ethics.
So we cannot know in 01 if zero has adjacency or not.
Let's pretend that six, it doesn't go to sick to zero.
So this means zero cannot be sync anymore.
If zero goes to six six two may be a sync.
So let's pretend for now that six is a good note.
Now let's try it with number seven.
We'll find that seven.
Go to six.
Let's define new number eight eight good two six.
This means that seven cannot be, I think, a good thing.
Now let's say we have node number nine and we found that node number nine doesn't go to six.
This means six.
It cannot be sync anymore.
Now, let's a check of six to go tonight.
Six also doesn't go tonight.
This means that even nine is interesting.
So try the next idea, which is still and let's try the next one.
Let's say we have not No.
10 and now we had Newt number 11 and 11 go to 10.
So 10 may be a sink and then Newt 12 and 10 go to 12.
It is the point, and here is the critical mass of stronger proofs.
Now we know that zero one two three up to nine were enticing.
We also showed that 11 is in sync.
And also, you are sure that 12 isn't the sync.
And we know that Dean was good, was clever and good was 10 12.
Question for you.
Stop the video and think for five to 10 minutes.
Is really it in a sink or not?
The answer is we don't know why.
We don't know the status of dead with all of these previous problems may maybe not number two doesn't
go to two to 10 for 10 to be think we need every other note to go to 10 all what we are assured from
it.
So far that 11 go to 10 and 12 will go to 10.
We do not know about the previous problems.
So even the program ended now didn't.
Maybe a sink.
Not sure, I think the only thing that we are sure from it, every other note, except it then isn't
the sink.
So the only question that is remaining is sink A. C is a sink or not.
So to solve this problem in a trivial way, you just all what you need is to call it sink A..
One more time.
So the moral of that is you make all of this round and you will have one of two cases.
You end up there is no sink at all.
Well, you end up with a note that may be a sink which can be checked in movie.
If you observe it.
This processing it was, then your processing was started from zero move to one two three four five.
And then we discovered that six doesn't go to zero.
So six years or more and we started from six to directly.
Then we moved six, seven eight.
We have a linear cycle iterating with the.
The real thread and the importance of sketching the proof in a proper way.
So one might end the and think that 10 is a sink.
But it isn't because we don't know if ten is good with the previous nodes or not.
And if you try to to process this linear way, there is no way to be able to check in with the history.
Otherwise, you have to iterate linearly to do the check.
As you see, I hope, I hope the explanation is clear for you.
The algorithm is trying to find a node that may be a sink, and after the end of the processing, it
double check one more time.
Let me show you the could here that I wrote initially for this task.
So we start with I equals U g equals zero.
And now, as long as I resent you, says I, first of all, have here a case where I equally colleague,
so I'm doing some checks, so I would like always to jump with Angie to the property.
Let's leave that for now here.
So now we have four cases, as I mentioned zero zero zero one one zero one one and we would like to
check in every one of them.
So in the first one so far would like to check if I like develop I as a thing or not, if there is no
edge from IAG.
This is very good.
Now, if there is a zinc link from G2, I then we can get him into the G.
So we started with not zero and which would one go to zero?
Yes, zipless plus want to go to zero?
Yes.
Gymnast plus three go to zero.
Gymnast Plus.
Now, let's say we we found no food.
Now I, which is zero, doesn't go to for good, but also doesn't go to food, which means we are in
the zero zero case.
None of them is a sink.
So resemble was I and both of them to the next index, which is five to tried as I think maybe a sink.
Let's continue.
Assume we check the five with the six and found that six to go to five.
So so far, five is good when it comes to seven.
We found that five go to seven.
This means I cannot be a sink.
No, there are two cases for seven.
No.
First of all, does Jill go to I mean, the six one one.
If this is the case, both of them cannot be a thing.
So we start from jobless one legend after seven, which is eight.
OK.
What if she doesn't go to G?
But she doesn't then see if it could be a thing?
So we just put the I equals g, which mean that started from seven anything.
Once you're done with pursuing these four cases, you have one of two cases.
The first case is I ended because of such increments without finding anything.
The second case you entered was only a single variable, which may be a sink.
I hope the algorithm is clear for you, but before ending, I would like to show you that we can write
that in a way similar to that, that it's a bit slower, but still also nice.
They did this for of video, but this is just like a lake grabbing the implementation.
I needed to check different cases to make it like really solid one, but I will show you that we can
actually write that in a simpler way.
We start with equals zero.
And the only trick that we do is mainly about the graph AMG.
So instead of chicken zero one zero zero zero one one zero one one one, the chick about the zero and
one of the first one.
So now I see here if graph on I and G is correct.
Just if there is an image from A to Z, then this is invalid.
Otherwise, G is good.
So here is the case.
Let's say we have zero on one Allison.
One go to zero.
So zero is good.
So C++ now let's two go to zero.
That's good job numbers.
Let's say three go to zero, then you have less.
Plus, let's say that food doesn't go to zero.
Now in the previous good, we have a lot of cases now.
What if you just started?
I was able to swat, so you started to check from food.
If this is a Syncrude or not and then look forward, do the cycle normally in a very normal way.
So it would be chicken for was four four, was five and so on.
Why is that valid?
Why can we avoid all of this, this two cases?
The point is, in all cases, you will have any way to check is it valid or not to check is valid or
not because you do know the history of food with the previous ones.
So let's say four ended five two four six two four seven two four and the program ended.
You were just run one more.
Check on four to read that.
I hope you did pretty well in explaining it in a in a nicer way.
You will find in the IDF and implementation and the like a solid proof for the correctness believes.
Read it.
Keep in mind that the ideas that I mentioned um by the way, free open.
Is away in C++ to read from text, from the file without changing the scene and see out it.
You do need that.
So when I use Free Open, I have testified that I just would like to read it if any time I forgot to
mark the free open and you would like to read from counsel, just mark them here.
It was something that's off.