Let's solve the second homework about the metrics for.
Um, so let's see, here's um to start to like find an answer of this question.
Let's think about let's build the simple graph here.
Maybe node number zero, go to node number one and go to number two and no to number three.
And all of them goes to node number fourth here.
And maybe to the with number five from here.
Now let's build it there, just to see metrics of this metric.
See it.
Um, let's make a small one.
We have six nodes.
One two three four five six.
Okay.
One.
Two, three or five?
Six year.
Now let's.
Would that just a symmetric so we know zero go to one two, three zero to one and two and three and
then one two three, all of them go to four one two three, go to four here one two three go to four
here and four itself go to five.
Uh, zero one, two three.
All of them go to food for itself, go to five, uh, one two three four five Why-Why zero one two three
four five it should be six rows.
What's wrong here?
Zero one zero two zero three Burfict, now one and Food two and the Food three and the Food Perfect
Food and the five.
Yeah, and five.
Go to that tuna.
OK, so this is now the The Matrix.
Let's call it em.
Now who we try to square the matrix empties em.
As you know, the matrix.
You, I and G is a good product between the I threw with the gist column.
Great.
So let's index them zero one two three four five and zero one two three four five.
So now let's think about, for example, that sea of zero and the four sea of zero and the four.
What would be that seizure on for means that the application of the rule number zero, which is this
rule with the code of no food, which is this rule?
So clearly we have zero one one one zero multiply times zero one one one zero.
So when we come out of this together, it will be three.
So now six, zero and four equals three.
This is what you will get from the matrix multiplication.
And the logical thinking about it here will be what does he?
I mean, so N.G. means multiplying the Rule Times column.
So we've got three now thinking back about the graph in terms of a graph.
What does it mean to have this three here?
What does it mean in terms of the original graph?
So let's think about them.
What does this one and this one and this one?
So for the first one, this one here means zero one each.
The second one here means one and two one in four three.
And this one, the coming from this two means zero two and then two fourth.
And this one coming from here is the three and the three four.
So out of this multiplication ended up with three.
Can you get now?
What does the values three means?
The value three is the total number of births consisting of two.
It just so here is best 014 is Isobel's 024 is another Earth, and the 3:04 is a third the bath.
Now.
As you see, again, we started by thinking, what is CNG mathematically?
The eye through both of the this column, OK?
Zero and four, we found the value three investigating the three.
The three values come from this three submissions.
Each submission is relevant to.
The original graph is an edge and another age, and we can see that all of them start at zero.
All of them in the AT4 and this are the intermediate nodes.
So we can see that the metrics in the square represent the number of births between I and G.
That consist of two images that consist of two edges.
And here's the same logic as I said.
Now, if you wanted to generalize this idea much more, what is emitters of our key?
Here is the idea.
Let's say we computed Emma Square, which represent the number of edges for four between a square of
I and G represent the number of edges between I and G of twenty two.
If you try to square em square again, so imma square them in the square.
Now the Senate of zero and for example, two and two and for example, maybe seven.
Let's say this one has three.
This one has five, which here means that there are three edges from zero to do with Lens two, and
this one means there are five edges from three to seven of to two.
When you multiply, the two values together is fifteen, which means there are fifteen edge if fifteen
birth of length before two from here to from here, for example.
Zero one two is when Beth from here and from here to five seven is another Beth from here.
So Ember two.
The power key is the total number of Beth is between I and G, consisting of key edges.
If you look to the example in the homework image, the bulletin was completely zeroes y because there
are no births of lines then in the in the graph.
Now, the and I still appeared to notice C.I. and I tell us if there is a cycle or even the number of
cycles iterating from eye to eye of Linthicum.
For example, if you have an edge from zero to one edge from one to two edge from two to zero.
This is a simple graph if you try to bauer this matrix to the edge of three that a real four, zero
and zero will have one, which you mean you can go in a cycle of three.
It just to go back to Matrix is you?
Now there is a thing here is that the math is that we are referring to is it symbol or not?
Symbol?
The idea was following in kiss of directed graph.
If the graph is there, which you mean it doesn't have any cycles, then the best will always be symbol.
Otherwise, and both undirected graph, which is the same logic, exactly, but definitely it will not
have symbol about this.
But in a simple best, it means that the values could repeat in the middle.
So for example, if you have an edge zero going to one and one going to zero, then if you build the
metrics of the bulletin, you will have a lot of faith is you would have thought you would have a zero
one zero one zero one zero one two one four up to zero.
So the model that the best would be symbol or not based on cycles, undirected graph or I say it like
because when you have an edge zero one, this by definition means you go to one.
I want to go to zero.
If it is a directed graph, then it depends.
Does it have cycles or not?
The last thing that they would like to say, and this is more for seniors, what if I would like to
like, I would like to get the number of birth is of utmost to give it just not just the exact ages,
just just at most one.
We can build a matrix modified from there and decency and the compute something like that.
I will leave it for you to think about it.
We were doing that back then in 2007 or so, and there are a lot of things that we can do about metrics
of power, but they are all competitive programming.
Get reps.
Please verify this information.
I am trying to get it back from my memory like I was playing with this stuff back then in 2009, 07
or so.