Graph theory field is filled with many, many terminologies.
It is impractical to keep explaining all of them in the beginning because most of them would be just
confusing for you.
So I selected here a subset of examples that are fit enough to be explained early.
It is OK if you don't get some of the like the concepts now, maybe when you meet it later again, just
revise it later again.
Uh, again, as we learned so far.
Graph is just consisting of V vertices, we call them vertices or we call them nodes and also consisting
of edges.
So when you think about this graph, we have here six nodes one two three four five six.
Usually, the graph nodes would be actually zero based, but here in this example, they are one be.
The second thing would be the edges e um.
So we have here one edge here two, three, four five, six and so on.
Each is a bit of vertices, so edge is a connection between vertices and in mathematics.
When we say this symbol here, it means that the count.
So the count of V here is just six.
And the count of E is one two three four five six seven seven.
OK.
Sometimes I would mention something like o e actually.
I mean, all that is itself.
When we have an edge of remote, it would be in some context, we would say that it is a source A. And
B is a target.
For example, I told you I would like to go from one to node number six.
So one here is the source and six is the target.
And we would like to go from one to six, which is one way this way like thinking that like whenever
you get lost and need a context, think about computer networks.
One is a machine.
Five is a machine for an exercise machine or c think Airbus one is an Airbus, five is an airport,
four is an Airbus and six is in Edwards and so on.
So anyway, this is a graph of definition.
Let's go in more a subdivision.
There are a lot of probabilities that are involved in the graph.
The most important of them is what we call directed graph and undirected graph.
So the word undirected means the issue doesn't have a direction.
It means it is a two way direction.
For example, node number four can go to number six and node number six can go to new number four.
Do you know the streets?
When you are on the streets, you can see like you can see a street that is cars can go in the two direction,
can go this way and can go this way.
So this is a two way your relationship.
So this is what we model it here.
An example in real life would be Facebook friends if Mustafa is a friend of Bilal.
Bilal is also a friend of Mustafa.
If we have a new one here for Mustafa and another new year for Bilal and we have an edge, it will be
undirected edge, which means the semantic is working well in both directions.
Mustafa is a friend of BLAT.
Bilal is friend of Mustafa,
another type of Graf's which is much more common than the interactive graph is a directed graph.
In the directed graph, it is only one way direction.
So you see here in this graph, we say three Arrow two.
So this arrow represented their relationship direction.
It means we can go from three to two, but we cannot go from two to three.
So this arrow direction is this way only.
OK, what if I would like to support both ways for specific nodes?
We can have something like that.
Three goes to four and four goes to three.
This is a very edge.
This is a direct edge.
These two together allow me to go in both direction.
So as you see, we can represent undirected graph was a directed graph, but the opposite isn't true.
Like if I would like to make an edge to be undirected or like two ways, I can add another edge here.
In terms of like building a graph, if I would like to build this, like if I would like to build it
is like I told you, this is undirected graph and I would like you to build it.
I will give you seven nodes one two three four five six seven.
So I give you only one edge between four and six.
But here the three four.
I must give you two edges because if one of them is an independent edge.
So this graph has one two three four five.
This one has five edges.
This one has seven edges.
So in terms of programming, you must take seven elements here seven beers as an input.
But for this one, you need only five inputs.
So these two, I must give them independently here.
As an example, if Mustafa follows, is the ad in the Facebook.
Mustafa is a person that is a person.
Then Mustafa can see the Adbusters.
But the opposite isn't true because Z doesn't necessarily follow Mustafa.
So the semantic here is just one direction.
Maybe Z also would follow Mustafa.
Maybe?
Yes, maybe no.
Yeah, so it can have also fallen support, but this is optional one.
So as you see from a domain to another, it decides, is it directed or undirected graph?
The second concept in graphs is waiting.
Sometimes we don't need to wait on the edge.
Sometimes we need it.
So let's say we have a computer network here and all what we care about it that we need to know that
edge number six, the computer number six, is connected with network number four.
So it ends up like a zero one case.
Is it?
Does it exist to exist?
Does it exist or not?
We say that this is unweighted graph.
In other contexts, we might need a value, a weed or acoustic on the edge itself.
For example, if we are modeling Airbus, it doesn't matter.
Just you tell me that Cairo is connected with a flight with maybe Toronto.
This by itself isn't important.
I need to know that this cost me $5000.
And this trip cost me $2000.
This trip cost me $3000.
So in unweighted graph, we in graph, we need to need a weed or a cost or a value.
We can even bet going back to the network.
Maybe we have here the time that it needs, if what Eric was to go from here to here.
This happened a lot in companies that would like their services to be very fast.
We need to know how much time does it take for a query to reach from like network number four or service
number four to service number number five?
So yeah, this way, as you see, sometimes we need weed, sometimes you don't.
If you are modeling your courses dependency, and I would like to say that algorithm scores.
That programming course.
So algorithm scores depend on a programming course.
So a student shouldn't take algorithm scores without taking a programming course.
So this is dependency.
We do need it here.
We just need just to know there is a dependency on.
This examples here show what is very common when the value is an edge.
But I would like to tell you that graph something or something is very generic sometimes to the note
itself has a has a has has a value.
We might say that Node six here has value of seventeen, not five here has value of two.
But this isn't the common case.
The common case is about ages themselves.
Sometimes there are a phenomena where the same two nodes may have multiple edges between them.
For example, the node here four and five.
Let's say that this is airborne modeling and food is Cairo and five is New York.
There are two trips here.
One trip was just the two.
And another trip was corsetti.
Maybe this one is in the morning and this one is in the in the in the night.
So sometimes we need this kind of multiple edges between two nodes.
A graph with multiple edges, sometimes we call it multi graph.
What could be really weird is sometimes that these are age from the new itself.
We call it lube or cell volume.
So the loop or loop is when the edge connected the node by itself.
It might look like a weird case for you.
Like, why do we have an idea from a to itself, the domain itself?
We can specify that, for example.
For example, in social media, like a graph, maybe.
Yeah.
Let's say you are in a social media and you you bought a very nice profile for yourself and then you
made the like on your personal boost.
So it's more or less something between the person.
Like if we would like to know which Burson like, which Ibbotson OK based on the posts.
So we'll find that Mustafa made a liking to his own post.
So it's more or less like Mustafa has a sales loop here.
Let me give you another example.
Let's say we are in a basement beach, so this is a big here and there are the basement information
like your credit card information.
And let's say here we have a successful beach or a failure beach.
If basement is succeed, we go to success.
If they meet fail, we get to fail.
But we need if there is a basic error in the bridge itself, we need to stay on the bridge itself.
So for example, let's say you entered your age with the negative value.
We don't need to make it successful.
We can depicted that very, very, very early.
So we say here that this is a silver loop.
If the graph has an edge between every two bit of nodes, every bit of distinct nodes, we see that
this is a complete graph or a fully connected graph.
You see here we have one two three four five six seven.
Four, five, six seven.
And if it is connected with one two three four five six zero connected with everything in such aircraft
and under two kids, we have a total of in terms of minus one over two inches.
This is a very dense figure that will come back to the audience in a few seconds.
Graf Bath there wanted the bath would be very common during this course, so there's a very important
term.
The bus is a sequence of images that joins the deceased together, for example, in this undirected
graph, one five four six is a graph.
So I write it as follows I write it like a graph of one, five, four and six.
It means that we go from one two six one five, then age five four, then age four to six.
So this is what a graph.
So as you see, there must be an age, for example.
Five four three two one.
Elizabeth.
But one two four six isn't like see one to exist.
Four.
There is nothing too much between between two and four.
So this isn't the best.
So the best was this must be an age in a very similar way in the in the directed case.
We have a birth from one to three to four.
But we don't have a bus from four to three to one.
We have from four to three, but we then have from four to three to one.
So this is what about and it's a very, a very important concept during that graph three sections.
There is also what we call a cycle, and a cycle is about the start and end at the same node.
Usually there are no other repeated moves.
So we call it symbol cycle.
So let's see here.
Here we can say that one two three four five one is a cycle we started and ended at the same note.
So we call this a cycle.
A smaller cycle would be one two five one.
This also is a that's like it.
If I if I wrote something like one two five three three one two three five one two three four five one.
Now you see, there are a lot of the locations we call that this is not a symbol cycle.
So if the cycle doesn't have repetition in the middle, we call the symbol cycle.
In The Daily Telegraph, in a very similar way we can have we can have cycles like here you see we go
from three to four.
This is a cycle.
This is the only way I could hear like one to three is in a cycle because there is no energy from two
to three.
If the directed graph doesn't have any cycles, we call it D&amp;G, and that is a very special and very
important case.
So directed acyclic graph or the DAG is a graph of the record graph that doesn't have cycles.
That doesn't have psychics.
Another concept is, is a graph connected or not?
When you look through this graph, we notice it is completely connected.
But when you look to this graph, we see it is disconnected.
We have one unit here, one unit here, one unit here, every unit of them is a sub-groups.
In the undirected case, we call it a connected component, a connected component.
Um, this is also we call it a forest here.
The forest is bunch of separated groups, so sometimes force is more about trees as we'll see.
Spurts and then SIGGRAPH is a very important information.
The Spurs means the graft has relatively few edges.
The density in the group has too much edges.
If it would like to quantify that.
We can say the following a spot SIGGRAPH would be all or we spoke of V this way.
As I said, I didn't.
SIGGRAPH would be obvious where.
This means that the Densey graph is very close to be a complete graph.
OK.
So here are a bunch of examples.
This one is a sports here.
We have six nodes.
We have seven edges.
Very close.
This one is a sparse also, but this one is dense.
This one is dense because the number of edges are very close to the total number of a complete graph.
So in a way it is.
How can you quantify that?
Why is it important because, well, some algorithms are good for denser graphs, some others are for
sparse graphs.
The new neighbor is a very simple concept, which I mean, simply, what are my neighbors and what is
your neighbor if there is an issue between you and the node itself?
So for example, here we see in this undirected graph number three, there are no three has a neighbor
to a neighbor food.
It means that there is an Egyptian 01:57, an aged from three to four and a direct last year.
The Note two has no neighbors.
The two has no neighbors because it doesn't go to anyone.
Meanwhile, no no one here has two neighbors, which are two and three.
There is also a very relevant concept here, what we call the new degree, the new degree represents
your number of neighbors.
So in the undirected graph and number three, the degree is to which because we have to do neighbors
now in the directed graph, it's a bit a bit tricky that the our degrees is the same as the concept
of the number of neighbors we established.
So for example, here we see that the degree of two is zero, which means it doesn't have any neighbors.
Then degrees represent for a directed graph.
The number of incoming edges, for example, then it to the degree of no.
Two, is two, which means there are two edges that come to node number two.
Then degree of four is one, the degree of one is zero because there are no nodes coming here.
So the degree and our degree is only concept of what directed graph.
That degree means that what's playing out, which is not my number of neighbors, then degree is what?
What's coming in?
The three is a special case, three is an undirected graph.
And there is there are lots of interesting birds about trees.
First of all, any two vertices are connected by exactly one.
So you see in the number six connected by five here, four here, three here two one one here, that
is only one way to reach a graph.
Another note now there is a question here.
How can I figure out this is a tree you cannot keep counting?
The bat is an easier ways, as following a tree is if there are any nodes, if it will be only in the
minus one edges and it will be all connected.
So look, here we have six nodes and we have five edges.
This is a tree without any further way to verify it.
So how can you verify tree?
It should be.
All of the nodes are connected together.
You should have any news and the minus one edges.
There are two other interesting but burgess about trees.
If you remove any edge, the graph must be disconnected.
Like, let's say you do this one here.
If you remove this one here, then we have one component here and another component here.
Another interesting fact If you connected anyone edge, you could it one cycle.
For example, if we connected the one in six, this is creating here, one cycle here.
A very relevant the concept is rooted tree in a tree.
You take one root from the undirected graph and like, let's say that this was an underrated graph.
You started from five as a root, every edge coming out of it, you make it in the other direction.
It and other direction make it in the other direction.
Then you go to this one every edge you make at other direction, the other direction, every other direction.
So now you see, it's to become rooted as if there are as if there are like a flu in a specific way.
So this is a rotary that is one interesting bit here.
Remember, this is a directed graph.
Um, every node has only one parent in this routing graph.
Every node, if you if you look to the undirected graph, you do know like there is no better and the
concept here, we have just something connected to something in trees.
We have this beer.
And the reason we say that Note5 is the parent of two, not three, so too is the parent of three.
Not one is abilita four.
So it follows the direction.
This is only for three.
The concept of the parent coming from a life like this is the John who is the father of Adam and is
the father of also, um, Maryam.
So we say that John is a parent of Adam and Mary.
So in a very similar way, when you create a rooted tree, it is, uh, it is like there are the parent
concept that then noted that doesn't have any children.
We call them leaves.
So this one Node two has two children, three and six, and six is a child of two.
Six.
It doesn't have any children, so we say three, four six are we call them leaves like a leaf of a tree.
There are different types of fruit, a tree of liberty, every angle for every arrow, for example,
here to the up.
It's also a rooted tree, so after you build it this way, you'll flip it.
Then it's also around the tree.
Sorry for the British boy.
So great theory and very dense in definitions.
It doesn't work for now if you miss some of the concepts that struck.
I would like you to know that graph is a data structure because it's a class that is built around its
seeded, around its roads and around its edges.
And we have many algorithms to it.
That's all.