In this section, we would like to start to learn more about how to represent the epigraph as the section
is graph representation.
We would like to represent a graph.
For a while, it might seems like a very difficult task.
How can we take such a graph and express it in computers in something?
However, it isn't by the end of the this citizens and their homework, so you will be very flexible
when it comes to graphs.
I would like you to take two minutes and ask yourself a simple question How can I express a graph with
five nodes like that in a matrix that is five times five?
Like, you have a five times five metrics?
I would like to encode this kind of information inside this five times five metrics.
How can you do that?
This is a directed graph.
As you see, the most thinking should be more than enough.
The idea is very simple we can create a matrix such that, uh, if the matrix of Ingwe represent how
many edges we have from node ideology as there are no multiple edges here.
So this means every two nodes will have either zero edges or one edges.
So let's see here node number one and number four, there is an edge between them, so node number one
and node number four here.
Should have I won here?
What else?
Two and the three, so array of two and the three should have won here one and two.
One and two should have won here.
A ray of zero and two should have won, so zero and two should have won here.
So as you see, this is very simple and very intuitive, right?
Like, you just put the metrics of high energy or the gratify energy with how many, just how many edges.
So this way we can even like if I told you that, maybe let's say, from two to three, like, for example,
if I said that we have another edge this way and another edge this way.
So now from two to three, we should have here three three edges.
So in this way, we build a very nice mattress.
So the wood adjacency that you just referred to two things who are adjacent, like when we have EMV,
this is a different relationship.
The what the metrics mean, just we use a 2D array to express their relationships.
This is one way and this is very intuitive.
So let's keep going.
If the graph is undirected, then one is connected with zero and also zero is connected with one.
So 200 that all what we need to make sure that matrix of energy is as simple as metrics of journey.
For example, if there are seven edges between one and five, the metrics of one five a matrix of five
on one should have a value of seven.
This usually would create a kind of symmetry in the matrix.
As you see, again, there are no multiple edges here.
So this is a completely binary matrix.
If I told you that between one and two, there are four undirected edges.
So one and two, one and two we should have here.
Four.
So again, so as I see the The Matrix, a 2D matrix is very flexible.
Either you would like to represent a directed graph or undirected graph.
Now, let's try to implement that, you would you will usually make a typedef and call it graph so we
can use a vector vector of integer to represent the graph so that it be flexible in the creation.
I would like you to create two function, one ad directed edge and one is add undirected edge, which
you take.
The from A to Z are zero based indices like the whole course most of the time, and the graph itself
that the graph is would be initialized and proper for you.
For example, if the number of modes is five, graph will be a 2D vector, that's five times five.
How can we implement these two methods?
But it's take five minutes to implement them.
Then presentation is very straightforward.
If you have in the directed function, if you have an image from from to you just go to grab from and
to and right plus equals one.
So the second one will will increase the count of the adjacency in the ad undirected graph.
You can go two from and two and read Blitz equals one.
And from the to and from AndroidPolice equal one.
So this way we are adding in the two sides in the same time.
So as you see overall, very, very, very straightforward.
Now let's use them.
It is how you will write a code that will like take an emblem from the user.
You start by reading the number of nodes.
And number of edges, as we would like to create a matrix of nodes.
The times inwards we create here a graph which is victor victor of nodes, and every entry is vector
of integer of nodes.
I assume that you are good enough in each state to understand this line of code, and then we iterate
on the number of edges every time we read the form and two.
This is a directed graph, so I'm quoting here the ad directed graph function, which you take the graph
graph from a tool and then we are going to print adjacency metrics to verify it.
So here is the inputs five nodes, eight edges.
Then we have eight lines.
Every line is two numbers that are zero based.
If we try to help with this one, it will say from zero to one, there are two edges because you can
see here we have a zero one here and we have zero one here.
From one to two, we have one edge from four to three, we have three edges four two three four two
three four two three.
How can we write the Brent adjacency matrix to Brent this could here?
Can you try?
The idea is very simple, but we have nodes, so we iterate on the first look like a tourist that loops
each one of them go afterwards.
I'm getting the first one from and the second one to have graphs from and to greater than zero.
It means there are idiocy and from from it to say Brent from and Brent two and Brent a graph of from
into that simple.
OK.
What about the wicked graph?
If the graph no has weights with the current metrics would be enough.
How can we change it or how can we handle that?
The idea is very simple.
Let the adjacency of Iron G equal costs, but it didn't.
For now, there are no multireligious OK, like this is just one inch here.
So here I would.
As you see, we have aged from zero to one here.
One and two was 15.
So you go one and two and what 15?
We have from two to four with 13.
You go from two to four here and 13 and so on.
Can you adjust the previous cuts?
Here is that just good?
We take Froman, too, and we take the cost to now hear from Graph from until we write the costs and
directed one graph from an to equal graph tool from equal the cost.
The reading is the same, almost.
You just read the cost, the here.
Read it here.
Best to you.
That's all.
So as you see, changing the good is very straightforward.
And here is the outfit.
Now, you might wonder, what should we do if we have multiple ages?
If the previous one, we assume two things, we assume that an all ages and also we assume that no age
would have a value equal zeal.
I assumed all of which equal greater than zero.
However, what of the which between the two two is actually zero or even negative value in the previous
good will depend on the cheek of matt and equivocal zero two.
There is an agent.
But what if it can be used one in a way, the handling of the multiple ages with which in reality depends
on the problem itself?
Let me give you some examples in a suit.
This to bethe problem.
How can we handle the multiple ages?
If you are, if you have interest only in the shortest about, and I told you that not one good to note
event was ghostwritten and good to note seven was close to 20.
Which one do you care about them?
Only the 10 because you would like to get the shots, the birth right, so we can suggest that the minimum
among all of the different ages.
And that's it.
So this is how we can handle multiple ages.
What about missing values?
One way, maybe just create another Boolean metrics that say, if there is an issue from here to here
or not.
So now we have the metrics for the Boolean and in other metrics for the values.
Maybe a third way you would initialize their tricks to have a very large value like an infinity, maybe
one each with nine, for example, and then you can convert against Guinness 08:40 and see if that is
a value or not.
So two that, you know, missing the key message here there is no standard and what a specific way it
is all about the problem, and you utilise your problem solving skills to come up with the proper representation.
So, so don't be stuck in a specific way through the course you should find in a way.
Examples of that handle such such cases before ending it is very important to understand the space and
time complexity.
So there are a bunch of questions for you.
What is the space complexity?
What is the time complexity?
But for the following scenarios.
So I would like to know if there is an issue between you and you and V. What's the name complexity of
that?
If you'd like to get your neighbors, what is the complexity that we would like to bring to the wood
graph?
Let's them complex of that.
And is this representation good for the Spurs audience metrics?
And what does it mean if the two metrics are there?
They are going to has some one zero values, but is it?
Stop the video for like a five minutes and answer out of this question.
Try to make it a of engagement and trying to make the calls involving a lot of engagement.
I'm asking you a lot of questions.
I'm encouraging you to curate algorithm scores, if you would.
So try to help me to make it an easy experience for you.
Here are the.
First of all, we created a 2D matrix of times of each.
So be square in the standard books that they were rated this way all.
Oh, the squid, OK, when I write it this way, I'm just writing it for short because sometimes I use
V and mean the number of notes, and sometimes I use it to mean the set of the.
So just flexibility.
But don't get confused if you'd like to know if there's an edge between you and V, you can do that
in all one by accessing the metrics directly.
If you'd like to get your neighbors, you have to iterate on your route.
Like, let's say this is true.
Number three, and there is someone here, and maybe there is some five here, so you need to iterate
on the wood rule to know that this is my neighbor and this is my neighbor.
So we need all of you to iterate on the road to get my neighbors.
To traverse that graph.
You need to trade on all of the rules and all of the columns.
So this is v squared now thinking about sports and dance?
If you thought about it, this one is very good.
If the graph is very, very complete, like if we have every kind of connection, this is very perfect.
The graph, because we have here, we can represent all of them.
We can put them.
So it's actually very good for denser graph.
Now think about the graph.
If I told you have a tree, you remember the tree.
The tree has, uh, any nodes and in the minus one edges, imagine that we have 1000 nodes, so we have
around nine nine nine inches.
You created one million entries, total the around 1000 of them or 2000 of them.
This is too much.
So this representation is good for dense a graph.
Not for the specific.
The last thing is, what does it mean to have a value in the diagonal?
Like, let's say we have here are three times the three metrics.
And I found zero zero seven zero.
So here in the diagonal, it means that metrics of two and two is seven.
There are seven loops that are around the Pixel two.
That's of.