Let's move to the second and very common adjacency list, the representation and other representation
for the graph.
I would say many of them, but the mutations during the course would be based on that one.
Let's see.
So the adjacency matrix is in a good word for sparse matrices.
Now, just as he list to come to help this problem by saving more memory, the idea is very simple.
But every note you will have a list you will see usually in books at Detroit like could list you have
a list of nibbles.
Can you guess the full picture?
Like, how can we use Victor Victor of integers to represent, for example, unweighted graph?
They did this following.
Let's say that we have a new two here, not two here, it has four neighbors, one four five zero three.
Now you do the following you start to say that no two is attached only to this list of nodes, so no
two year would have a list of foreigners here.
What about, for example, node zero, not zeros on the attached to Note five has only five.
So we have here five.
What about nude, no.
Maybe nude number two, three, three doesn't have any neighbors, so empty list and so on.
If not, number five is also connected to nude No.
Six and also nude number seven and nude number eight.
So nude number five here would have the food and would have also the six and the seven and eight.
So the more of that is in instead of a complete one rule of zeros and ones or whatever to say if there
is a neighbor or not, this doesn't work because in a sports matrix, all of that is zero.
What about just saving the memory and just listing their correspondence?
Can you implement that using Vector Victor Frontier?
Can you give it a try it?
It should be easy and intuitive.
It is a.
The graphic definition is still as it is there, the graph in the creation will see it now.
The graph has here from an to as usual.
But we say graph from the bush back to.
So this is like instead of like attaching it to a list, we are attaching it to a vector.
And the undirected, edgy ad from the left and you heard from the right, the printing this time iterate
on every single note.
But now graph from represent a list or a vector of my neighbors.
For example, here in this, one graph of two g of two will be a vector that involve only the values
of zero, one, five and three.
So this would reiterate only for a number of steps and then graft from and to would be actionable.
So as you see them, but ambition now is less intuitive.
But over time, you will get used to it.
It is the main function.
Everything is as it is with one change.
When you create here the graph, it would be a graph of nodes.
This is in the previous same graph of nodes of victor of integral nodes.
This time was just to create initially a single vector of nodes.
Everyone has an empty victory in the beginning.
And the more more value that you add, the more they are here in the list.
Now, what if the graph is weakened?
How can we handle that in the clouds?
Can you think about a modification for the good try to be flexible like a challenge yourself?
It is one way you can create an edge glass construct and added the value to and add you cost.
You can even use the C++ beer internet.
Now our presentation is not victor of victor of integer, it's victor of Victor Edge.
Now this is very flexible because you can add whatever you need to there.
You can add whatever you need to the edge itself.
Let's see the implementation here.
The function now will have the coast and now the bush back will have the two and the coast.
This create an object from that structure.
And now in the representation here, the EJU will have the two and it cost.
OK.
A few concerns to keep in mind.
What about self loops, you can you rejected them and ignore them, if you would like?
What about, uh, keeping only one editor from multiple edges?
This is not as easy because I have no no to.
Would you have an edge, five A. in?
A. Three agita?
Now you don't, you would like to keep all one edge.
Well, for example, if there is a reason for that, you have to iterate through that.
Five exist to avoid adding it again.
Well, also the same, the same method looks I would like to remove.
Seven.
You have to find this and remove it.
Maybe some people will just find it, swab it with the back and remove it.
But in all cases, you still have to remove it.
OK.
What if I would like that the edges to be ordered like I don't need it five seven three two, I need
it to be two three five seven.
So one way is after you build the graph, you can sort it if you would like.
By the definition, what we would like by the coast, you can circle by the coast and so on.
So I'm trying to show you the flexibility now.
Took five minutes to answer out of this question like that every time.
And this is one extra question relative to the last time who would like to go into the degree of how
can we do that?
Let's see.
Now, first of all, the space complexity is Ebola's V.
When you create a vector, it is a Vector V nodes.
Everyone will have bunch of neighbors, right?
Like, I have two neighbors.
Sevigny was five neighbors, three neighbors.
The submission of all of the neighbors is somebody.
So the total is Fiddler's feet.
This is a very common complexity that you will see a lot during their graph theory.
If you would like to get to know if an edge exists or not, you have to iterate on all of your neighbors.
So let's call it ordinary here all of the our degree.
If you would like to list all of your neighbors, yes, you would have to go LORD°.
If you'd like to traverse the wood graph, then you have to straighten out of it again.
The same logic treat power over the nodes, pour over the neighbors, and the thick way to think about
these edges here is as a as a root here.
It's actually like a submission of the the neighbors, some submission of the neighbors of Node I.
If you try to sum all of the neighbors in a total sum, it just eat.
I hope it's clear enough for you.
Try to think of it in an intuitive way.
I have heard this vector, this vector, this vector is vector and this vector.
So I have your different neighbors, but think globally this is e edges.
So total is E and we have a V for the edges.
What about the in the group A.?
It would to to know the India Group A..
You have to iterate over the wooded structure to summit, which is very expensive.
This representation is more flexible than previous one specifically to maintain the memory, but it
is more better for the sparse one.
Um, we discussed two Boblo representations in the home work.
You will see other two bubbler representation, then I will challenge you with many other question that
about the representation and the message that I'm giving to you is a graph.
Representation is a very generic concept.
Don't trap yourself in a specific view.
Just think what are my nodes?
What are my edges thinking we did or not directed or not?
Multiple edges are not, uh, a lot of things.
C++ set Mab hash tables, vector list.
All of that can be used in the representations, so don't grab yourself in what we explained.
We are just showing you how people we're managing these representations.
Let us think that I would like to tell you is about the rotary.
You remember, the rotary is a directed tree was one root and then every every arrow is for down.
So as a three, it will have in the minus one edges.
Now there is a very interesting idea here.
We can definitely represented with adjacent cities.
But there is a very nice representation.
Remember the idea?
We say that, too.
As a parent of five, the parent of zero is five.
The merit of one is five.
The parents of four is one.
So create the one the array of eludes and in every one of them, put the beer.
And for example, beer into four is one parent of two is five beer and two of six is two.
And only for the root value would value like minus one.
So interesting about this representation, it is all v in the memory only.
It will be because in a way we have it just like spaces and we can know the beer and directly in 01.
But if you would like to know your beer neighbours, you have to do it.
In all, this representation is very important and is used by the -- data structure.
Uh, yeah, that's so.
Let me explain something a little more formal here.
Before ending that, I want to mention that I would be very informal in the course I would give informal
sketch for the groups and so on.
But the proof the format why this field involve a lot of mathematics because to prove something, you
need to do mathematics.
I would like to show you, what does it mean to explain in a formal way when it comes to graph?
I will tell you something later.
Given a directed Graph G equals v any compute g ts to subscript here or B it.
And this is explanation of fee.
I would like you to take five minutes and try to guess what does this mean?
So it is.
What does it mean?
First of all, g equal video because it is a graph of V nodes and edges.
Now here this is just a solid script.
You know, in programming, you write something like a graph to graph three.
This is just subscript.
So you see that here.
G D, which is a new graph, is V, which is all the vertices.
So we are using the same vertices and new edges.
We are substituting them with Steve.
Maybe some scripting, maybe another term I forgot.
Now what?
How to represent the new images the following way.
You see these part.
This is like a for loop, it says for every edge you and Vinnie would take Vnu.
This means if the graph has an edge two, we would have it five and two.
OK.
Uh, this simple mean belongs to.
So the idea here this is just we are reversing the edges of the death.
It says if you have a graph of one, two or three, the new graph is one to three, but the digits are
flipped two this way.
So that's okay.
Directed graph is an order the debate of nodes.
So that's why we write this way like, you know, like a directed one.
So if you envy is like a piece, like when I tell you the and v, it mean the first item from V and
the second item is also from V So B and V R Preview and V.
As I say, this is this is how we write something more formally.
Informally, I would just say, you know what?
This is a reference towards just the reverse of rage.
So as you see, the informant sometimes is way easier to sublease.
It's just matter of a single second.
But the format is very important.
Why many, many in mathematics, many formal proofs?
Maybe you didn't write the formal proof they will miss something.
Even in formal groups, people do mistakes.
So when people do informal proofs, they are more subjective for mistakes.
That's why formal definitions of of graph theory or other algorithms is very important.
It isn't a waste of time, you know, it takes more time to understand it.
But this is how you make something very solid and also a good way to discover your mistakes that solve.