Um, yeah, let's start with the homework representations, and the purpose of that board is sometimes
the students complain that they don't feel comfortable with the graph theory.
I thought maybe if we made them more comfortable with their graphic representation first, it would
make that life easy.
Overall, I would like you to be patient when it comes to graph theory, but I promise you, over time
you will get used to it faster and faster.
So just calm down and give it an opportunity to learn it.
Some tips are to consider during the graph sections, if I'm giving you the graph like I usually will
try to specify valid graphs like zero in the minus one range, for example for the vertices.
Um, unless I'm so you are solving a problem or lead could, for example, then it's up to them the
spec..
Sometimes I miss some of the specific issue.
It happens if this is the case, usually to a directed graph, usually unweighted multiple edges and
loops are possible.
And usually we use the edges is the representation.
If the graph is weighted, usually I mean integers.
Interesting bit is consider always the following Remember, you have to think about special cases and
you have to think in a systematic way.
So please consider a graph of only a single node, even a single node that has a silver loop.
Consider a graph in an order that doesn't have any edges.
Consider a bunch of different is the cases that are a bit special cases.
The key is to twist your code in a good way, in a systematic way.
So let's proceed.
The first homework about the larger idealist, the representation, we there are usually three standard
sibling representation the adjacency matrix additions, the list and the indigenous ID you list is the
simplest among all of them.
It is as simple as just that a collection of inches.
That's it.
If the graph has 10 edges, you have a vector of 10 inches that symbol.
So please define something that is graph that is vector of age and implement to the edge to contain
the relevant information.
Um, I would like you to add something here.
I would like the edges to be comparable.
Let's say we would like to sort to the edges based on the edge weight, for example.
OK.
So this is a weighted graph.
This is a weighted graph.
Now you should implement that function as we did before.
Add the adjacency function after you read the edges, I would like you to order them based on the cost
or the weight, and then you bring to them be resisted the state space and time complexity for you.
So this is Mindy, your first task reading the graph is just as we did before.
Now let's try some of the fancy representations here.
One of the representation people call it additions adjacency, adjacency set.
What adjacency has set the idea?
Is this following we would like.
We know that in the in the adjusted symmetric, the advantage was merely again, no even exist or not
in 01.
But there was a result here that we, if we would like to know the neighbors of me, I have to iterate
linearly on the number of nodes when we move to that addition, Celeste.
We note that we now can iterate early on the addition to a list with all degree, but we now cannot
know if an edge exist or not an old one.
So this creates a trade off and trade offs is something that is very common in the industry, in engineering,
in designing algorithms.
So sometimes we have to choose between that and that.
The good news is with the hash table based implementation, we can get the best of the tools we can
get.
Something that is from one side is all the to iterate on the neighbors, but still you'll want to check
if I don't exist or not.
So the graph representation will be based on the hash sit in C++ as following it will be vector of hash
set of type integers.
Uh.
This is wrong, I'm sorry for that.
Let me think this is wrong.
It should be vectors.
Uh, this is correct.
I'm sorry.
Yes, it's like that.
So.
Yeah, mainly.
Previously, every element was a list right now, every element is a hash that every element is the
hash.
But you can assume that their representation is that we did implement this version of our code that
added edge of the printed state, the time and space complexity.
But more importantly, I would like to think that this advantages of this representation, this definitely
assume that you know what is a hash table.
If you don't, you can skip the segment, but I just feel free to to to be aware of that.
The second thing is the multiple ages.
We had the discussion during the lecture about the multiple ages and women gender strategy if we would
like to pick only one edge among all of the ages.
But what if we have to keep out of them?
This also might be the case.
So now I would like you to bring to the graph such that for each Inuit.
Uh, we would like to anyway, we would like to maintain an implementation that that is following here.
Here is five nodes, then edges and then we will have multiple edges like zero one, 10, zero one seven
and so on.
No imprinting them, not by nodes like the edges of the node zero edges of not one, two, three and
so on.
I do not care about that.
So here are some nodes I would like you to bring to the graph such that the edges of each node are represented
first.
But the order of the printed edges themselves doesn't matter.
So here I need you to print for me four lines for net zero, which order?
I don't care, but I need you to be ordering them this way.
Now there is one thing here.
Uh, yeah, the graph here is directed there, the graph, which are integer values.
I think that's all I don't want to complicated at the moment.
So the moral of that is.
Brent Them Group, Dubai.
The source said if you could confuse them, good, divide the system with what is the exact order here?
We don't care what is the exact order here.
We don't care.
But every source in food would bring its own stuff together.
Look why printing?
So this is mainly an implementation that will force you to keep the multiple edges.
OK.
Uh, and this is should be an addition to metrics.
So you should implement it.
You should merely to change their adjacency matrix itself to include the multiple edges for us.
Yeah, that's awful.
First of all.