Let's solve the homework, the first problem is about the ageless, the representation.
So this is an easy example.
So let's see here.
First of all, the edge is what the ages from and to and wait.
I created a constructor here.
Now, one of the tasks in this problem, if we have a bunch of edges, would like to search to them
based on their weight.
So this means they can C++, they can provide the pool operator Lizette.
You can also make this like a class and public and private just kept it simple here and just compared
the weight with the weight.
In this way we can compare to is the brain function is just printing the content here.
And this is our graph now.
Now, when you think about the adage you function well, what does it do is adding for your victory,
it just the from too and cost as an edge.
So this is merely what's happening here and there is now no way to like to to bring things just on what
you can do.
It did it on the edge of the edge and just sprinted.
Sprinting here is very simple.
The last thing that the graph here is pretty straightforward, given that we define the greater less
in our function, we can search the graph in a very normal way.
In terms of the complexity, the space complexity is very clear.
We have a victor of a just so it's only now now imagine that the complexity for operations like I would
like to know if two is connected with three or not, you have to threaten all of the edges.
So only if you would like to maybe get the neighbors of node number three, you have to threaten all
of the nodes.
So I think all of the operations are all.
This representation in general is a slower representation.
That's why it has a very limited usage like Billman for the, for example, algorithm.
Use it.
But generally speaking, a few a few algorithms use it.
But as you see the advantages, it is very similar to a large extent.
Okay, so what is the next problem and the next problem I would like to make, the agency has it, which
is a very interesting program, I hope here, you know, the deal with it so that you can get the advantage
and learn about that.
So the adjacency CET approach is a try to get the get the best of two worlds.
We know the adjacency adjacency matrix is a 2D matrix like that.
It is great to know that if edge like zero one zero one two, if you'd like to know adjacency of one
and two exist or not, it would be all one from adjacency matrix.
But you have to iterate linearly to get the numbers when we go to that.
That the the list, the state.
We can't get the neighbors in all the green, but you know, if there is a GNC, we have to iterate
on all of them.
Now the question is, who comes here?
Can we get something that is one to check if one and two are adjacent?
And also is would agree if we would like to get the neighbors of would number seven, for example,
this can be achieved by an adjacent, he has said.
The idea is as following we will have again a victor.
Onwards, but then instead of having a vector of engine lists, we would have a vector of hash that
the hash cities, the hash table that we just can put items in it in and remove them in 01.
So you want to add, you want to remove along to look up, but you lose the advantage of the order.
The current order, like they would be seven to 20 zero.
You lose the order in hash tables.
Now, if you would like to add directed edge, you get a graph from which is the asset.
Then you inserted the two down there.
It is the same logic if you would like to print.
Then we iterate on the node by node.
It is easy to use the other like for like this is tied in C++ to Brent to them.
So graph from here is this is this set your data on them one by one to two printed.
As you see, the code is almost the same as the hash that GC list.
The advantage is you cannot check a graphical graph like if we'd like to know the to exist or not,
you can check if graph graph of from.
Don't count.
To if this function return a value that is greater than zero, then the room has this too.
So this is mainly what we get, get a full frontal view of the adjacency neighbors that count, will
you and 01 the if there is an edge or not.
OK, so now about the complexity.
It's again this this complexity was, oh, we have to keep all of the edges now as you see, it is all
one to add, remove and a chicken edge, which is a great advantage, including the remove here.
And it's all degree of degree of specific not to iterative neighbors, but there are some disadvantages
for this representation that you have to keep in mind.
First of all, there is no order guarantee for edges.
There is no order guarantee for edges.
Has set her stable doesn't guarantee any order.
The second thing it is impractical for a multiple edges.
It is hard to extend it.
It's doable, probably, but it's hard to extend it to multiple edges because the Hashid, by definition,
just about one thing.
Maybe, maybe we can use the I think I do remember.
I think there should be.
Maybe, maybe not.
I do remember if there is an order, the multisite or not.
The third thing is, remember that the the hash tables has internally extra memory, so the hash table
internally has, uh, with them, the representations has a bunch of internal variables internally to
do this stuff.
Generally speaking, like any hash table, high tables are very powerful.
But one has to be careful about using them.
For example, if you remember from the hash table study, you have to be careful about the root factor
because in a in a in a longer setup, you can end up with a very slow procedure.
And what we thought is one could be very high value.
So overall, it's very interesting data structure.
But still, there are a lot of things that we need to take into consideration before deciding to go
with it.
This is mainly about the second homework.
OK, let's see the third one.
The third one is about creating multiple edges, using adjacency metrics like how can you change that
distance in metrics to include multiple edges?
This isn't a hard division at all.
So here's the here's the idea.
Remember the metrics?
Originally it was a 2D matrix like that like, say, two times the three or three times the three metrics.
And we put a single value.
What if we were yet another victor victor of edges?
So now it's vector vector.
These two vectors are the matrix, and the internal vector are for their multiple edges.
That's it.
Now you start.
If you would like to put across the four of RAM two, this internal vector would be for the cost.
If you would like to put a cluster here, you would go to graph from and two, which is this cell and
then you push back a cost in its its value.
That's symbolic.
That's all about the how to extend it.
Um, now the complexity might be a bit more tricky.
We are sure that we have at least v squared here.
But now, as you see, every single node has has the corresponding edges.
So this means that we have also built each year in the complexity.
So this is a time complex.
This is a space complex, you know, v squared for the original metrics and e for every single, um,
like the total order, like a ghost in every one of them.
Uh, the pushback is all one.
So insertion is now.
Is it still, um, adding a vector is one if you would like to check if this is enabled or not.
You can just check if the list has a size or not.
So.
So it's still one to get the uh, I want to know that.
Just see if you'd like to know if there is an edge with the specific cost, then you have to check to
have to iterate through the digits.
Um, yeah, that's all here.