Homework number two.
We still continue the some of the homework about the representations itself, so in this one, I would
like to teach you about domains in real life.
The problems are about domains.
So now we are in, we have airports and we have a lot of flights.
Every flight is from and to and coast.
But instead of giving you the front two in range, zero in the minus one, we you will have strings.
Strings to those pieces.
And the cost is just an integral value.
Now you should build a directed graph based on one of the adjacency style and also consider that there
could be multiple edges.
This means that there could be multiple flights between the same source and same destination.
Your branding function should be very sorted as following.
So let's see here the input.
We have five airports and we have nine flights.
California, Texas with thirty thousand dollars.
California, Texas, $10000.
And so on.
Now you should Brent exactly in the following July.
It is a two level sorting.
First of all, the source itself, like the from California, should come first before Florida, before
New York, before Pennsylvania.
And so it now inside every same source like from California to these cities also, or these states also
should be sorted based on him.
What if we have multiple states with the same name?
Then you should sorted them by coast from small to large.
So again, you have three conditions for sorting one of them based on the from.
Another one based on the two and a third one based on the cost.
If the two is the same one.
So please refer to the description here.
If you are confused.
After you are done with the previous homework, we will move to Division two, please relation to that
after you are done with the previous one.
So now the exhibit that we have is a domain example.
So remember, we mentioned that we have several domains like here, we have airport domain, for example.
And we see that the urban domain can be converted, as we learned in the obstruction in the introduction.
We learned that we can represent that to the standard, the graph theory.
Now there is a problem here.
Let's see.
The graph theory has 100 algorithms.
If you would like to model everything in terms of Airbus, you will have to rewrite all of these hundred
algorithms to have a airport from Airbus through urban flight course and all of that.
Now if you have another domain, let's say for a computer vision, you would have to rewrite the hundred
algorithms for computer vision.
This doesn't work.
This isn't scalable.
So the way that we actually do is we reduce the domain to the standard.
The problem?
This means as much as we can.
We converted a domain such that it can use the standard algorithms in this, uh, homework here.
Well, I would like you to use this as a code that we used in the lecture for for the adjacency list
as it is the room two and wait for the edge.
The ad directed edge exactly as we did in the lecture.
The same could.
So now you have to take all of this strings and find your way to reduce it to.
Standard graph, I hope you got the idea.
We cannot keep representing every graph problem in its original domain.
We will have to rewrite all of the algorithms again from scratch.
This doesn't make sense.
So the idea is we reduce the domain to the standard graph and then we use it for simplicity to keep
things easier.
You don't have to care about the order anymore.
You just printed them like a city by city or like state by state.
And that's it.
In the thick of the problem, we would like to move to another domain, which is images like in fields
like image processing and computer vision, they are all about images.
The interesting thing here and image is eventually just the rectangle that is our time.
See now.
The rectangle, Eddie, any any 2D array can be represented as a graph.
How?
If you have an image that is our times, you see, we have our time see nudes.
For example, if I have a 2D array that is 10 times the 20.
This represent, for us, 200 nodes.
So this is about the nodes.
OK.
What about the edges?
The it just comes in from the surrounding cells.
Use surrounding cells are your neighbors where you build your edges.
There are a lot of ways to build different levers for simplicity.
If this is a set of AI and then the up and right and down and left are your neighbors.
This means every edge will have a maximum of four neighbors.
I would like you to create a graph with an image, so you think you mainly read to an integers the rows
and columns of two the metrics and create a graph based on that in the next section?
We will go deeper about representing grids in the Diffa section, so we'll get to more details about
that.
But for now, we would like you to be familiar with that.
So here is the program.
You will read something like three and four and you will write for every note.
The neighbors.
Now how would you represent to the neighbors?
Remember, if you have a metric study or time C, we can flatten it two zero one two three blah blah
blah.
Up to our C minus one center, the C and we have a metrics three times for this mean we have varies
from zero to 11.
So I'm here writing zero to 11.
Now here is node number six.
Who are its neighbors hub, right?
Live.
Don't bring to them in any order.
But what?
I care that to find their exact four neighbors.
What about something like node number three?
It only have one neighbor from here and another neighbor from here.
So please taken andbut and Brent for us, something like that.
It's OK if you bring to them like two, five, seven, 10 or whatever, order here, but you have to
follow this format overall.
OK, we are done with the graphic representations.
Let's have a few functionalities on them.
The first program, I would like you to read undirected unweighted graph.
So as we did before you start to read the and nodes, the images, you start to read the from until
we did that several times.
I would like to introduce for you a new graphic concept, which is a chin.
The chin is something like a linked list.
Remember the link in this just sequence of nodes?
This is only the graph.
It is the simplest to ever graph a state like any graph that involve the buses.
This is a symbol among them.
So this is a sequence.
It cannot have an extra edge here.
It just something like that.
One sequence of edges.
So zero five five three three four one one two.
So this is merely the end would achieve.
That's it.
Now I would like you.
After you read the graph, you will read an integer key for queries.
Every query will be a single number, a single node, and you should list the birth starting from this
node until the end.
So this is a function.
Merely bring the chain it.
Take a graph.
It took a starting node and bring to the chain.
This function should be implemented as a simple, recursive function symbol, recursive folks, so we
can definitely make it an iterative function.
So let's see here an example.
I told you we have six loads and five edges and then zero five.
So what we have here are for one.
Then after that, they told you about the one two, then the five three, then the zero five, then
the three four.
So have this achieved?
Now we have four queries, the first the first equity at zero.
So you print from zero up to the end, which is zero five three four one two, then query number engine
number three three four one two one one one two two just two two.
As usual, all of my values for the rules would be always from zero in the minus one range, so you
don't have to worry about verifying that.
So this is a first function we deliver on a graph.
Let's see another one.
You read a directed graph in a very standard where you read the number of nodes, the number of edges,
then you read the nine edges and then you will print all the births of Linfa to.
All the Baathists of Lindsay, too.
So, for example, this is a group of six nodes and edges.
You will notice we have all of these two edges, for example, we have an edge from zero to five here
and each from five to four.
So we can see that zero five.
Four is a birth of two inches, so in the given graph, find all of the birth is that consists of two
edges and the bent to them.
The don't keep thinking about narrow things like what about multiple ages, what about for loops?
Assume a very simple graph without multiple edges or silver loops?
Um yeah, this should be a simple, iterative function, so don't overcomplicate things.
Yeah, that's not here.