Let's solve the first homework about the Airbus domain.
So this is the purpose of the of the homework here.
So let's see.
First of all, we're going to we have a look at concerns.
We have Roman too, that are strings.
We would like to maintain an order on the from an order on the tool and order on the coast.
So this is thought to be that let's define an age across the age this time would have instead of integrated,
it would be string two.
And it has integrated, so we are going to build a decent system.
That's why we're doing better from here.
Now here is little zen operator.
There is an operator should commit us following if the are equal in the two like taxes.
Hundred and taxes to any.
Then it will.
But the one that has a smaller cost the first.
Otherwise, it would sort of be.
This is a standard way that I teach you guys in programming quotes to certain elements.
You go ahead with a bunch of equal conditions.
One by one.
What is your first criteria?
The two so you can be equal if they are into equal equal, then you can bear directly based on them.
Otherwise, you return to by, by the way.
So this is a standard way to combat elements.
So the moral of that is we have an edge class that has the two.
It has the cost and is ready to of us based on these two criteria.
Now the second challenge is we do not have indices anymore to sort of is them.
The good news about the map is as following the map can have a key as a string.
What is the great advantage of Beheshti will compare to hash table or like a balance of by necessity
compared to arrays, the array and the 2D array has to be based on integers zero one two blah blah blah.
But the maps can have a key anything like it can be a string.
So this is one thing here now.
Map in C++ will sort things based on the key because maybe internally is implemented with a balance.
Had been there such a tree, which is sort of by keys?
So this is now about the key itself.
What about the values now, now this is a.
Now here.
I have here this is addition to this, the style, OK, remember, and this is a great exercise to to
learn how to do the right things.
What is an just to this is that you have a bunch of elements and every elements has his own directly
items.
This is a general view of their adjacency list.
So now the key here is handled through Map, which is here, for example, string.
So let's say here we have your string California.
Now we would like to have a decency list here of any type, anything that is a bunch of elements is
OK.
Now I am going to implement this internal one using multi set.
So here is the two advantages set in C++ can also set a multisite can order for us there.
Elements set and multisite can order for us their elements and can also allow for us objects or strings
or whatever.
So this is a multi set of edges.
Now this edge has a pretty list then, which is used by the multisite.
If you don't have this function here, the code will not work.
So again, the map is to have strings and also allow sorting them.
There, multisite here, allow us to have edges and allow have them to be sorted, allow them to be
duplicate.
So if I have to have a trip from California to Texas was very thin and another one from California to
Texas with very thin.
Both of them would remain here.
If you would just set the noblest values would be would be good.
The moral of that to maintain the two certainly criteria, I use the map for the key and I use the multisite
for their value.
I hope the overall structure is simple.
Anything after that is just like a very normal, very, very normal goods.
So the adage here will go to the graphic from which is kill a group of California and inserted the age
of two and cost like a 10 with the value to Texas with value 10.
The print for the adjacency would iterate on like a normal, just as it trade key by key.
And after that, get the edges.
But remember, the map of the map had the first and the second.
The first will be the key.
And the second would be the value.
And the key here is a string.
But the value here is a set multisite.
So here, not the second will be our monkey set.
We iterate on it edge by edge.
But the two variants that with.
That's it.
So I hope overall it wasn't that annoying to at least understand.
I would like to stress here that how can we generalize the graphic representations?
Don't get too stuck into your mind that we have to do things in a very specific way.
Graph theory is all about nodes.
It just connected them in some way.
In some way.
OK, so let's see the second.
Um, the second homework, which is asking you for the reduction.
This is a very great and very important task.
Now the reduction is actually pretty simple.
So I asked you to, uh, map for me.
For example, California, Texas was Valley ten, maybe California was maybe New York.
Was 20 and so on.
The idea is, if I would like to use the normal adjacency, less the normal adjacency, this is expecting
integers, not strings.
What if we just to give a string idea forever, forever, forever string.
So you seek a frontier, let's give it zero here and zero here.
You see Texas.
Give it one.
You see New York.
Give it to you.
See, after Hawaii, New York to Texas.
Seventy.
OK, so New York is limited already to Texas.
We made it already one.
And that's it.
So it's actually was trivial idea.
Like instead of building a complete graph based on strings, just convert every string to some internal
idea and use it.
That's that simple idea.
I remember into Gear, a very useful utility that I used a lot in competitive programming.
This utility has emerged from a string to integer and another map from integer two string.
By the way, we can use it, we can use an order, the Mab, which is a stable.
It would be more efficient because this could now is look.
And if you'd like to make it over, just use an order map now and the function is working as following.
Every time you give it to string it, ask us if we have this string before or not.
If it is an old one, it returned its ID.
If it is a new one, it would give it new ID, for example.
Let's see.
Let's say we have at the moment, California was index zero and Texas with Index two index one, they
would be always zero one two sequential.
So now let's say you ask it for the get idea of Texas.
It would say, does it string two ID has a Texas yes return, it said.
If the answer is no, well, first get the size.
What is the current size of the hash table or the table two?
We call it ID here.
No stranger to idea of is t are equal IDs who are mapping now.
Let's say we are asking for New York.
So New York would be two.
So I'm adding New York to two and also adding that two is for New York.
So it is a two way mapping.
And then I'm returning the ID.
Uh, there is implementation bug here that happens inside C++.
I would like to tell it about you.
Some people would do the following there are two I.D. office.
They are equal.
They are two I.D. dot size.
In other words, he will try to merge these two lines together.
This will cause a problem.
This will cause a problem because this is getting an information about the star and this one is updating
it.
So it depends on the internal implementation.
This might cause a problem.
So the best thing is get the idea first and then of it to avoid this potential mistake that might be
based on the implementation.
The Guinness Star idea is just taking the idea and returning the corresponding string.
So now let's see the implementation, which is if you if you look to here, this is just the normal
adjacency list.
I did nothing here.
No changes.
Now here you read from two anchors a Mab, the from to the from index.
I met the two to two endings and a direct which so you see this, this couple of flurries of good reduced.
The domain of the Airbus to.
The standard.
Algorithms now, if you have an algorithm to do shortlist to birth, if you have an algorithm to do
a minimum spanning three algorithm to do strongly connected component, if you have an algorithm to
do blah blah blah, we can use them directly now.
This algorithm doesn't know what its airport does in know.
What is a flight cost?
No, nothing.
It just know about at a standard digital presentation.
I hope you get the message behind this algorithm.
This homework?