In this section, we will learn something about the class diagram.
This isn't a coding section, but it is an important section. Let's motivate it.
If you would like to represent some task, how would you communicate it to someone in the team or to some
manager or so?
There are some different ways for that. The first way is to write a text that represent it, something that
we call like function requirements.
What exactly the system is going to do for an online shopping system.
Another way is just to code it.
If you provide a code to another developer, he reads it and understands what is a purpose.
There is a third way to draw a diagram that represents some information.
Looking at this diagram seems we have things that look like boxes,
there are arrows between boxes,
there are numbers on the edges,
there are names here like customer user status, shopping cart, account, looks like classes names,
and this is what is called
a class diagram.
A class diagram eventually represents relationships.
So we use something named UML for a unified modeling language.
It is a standardized modeling language.
So it's language,
So we communicate with each other with it.
It is also standardized like we have some agreement between each other on what kind of notations to
use to express what we need.
It has many purposes.
One of the most important to them is the visualization purposes.
Imagine that you have a big system, and it is actually three subsystems.
Each subsystem has like 10 components, and each component has 100 classes.
Now, with such a very big project, we can communicate it definitely in a document, but we
can also use diagrams to visualize it from some perspectives.
There are many UML diagram types, and we are going to focus on the class diagram, which is one of the
most important among them.
So remember that we can represent, say, a book as follows:
We have a private section, we have a public section,
we have variables here, methods, here also variables, and some function.
A class diagram for a single class is as simple as you have a bounding box.
It could have only a single name, like just a book,
or you can go in more details.
The above section is four variables,
the blow section is four methods and functions.
If it is minus, it means a private.
If it is plus, it means public.
OK, so let's see here
the naming. I'm seeing here total quantity, colon, integer. Here,
we saying integer total quantity.
So as you see, there is some rephrasing.
We say here ID, colon, an integer.
We see here integer ID.
OK, we see also here some plus num integer.
This is a public variable, and also we see it equals zero.
So this is an equal zero variable,
this is an initialization. In a similar way, a method,
its function starts first, then parameters are defined in the same style as here, and then some
return type after the colon.
So to string colon string is a function that is public and returns a string.
So the interesting word here is a class in C++ has a private section for variables and methods and a public section for
variables and methods,
but here we have a section for variables and another section for full functionality.
This is mainly how is a diagram for a single class.
There are actually many other types of diagrams.
So we just here in the class diagram, which is of a structural type, there are also other behavioral
diagrams.
For tools, there are many tools that I have tried during my career, I tried nowadays this online web
tool for the course, and I found it very nice and very easy to use.
That's it for today.