Classes relationships, we definitely have in our system too many classes, and these classes have some
relationships among them. There are four types of relationships.
The first type of relationships are normal relationships, just like, say, user and a book, and the relationship
in the systems that the user is going to borrow a book.
So they are two different entities,
but it happened that there is some connection between them, user and an item in his shopping
cart, and so on.
There are also other two types of relationships that follow what we call the has a_pattern.
It's like the following: the department has employees, the car has an engine, the university has departments.
When you think about the semantic, it has this has thing.
So typically if we said a car has an engine, you can think of the car as a whole and the engine as a part.
So it is like a whole-part relationship.
OK, so what's the difference between aggregation and composition?
Both of them are has function.
Composition is a strong relationship,
aggregation is a weaker.
What does it mean?
It means the following: Let's say here in the composition, it means a strong relationship.
Let's say that the university got closed.
What would happen to the departments?
They will also get closed.
There is no meaning for a department without its university.
If there is a car, we know it has an engine, and we know that this engine belonged to this specific
car,
and if the car got destroyed for a reason or other in a crash, then the engine doesn't have a meaning.
So the relationship is very strong between both of them.
On the other side, for the aggregation, the relationship is a bit weaker.
So department has employees,
there could be even employees that don't belong to departments,
and if the department got closed, the employees are still there.
So although there is some whole-part relationship, it is of a weak type, then the generalization or
inheritance is a complete topic that we will discuss in OOP,
It is of the is a relationship.
We say that circle is a shape, a bicycle is a vehicle, and so on.
So there is like is a relationship.
You feel it like a parent-child relationship like a circle is a shape,
rectangle is a shape,
triangle is a shape,
It seems like shape is something generic, something general, and there are many types of it.
As you see, composition here is very tight.
Aggregation is less weak, the association is less and less weak.
If the relationship is an aggregation or composition nor generalization, then it's typically just normal
relationship, or even there might be no relationship. In the next
videos, we will discuss more of these relationships types.
That's it.