Let's discuss a little more details about the composition relationship.
As we said, a composition relationship is has a relationship between a whole and a part, so the car has
an engine, thinking about the car, it is composed of too many components.
More importantly, thinking about the relationship of the engine to the car, to what degree it is a
stronger relationship.
The engine has no value to be used independently,
and if a car got destroyed for a reason or another, then this part has no value.
The same for car's wheels.
Another example might be a room.
A room has walls and floors,
but these walls and floor has no value without a room.
If we mentioned to the room, they are definitely existing. if got destroyed, then they are also destroyed
semantically or practically.
In terms of code, you would decide
here you would build a class engine, then you build the class wheel, and then a class car would have an engine
object and wheel object.
This isn't the first time that you see actually this composition.
You were doing it.
When we do a class employee that has an object of type full name,
this is a composition
relationship. As we said, it's a strong relationship.
Let's say
what might this imply in terms of coding, this kind of strong ownership?
First of all, the whole typically creates or destroys the parts,
for example, the car would be the one that creates an engine and creates a wheel, and use it.
Also about is used only by the whole, so the engine will not be shared between two cars.
In addition, the part has no life of itself,
it is attached to the life of the whole object. Semantically, if a university is closed, not departments anymore.
So composition is very critical in OOP because it allows reusability.
Reusability refers to the ability to reuse something over and over.
For example, here the engine.
If it's a class, we are reusing it.
So instead of writing our own logic for a car from scratch, we can reuse something.
If we have an object of full name, we can reuse it inside, say class like an employee.
In terms of UML, reading here, here is a car and has doors an engine.
This black diamond represent the composition.
You find it typically at the whole part,
so it means that the car is composed of doors, the car is composed of an engine.
You can also read the relationship in the reverse
like engine belongs to a car,
doors belongs to a car, and so on.
That's it.