Let's learn more about the aggregation relationship. So the aggregation relationship is a weak
relationship, and there is no ownership in the relationship.
This means that the whole doesn't own the part like in the composition the car owned the engine,
...
It's own one,
here it doesn't exist.
Let's say that the department has some professors.
If the department is shut down, they are still professors, they still exist.
So in this set o terms of code, the whole class or some other class can create the part
object,
and if the whole object is destroyed, the part may still be in use by others.
This is a critical difference in semantics and in coding style.
So you can think here, this empty diamond is how we express aggregation.
This means a magazine is composed of articles, but the article can exist even without being at all
like being specific to a specific magazine,
and so on. So this is mainly what the aggregation relationship means.