The generalization relationship is a relationship. When you figure out that there is some is a relationship,
you know there is some generalization or inheritance.
So we say that student is a person,
teacher is a person, dean is a person.
So this is a relationship.
The is-a has an implication.
It implies that there are some common variables and functions that should exist between a student, teacher, and dean,
and also there should be some unique variables and functions for every one of them.
For example, you can think that all of these people would have a name, all of them would have an email,
all of them would have an address.
So this is what's common between them.
You can think, for example, the student has a GPA, but the dean has a salary,
and so on. Circle is a shape,
rectangle is a shape, triangle is a shape.
We need to draw all of them,
We need to compute the area for all of them,
but the rectangle area computation is different from the circle area computation.
The software engineer is an employee, the manager is an employee, also office boy
is an employee. Although there would be some common features between them, there would be definitely
different variables and functions for everyone,
and so on. Apple is a fruit, orange is a fruit of food, watermelon is a fruit. Bicycle, motor, vehicle, and railed vehicle
are all of them a vehicle, and so on.
In terms of UML, we use this empty triangle. So let's say we are in a bank, modeling a bank,
then we can have a checking account, savings account, credit account,
but all of them are eventually accounts,  there should be something common between them.
Here is a bigger hierarchy where we have a mammal is as an animal, and also we have a horse as a mammal.
So you see the relationship can get bigger.
Let's see an example we were building the composition with the generalization.
We have a vehicle which could be water or road,
the road vehicle could be bicycle or a car,
the car is composed of an engine and of four wheels.
This how UML might start to grow up with different relationships. That's it.