Another important thing about class diagrams is multiplicity, which is all about numbers.
Let's say that we have a visitor center, then this visitor center would have a lobby and would have
a bathroom.
The relationship is clearly a composition, so the lobby would belong to a specific visitor center,
the bathroom belongs to a specific visitor center or a specific building,
but the question here is how many lobbies exist in the visitor center?
How many bathrooms exist in visitor center?
This is the multiplicity.
It specify what we call in databases
cardinality. In general, it is just number of elements.
We would think, let's say we're designing based on the requirements and each center will have only
one lobby, but it will have at least one bathroom.
OK, so multiplicity come to express that as following:
you see here this one, you will read it as following: visitor center is composed of only one lobby.
However, you see here the one asterisk. One asterisk means one or more.
So this is like a visitor center is composed of one or more bathrooms.
If you know the exact number, say four bathrooms, you can say four bathrooms.
If it is a range like 2 to 4 bathrooms, you write here two, dash, 4 bathrooms.
So multiplicity starts to communicate this counting over the relationships.
There are different ways to write multiplicities.
I would like you to read them very well.
So if we wrote, for example, five colon-colon five or just five, it means that there are exactly
five instances. M-N or some specific numbers mean there is some range here
like say 5 to 10 within 5 to 10.
Zero asterisk means zero or more, zero-one means no instances or one instance.
Let's go back to the associations.
There is also one interesting meaning here.
There are three types of associations.
One to one, one to many, many to one. In a one-to-one relationship,
there is only one type of this class with this one type of this class.
Let's say that you have a class for a citizen and a class for a national ID.
Each citizen has only a single one ID. On the other side,
let's say there is a car and wheels. We know that car
one car has 4 wheels, so it is one to many relationship.
A customer has, say, three bank accounts. Many to many, it could be like the student has courses and
each course has students.
When we come to code it, you will notice that there is a vector here for courses, a vector here for students, and
there is some common usage between the courses, for example, here and here. That's it.