Let's put the relationships and multiplicity together. Thinking about this diagram,
we have a university that is composed of departments, and the department is aggregated of professors.
Sorry, the department is aggregated of professors.
The logic here is if the university got closed, there is no meaning for a department without the university,
but if some departments got closed, professors will remain professors.
So that's why this aggregation,
but this is a composition.
By the way, we can read always the relationship in the two directions
as I said before like the university has departments, or a department belongs to a single
university, and so on.
So now thinking about the multiplicity. Now, the department would belong to a single university.
Right?
You see here the one
so there is a consistency here that you should take in mind.
If you said that this is a composition relationship, and you said here that this is zero, for example,
this is contradiction.
If you said it is a composition, it means that these belong only to this university.
That's why typically you will find a one as a multiplicity in terms of the composition.
In a similar logic,
if you said that this is aggregation, it means a professor may not belong to a department.
So this means that it should have zero.
So as a rule, you typically put one beside a black diamond, and there is typically some zero beside
the empty diamond.
So consistency is important.
Here is a bigger example of a shopping cart example. We have here a user,
there are two types of user,
administrator is a user, customer is a user.
So this is inheritance relationship.
Here we have the common features and variables, and we have the non-common features and variables.
You see that the customer has a shopping cart, and there is an aggregation, so you see here the composition
has one, a composition has one, a composition has one, a composition has one.
This is consistent diagram.
The customer also would have a single order.
Each order might belong to a specific customer,
each customer may have zero or more orders,
each order has also exactly one shipping information.
This is one to one relationship, and this is one to one relationship.
OK, this is one to many relationship.
Yeah, These are a bunch of examples. I would like you to think about them in terms of relationships
and multiplicity. Thinking between student and course, the student registers in a course,
So this is many to many relationship.
This means that a student registered in many courses, and the course attended by many students. Think about
the following in a similar logic.
Customer, bank account, savings account, checking account.
What is the relationship?
Let's say we are modeling a parking lot.
We have a vehicle, car, seat, engine, door, driver, passenger, gasoline, garage.
Let's say that these are a bunch of classes in our system.
What is a relationship? If we have a google form of question and answer and options, how to model it?
The computer,
its cpu,
its motherboard, cache, memory, relationships.  Project, project manager, and so on.
Just think of them as an exercise for you. That's it.