One of the critical concerns about UML is how to use it in practice? Sadly, typically courses academic
or online, doesn't stress on the quality of UML.
So in this video, I would like to highlight for you five different tips on UML so that you can
generate a good UML.
The first one is less is more.
When we say by less is more, read this diagram. It seems someone wanted to communicate a lot of information,
but when you give a diagram like that to someone to read it and understand it, you just get bothered
and maybe get 10 percent of it.
So although you provided a lot, actually people got less.
You know, this is like explaining courses.
If you explained to someone a lot in the beginning, they just get confused, and they get much less of
what they learned.
So don't provide such a diagram, but think in the priorities.
Think about what is really the important information to communicate.
So UML diagrams and class diagrams aren't about communicating every single piece of information.
It's about communicating the big picture, the core items, the core features.
OK, so feel free to drop something that makes your diagram complicated or ugly and so on.
The second rule is crossings.
When you start to cross arrows this way, either you are using a lot of relationships and classes,
or you need to think in a better way to arrange diagrams. When diagrams are this way without crossing
so that every line here almost is by itself,
this is a much readable diagram.
So, minimize the crossings as much as you could. A third rule is an orthogonality.
Orthogonality makes your UML looks very good. Orthogonal means 90 degrees percent
between a couple of arrows here.
So you see this arrows have different angles.
It looks ugly really,
but on the other side, this one was 90 degrees arrow in the relationships. It looks like much more
readable.
I would like you to think about how others are receiving my work, OK. A fourth note is about inheritance.
Remember, inheritance means like a circle is a shape, a rectangle is a shape,
so the shape we call it a parent class. This class has here some parent class, but
they loo down.
The semantics of a parent or this shape class is that it is a higher logic than the circle and the rectangle.
So a better way is to put this inheritance relationship to go up.
So this is an arrow inheritance going up, arrow inheritance going up.
Generally speaking, don't provide things that look ugly for the people.
Consider alignments, for example.
Make sure that it looks like a good UML diagram.
The last thing to say about UML is about how software engineers receive it in the industry.
Some companies never or rarely use UML.
They just use whiteboard,
and as a team, you brain storm, you draw on a board.
Maybe you take some pictures of what you draw, and that is it.
There is a problem typically they face when there is a newcomer, they don't have material to provide
for him.
So the workaround is someone to explain with him some high-level explantation and then they do some code
deep dive together.
This is one thing. Typically in many small projects, like something that takes three to six months from
a team, there are no diagrams. We can just keep information inside our mind,
and it isn't that big.
In big projects, we typically start to create high-level diagrams.
We focused on the class diagram, and we highlighted the rule less is more.
There are many diagrams in UML, but the other three critical ones, if you would like to prioritize,
are the sequence, state, and activity diagrams.
These four are the most common in industry.
There is something in software engineering named agile.
Agile is an iterative process to implement your projects like this course,
I explain it in an iterative way.
The problem with Agile is that UML diagrams that we build early become wrong in the end and outdated,
so they typically would have problems with that.
If I would like to give you a tip, I would say learn UML, learned annotations, but think twice before
creating a diagram,
and if you decided to create a diagram, focus on the high level of the diagram. In the future,
you might read this things.
That's it.