Many students complained about the design skills, and how to improve them, so I would like to share with
you a tip from my personal experience.
First of all, remember something skills takes time.
There is no course that teaches you skills, the only way to teach in courses is knowledge.
So how to gain skills? Through practice.
That's why this course emphasizes a lot of homework and projects.
So don't feel bad if you cannot design your project from the first step.
This is very natural and very normal.
Remember, for example, the class diagram.
The class diagram helps you to see the big picture.
One way to improve the design skills and seeing the big picture and all of the details is as follows:
Before coding anything, you start to sketch your initial UML diagram.
This means you think about the potential class diagrams, the relationships between them, the multiplicity
between them, and some of the major features like variables and functions, and so on.
Once you're done with that, start coding your system.
There is a common observation here.
You will notice there are a lot that is missing, critical variables, and functions.
You will notice also some classes were wrong, some relationships were wrong, or some multiplicity was wrong.
This is OK.
Once you are done with your project, redraw your final UML diagram.
Start to compare your initial diagram with your final diagram.
Ask yourself why I missed this thing, why I missed this class, and through the answer of why, you will
notice what got wrong in your thinking process. Iteratively, you will learn from your mistakes this
way, and you will realize that you became a good designer
when you bridge the gap between your first and last diagram. You will never have your first diagram
like your last diagram,
but what is a gap between them?
If it is a small gap, then you became a good designer and have good design skills. That it.