In this section, we are going to learn one of the fundamental methods that we use in industry to handle
big projects, which involved really what we call header and includes that you were using before
already.
So let's think about this
code. You have here a function that would like to do summation from 1 to n.
So we mainly sum from zero to N-1.
Anyway, this is a coding mistake,
and then here in the cout, we say cout square root 25, which is something we use it in
C math,
and also we define a vector here, which is coming from here, and we are calling our function here.
So thinking back about these three hash includes, the IO stream for the cout, this one for this code,
this one for the vector.
The moral of the hash includes if you remember that this includes has already a code that is implemented
and ready for you to use.
So instead of you as a user would go, write out, and compute this sqrt function, or implemented a vector data structure
by yourself, you are using existing code.
So this is mainly what hash includes means, and now we have a function here that is doing some operation,
and we have a question here like — let's say that this is a very common utility,
Can we make this function available for others?
Like — can others just somehow hash include something then it would involve
my code here then everyone is using it instead of rewriting it?
So how can we make it easier for our teams to do such a track?
This is amends through something we call a header
file.
We will start to create multiple files where these files include our code content, and then we let
others to just hash include that. In any IDE, you can create just a new file. In eclipse,
If you did that, you can right-click and select a new then header file.
If you did that, some auto-generated code is going to be generated for you.
But if it isn't, you just need to create a new file.
We typically give it an extension of dot-h, sometimes dot-hpp. So just go ahead
with whatever,
and then create your file. Once you code that, you asked for the name and just use this dot-h. In C++,
you can go more complex and can have some templates for this file, but anyway let's make it simpler
for now. For seeing more,
the first thing is you get here the sum dot-h file.
So we now wrote our code here.
Now going to our main file, the first thing we are going to do is we are going to add hash include
sum dot-h, and then notice here we are calling the function.
Now, this function isn't implemented in our main dot-cpp here,
It is implemented in a different file.
So someone from our team can simply just go and hash include that here.
I would like you to notice two observations here.
First, we are using here two double quotes, but less than and greater than.
So when we add our own ones, we use double quotes, the less than and greater than are for the official system.
The second thing is, if you tried to hash include IO stream more than once, there will be no problem,
but if you tried to hash include this sum dot-h twice, the program is going to give you an error until
you redefinition of integer sum of int. What happens? I would like to think of
sum hash include as following: every time the C++ find you are hash including something, it just to go and
copy the whole content as it is and put it here.
So when you say hash include sum dot-h, it's going to copy this code and put it here. If it is another
sum dot-h, it go to copy it and put it here.
So now you have two functions with the same name.
That's why you get the error or redefinition.
Redefinition means this thing (a variable or a function) exists twice.
So now, there is a methodology technique in C++ that helps you to avoid this problem.
It's as following:
If you are in eclipse, you will find an auto-generated three lines for you.
This line and this line and this line here. These lines we call them in C++ include guards,
You don't need to understand them,
You can just write them as they are. Pick
any keyword of your interest. Let's say here it's SUM, then we are using the word sum dot underscore-h
...
It should be a variable name like in C++, for example,
It cannot start with a digit, it cannot have spaces,
just any variable name,
and use it here once and use it here another,
and then in between, you write your own code, and then you write this statement again.
This way, the C++ compiler would add this function only once, only the first time, and we will not add it
again.
So there
Will be no multiple redefinition.
In case you would like to understand what does this means, just would like to give you some informal idea.
This is an if condition, but written in a way named macros directives.
So this is an if and this is the end of this if condition,
and this is the hash defined for this variable. The logic is as follows: the C++ compiler is saying if
not defined sum underscore H, if this variable never used, hash defined it (add it) then add your logic,
then end it.
So this is traced twice. In the first time, it says is this variable defined?
No.
OK, define it,
get this code, end the if condition. In the second time, is this variable defined?
Yes, then it goes out the if condition. In the third time,
is this variable defined?
Yes, go out of the if condition and so on.
So anyway, the moral of that is you need to add these two lines and this one in here,
and this word should be unique per the project,
and this three lines are auto-generated by eclipse.
That's it for now.