In this video, we're going to learn one more standard feature in the industry. So far,
we learned to have two files in our project.
One of them, let's call it the main dot cpp, and another one is sum dot-h.
When we defined sum code in sum dot-h, we just hang hash include in the main dot-cpp.
Now imagine the following:
Our current implementation is slow, so we sum from one to n.
What if we would like later to provide sum faster version?
What if we like to provide something that fixes bugs and so on.
Let's say that we have an implementation for Windows implementation, for ubuntu, for Mac, for reading
something from the hard disk and so on.
So C++ allow one more
very interesting feature.
It now creates a new dot-cpp file to have the implementation of sum dot-h.
So we actually now have a new file, but it is of the type source file (In your IDE like Eclipse or other,
you can just create a source file or something that you name dot-cpp.
So here is what you have. Now you are going to have three files.
The first one is the main file, like the first time you hash include the sum dot-h and you are going
to call it.
That's it,
like we did.
The second one is the sum dot-h file,
but notice here we are declaring only the function not defining it.
So when we say a declaration of a function, we just mean the function return, name, parameter and
then semicolon without the details of it. When we say a function definition, we actually mean
the whole function.
So now what is the difference between that one and that one?
This way here, the declaration, it's focusing on the what, not the how.
What does this mean?
This function,
what is it?
Just some function doing summation from 1 to n.How is it done?
We don't know.
Is it just the summation from zero to n-1.
Is it an equation,
just multiply
n items plus one over two? we don't know.
So when we separate this declaration from the implementation, or the declaration
from the definition, we have one file that's focusing on the what and another file that's focusing on the
how.
Now this dot-cpp file, do I care here how this function is implemented?
I don't care.
Have you ever cared about how the square root function is implemented or how the vector of
integer is implemented?
You never care, you care about the what.
Guys, I would like a function that sum from one to N, and this one is about the how. It's now slow.
Maybe in the future, we faster one or someone that is bug-free and so on. We don't care.
So anyway, the moral of that we now have three files. The dot-h file and two dot-cpp files. What is a cpp file?
(which are we are calling here sum-slow dot-cpp) Just has a definition of this declaration.
And another fun, which is our main dot-cpp, has one main function.
Remember, in C++ when you have one compilation unit, you have to have only one function that is named
main.
So this file, although it's dot-cpp, it doesn't have any main function. In practice,
we also call the declaration the interface.
That's why they call it separting interface from implementation.
Think of the word interface like — let's say you are seeing a building, then you are seeing the interface
of the building.
You see, oh, this building is like ten floors and it has windows of this style. You don't see...
... how the building is designed from the internal,
you just see the external thing. When you are visiting
an atm machine, you see the interface of the machine.
You see a button to enter the password,
a button to cancel, you see the interface.
You don't know how the ATM machine is implemented.
That's what we called interface and implementation.
So the moral of that, we are going one more step in dividing things.
So in reality, this hash includes sum dot-h is referring to this sum dot-h,
and the compiler is going to relate the sum dot-h with this dot-cpp file. In the future,
If the company decided to remove this file and replace it with a faster one, file number one main dot cpp
doesn't change.
File number 2 sum-dot-h doesn't change.
Only this file is changed, and this is very important and useful in reality.
One more interesting thing here to know is about the global variables across files. At this
moment,
you see one dot h and one dot cpp. In reality,
you can have like 10 files dot h and 10 dot cpp files.
So we have in total like one plus all of these files that we have.
There is one interesting thing here is: can I have one global variable that is visible from all the files?
C++ do that through the extern feature.
The process is as following: you first declare a variable
in the header file with extern (The header file the one with dot h) then you define it in sum dot cpp typically to
the corresponding to the dot h then uses it whatever the hash included exist.
So here is what happens: the first thing you are declaring the variable,
(This is the sum dot h) you say extern integer total calls. Notice,
this is just a declaration(a declaration for a variable meaning it doesn't have equal and some initialization
variable.)
Now in sum-dot-cpp, let's say here sum dot h the corresponding sum dot cpp, then we are
here defining the variable.
Now, this total calls variable is used here because hash include sum dot h, it is also visible
in the main.
So we have here a main that has sum dot h,
It called our function three times,
and this is a number of total calls.
So with every call to this function, this call variable is going to increase.
So we are doing three calls.
So we expect this variable to be incremented three times.
You see here with every call, the variable can be updated.
We are incrementing here in the main, the variable, and then we are giving calls again.
You see, again, the same variable is incrementing again.
So this variable, total calls, is visible and we can change and affect it from the main dot cpp, from the
sum dot cpp.
The moral of that is you want a variable that is visible from any file that does hash include, do the following:
declare it here with extern, do not initialize it, initialize it in the dot cpp and start to
use it.
Who can see this variable?
Who ever have the sum dot h?
I would like also to know something about this file.
What is really visible for him is only this file, not this file.
So when we defined things here,
they are invisible here.
OK, so this is something very important, and that's why we separated the implementation from the declaration.
So the main dot cpp know only about sum dot h, it doesn't know about what's happening in
sum dot cpp.
Just the compiler is doing the linking.
All what you know is you have sum total calls variable that will have some value in the future.
You have sum function, sum-underscore-one which will have some implementation in the future.
What are the other details here?
We don't know. If this file, sum-dot-cpp has extra functions here, sum-dot-h doesn't see them, the
main-dot-cpp doesn't see them.
So again, and remember, the main-dot-cpp see only what is in sum-dot-h, it doesn't see
more details here,
and this takes us to some interesting comparison between the external, static, and global
things.
So here is the point because there are different cases.
The first case is defining the extern variable.
This is just what we did
right now. if you defined a header in the header variable and extern variable, and you defined later
in sum-dot-cpp with every hash include for sum-dot-h, for example, the same variable would be visible
and used.
Now, notice the following: if you decided in the header file to create the variable as a static not
as extern with every hash includes to sum-dot-h, there are a different copy of it would be used.
Now, this is very confusing and useless, so we don't use that in the industry.
I'm just telling you that you can have a static variable in the header variable, but don't use it.
OK, it just very confusing and really very useless.
The other two cases is following:
You are defining a variable in the dot-cpp file,
but it is neither external nor static, OK?
It just exists in the dot-cpp function and you are defining it definitely out of function. If it's inside
the function, it just local variable.
There are two cases:
The first case is you are defining it like integer
some global equals zero.
This means what?  this something we have file scope.
What does it mean to be file scope?
File scope means it is visible in this file. Definitely
if you defined it in line hundred, then it's visible from line hundred till the end of the file.
However, there is a point here.
There is no other cpp file that can have the same variable name.
So for example, let's say you have a file named sum-dot-cpp  and file named hello-dot-cpp, and defined
integer some-global equals zero in sum-dot-cpp.
You cannot in the hello-dot-cpp define a variable globally named integer
some global equals zero.
C++ will give you a compiler error, and say multiple redefinition error.
OK, think of them as if they are in one big file.
You are defining the same variable twice.
Do not use that.
This is bad again,
don't use that.
What we use is actually what we call a static integer
some global view.
This is the same as the above one,
it has a file scope,
it is visible in this file,
However, other files can use the same name in the dot-cpp.
So if someone defined here static integer global, someone in another file (let's say hello-dot-cpp)
can define also integer some-global.
So this is has a very great advantage.
Your friends while they are defining their own global variable and this
is a bad thing, but in case they are doing it, they will not get compiler errors because of you
are defining some variables. So the moral of that is as following:
I'm telling you two bad things to not do, but what you can do is as following:
You either are defining a global variable that is visible everywhere.
In this case, you define it in the header with extern, declare in the header with extern, and define
it in the dot-cpp file.
The second case is I would like a local variable per my file. In this case, you define it as a static
integer some-global. So you can use it in your file, and your friends can define in the team
other dot-cpp files and both global names
without caring that you used this variable name.
I have attached some code for this point.
Feel free to to check it in case you would like. That's it.