Let's see how eclipse can help us to create a header file. You can come here, right-click new, and then
you see header file and let's give it a name, for example, calculator
dot h. In the future, you can learn how to configure the style of the header file, but
for now, let's go the default and we say finish. You notice here
it created directly for you the file that you want.
If you would like to create
It's cpp version,
you just come here and say new source file, and give it a name, let's say calculator
dot cpp,
and then it is going to create for you a cpp. If you'd like to remove them, in C++
this is very easy.
Just right here
come on and delete and that's it.