In this video, you will learn how to create header files in cookbooks. So we go file, new,
and select file. It gives you choices,
do you want create a header file or a source file.
So let's start with the header file.
We say go. Next,
It asks you what is the full path. Open,
It would be the project.
Let's call it calculator dot h, enter. You see here
this will be the guard name.
It asks you would to add it. add it in both of them and then finish.
You will notice a header file created for you with some initial guard and you will notice it exists
here.
You can also come here and again create some source file for it.
So you see files, go with source, go next, and C++.
Let's give it a name.
Let's say calculator dot cpp, save, add for both of them, finish, and then it appeared here.
If you're right click to go to the project itself.
Yeah, open project in the file browser.
This is now what is in the browser itself.
Remember, if you would like to remove them, remove them first from here, it will remove them completely
from the hard disk, then, yes remove from the active project.
Sorry, yeah, we need to close them also.
No.
It doesn't exist anymore and come back to the project.
You come here and here and say remove. Now you also removed them from the project.
Remove.
That's it.