So far, we learned how to make separation when it comes to a function, how to declare and define, and today we will learn about the struct.
So let's say we have a simple employee class here that have some name and two things, a constructor
and a function.
So the current style is the old style
where you declare and define in one single file.
So all of that in a single main dot cpp file.
Now, I would like to see how that could be separated in a different way.
Let's do it in two steps.
The first thing is let's ( per our single main file) see how we can separate the interface from the implementation.
we have here the struct employee and for every function inside it, for every member function,
you just add here a semicolon instead of the braces to define the function.
This is now what we call an interface of an employee class.
What does this mean?
It means that there is something that is named as an employee class.
It has a constructor of string name and it has a print function.
How was it implemented?
No one care.
So the declaration here is focusing on the what not the how. Now, here we have two functions that are defining
the how.
Now, look to the following:
here is the function name of the constructor and the body of it, and here is
the print function with the body of it.
The extra way to relate in C++
the definition to the declaration of a struct is using the following:
You use the same class name with colon colon.
It's called a scope resolution operator, I guess,
then you put whatever you have.
So for every function or every variable, if you would like to access it from outside,
all what you have to is to use here employee colon-colon and anything.
So here is a void function print,
you come here before the function name and use it.
If you would like to refer to the variable name here outside, you can say employee colon-colon name and
so on.
So the way that we separate the class is mainly you declare it, which means you replace the body with
just a semicolon.
You start to define it outside it, but you use the employee colon-colon or the class name colon-colon to refer to the
implementation of a specific function for a class.
So far, again, we are one dot cpp file.
So let's go one more step.
Here is how you split them into three files. let's define a header file, we will name it employee
dot h. Notice here in lines one and two and the last line 18, we have the include guard,
and then we have here the declaration, as we saw in the past.
We don't need to the hash include IO stream here, by the way.
You don't need them.
Now, let's go to the employee dot cpp.
It will start with hash including employee dot h, and then it's going to copy-paste here the two
functions as we did before.
I would like you to notice two things here.
The first is this function is doing cout so this class doesn't know what is cout. Remember,
the purpose of hash includes is to add something.
So here, if you noticed, I put the hash include in the header file, and this guy is doing hash include dot h,
and remember when the compiler sees hash include dot h, it just goes and copy-pastes this code here.
So what happened in reality actually it's one step before the compiler
as we will know. Once we see the hash include, then it just removes this line number two and just go-ahead
and copy the content from line 4 to line 17 and just copy and paste it here.
So thinking about that, what happened is as following: this file here has hash include IO stream
in std.
So all of that is being copy-pasted and be put here, then this cout is actually seeing this hash include IO stream.
...
If you tried to remove line 4 and line 5 from the header, this code is going to compile an error.
OK, then because it doesn't see cout anymore. To have it in a more proper way,
the right way isn't to have the hash included in the header here because this class doesn't need
them.
So doesn't create this hash include IO stream.
You don't need to put it here,
you better move it to here,
but there would be another compilation error in the header.
It will not know what is a string.
...
The string is visible still from the IO stream specifically from the std.
Anyway, this is just for now.
We'll talk about the namespace later.
One extra thing that I would like to show you is I defined an extern variable also here.
This is just for sake of showing you the global variable again.
...
I'm defining it as a pointer.
I'm saying extern employee pointer employee,
and here I'm starting to define the extern varilabe.
I'm just showing you here to see how I can define extern from a class,
and even with the pointer. Just simple as you declare it here and then you define it here.
That's it.