In this video, we will learn about something named forward declaration C++, which help us to solve a
specific problem.
Let's say that we have a company that has departments. Each department has a set of employees and
the employee can be shared between different departments so also employee has
set of departments.
Now, here's the issue.
The employee needs department and department employees and so on.
In other words, let's say we would like to separate that into two different header files.
So you define the employee dot h,
and start to say, hey, I need to see the department dot h, and I am to be a vector of
departments, for example.
Now with the other side, the department also says, I need employee dot h, and I have a vector of employees.
Now, here's what happened.
Here the employee dot h needs department. we go to department dot h, it says, no, no,
no, I need employee dot h.
We go back to the employee dot h.
No, I need department-dot-h. You see here, this is a circular relationship.
Remember, we said how in C++ sees the hash includes, it just go and copy-paste this content, but before it caused that if it sees another
hash include, it is going to get the content first.
So I need your content and you need my content, but I need your content.
This is a circular relationship.
So this is going to make a problem in your implementation, so you cannot define such a circular relationship,
then
here is a solution.
The solution is what we call a forward declaration.
The forward declaration means we are just highlighting what is a potential declaration before the definition
itself.
When it comes to the struct, we can have two levels of declaration.
You can only say here like there is something named strcut department.
So we are declaring that. Guys, there will be some struct that is department. The second level of
declaration
when you define the struct with the function inside it, you declare them, but you do not define
the functions.
So here we are just one higher level.
Now, the moral of that is (remember in the previous class, the employee struct
has to hash include department dot h,
but now we have the struct department, we have it, then we don't need to hash include department,
because at the moment I know sometime in the future, there will be a department struct which
would have more implementation and more details.
This way I broke the cycle. At least the employee
doesn't need to have to hash include another file and the file needs to hash include me so we get rid of this cycle.
There is one problem here.
If you tried to compile your code, C++ will tell you invalid use of incomplete type.
What does this mean?
Is this struct department is a complete one?
No, what is complete?
Complete
it means that it's declaration or even an implementation
depends is really complete.
However, at this moment it isn't complete at all.
We even don't know the declaration of it, the full declaration of it.
We just declared its name.
So the C++ cannot have it this way.
There are two solutions for this problem.
The first one, which is a wrong solution, let's put the employee and department together
in the same class (their declarations together).
So here's is how it goes.
Notice here the employee needs department and the department needs employees.
So even in a single file, there is a cycle, but with a declaration for a declaration, we solve.
the problem as following: In line 12
we say there is something that would be named struct department, and you will know about that
very soon.
Now, the struct employee has a vector of departments, so it has no problem at the moment.
After some time, we say, but you know what?
the struct department is actually is this way, which is a vector of employee and employee is now defined. This
way,
the forward declaration at line 12 solved our problem,
but this is a bad idea.
Why?
The idea of full separation is very important in industry because it helps us to be very flexible
when it comes future code changes.
When we study the OOP, we will understand that very well.
Now, the way to print that is as following:
We do that using pointers.
I would like you to follow my code structure here very careful to avoid problems. The idea of
the pointers is that you don't need to know about the exact details at the moment.
You just need some pointer for it, which is just some address in the memory.
We don't care more about that at the moment.
So it goes as following:
You are going to declare one of the two classes that have a circular dependency in the very normal
way, just as very normal.
You just declare it and you hash include its dependency.
But the one that you are doing a forward declaration for it, you are using a pointer with it.
OK, so here is the structure.
The first class, let's say the department dot-h and department dot-cpp, you are going to declare
and define it in the very normal way.
This is implemented in the typical way. I decided that the department will go and see the employee and
the employee dot-h will not depend on me directly,
then in this case, I am very normal.
I have here the employee class and have here the definition.
Everything is good so far.
Now here is the tricky part.
The first thing is the employee dot-h is going to just has a forward declaration
of struct department.
Notice that in line 12 here,
I'm telling you that you do not include the department dot-h here.
If you did that, remember, we will have a cycle.
So instead of the normal hash include, we replaced it with line 13, the forward declaration.
...
Oh, sorry.
The critical information here is that in line 17, we don't have a vector of department, we
have a vector of department pointer.
This is a clue for that. The C++ is OK with referring to a pointer and we don't care about the
complete declaration at the moment.
Just pointer will be enough and then in your header file, your CPP file, you are just implementing your code
in the normal way, and you are doing the hash include for the department dot-h here.
There must be somewhere in both of these files that we need department dot-h because I need to see the
remainder of the declaration.
I need to do what I'm doing.
So notice here, I have a vector of department pointer.
I'm here in my function,
I'm calling department to print department.
If we don't see the hash include department dot-h, we never see the declaration, and we never know
what is the function that is available.
So we need it.
So the moral of that is in this file you forward declaration line number 13.
This is one step.
Step number two, the class that you depend on it in line 17 should be a pointer. Step number three
in line 4 here,
You hash include the file and then you code normally.
So these three lines are the trick to solve the problem that we said about it today.
Line 13, line 17, and line 4, using these extra three lines,
you solved the circle dependency that we saw.
That's it.