In this video, we would like to discuss two processes that happened behind the scenes. If you didn't
get some of the details of this video,
This is totally OK.
There is nothing about code today.
So the first thing is what we call a preprocessor.
You need to think, here my code.
We compile it, we got executable to use. This is OK, but there are actually more steps in between.
The first thing is your code, first of all, is going to be changed to a new code through something
called a preprocessor. The preprocessor reads your program,
and find anything
start with the hash.
If there is something like that, there is some preprocessing that happened first, and your code
is going to be changed, and then sent to the compiler.
If your code doesn't have anything that starts with hash, your code is going as it is to the compiler.
Once you compile your code, you generate something called object code (the dot-O file).
The linker is going to take all of the dot-O file to generate an executable.
So let's highlight
this little more.
When the compile find any line of code that starts with the hash, it needs to process it.
...
We call them preprocessor directives,
for example, the hash-include IO stream, the hash-include sum dot-h. Remember, we once said when the
compiler see the hash include sum dot-h, it is going to remove this line and copy all of the content of
this file in my file.
For example, if my main dot CPP file is a hundred lines of code and I'm copying sum dot-h
which is 5 lines of code, then your code would be 105 lines of code.
So the content of all of the IO stream is actually copied inside your code.
The content of all hash-include is going to be copied in your code. So this is what happens mainly when the compiler
see the hash.
Another one is the hash-tag defines, (remember here the include guard) the compiler when is doing the
copy-paste, it is going to decide to make a real copy if the content is never seen before.
If it's seen before, it will not be copied based on this hash defines.
In a third case, for example, you say hash-defined here table size.
We didn't see this case, it's a macro, let's delay for now.
Let's show you an example here.
I have a program dot-CPP, which is hash-include IO stream and also hash-include program-dot-h. The preprocessor will
take the three files and merge all of them in a single file.
So you see here the IO stream part here, the program-dot-h part is here,
and then here is your dot-CPP file.
Once your whole new file ready,
we send it to the compiler. Going little more in details,
your program, see here the program-dot h, is going to be removed from here, and its content would
be copied to here.
Now, interestingly, here there is another hash here in the program-dot-h, say hash-defined name
size 25.
This is a command for the preprocessor to replace every name size with the value
25.
So you see here we say cout name size, the compiler would replace every name size with 25.
So now this is your final code to be sent to the compiler.
This is a preprocessor.
Let me also highlight here something. If you tried to open your IO stream file,
OK, just open it,
You will notice the following:
The IO stream file has an interesting thing.
It has an object named cin of type  I_stream, an object of type O_stream cout.
The second thing is they are extern. Extern, as we learned, means that it is visible
in every file that is using this hash-include.
So it is one thing that answers your question why we never define this cin and cout and we still can use
them? because they are defined and declared in the IO stream,
and this means when you hash-include this file, these two lines would be copied in your code. This
way, they actually can be used because they are copied inside your code.
The second thing to discuss is the linker. Let's say that you have something
that's called main-dot-cpp and another file called add-dot-cpp.
Every file of them is going to be processed by the compiler independently.
So the main dot-cpp has to hash includes here, it would be reprocessed and compiled to give main-dot-O.
This add-dot-CPP will be compiled and give add-dot-O. The linker is a thing that is going to
mix all of them, link all of them, and gather all of them together to give you the executable.
The final executable
needs all of these guys together,
and the linker, as it's name say, is the one that's going to do all of this magic for you.
Now, there's an interesting thing here to discuss about real projects. Let's say you have two projects,
other two projects that have some files that you would like to include.
There is something interesting here.
When you do something like hash-include sum-dot-h, the compiler understands the following: that
there is a file named the sum-dot-h directly beside your file named main-dot-cpp.
Let's say that there is another file in the dot-dot, slash, more header, slash, my other header dot-h.
OK, this is a relative path.
It's confusing for you.
Just think of a complete path in your code.
Now, if you would like to include this header which is in a different path, there are two ways to
include it.
The first one is to use the path in your code, either relative like that or full.
So you say something like hash-include dot, dot, slash, more headers, slash, my other header dot_h in your
code. So the compiler understands that using this path he can find it starting from the main dot_cpp.
Or if you have something like mostafa, slash, header, bla, bla bla, or in Window, C, colon, same path. This is bad,
Why?
Because it's hard coding
the path in your file.
If we changed the location of this file, your code now doesn't compile.
the proper way is through adding your path something
we call include paths. Later when we learn compilation commands, it is done using something called dash_i.
For now, every IDE should support a way to add the path to your program.
Here is how we can do it
in Eclipse. You go to C++, building, settings, go to the g++ compiler, includes, and here you
find a section where you can add the path, as you see here, adding a couple of paths. In the future, you
would need also this menu linker to add libraries.
When we depend on libraries externally, we add them here in the library. For the guys in code
blocks.
...
Right-click on the project, select build options,
then you find here something called search directories,
and then you can add here the couple of lines here.
What does this two lines mean, here in code block?
It means please consider these paths, these directories, to find the extra header file that we are referring to it.
...
What will happen if you refer to a file that is invisible within the directory? It just going to give you a compiler error.
Here are some final notes.
In practice, projects just grew up.
So using headers with separation is a standard.
In practice, no one is just boating every single line of code in a single file.
We don't do that. If I'm doing that sometimes in the course, this is just for educational purposes,
but this isn't how we do it in practice.
Don't try to declare variables in the header, just only declare the extern for global values.
If you would like a file scope, as we discussed, use the static, ( static not stat )in a dot_cpp file.
One good thing also for the header files, use something like sum dot_h and sum dot_cpp, use the same name for
the two files.
There is one more extra information I would like to know.
We learned templates before. In templates, you cannot define and declare in two separate files.
You sadly have to make all of them in a header file.
This is a bit complicated.
You might start to read about it if you have interest.
Historically, you might ask why the file is named IO stream, hash-include IO stream not IO stream dot_h.
If you have interest, you might find here some reading about that. That's it.