In this video, we will learn about an interesting feature in C++ named namespaces.
Let's first motivated, let's say that we have a website and our team is developing it,
and we typically have something in the global scope, like let's say we define something like integer total_users.
...
We have a struct named user, a function named integer read choice, and so on.
So far, so good.
After some time, we wanted to download an open-source library. For simplicity,
think of an open-source as some code ready by others for us to use with some good conditions for us.
It's important to know about that.
And we started to add this new project to our project and then our code overall didn't compile,
Why? the compiler say multiple redefinition,
and when we investigated, we noticed that they also have a variable, for example, named total_users.
So now the problem is it's like - now, you are defining the same variable twice,
and notice that developers everywhere would use similar names in their projects.
This is what we call name collision.
These guys have a name and we have a name and it is the same name.
The compiler now will not compile your code. C++ solved that using a very simple idea named namespaces.
namespaces as simple as allows us to group things together under a single name.
This way, instead of having your variables in just the very global scope, you have it inside
some well-defined scope by you.
Let's see an example of that.
This is here
the integer total_users equals zero variable.
If you tried to define it twice, to declare or define twice, you will get a compilation error of multiple
redefinition.
Now, here is the name space.
You define as simple as. You say namespace,
give some very unique name, open a brace, you end the brace, and you put here all of your code.
Notice here,
these total users is now inside the namespace.
So it do the same name here,
but it's like you can think of this one that
Its actual name is like our system dot total_users something that.
So although they are the same name, they are actually different names,
and then also we define here another namespace, give it like, say, downloaded system,
and it also has to total_users. This code is going to compile.
here is one more interesting thing.
After a few lines of code, we see again namespace our_ system,
and then we started to add const integer size 10.
So now the grouping scope of our system has this variable and this variable.
Can I come here and say integer total size equal 10?
No, because under our system there are total users and there is size.
Now, I would like to print our things. Instead of just printing total users, we say our system,
colon-colon, this is named scope resolution operator,
Our system, colon-colon, total users, will print the ten. Downloaded system, total users will print
20. Our system, colon-colon, size will print 10 and so on.
The word namespace isn't a variable in the memory.
This is just grouping things together.
You are expected to define all of your systems within such a namespace, but you don't need to have
it here in a single file.
As as you see, we can open it again and again in different files.
Let's go more complex and learn a few extra stuff about that.
The first one is using keyword directive declaration. You have here some namespace, we named it
customer, another namespace named admin.
Now, if you would like to use this first, as we learned from a few in the last slide, you can use
here customer, colon-colon first.
If you did this declaration here and say using customer, colon-colon first, this variable first is going
to be visible through the program, and you can directly refer to it without using the customer now.
OK, what about second?
Second is invisible.
Second is invisible because we didn't declare it here.
So we just declare first,
we can use it. If you would like use second,
you have to say here customer, colon, colon, second.
There is another case here.
Let's declare here
but internally using admin total. We can use here total. The difference between that and this one.
This one is defined globally through it's visible from here to the end of the file, but this one is
only visible inside the main function.
So one of them is global and one of them is local.
So using the keyword declaration of using, you can declare it once so that you can use it
in the whole program. Definitely, you might face collisions here locally if there is something else
that's named first,
but this depends on you. Let's take it one more step further.
Let's say using namespace customer.
Now, I hope you noticed the similarities between using namespace std and using namespace customer.
When you say using namespace customer, this takes everything under the customer and makes it visible.
So at this moment, you can say here first and second without compilation error because when you
say using namespace, you're telling him, I want all of this namespace to be visible for me.
So everything inside it is now visible for you.
But for the admin, for example, you have to still, like, access either directly admin, colon-colon, total
or you declare it to use it.
If you say using namespace admin, then everything also inside the admin is now visible.
That's it for today.