Let's continue our talk about the namespaces. we would like to learn how to use the namespaces
when it comes to headers and includes. So, I have here an employee_dot_h and employee_dot_cpp file. To use
the namespace with them
as simple as come to your code and start with namespace, our system, brace,
and then in the end, you put another end brace,
and when it comes to the employee_dot_cpp, again come to the top of the file, write here namespace, our system,
brace, and after your last line of code here, close the brace.
At this moment of time, this code is invisible without our_ system's scope, and this code is invisible without
our_system's scope.
To use that in the main, you can come and do the following: using namespace, our system, If you did that,
now this global variable here is now visible for you,
you can use it. If you didn't using namespace, our system,
you can come and say here our system, colon-colon, employee, global, or you can say here using our system, colon-colon,
employee, global.
So this is like the last session
exactly,
but you just here is defining our system in different areas.
Now, let's go back to the IO_stream, and let's start to browse it. If you tried to open the IO_stream, you
would notice here something called namespaces std.
You will also notice the I_stream cin and  O_stream cout with the word extern.
We talked before that when you hash_include the file IO_stream, it is going to copy all of this code inside your code.
That's why you see  I_stream cin and O_stream cout, and they are global everywhere.
But now what is the interesting thing about this using namespace std. The reason that we see cin and cout
in our code is two things:
The first is we hash include their files.
The second is we are actually using the namespace std.
If any of them is missing, you get a compilation error.
If you try to browse more files like the C math and the vector, you will notice also they are under
the namespace std. The namespace std, all the files in the C++ Standard Library are declaring
in all of its entities within the std.
That's why when you use in your code some hash include, let's say vector or map with the
using namespace std,
you are seeing them visible in your code.
Let's try to remove using namespace from our code to see the effect of that in our code, like how to
handle it in a proper way.
So let's go back first to our employee_dot_h.
If you thought about it, is there any reason to have hash include IO_stream? the answer is no because
we aren't reading or writing.
OK, but we have a problem now.
We have here something that named string which is inside the namespace std.
OK, hash include the string for it.
OK, but still this is invisible because this is inside the using namespace std. Use here std
colon-colon,
now you see the string, use here std colon-colon string. There is another way, you can come here and say using std
colon-colon, string,
but this is a more standard way in the industry. At this moment,
We are done with this file.
Now going back to the employee_dot_cpp, there are two things here.
The signature of the function which you need the std and the body of the function itself.
For the signature itself,
there would be nothing missing because the declaration here is the same as the declaration here.
So if employee_dot_h is OK, then it means that it has a proper declaration that you need for the signature
itself.
Now going to the body,
What is the extra thing here?
The extra thing is we need to cout.  Cout exists in the IO_stream.
Now, so the first thing you have put the hash_include that includes it.
The second idea is you either use using namespace std, or you are going to access using the namespace itself
directly.
That's how you handle it here
the employee_dot_cpp. Going back to the main itself, let's get rid of this using namespace std and this
one. Now, you have to access all of these guys using the scope resolution.
So far, we've learned the three ways. Learn to access directly using that one or come and say using
std, colon-colon, cout, or using namespace std, or using namespace our system.
This is what happen
if you tried to get rid of completely using namespace, you have to define every one of them by yourself,
and this takes us to an interesting question.
What is good and what is bad in using namespace std? the good part is it is an easier educational experience for
beginners. Notice that
since the beginning, we didn't have to tell you what is really  cout and what is defined and all
of that.
The second thing is when you use using namespace std, it makes your code shorter and readable so you don't have
this bunch of std, colon-colon, cin, std, colon-colon, cout, std, colon-colon, square root, and all
of that.
But here is the bad part: When you say using namespace std, it makes all what in std visible, which is a lot
everything in C++ under std.
This typically creates a lot of issues and then conflicts in real projects because now the visibility
of your program is colliding with the visibility of a huge thing.
In industry,
We don't use at all using namespace std.
We do not do that.
What we typically do is we are accessing things using something like std, colon-colon, cout.
we just keep them this way.
It makes the code a bit bigger, less readable, but overall, fewer collisions.
here is one choice:
During the course, I decided that I'm going to keep it simple.
By that I mean through the whole course I'm using using namespace std,
but remember, this isn't a professional choice.
We don't do that in the industry.
I'm just doing it because I believe it is an easier educational experience. The negative side of
that,
Your eyes don't see the proper way a lot, however, as you see, this just
very systematic code change.
Let's go back to our topic.
One last thing, C++ allows you to have nested namespaces.
This means you have more and more divisions inside your code.
So we have a group and subgroup and subgroup and so on.
So here I have something named namespace, our system inside it, namespace customer, and another
namespace for admin.
If I would like to use a variable limit, I can use it as following: our system, colon-colon, customer, colon-colon, limit.
So as you see, the colon_colon is just getting one more inside level.
You can also defining in C++ what we call alias.
So let's say you don't need to use this very big name all the time.
You can see something like namespace, whatever name here, then our system colon-colon customer.
Now you can access the limit variable directly with the scope
colon_colon. If it happened here to have a namespace inside a namespace
inside a namespace,
the code looks ugly.
C++ 17 simplifies that as follows:
You can define it as follows: namespace, our system, colon_colon, customer, and then you define what you
have.
Do not compile this code unless your compiler supports C++ 17 or beyond.
That's it.