Hi Everyone, in this section we will talk about bit manipulation techniques, and these are nothing
but these are some..
Maybe you can say algorithms using which you can modify the data are binary representation level and every
programming language provides us some bitwise operators which allow us to operate on the binary representation
of the data that we have.
OK.
So we will look how to use these bitwise operators, what are the different types of bitwise operators
and how we can use them to solve some problems, OK?
And the reason why we use Bitwise operators sometime is ? because they operate on the binary representation
of the data and they're fast as compared to the use the non bitwise operators.
And what are the different types of operators you can see on the screen?
And we are going to talk about AND, OR, XOR, One's  complement,
Binary left shift and binary right shift. Ok. so these are the Bitwise operators and if you're new to them,
so let us explore each of them one by one.
So the first one is a binary.
And so basically, let's say AND has very simple rules. let's say you have two bits.
One and let's say the other bit is zero.
So if you do AND with a zero, then it is going to give you a result of zero.
Similarly, zero AND one is going to give you a result of zero and only when both the bits are set.
Only then you will get a result of one and zero AND zero
is also going to be zero.
So anything done an AND with zero is going to give you a zero bit.
OK, so these are the simple rules of doing a simple AND.
And now what?
How do we use it?
OK, let's say I have a number five and I do AND with seven then what I'm going to get.
So let's see.
So five five in binary is represented as zero zero zero followed by let say one zero one and it's let's say
32 or 64 bit number. seven and binary can be represented as lots of zeros followed by triple one.
If you do AND so it will happen on
bit by bit level.
OK, so one and one is one, zero and one is zero, one and one is one and followed by lot's zeros.
OK.
So if you convert this number back into the decimal you will see this result is going to be 5.
This is how binary AND works.
So I hope this is clear.
And now let's see what is binary OR.
So the rules of the OR are very simple.
If one of the bits is one then the result is going to be one. for example,
one OR zero
Is going to give you
Ok, this is denoted using this operated one OR zero is going to give you one.
Similarly, zero OR one is going to give you one, zero OR zero is going to give you a zero and
one OR one is going to give you one.
So if one of the bits is one then the resulting bit would be one.
For example, if I do five OR with eight.
OK, so what is five?
Five is one zero one.
What is 8?
8 is one triple zero.
Yes.
And if you do OR here, what you're going to get ?  you're going to get one here, one here, zero here
and one here.
So what does this number?
This is eight.
This is four.
This is two and this is one.
So if you are eight plus four plus one.
So this number is actually 13.
OK.
So these are actually powers of two. two raise to the power 0,
two raise to the power 1,two raise to the power 2,two raise to the power 3,
So you can see I'm doing eight plus four plus one, that is 13.
OK, so this number is actually 13.
So if you do this in your code, you will get an output of 13 in this particular case.
So I hope binary OR is also clear.
Now let us move on to XOR.
So XOR is also known as exclusive OR.
.
OK.
Exclusive OR.
So what are the rules of XOR?
So it basically means if both bits are same then there is going to be zero. for example,
zero XOR zero is zero.
And also one XOR zero is... sorry, ones XOR one is also zero.
If both the bits are same the result is zero.
Otherwise if both bits are different than the result is one.
So if I show you maybe if I do five
XOR seven.
So five is what five is zero zero zero one zero one and seven is zero zero triple one.
If I do XOR here then one XOR one is going to be zero, zero XOR one is going to be one.
This is going to be zero and lots of zeros.
This result is going to be two.
OK, so if you do something like cout five XOR seven then it is going to print two in your code.
OK.
So I hope you understood this XOR operator as well.
So the next  that we're going to discuss is NOT. OK.
So the NOT is a very simple operator.
So what what it does if I have a bit zero. Ok. let's say this is... this is not a integer zero.
This is the bit zero.
So if you do NOT of zero, you're going to get one and suppose you do NOT off some number.
OK, let's say you have a number like zero zero zero one zero one.
let's say This number is five.
If you do the NOT five, then it is going to flip all the bits. OK, so NOT of one is zero.
and NOT of this is going to be lots of one's followed by zero one zero one.
OK.
So this you will see it is going to flip all the bits including the most significant bit.
That is the sign bit.
OK, that is the sign bit.
That means this number could be a negative number as well, OK?
Now, if you have little idea here, I can give you one example.
Let's say I take something like this.
Let's say take int A. and i say int a is  zero and I simply do cout NOT of A.
Then what you're going to expect. OK. what would be the  answer?
The answer is going to be actually not one but it would be minus one.
OK, now you may wonder why, why it is so.
So if you look zero at the memory level to what a zero?zero is a 32 bit number in which
Everything is... everything is zero. all the 32 bits are zero.
If you do a NO of it you will get all 32  bits as ones.
Ok?
And
All 32 bits are ones and the most significant bits represents the sign bits.
OK, so if this sign bit is one that means it is a negative number, so that means it is a negative number
and the remaining 31 bits they represent
the magnitude. ok ? now for the negative numbers, if we want to find out the magnitude of that particular
number.
These numbers are stored in a form known as 2's complement form.
OK, that's stored int a 2's complement form.
So in order to find out what number is this what we need to do, we need to take the 2's compliment.
That means invert all the bit's and add one to it.
OK?
The number is this this this. in order to find the magnitude, we have to first invert all the bits.
If i invert all the bits, it becomes like this
And then I will add one to it.
This number is zero zero zero zero zero one.
So basically, this is a negative number with the magnitude of one.
And this number is actually minus one.
OK.
So if you do NOT of zero and where zero is an integer, you are going to get minus one as output, OK?
And Not of  zero where zero is bit.
It would be one.
OK.
So that is something that you should be very careful while working on.
So that's something you can try it on your own as well.
OK, if you don't trust me I'm going to show you demo as well, so I have just code where I have
x is zero and I'm doing cout NOT of x?
So let us run this code and see what we get as a output. sorry... and this should be a dot slash bitwise.
So you can see this output is actually minus one.
That is because of the same reason I have discussed.
OK, so doing a negation of all zeros gives us a number in which all numbers are ones and since it is stored as
2's complement form. the first but denotes the singed bits.
The remaining bits denotes the the magnitude.
And in order to find the exact magnitude we have to take 2's compliment.
So this process is known as 2's complement where we invert all the bits and add one to it.
And whatever you get this number, this is the magnitude of the number.
OK.
So if you convert this number into decimal this number is one and sign is minus one because
the most significant bit is one.
OK.
So I hope this is clear.
And Now you understand that doing the negation of bit  zero is one and doing the negation of integer zero
is minus one.
It's an important concept.
So I have explained it to you.
So binary NOT is clear.
Now we will talk about two more operators left and right shift in the next lecture.