Hi Everyone, now we're going to talk about binary left shift.
So what is this operator ? so generally you will find this operator a written like this.
Let's have five left shift 2.
So what does it mean?
It basically means we have a number five.
OK.
And whatever is the bit it has.
We're going to left shift all the bits by a factor of two.
So everything is going to move towards left by a factor of two.
So what?
What will happen?
These two bits will fall off, OK?
And you will have something like this.
Zero zero one zero one.
And from here, you will add two zeros.
OK.
So you will add like this. if you try to understand what is different in this number?
So this was two raise to the power zero.
This was two raise to the power one.
This was two raise to the power two and here it is two raise to the power zero, two raise to the power one,
And this is two raise to the power two.
This is two raise to the power 3 and this is two raise to the power 4.
What is the original number?
So original number is five.
OK.
And that is equal to 2's square plus
2 raise to the power zero and we know this is five.
And let let let us call this number as x.
Now if I talk about this number.
OK, so what is this number?
So it is nothing, but it is two's square less plus 2 four.
If you take two square common, what you're left with ? you're left with two square plus two raise to the power zero.
zero.
That means it has two square off the original Number X, basically doing a left shift by two
Has multiplied that number by two's square.
OK.
So basically A left shift B will multiply A with 2 raise to the  power B.
This is what I'm trying to say.
And if you see what is this number?
This number is nothing but 16 plus 4.
This number is 20.
Effectively have got multiplied by two raise to 2.
that is five into 4 that is 20.
Effectively, when you do a left shift the number is multiplied with the power of two.
So this is the left shift operator.
I hope this one is now clear.
Similarly, we also have something known as a right shift.
The left shift does multiplication, right shift divides OK?
Let us start with one example.
Let's say I have a number 10 and if I do a right shift with one, that means I'm going to divide by
two raise to the power one.
OK.
So if I show you this number 10 in binary is one zero one zero.
And that means if this is the number doing the right shift means we are moving every bit towards right
by one step.
This bit will get discarded and the original number would become zero zero zero one zero one.
OK.
And clearly, we know this number is five.
So if we do 10 right shift one that means divide by... 10 divided by two raise to the power one.
This number is five and this number is also five.
Again, if you do right shift one here, it's a odd number.
You should get two. this doing right shift one here means zero zero zero.
This one will fall off and we will get something like this one zero.
So this number is two.
So this same as doing five divided by two raise to the power one?
That is. OK.
And similarly, if you do it once again you will end up getting zero zero zero one.
And this number is one.
And let's do it once more.
You will do zero zero zero zero.
This number would be zero.
If I do 10 right shift four then that means 10 divided by two raise to the power four.
And that is 16.
So this number would be zero.
OK.
So A right night shift B basically means A divided by two raise to the power B. OK.
So I hope both left shift and right shift are now clear to you and in the coming lectures, we will see
some examples where these operators can be used.
That's all for this lecture.
Thank you.