Hi Everyone, now we are going to look at very small example of a bitwise operator.
So we need to write a function to check whether a number is odd or even. OK, so not even a function.
even we can write a small expression to check whether a number is odd or even. OK.
So one thing you might know is we can simply do
n%2 if this gives us zero, then we can say the number is even if it gives us one the number
is odd. OK.
But since we are learning about Bitwise operators, we want to solve this problem using the Bitwise
operator.
The one thing you will observe is all the odd numbers will have the last bit as one and all the even
numbers will have last bit as zero.
OK, so I'm writing for
So this number is one.
This number is two, this number is three.
This number is four.
This number is five.
One thing you can clearly observe is for Odd the number... four four odd numbers,
The last bit is one.
And it contributes 2 raise to the power zero.
That is one to the answer.
And that is what it makes the number odd.ok.
So everything else is a even number. OK.
Everything else is a evennumber.
That means the last bits decide whether the number would be odd or it would be even.
What we need to do.
We need to check if last bit as one.
Or it is not. OK, what we can do is let's say we have some numbered zero zero zero one zero one zero
one one.
What we can do we can do
And with this one?
OK, what is this one?
This one is nothing but zero zero zero zero zero zero zero zero and one. if you do an AND and what
could be a possibility doing in
AND. so we have lots of zeros here,
the only thing we will get is at the last positions.
If the last position is one that means this position was one, OK?
And that means, this number is odd.
But suppose the last position if it is zero, then we will get a zero here.
That means this number is actually even. OK.
So I hope you understood how we can check whether the numbers is odd or even.  let me show you a quick
demo in the code as well.
So if I have... let's say.
this code
I can simply put a if...else... so int x, cin c. I can check if x AND one, I can cout odd else I can cout
.
So. ./odd, if I give five So file is odd. if I give 8, 8 is even. if I give 32
It's odd.
It's even, if I give 33.
It's odd, OK, 32 is even 33 is old.
So I hope now you understood how we can use this AND one to find out the last bit.
OK.
And that's it.
That's it for this lecture.
So thank you for watching.
Bye Bye