Hi Everyone, in this lecture we will talk about some common operations that we can do using bitwise
operators.
So let us look at some examples.
Let's say we want to get the i th bit of a number.
For example, let's say the number is five
And in binary, it would look something like this zero zero one zero one and the numbering of bits that
I'm going to do is from the right.
So this is the zero th bit.
This is the first, but this is the second and so on.
If I say OK, give me the second bit then I'm talking about this bit .I want to check the value
of this particular bit, OK?
Similarly, there would be a function like set ith bit or update ith bit then clear ith bit
then clear a range of bits.
So we are going to see multiple functions in this set of lectures.
So let us start with the first one.
I want to get the ith bit
of a number n.
And so now you may ask. OK, how we can extract that bit ? so it's going to be pretty easy. let's
let's int n is five and the position of bit that is I that I'm going to take input, OK?
And we will print the ith bit of
the number.
OK, so now let's see how we can do it ? so we know we can use bitwise operators but how ?
So if I do something like this if I have let's say, one zero one. OK.
And I actually want to extract this particular bit.
So we have seen how to get the last bit. OK.
So we basically do with the AND with the one but doing a AND one will not help us in this case.
So what we want? we actually want a variable in which we have, uh...
We have one at this particular location and everything else is going to be zero so if I put everything
else as zero then I will get this number.
And how do I get this number?
So it is nothing, but it is one left shift i.
if you left shift one i times.
Okay, so I is two. OK. and we are talking about zero one two.
We are talking about this bit.
So one left shift two basically means this number one zero zero which is this.
And if you do AND here what you're going to get ? you're going to get a number
Zero zero zero one zero zero.
OK, because everything else is zero.
So doing a AND will convert everything else into zero.
And for this position, since you have one here so doing AND with one will give you this number.
Now you can check if this number is greater than zero.
That means the bit is one.
And if this number is equal to zero. OK, which would happen if this bit to zero then you can say
this bit is actually zero.
So what we need to do, we need to create a small variable. let's say mask.
OK, I'm calling this number as a mask and we will do the AND with the mask. ok. So mosques is nothing but
one left shift i and I can see the last bit is nothing but the number AND mask.
OK.
If I do the AND and if it gives me a result which is greater than zero then I can return one.
Otherwise, I can return zero and this is going to give me the ith bit.
So let's run the code and see.
So if I do ./commanoperation ,so I say,ok. tell me the second bit of five, so
it is one.
Tell me the first bit.
It does zero.
Tell me what does it not?
It does one that means it is working fine.
So that's all for this lecture.
See you in the next video.