Hi, everyone.
So now we are going to look at how we can clear the ith bit. OK.
So basically if we have a number like. let's say, one one zero one and I want to delete this bit
and I want to make it zero. OK. I want to clear the ith bit, so I is two for this example.
Let's say. what I need to do.
I need to create a number in which only this bit is zero.
Only this bit is zero and rest everything else is going to be one, so I need this as zero and rest
everything is one.
can you guess how we can get this particular kind of a number, OK?
The one thing we know is the ith... we want to work on the ith bit. so we can create a mask using one left shift i.
.
It will give us something like this zero one zero zero.
OK ? that is fine.
And how do we get this number?
It is nothing but it's a...
It's a NOT of this number. So bitwise why NOT.
So what we need to do we need to do a negation here and we once we are getting this, what we can
do ? we can do AND.
if we do a AND all these bits will be reserved so we will get one zero one.
And since we have a zero here, zero and something it is going to again zero.
So that's it.
So this is going to clear the ith bit.
So if I show you the mask now, the mak is going to be nothing but NOT of one left shift i.
And what you need to do? you need to update the value of n so you need to say n equals to n AND mask.
and we are done. Instead of calling setIthbit
I'm going to call clearithbit.
I give N and I.
And let us clear the...
So this number is what?
One two four eight.
This is this number is 13.
So if I say, let's say n is 13 and I want to clear the second bit.
If n is 13 and I want to clear the second bit.
I should get a number which is nine. zero one two.
Yes.
So let's see.
I want to clear the second bit.
OK, I need to run this code, build this code first.
If i clear the second bit.
I'm getting the output which is exactly equal to nine.
OK.
So I hope this is clear to you and this is how we can clear any bit in a number.