Hi Everyone, the next thing that we're going to look at is how do we set ith bit. Ok. we need to write a
function.
void set i th bit and we get the number and we get the position.
So one thing you can do is you can take this number by reference and you can change the value
here or you can return the new number. OK?
So maybe another way to make this function is like this.
OK.
And here you have to return the new value.
So maybe I want to go with the first one because we we want to change the value of n in the function
itself.
So let's see how we can do it.
So it's actually very easy, very similar to what we have seen in the get, let's say the number is five.
And I want to say the first bit.
OK.
I want to set the first bit.
that is this one.
OK, so what I need, I need to do OR operation, a bitwise OR with the number which looks like this.
zero one zero. which has set bit at the i th index.
OK.
And i th bit should be set. so what we need to do? we need to create a mask that is again, this
number is going to be one left shift i.
I will get this number.
And we will do a Bitwise OR with the value of n.
And so let's see, so we can say int mask equals one left shift i.
And what we can say? we can say,
Let's update the value of N as N OR mask.
And we are done.
Now, if the number is five if I say, OK. get ith bit. OK. I can say void, I can say set
ith bit.
Instead of calling this I can call set ith bit.
I give the value of n and i and maybe I print the new value of n.
And so let's try to run this.
I say. OK, I us set the first bit so you can see after setting the first bit the result is seven.
which is fine. if I set the zero th bit then the result will not change because that bit is already
set in five.
So that's all.
That's how it is going to work.
So we are getting this number one one one by setting the i th bit as one.
That's it.
See you in the next lecture.