Hi Everyone, So now we're going to discuss one more method that we need to complete a update i th bit.
OK, so what we will get, we will get n, the position and the value that we want to put in a particular
position.
So let's say we have a number like this and I say. OK. this is the i th index and I want to update
this index as zero.
OK, so what I need to do? I need to put this as a zero.
Or it may happen that, OK. No, this is the i th index.
I want to put this index as one.
So we need to write a code such that it handles both the cases. OK. one way of doing this is what we can
do?
We can create a mask.
OK, we can create a mask and we can...
We know how to set this particular bit to one.
That is something we have already seen.
But suppose if this bit is one I want to set it to zero.
OK that we have also seen.
So basically, we need to combine the functionality of set bit plus clear bit
in this particular case.ok. what...
What we can do is, let's say we're talking about a particular position one one one zero zero one zero
something like this.
I want to do some work here.
The first, what I can do? I can just clear this bit.
I can make it zero.
OK. I can destroy this bit.
That means I'll make it zero.
And once this is zero, we can actually do OR operation with the mask.
and the mask would look something like this if I want to...
If the value of  bit that we want to say should be one or the mask would look something like this all zeros.
If the value that we want set is going to be zero so if you do the OR you will have the right
bit here. OK.  you will have the updated bit and rest
all the bits will remain same.
OK. rest everything will remain same.
So here you will get the right value.
So basically, if the value zero we just need to do the clearing part and if the values one we first
need to clear that bit so that it handles both the cases whether the old was one or zero it
will work for both.
So what I can do? I can simply call clear i th bit. I can give n and i.
And once it is done we... what we can do?
We can create a mask which is like this. I can say OK int mask that is equal to one left shift i.
And we can return...
OK, it's update method.
So we can pass it by reference..
we can say n equals to
n  OR mask. that's it.
This actually sets the right value.
OK.
And Sorry, this not... this... this should not be one left shift i, this should be value
left shift i, OK, so that as v left shift i.
So if the V is zero. if the v is zero, this will be entirely zero and doing OR with zero will not do anything OK.
And if we is one, then this number would be something like this and this will create the right mask
for us.
And the i th bit would be set in the value of n. so let us try to do some work.
Maybe I can call this method update i th bit and endl.
So let's say the original number was 13 and I can say n, i and  value.
let's say I want to set some bit in 13 to one.
So let me show it to you.
OK, so I want to set... so 13 is one one zero one. I wante to set the first bit as one.
Mm.
Let me build a code.
OK, so 13 was like this one one zero one. if I set the first bit, then this number becomes one one
one one, which is 15 that is fine. if I want to update the second bit and I want to make the value
as zero.
So let's see what happens.
I want to say, OK, said this bit as zero and take I as input from the use it.
The second, which would be zero, then the number would become if this is a two zero, it would become
one zero zero one and this number is nothing but nine.
So I hope I'm dead, but it's clear to you and this is how we can implement update.
I had to wait.