Hi Everyone so now we're going to discuss one more method that we're doing, right?
So we want to clear the last i bits.
So we're give... given a number n and we want to remove the all the last i bits of that particular
number.
For example, if we have a number one one one zero zero one zero and if I say OK, I is five that
means we will remove the bits from zero one two three four.
All these bits should be made to zero.
OK, so we want to convert them to zero.
And this should be the resulting number.
This is what is expected from the function.
Now how we can do it ?
So clearly what we can think of is we actually need a number of this form
In which these three bits are set and rest everything is set to zero.
OK.
And it may happen
We... we may also have something like one zero here then this... this should remain intact.
OK. so the mask would be like this.
So we want to create a mask in which the last i positions are zero.
And once we create this mask what we need to do? we need to do
AND of these two numbers to get this as  a result. now how do we create this mask ? OK.
So it's going to be quite easy.
So what if you I tell you if  you have a number in which you have all ones. OK. and then if you left shift it
with I, what you will get ? you will get i number of zeros in the right.
OK, so basically you will get a number like one one one one followed by a number of zeros and this is
what we exactly need.
This is what we need.
Starting from the index i+1 till the zero th
index we need everything as zero.
We have already seen if you have this kind of a number, now what is this number in binary?
OK.
How do we represent this number as a integer?
This number can be represented in using two ways.
One is it can be represented as NOT of zero because if you talk about zero, zero as all bits set zero and  not of zero as
all bits set  one and we... we also said that this number represents minus one.
So either you take minus one or you take not of zero.
Both are going to remain same.
And what you need to do? you need to do the left shift of minus one with i and then do it a AND with
your original number.
OK.
So this is what we need to do.
So I can say int mask is nothing but let's say minus one
Left shift I. that's it.
And the number would be n AND mask.
That's it.
And our work is done.
So maybe let's say n is 15.
And let's say I is  two. I don't take input. if I remove the last two bits of 15
Let's see what we should get.
So 15 is like this one one one one. we are saying... Okay, let us clear the last 2 bits.
So it should be one one zero zero.
It should be 12.
We should be getting output as 12.
So instead of calling this method we can call clear last I bit. I give n and I. that's it..
OK, this should be void.
And yes, we are getting the output as 12.
So, I hope this functionality is clear. in the next lecture will discuss one more function.