Hi Everyone, so now we are going to discuss one more function that is a bit tricky than what we have done
so far.
And so what we need to do? we need to clear bits in the range i 2 j.
So what we are given we are given a number, maybe something like this one one zero zero one zero
zero one one zero and let's say I'm given Index I and Index J.
I want to clear all the bits in this particular in range ok.
let say this is i.
And this is j, and this is i.
So I want to remove all the bits starting from index...sorry I want to.
Yes, I want to remove all the bits starting from index I
till the index j. they need to be cleared out.
I want to set them as zero.
So we have seen if you need to clear a particular bit you need a mask in which we have zero at that
particular index.
So for this case, what we need is we need a mask in which we have
all the bits at this position as one and all the birds at this position as zero and all the bits at
the positions starting from I plus one till the zero as one.
OK, so we need something like this.
ok this index is I, this index is J.
These bits should be zero, so we need to see how we can create this particular kind of a mask.
The thing is very simple we can actually break this down into two components.
How to create this mask ? let say to this one part is A and A looks something like this.
we have lots of ones followed by all zeros and we can also have B in which we have lots of zeros
Followed by ones starting from the index I +1.
OK, this is something we can actually do and this is what we have....
We have J number of
We have J+1 one number of zeros here.
OK, so basically in order to create this mask we have already seen what we can do.
We can take
all ones and we can right shift it with J plus one.
OK, so if we have all number of ones that is nothing but that is NOT of zero or that is minus one.
So if we do a left shift with index J plus one we will get the number A.
OK.
That's it.
How do we get the number B? finding the number we is
You can find that this number is nothing
but if you look at the number 15.
So what is 15 ? 15 is lots of zeros followed by four ones.
What about 31?
This is lots of zeros followed by five
number of one. we need something like this.
So this number is of the form two raise to the power n minus one.
And what is two raise to the power n?
So for 15 we get 4 bits.
OK.
So if n is four we get last...last four
Bit as four. how many bits we need it? we actually need i number of bits here. Ok. we actually need
so this is from zero to i minus one.
We actually need I number of bits here.
OK.
So basically, it does nothing but this number is nothing but 2 raise to the power I minus one.
And what is 2 raise to the power i?
So we can write this as one left shift I.
And subtract one out of it.
So B is nothing but one left shift I and subtract one out of it.
And what is mask?
mask is nothing but A or B.
Now we get this number.
And what is our final number?
So mask we now have.
And what is the value of N?
So if you do a AND of this mask with the number, it is going to clear these bits from I index to till J.
So n is going to be n and mask.
That's it.
And we are done OK and we are done for the
Method.
So let's try to implement the code and then we will see in the output.
So let us first find out A. so A is nothing but NOT of zero or minus one, you can take left shift
j plus one. OK.
And what about B?
B is one left shift i minus .
And what is mask?
It is nothing but A or B and what is n?
N equals two n and mask.
That's it.
Let us see our N is 31 and I want to clear the bits in the range.
let's say one, I is one and
J is let's say three. OK.
So I can say a...
Clear bits in the range.
I give the number n, I give i and I give j.
And let us see what output it produces.
So it is giving us the number 17, so let's see what happens.
So 31 is five times one and zero one two three.
So I said ok. cleare
All these three bits, I get the number one zero zero one.
This is nothing but to raise to the power four and this is two raise to the power zero.
This is 16+1, 17 and we are getting this number 17.
That's it.
That means the code is working perfectly fine and I hope this is clear to you.