Hi Everyone, so now we will solve a very interesting problem using the concept that we have learned so far.
So what I'm going to do? I'm going to explain you question.
The question is very simple. it says we given to 32 bit numbers n and m and we're also given two bit positions i and j.
so we need to write a method to set all the bits between i and j in m equal to n.
So let me... let me give you one example also.
So if you look at this, this is what n is given this is what m given. what I want is I want
to put m inside n from index j to i.
OK, so starting starting from index j till the index i, I want to put all the bit of in which
should be same as m.
OK, this is what we need to do.
So let me try to show it to you.
So we have n one followed by let say 10 Zeroes.
OK.
And indexes 2 and 6, so basically it is like this zero one two three four five six.
I want to replace these bits
with bits from m so the Bits from m are one zero one zero one.
OK so basically these bits may also have one or they may also have something else as well.
I don't know.
What i want is if I want to replace these bits with this.
So first I need to clear these bits. Ok. so first I need to clear the bits from Index J to i.
And for that we have already implemented one function in one of the lectures so we can first call
that function clear bit j to i.
And once we have done. what we can do? we can do OR with of m.
But m should also have
these number of zeros here that means m should be left shifted by a factor of I.
So what we need to do? we need to left shift m by a factor of i.
And we need to clear the bits .
once we're done that we can do the operation of n in which these bits are already set to
zero with m which has been shifted to the right index
And then we will get the right result.
OK, so that's it.
That's what we need to do.
So if I give you this example now you can see output is like this.
So I will first copy this function clear bits
in the range j to i.
I I'll pasted it here.
And let me just comment out the problem statement.
And now what we need to do? we need to create this method void replace bits.
I have n, I have I, I have J.
I have M. So what we need to do.
First, we need to call the clear bit in range method I give n, I and j and then we need to create
a mask. ok so  mosque is nothing but m left shift
I.
And finally we need to return or we need to say n equals to n or mask.
That's it.
And we are done.
Ok. so let us look at one example lets say n is 15. i is one, j is 3.
j Is three and m is two.
So if I say okay replace bits n, i, j and m and if i do cout n now I should see some output.
Let us try to build this code.
And let us try to run it.
So this is...
so I'm getting an answer five. so let's see what we have done. so we have n, which is 15 so it is one
one one one.
We have i and j.
So this is zero one two three.
I said OK, replace these bits with bits of two.
So what is two ?
two is One zero.
OK.
Two is zero one zero.
And this is what we are going to get. now if you see these bits replaced
.
What we did ?
We first cleared these bit.
We made this number as a 0001.
Then we left shifted two by a factor. two by doing a left shift of i becomes like this.
And then we do a OR operation so it becomes 0101 which is equal to five.
That means our code is working as expected and we are done.
That's it for this lecture.
Thank you.