Hi Everyone, in this lecture I will teach you an interesting property how you can check whether a number
is a power of two or not.
OK.
And we will use Bitwise operators to do this check.
So let us talk about the power of two. let's say 16 is a number which is a power of two or 8 is
a number which is a power of two. so what is 16 ? 16 in binary
Looks like this.
Yes.
And what I can do is?  this... let's say this number is n.
Can you tell me what would be n minus one ?
Clearly, we know the n minus one would be.
Something like this, if and if n is power of 2.
OK, so we know n is a power of two then the previous number would look something like this.
So this number is actually 15.
And an interesting property is if n is a power of two then doing a AND of these two will
always give me a zero.
OK.
And you can see this number is zero.
similarly It is true for eight and seven as well. if 8 is like this
And seven is like this.
And if you do a  AND here of eight and seven then you will get the number zero.
But this will not be true for any other number.
For example, five. five is one zero one.
What is four?
So four is one double zero.
And if you do a AND  here you will not get a zero.
OK.
So basically, the check is if... if you get something like this if n AND n minus one, if they produce
a result that is equal to zero then that means n is a power of 2.
OK.
So simply what we can do in the code, we can take input end and I can check if n and n minus
one.
And I may be put a bracket here.
If this is equal to zero then you can cout Yes.
power of two.
else you can say, not a power of two.
OK, so let's build it.
Ran it and check it quickly.
So 128.
Yes, it is a power of two. one twe... 144.
It's not the power of two.
OK, and 1024 is a power of two.
And 12 it's not power of 2.
So yes it's working fine.
So it's a order one check without doing anything with just this AND operation with n minus one, we can
tell whether a number is power of two or not.
That's it for this lecture.
Thank you !