Hi Everyone, so in this lecture we will see how you can count bits.. count the number of setbits in a particular
number.
So what are setbits? setbits are those bits which are one, for example, if I give you the number
nine which is like one zero zero one then I can say it has two bits which are setbits.
I want to count the number of set bits in the binary representation of any number.
That's what we need to do.
So let us see how we can approach this particular problem of counting set bits.
So let us discuss the approach.
So it's pretty easy.
So we know the number is stored like this and we also know how we can find out the last bit so we can
do a AND with one.
And this will tell us what is the last bit we will get to know?
ok this bit is one.
And for the next iteration what we can do? we can remove this bit by doing the right shift.
Okay so we can see the last bit is n AND one.
And if this bit is one then I will increment the count of my setbits.
if it is zero I will not increment the count. Ok. Or I can simply write let's initial count zero,
then i can say  count plus equals to n ANDone.
If the last bit is one.
Then count will increment by one. if the last bit is zero
The count will increment by zero.
And I want to remove this so I can n equal to n right shift one.
The next time you will get one and zero it will be zero, count will change by zero.
Next time it would be you remove this one, zero and one, it would be still zero.
So count will change with zero.
Next time you remove this one and one it as one. so count will increment by one final count would be
two.
OK, so this is what we can do.
So I can write the function count bits I get the number n and here I can see while n is greater
than zero.
What I can do? every time find out the last bit. I can say int last bit.
I don't know or may be I can say int count that to zero.
And here I can find out the last bit.
So last bit is nothing but n and one and I can say count plus equals to last bit.
OK, if it is one count will change by one.
If it is zero count will not change.
And then we can do is n equal n right shift one.
And from here we can return the count.
so here we go. so what I can say int n, cin nand i can say cout count bits of n
And that's it and I hope this is now clear to you.
And what we're doing is we're doing a very simple operation. every time we are doing the right shift.
OK, so we do a AND
here this goes of
Next time these two bits are interact, OK?
And.
Finally, we will get to one here so this one is added to the count.
So this we will do for all the bits and for a number n the at most the number of setbits is going to be
long(n). OK.
The number of times this loop is going to run it is going to run at most log(n) for a number.
because a number n has log(n) bits that you can easily verify by taking some example also, let's
say 16. 16 is like this.
Those 16 has
It's like 2 raise to the power 4
it would have it
Most four plus one that is 5 bits. Ok. talk about seven
So it's going to be around two raise to the power three.
So seven is going to have
at Most three bits.
log of Seven is close to three.
Log of 16 is close to four.
That's what I'm trying to say.
So for any number n you have atmost log(n) bits and
OK, count... count is not declared so this should cnt and yes, we are done and now we can actually
run our code and see the ./countbit. if I give 16. 16 has only one bit. if I give 15.
15 has four setbits
But if I give 8, 8 has also one setbits.
So that's all for this lecture.
Thank you.