Hi everyone, in this lecture I'm going to discuss the hack to count the number of setbits.
So first, I will show you the code then I will tell you why this code works.
So what we are going to do? we want to count the number of setbits and I have the number n. what I will
do else? Ok.
The number of bits is let to answer
That is zero.
And while n is greater than zero, I am going to do one operation that is the main part of this
method.
I'm going to do n and n minus one.
And I'm going to do answer plus plus.
OK.
So what we're going to do ? we're going to count how many times this loop is going to run.
Basically, what this operation does, it actually removes the last setbits from the current number.
OK.
And we are going to return the answer.
So let me give you one example
let say n is nine ?
And 9 in binary is like one zero zero one.
What I'm doing, I'm updating n as nine and 8.
If you do and with 8.
So what is eight?
eight is one zero zero.
OK.
And what is going to happen is after doing this and, what you will get ? you will get this big will become
zero.
Basically, this will get removed and you will get one zero zero zero.
And again we are going to do the same work.
now the value of n is eight and we are going to do an and with seven and is seven is what ? this
is
What ? what is seven, if you do and here, you will get the number zero.
That means in just two iterations, we made this number zero.
And what happened is the first iteration.
This bit got removed, in the next iteration, this bit got removed because we are removing this bit
here.
OK.
So every time we are going to execute n equals to n and  n minus one, it is going to remove the last
setbits from the current number, OK?
So if a number has let say bits like this one one zero zero one zero one. in the first iteration, it
will get removed, in the next iteration it will get removed ,in the next iteration.
It will get removed, in the next iteration it will get removed and the number will become zero.
OK.
So if you will, with the first method, you would have been iterating one two three four five six times.
But if you go with this method, it will just take the number of iterations that is equal to the number
of setbits.
Now, I think with this example it is clear to you why this method is going to work and let us also
test of over functionality.
I can call both the functions I can call countbitshack and I give in n here.
And if I run the this code now, we can see if 15. 15 has 4 bits. in this case, the number of setbits and
the total bits is four.
So both the methods are going to take the same number of iterations.
But if I do it for, let's say 16.
Then the second method will just run for one time, because we are counting the number of iterations
and that is equal to answer. Ok. so that means in just one iteration it could tell that 16 has
only one setbits.
And maybe we will do it for nine. so nine has 2 setbits, both methods are working as expected,
so that's all for this lecture.