Hi Everyone, in this lecture we're going to discuss how we can convert a decimal number into its binary
representation using the Bitwise operators, OK?
So what I'm going to do? I'm going to write a method int convert to
Binary and I'm going to get a integer.
And let's say the integer is nine. I will return a number which looks like one zero zero one.
OK.
So I am also going to store in a form of integer?
.
Now
let's see how we can solve this problem. so it's easy.
What we need to do is? let's say this is a number
And we know how to extract the last bit every time. we will extract this bit and we'll create the
answer variable.
OK, the answer is initially zero we will add one to it.
It will become one.
OK, and next time we're going to discard this bit by doing the right shift and equal to n right shift
one.
And we are also going to maintain a power, so power is initially one so  will multiply one with one and add to
the answer so this is actually one into one.
now next time this is actually 10 raise to the power zero.
This is ten raise to the power one.
This is ten square and this is 10 cube. what we're going to do?
We're going to generate the powers of tes in the next iteration.
This power would become 10 and we see this bit is zero.
OK. so this is zero, what we will do? will do zero
into 10. the answer is not going to change but we are going to discard this and we are going to go
here and the power would become 10's square.
So next time we get this bit  this is zero and multiply 10 square.
This is zero so the answer is not going to change.
It is still still one.
But next time what is going to happen we discard this the power is going to become 10 cube and we see this
bit is one.
OK, so this bit is one. basically ,we can see for this bit we want to add one thousand to over answer.
So we will add one into ten raise to the power three.
If you see what would be your final answer, it would be one plus and 10 raise to the power three.
That is, it's going to be one thousand one.
And this is how the binary representation of nine would look like.
OK.
So I hope you understood the logic now and try to code it yourself.
And if you are stuck, then take the help from this tutorial.
So what I'm going to do? I am going to you take input n and I'm going to convert it into binary, OK?
And what I can do, I can say initially, the answer is zero.
The power is one.
And while this n is greater than zero I'm going to extract the last bit that is n and one.
And I'm going to add something to my answer.
So answer would be incremented by a value of power into  last bit.
And for the next iteration power will be multiplied with the 10.
Initially, it is one then ten, then ten sqaure and then 10 cube and n would be update as
a n right shift one.
That's it.
And we are done.
And from here, we can return the answer.
Let's build the code, so we can say cout, convert to binary and we give the input n here.
And now let us test over code weather it works fine or not.
So what we need to do is go to the terminal and I can say convert
Decimal to binary.
OK.
number is 10.
OK, so if I give ten as the input i get one zero one zero as the output  which is fine, if I give
15 then I get one one one which is the binary representation of this particular number.
That's all.
Thank you.