In this video, we will learn more about printing.
Remember, there is a life cycle that typically involves writing code, compiling it, running it to get
some results.
And also remember that we say that, there is a compiler that double checks if you have any compiler errors or not.
If there are any, it generates the compiler errors and stop at
this stage. There are actually two types of errors,
What we call compiler errors, as you know now.
It should be when you have a problem with the syntax rules of the compiling, of the language.
itself.
Another issue is (run-time) error.
Run-time error means, the syntax is very good
and we are running now the program
and somewhere in the middle of the program, the program crashes during running the program.
As an example for that, let's say that you run a program that divided by zero, which is totally wrong
and will cause the program to crash.
So compiler error before running, run-time error during running.
So the overall of the cycle, your code goes to the compiler, it double checks if you have any compiling errors.
If nothing, it generates a program,
we run the program and if any problem in the middle, it's must be a run-time error.
So compiler error, compiler.
runtime error during running.
So let's now go more in writing.
Let's say that I want to write the following three statements, "I am Mostafa", "I Was born in Giza",
"I graduated from Cairo University".
When you double check the console, you will notice an issue.
They are all printed in one line, but we actually want them to be on separate lines.
There are two ways to solve this issue.
One of them could be 'endl'  and another could '\n'
Let's see how to do that
Here,
Let's do something we call (code-tracing).
When the compiler sees 'cout', it knows it's going to print a message, it is expecting 2 less than '<<'
no space among them, then a message.
Now, the compiler printed
"I am Mostafa", semicolon ';' means the end of a message. In the second line it found itself printing but something
called 'endl', 'endl' is an abbreviation to "end line", it means to go one line down.
Once we go down we have another message that say, "I was born in Giza", It writes it
"I was born in Giza"
However there is here something called '\n', again
the compiler understands that as we are going to one line down here, finally there is a new message,
here,
"I graduated from Cairo university" and again 'endl', So the way to go to one new line is either you say 'endl'
which means "end line", or you put '\n', which is part of the message.
As you notice, the '\n' is very convenient because you just append it to your message. Let's write
this time in a different way.
I now wrote here more printing using the '<<', by the way we call it
an extraction operator.
Extraction operator.
So you see here we say 'cout' and then we say extraction operator "I am" and it's going to print "I am",
it finds  another extraction operator with a message "Mustafah".
So it prints "Mostafa", then another extraction operator with 'endl' so it goes to a new line.
Then another message, "I was born in Giza\n" and it goes to a new line, and again now here notice the statement is done
so, in this is statement we printed,
One, two, three, four, we printed four items, and again we are doing the same here and then here.
So you notice here that the trick here we can have more messages or more outputs attached to the same.
'cout' statement.
OK, let's go deeper.
We now, put all of them on the same line, all of them together.
So how many messages here?
How many printings that happened?
One, two, three, four, five, six.
So we put six messages on the same line. OK, this is the same as the code from the last time.
Exactly
We just put it on on several lines.
Notice there's only a single semicolon here so you can keep writing on different lines of code to make
it like more, say, visually readable, but using one semicolon here in the end.
So we saw cases, we were writing them on different statements with different semicolons.
And now as a one big statement with one semicolon. And even more, you can have them here as one big message
with more '\n'. How many printings happened here?
Only one printing.
OK, so every extraction operator, every '<<'
is going to print one thing, and here, it is one big message with several lines.
Your turn.
I would like you to start using my provided codes, play with them, and after that, try to remove
the whole code and start writing it from scratch.
You probably will do a lot of mistakes.
Start to compare my code with your code, and learn from that.
That's it! :)