In this video, we will discuss more printing notes.
Let's start right with tracing this code. The code says, 'cout', then prints something,
"I am Mostafa" and then it says 'return 0;'.
What does a 'return' statement mean?
A return statement is a message to the compiler that we are done.
So what does happen after the 'return' statement?
It is completely ignored.
So remember, if you put something after 'return', it is going to be ignored. '0' is a message to the running case
that everything was normal.
In the future, you should know that we can return different things to mean different errors.
So some messages come from what we're returning from here.
The second thing here, '//' this is something called a  (comment)
A comment is something that ignored by a compiler.
For example, here we see "I am Mostafa", then it's a new line then 'endl'.
So it goes to the next line.
And then "I was born in Giza\n", has a '//', that is a comment, so the compiler is ignoring it.
So why do you write comments?
We write comments to have some messages.
For example, you might write a note for your friend about what this good means.
There's another type of commenting which allows you to ignore a bigger scope.
Let's say you would like to ignore all of these lines of code.
Then you put here '/*', no spaces among them and end up with '*/' no space
between them.
Then the compiler is going to ignore all the text between of them.
Notice how Eclipse changes the color of this part to mean that it is a commented-code.
So far we just were learning about printing messages, but also we can print numbers.
So say here, we say 'cout<< 1;' just print the number 1, 12, 123
123 is a number.
OK, now here, when you print "123" as a message, this isn't a number.
So in C++, as we will know later and every programming language, there is something, what we call
(Data Type). The data type of 123 is something called integer.
It's a number.
Let's call it a number for now, and here "123"
Between double quotes,
It is a string.
OK, so while you see here
123 and 123
This actually was coming from a number, but this was coming from a message.
You can also have something like "15.7"
So fractions are supported.
You can also have something like a negative number, "-12"
This is a number, this is number.
Look here.
These two lines are printing almost the same number here.
But however, this is coming from one single number, but this is coming from two different numbers.
And finally, you can see here, printing a message followed by a number is just be like that.
So what to know here is that we can also print numbers, we can print messages and so on.
In addition to that, we can also make some math on numbers.
For example, if you printed (1+2+3+4), it is going to print for you "10", if you
put this equation, simple equation between double quotes "", it is going to be printed as a message. so you can
make things more advanced like
put "1+2+3+4" equals (1+2+3+4), for the compiler
this is between double quotes,
So it's going to be printed as it is.
And then this looks like math.
So It's going to sum it and print "10", so you can do more math and more math and so on.
"2*3*4 = ", is just 24.
You can divide 12 by 2, is going to give you 6.
You can divide 12 over 2 over 3.
Do it from left to right.
So 12 over 2 is 6.
6 over 3 is 2.
Now here's 6/2,
is 3, 7 over 2 is also 3!
This is very weird!
So one of the things that you should know about the programming language is when it comes to division,
are we dividing what we call "integers" or dividing what we are calling "double" or "float"?
What is a "double" or a "float", it is something that represents the fractions.
When you are doing a division between two things that are integers, an integer is something that doesn't
have this ".0" and ".0"
It doesn't have it.
If you did that, it's going to ignore the fraction part.
So if the operation is coming from fractions, the output is going to involve fraction.
if the input doesn't involve fraction style, the output would ignore the fraction part.
So actually,
7 divided by 2 is 3.5, but as these two numbers aren't in a fraction style,
It's just printing 3 and dropping the fraction style. We will learn more about that when we come
to the data types.
The last interesting thing here is we might multiply these 10s in each other to get this number.
But when we added one more 10, it gives us a very weird number.
This is called overflow.
Every, every...., There is a limit to your numbers in C++.
You cannot have very big numbers.
And in every language like that, there are some limitations.
We will know more about that later.
"Code Tracing"
Let's trace this code.
a tracing means you go over the code line by line and act like a compiler.
So when we say here
'cout <<'
It means that there is a message "If your dream only includes you, it's too small \n\n",
\n\n".
So it's going to print this message with one line empty and then another line.
So the message is going to be printed, go a line and then go another line.
Then, we sum some equations that ends up with zero then would print the string that is "70/10",
This is.
just a message.
Then we divide (80/10) which is eight, divided by 2 is 4.
Then every one of them has "\n" and this 'endl' then so everyone is in a separate line.
We started a new message starting with '\n', so we go one line below, then "opportunities don't happen".
"You create them".
So you have a new message here and then another 'endl'.
After that we have a comment,
It would be ignored and then another big comment would be ignored, then we return zero.
So the program is going to be ended now.
After that, there is a message that is going to be ignored by the compiler.
Code tracing is an important skill.
You should get used to that. To read the code and decide what the compiler will output before running it.
That's it for today!