In this video, we will highlight a lot of different errors that typically new programmers are doing in
their codes and it costs them a lot of pain and takes a lot of their time.
The first and very popular error here,
I would like you as a useful exercise,
try to stop the video with every screen and think for a while.
What's wrong here?
For example, if you thought about it, there is a missing semicolon here in the end of the message,
if you didn't figure out that by yourself, double check here.
The message.
It says here at this line, "there is an expected semicolon  ';' before return".
So here, a missing semicolon.
This is a very popular mistake.
Again, stop the video and try to figure it out by yourself, what's wrong. Here, if you notice, the user
did four '<<', which are wrong, and he did two,
This is good.
But there is a space here in between.
This is wrong.
Violating the C++ syntax.
It should be exactly the extraction operator '<<'.
Here we want to print a message, we say double quote, "I am Mostafa", and then we forgot another quote.
So it's saying, "missing terminating double quote character".
One of the very useful thing to do is to get used to the type of the error messages from the C++ compiler.
Over time,
Once you see the message, you know
what is wrong.
Here we wrote our normal, very C++ code, but we forgot the two braces '', remember, the braces are
where we write the body of the code.
Another mistake here is that we forgot to (#include iostream), iostream is one that gives us the
capability to write using 'cout', and later to read using 'cin'
Here we use a word 'MAIN' with capital letters.
So now here it says, "undefined reference to main". when we run our C++ program, the compiler
goes and searches for a function named 'main' with a lowercase letters.
It must be that way ('main').
C++ is a case-sensitive language.
Everything is good here, but we put our 'cout' statement outside the 'main' function, outside these braces
and this is wrong.
There are a few things that we can put here outside the braces.
There is nothing wrong in this code. This code doesn't have a compiler error,
It has what we call a compiler warning.
This code is missing a 'return' statement. A 'return' statement that tells the compiler that we are done and the
status of ending the program, here, we are missing it.
We still can run this program. As an advice,
If there is a compiler warning, double check it and solve it.
Another mistake here, we highlighted that before in our first program, if we multiply all of these numbers,
it is going to work well.
But if we added one extra 10 here, it says that there is an integer overflow.
So, a new concept here to learn, is the "overflow".
Imagine that you have a cup of water and you keep filling it with water.
It's eventually going to be dropped outside, right?
So an integer, every data type is like a cup,
It has a limit,
It has a maximum,
It has also minimum.
The maximum value for an integer is this number.
In future, you should know why, it's 2 powered to something. If you try to add more than
this number, it will be like this water.
It will just fail. Similar to the the overflow,
there is another concept called "underflow", where you cannot put below a specific minimum value, but you will
see this later.
So far we saw the compiler errors and compiler warnings.
Remember, the compiler error and warnings are something that happens on the code level before running.
it.
If everything is OK, we just run the code.
But there might be what we call a "runtime error".
This is due to something wrong with your logic. Here,
If you see in the line number seven, we are dividing by zero, dividing by zero will cause the
program to crash. here,
The program is going to print the first line, crash in the second line and nothing will be here.
And even 'return 0' will not be reached.
OK, this is a nice reading.
Just give it a try.
That's it!
I hope by informing you about a lot of the potential mistakes that new guys do, then you can save a
lot of your time.
You have two tasks today.
First, try to create all of the errors we did today by yourself, try to introduce more errors by yourself,
and then look to the messages, read them, learn them.
If you couldn't figure out, just Google it and so on.
That's it! :)