In this video, we will have our first real homework about printing. One of the main promises in this course
is that you gain a lot of skills. And the way that you will gain these skills is mainly through
solving and practicing a lot,
comparing your solution with the provided solution. Homework will be ranging from easy to
hard.
So take it easy when it comes to hard problems and don't get disappointed. In the first program,
you are giving this simple program. You are requested to trace it.
So, line by line, go over it and decide what would be printed in the runtime.
In your second program, you write something to print this triangle using Asterix '*' and spaces.
This is another triangle in homework 3. And homework 4,
it is more like a diamond.
So these are your four homework.
Finally, you are to identify all the possible errors that you can find in this code,
fix all of them.
You will find the code inside the unit.
So download it and start to fix one by one.
That is it. :)