We are like halfway in the OOP, so it's a good time to make some summary to enforce what we already
learned so far.
So we discussed that OOP is a paradigm,
it isn't the only paradigm that we have,
and in OOP, we are very centralized around the objects and the relationships. So far,
we studied the following concepts: class object, encapsulation, data hiding, and abstraction,
and also, we saw a lot of C++ syntax about class, and what it takes to apply it in a proper way.
The remaining concepts are mainly something called inheritance and polymorphism, these are the other
two concepts in the OOP diagram. There is also something called
operator overloading. It isn't OOP,
it's more about making OOP looks like a more beautiful code.
There are also, as we said in the, remember, the initial triangle, there is also OOP principles
and OOP design patterns. OOP principles are very critical. In the homework, I already embedded
many of them like the single responsibility principle, open-closed principle,
don't repeat yourself principle,
you aren't gonna need.
So this already was embedded in the homework.
Also, we discussed the design patterns and how they are more repetitive tasks. In the homework,
I also stressed 2 design patterns, the singleton design pattern and the wrapper design pattern.
When I say that these guys were in the homework, they definitely weren't explained to you.
So the point was to let you find them and identify them to some extent by yourself.
When you come to study more about the principles and design patterns, it should be much easier
process.
I think the OOP courses that just teach programming and the design are wrong like it's very
useful in the early stage to expose students to the principles and patterns and a lot of design issues,
so that they keep consider it during the project's implementation.
We also discussed the differences between OOA and OOP and OOD and the difference when it comes to a small
project and a big project, and what could be applied and what code it?
The encapsulation, as you remember, is more about let's get together the variables and
the functions together.
One interesting thing about data hiding that it reduces the complexity.
So as an external user for a class like a search engine in Google, you don't know about most of
the hidden implementation.
You don't know about it.
You just care about what is provided for you,
and here data-hiding comes for us to tell us there is public and there is private and the user only
see the public part, and all the private part is hidden for me.
We discussed that
how this reduces the complexity also
and as an advice design tip, it is good to reveal as little as possible your data members and functionality.
So your public interface with the others can see should be much less, very focused, very simplified
exactly like the search engine in Google,
we are just searching for something and getting back the results.
That abstraction is a very fundamental concept in OOP.
We see how the getters and setters play a role in that,
and we also learned about providing getters and setters in everything.
So you have to think twice, make sure your class is doing its own job,
you don't force others to try to do a lot of getters to do something
that you are missing as a critical functionality.
So it's also a good design tip to depend on them inside the class.
Sometimes the developers would be afraid from that because calling a function is a bit slower than just
using a variable directly.
However, the good thing is there are a lot of hidden compiler optimizations that improve the time
alot.
Remember, depending on the variable on the getters and setters internally in the class would save your
time if you decided to change the layout of the class.
We talked about separating the implementation,
we talked about two perspectives, separating the WHAT from HOW and also separating the WHAT in header
file and the HOW in an implementation file so that in the future you can fix the bugs or introduce
new implementations in a smooth way.
Abstraction is all about hiding and also showing considering some context, we highlighted the three
items.
Then we move to the C++ class features to stress the different concepts that we have. A constructor
is something that helps us to create the objects, focus on the initializer list, avoid the default
initialization.
Remember that constructors are code-based on the class data members, not the order of the initializer
list. We have a homework about that.
The destructor mainly is executed, when an object goes out of the scope like out of the
function or deleted, and so on.
The critical usage of the destructor is when we have a memory to deallocate.
So whenever we have pointers, we should provide destructors.
Destructors are called in the reverse order of constructors,
but remember, static objects are there till the end of the program.
So don't mix the destruction order of the normal objects with static objects.
In addition, we know about the copy constructor, and it's very critical mainly when you have internal
pointers.
The copy constructor helps you to make a deep copy
not a shallow copy.
Be very careful with memory leaks.
When you create a pointer, delete it. If you created a pointer inside the class,
this class is supposed to delete it.
If a pointer was created outside the class, who created it should remove it.
If you removed a pointer, it is very useful to put all of the null pointer for it.
Be careful from deleting a pointer twice, which is causing a runtime error.
That it.