Let's continue our summary. The class features, remember, using const functions are very important.
Try to maximize the number of the const function that you have.
Remember, the principle of least privilege.
If someone doesn't need some permission, then just don't give it to him.
If a function wasn't expected to change a variable, just make it const and forbid others to make a
change for it.
Remember that the const member variables must be initialized in the initializer-list, but it's better to
avoid them due to some performance issues. In function parameters, use const and reference as much
as possible and convenient.
This saves time in memory.
It also shares an intention that you are telling someone there is no change for this parameter.
So if you pass for me a parameter to my function, don't worry, I'm not going to change it.
Remember that static variables are declared once, they are in memory till the program ends.
They are also shared access among whoever access it. The static functions shared among
all objects,
but they cannot access data members because they aren't normal functions. The
only access, the static variables.
So static functions access, static variables.
Remember the friend, we have a friend class, a friend member function, and a friend global function.
The class here can access everything. Here
only this function can access the private section, and the global function can access only the private
section.
The usage of the friend should be limited and should be reasonable because it might corrupt your
OOP concepts and OOP implementation.
Let's highlight some general tips.
Remember, the temporary objects, an object doesn't have a name, and one of the main rules that you cannot
bound to an a non-const reference.
A good class is responsible for one concern.
This is a single responsibility principle.
There should be one reason to change it.
For example, let's say you have an email service that supports the retrial feature.
There is some logging, there are some caching features.
Every one of these is a reason for a change, and every one of them would need a lot of code.
There are four reasons now to change this code.
This isn't good. You have to find a way to separate these different features into different classes. Avoid
duplication,
otherwise, if there is a bug in some code, you will have to fix it in several locations.
Move to common functions or use templates
like the standard library. Use context to decide relevant features in a class, so that you know
what you can put and what you shouldn't. Use
available functionalities, don't duplicate your work. STL provide for you,
for example, the Date class, provides for you sorting function, and so on.
If there is some available open-source code, go ahead, experiment with it.
If you found it good, you might use it,
but be careful.
For example, do you need to have it?
and so on.
If a feature has a getter and setter use them. This is better. Remember the time class 2 representations,
if we changed one of them, we change a lot
in the code. Also take care of correctness.
When you have a function or a constructor that takes a parameter, make sure that you verify the parameters
and don't duplicate the code for verification.
You might have a single function and all of whoever needs to verify, just is calling it.
Remember the delegation like delegation in the constructor, if there is an object or function should
do a task,
you just give it to this task.
Testing is very important.
When you start to test your work, you will discover a lot of hidden errors.
So provide at least a black box testing for your work so that you are sure that it is working fairly
well.
It is important to provide a clear and maintainable code.
Don't just write a code.
Think twice if the person who is reading your code would find it easy or not. Avoid local variable names
with the same name as data members
like if you have a price variable in data members and a price variable in your function, this clash will make problems for
you.
We also highlighted the Singleton design pattern, which mainly is a private constructor plus a static
function to get the static instance.
We highlight also the iterator design pattern, which has hast_next, get_next, reset iterator. Later,
you should restudy them again with further details and notes, but it's good to be exposed to them that
early.
When coding, do printing in all constructors and destructors. Why? this would give you a hint about who
is being called and who is being destructive.
It is very good for heavy classes to prevent the copy constructor and assignment operator.
The purpose of that is for you to notice if there is something being copied and you didn't expect that,
but support them later if needed.
This is at least how I start coding my own objects.
I initially make sure the copy constructor isn't allowed so that I prevent any unintentional
code that is making a copy from some object
and I don't notice that. One is the logic is that you can move the copy constructor to the private section,
but C++11 give us a good way to do that.
Let's say you have a class named user.
You can say user const user reference equal delete.
It means to delete the copy constructor. To the assignment operator,
remember, this is an equal assignment operator like Y equal X object.
You just write this line, void
Yeah, void operator equals const user reference equal delete.
I know that you don't know operator overloading so far.
So this is weird syntax, but for now, it just going to forbid this kind of assignment. Again,
assignments like copy constructors may be a problem if you don't notice that about pointers.
Yeah, that's all so I hope this midway in OOP, you realized how hard to build a proper design and
that following the best practice takes time. I also would like to warn you about something.
I was a software engineer for like six years.
The local market has a lot of weak software engineers.
These engineers didn't put time into mastering basics.
So don't be one of them because after three or four years in the market, you will find yourself facing
difficulties.
It's very important to be very good in OOP, in basic programming skills, in algorithms, in data
structures.
Don't be the guy who just jumps directly to android or front development or backend development.
This is a fatal mistake.
Also, remember that any skill takes time, it needs a lot of practice and practice and practice. Practice is
the only way to make it perfect.
I did my best in this project to provide a lot of practice so that you have the chance to improve your
skills as much as possible.
That's it.