In this video, I would like to communicate some of my experience with OOP projects in practice.
The first thing is and remember, skills takes time.
You also need to do it in a gradual way.
So do not try to learn a skill the hard way, like don't a big project before doing a medium project,
and don't do a medium project before doing a small project.
OK, going back to projects, it's very important to start with the requirements, the functional requirements
coming from a customer.
One of the big problems is just to jump to solving or coding a project that you don't completely
understand. There is something in industry
we call it minimum viable product.
What does this mean?
Let's say someone has an idea about startup, and let's say there are like 20 different features in
this product.
There are two choices.
The first choice is, and this is a bad choice to collect a team, implement the 20 choice in a
couple of years and go to the market,
and then you might have a sudden shock that most of the people don't have an interest in your application.
There is another way you figured out the major use cases in your system.
The word use case is a fundamental word in software engineering.
It refers to the functionalities that the user is doing in the system.
So in a shopping cart system, you might add an item to the shop, you might add your credit card, you might
pay, and so on.
So when you figured these minimum use cases that are major, you are building a minimum viable product.
An MVP product is a product that has, say, the best five features out of the 20, but we still
can release number one from it to the customers and see their impression. If they liked it, then
we add more features.
Otherwise there is no need to go more in the project.
So one approach is to implement 20 features in a couple of years.
Another one is to implement the best five features in six months, for example.
So how was that would be helpful when you are building your own projects?
The idea is, let's say that you frame a project to implement.
I would encourage you to identify the MVP of this idea and then start to implement it.
This is what I meant by gradual here.
Take the project, implement a very small version of it, and then in an iterative way, add more and
more features for it.
Sometimes when the students know about a project, they just get stuck, and they don't know how to start,
and how to proceed.
The right idea is to figure out the major use cases and just go with them.
OK, so here are some fundamental steps.
When you are done with what exactly to implement, what exactly features to consider.
The first idea is identify the key objects.
These will be your own classes.
For example, in a parking lot, it might be a vacant, parking spot, parking garage, entrance, exit,
garage operators.
This might be your major classes in the system.
After that, start to consider the operations that every object is providing.
For example, Car should be able to move, park in a given spot, and hold the license plate.
A parking spot should be able to accommodate a two to four wheeled vehicle, for example, to be
able to have a truck in it.
After that, you identify the relationships like a car should be able to park in the parking lot spot,
parking garage to be able to fit multiple parking spots.
You start to figure out that.
So key objects, key operations, key relationships.
This is how you go in your project.
There is something standard in the industry, we call it crud operations. Crud is for create, read,
update and delete operations.
These are four basic functions of persistent storage.
If you are dealing with databases, then these are the four things that we typically might need.
Think about it.
Let's say that we have a book manager.
We might need to create a book, load a book, update a book, delete a book.
So these four operations are very standard, and we use them all the time.
The third thing about structuring your code. One very interesting way to structure your code is the
model view structure.
What is that?
The model is mainly focusing on the database, business logic.
For example, focus on the user and the user manager and so on.
You don't print inside the model.
This is more of the of the core logic of the system.
The view is what takes care of the printing, what takes care of visualizing.
There is no logic here.
So the logic in the model but not printing, and the view is printing but no logic.
For example, you in the View, ask the user manager to get update things for you.
Now this separation for viewing code from the logic code.
You will notice in the old projects there was a mix between viewing and logic,
but this isn't the proper way to do it.
The proper way is to split as much as you could. In practice,
this makes the development as much as easy.  This is very close to an idea
we call it the MVC architectural pattern.
It is something to learn in deep in the future.
The last thing I would like to highlight here is about the front-end and back-end.
This is a probably a key word that you hear.
We have front-end developers, and we have back-end developers.
Front-end is more about the view,
and back-end is more about the model and the business logic and business data.
Some guys in the market are front-end developers,
some of them are back-end developers, and some of them are fullstak.
They do the two tasks. Anyway back to the idea, focus on the view, on the viewing no logic, and focus on
the model, on the logic, not the view.
That's it.
Consider that during development your projects.