In this section, we will start to know about polymorphism, which is one of the strongest features in OOP.
Let's trace this code. We have here a class person which has a constructor and a destructor,
and a class student which is extending from a person with a print function and destructor.
Now, let's define a person object and a student object.
If we did person dot print, everything goes well, and it goes to the print and just prints student.
Sorry as a person. If we printed as a student, it also goes to the student and prints student.
so far, so good.
Let's create some pointers.
The first pointer here is pointing to the reference of the person and its type person pointer.
The second pointer here is of type student and its reference to student.
OK, so drop these two lines for now.
Let's make these two printing.
Everything is still OK.
Here is a problem.
At line 25,
we take a reference to the student, but we put it in the person pointer, or we created a new student and
put it in the person pointer.
We saw something like that in the homework.
So what is happening here is we are using a pointer of type parent to point to an instance of the type child.
Semantically,
this is valid because a student is a person.
So we can easily in c++ logic,
we create a pointer of type parent looking to the child.
This is OK, but where is the problem.
If we started to call the pointer print, it goes and prints person, it doesn't print student.
This is very counterintuitive because here in line 24 when we have a pointer of the type student,
in reference student, the printing function is calling printing a student,
but if we took it in a person pointer, and we call print, it is going to print in the person, not on the student.
So what does this mean?
It means that the member function is called based on the pointer type.
So if you use a pointer of type student, it will call a student.
If you use the pointer type of person, it will type person.
Let's say you now would like to delete your pointer number three here.
Remember that the destructor is just a function.
So if you are treating here this function, which one would be called the function
that would be called if this person called?
But this one is created in memory.
There is undefined behavior here and potentially a memory leak that you would face.
So the rule here is now so far, the member function is called based on the pointer type.
So you have to be careful about what is a pointer target,
and here is where the virtual function comes.
The virtual keyword is what makes for us the polymorphism.
So the rule so far is, as we know, if we have an object that isn't reference, isn't a pointer, we call
it, then the right thing would be called like we see here in the student person,
they are non reference, no pointers,
so they would be normal printing.
And also we know the second rule that the member function is called based on the pointer type.
If we used the keyword virtual,
when we will mark a function with virtual, we are actually calling based on the right object, the drived
one, not the base one.
So here we are creating a student pointer, putting it in a person pointer.
If we called the print function, it will call the student, not the person.
So, again, the virtual keyword, if we put it, we will call based on the actual object, not the
used pointer type,
but if we removed the virtual keyword and make a call, it will call based on the pointer type.
So one case will call the person class itself.
Another case will call based on the created object itself.
If we use the virtual, we get this property.
If this function is virtual and we overridded here, it would be virtual also, even if we did not write
the word virtual.
So someone is extending from a student, then print would be also a virtual function.
The word virtual means exist in appearance, but not in reality.
That's why when we put a virtual here, this will not be the function that would be called.
It is actually the function here that would be called.
OK, what if
no, I would like in an explicit way to make a call to this function,
then you can use this operator to just make the explicit call.
This property is very fundamental in virtual function.
That's it for today.