There are two ways of casting like we can do up costing, and we can do down costing. When I have a
hierarchy like for example, an employee who is extending from a person, if I am costing the object
of an employee to the object of person, which is very safe and very normal, and for the inheritance we
call it up costing like we are going from bottom to top,
but on the other side, if you have to cast the parent class to the child class, we call this
down casting.
Now, there's a problem here.
Suppose polymorphism is about generic code.
If I have a class that's working on a shape pointer, for example, I shouldn't have at some point
of time to start to cast the shape to circle to check something with a circle and cast it to a rectangle
to check something with the rectangle.
If I started to do that inside the function, then it depends on the current shapes,
and at the moment that I have to add one more shape,
I have to go to this place where I have to do If-Else's. Is it a circle, is it a shape, is it a triangle to
add one more for is it polygon or not.
So the moment that you have to do downcasting from your parent to your child, something is wrong in
your design most of the cases.
Why did this happen? Typically because our designs are imperfect, or we are facing very difficult requirements
and this is our best to do it.
There are a bit few rare cases when such downcasting is a proper way.
For example, if your class like let's say an employee class, you are receiving
a generic object and you are just casting it to one specific  child class which is now the
employee, for example.
So nothing is wrong about that.
But when you have to do a lot of If-else's, is it a rectangle, is it a triangle, is it a circle?
Something is wrong.
So anyway, let's say this again.
Downcasting is about casting the parent class to child class. There are two casting styles in C++.
...
One of them is named static and the other is named dynamic. The static happened in the compile time,
and it is fast but not save. The dynamic one
happened in the runtime,
It's a bit slow, but save.
So what does this mean?
The static type isn't safe.
It means if there is some wrong conversion, then you might face a problem in the runtime or even
get an earlier compile error. In the runtime,
If you tried to make a wrong conversion, you will get always a null pointer.
Let's see some code for that.
So this is a class A and then B is inheriting from A, C is inheriting from A, D is inheriting from
...
You have here a Class B, which is a child class that is now saved in a pointer for a parent class.
Now, I would like to cast this A pointer back to B pointer.
So this is a syntax of casting.
You write
static cast.
You write here
the destination, which is the B pointer, and you give it to the pointer itself.
Now, thinking about this conversion, is this a proper conversion?
The answer is yes because B is a child of A, and we are sure of that.
If we did this static casting, everything will be OK.
Now, on the other side, let's say I would like to cast this B pointer originally to C pointer.
...
This is wrong
conversion, C and B aren't related.
You shouldn't cast them.
However, the compiler is going to let you go thinking that this is a proper conversion, but it will
not be, and this C object will not be a null pointer, and you are going to use it, and your program is going
to crash.
So this is what's wrong about static cast if you aren't sure of what you're doing.
The last case is if you tried to cast B pointer to D, the compiler will be smart in this case and
notice that there is really no relationship between D and B, so it's going to give you anyway a compiler error.
So in static casting, if the compiler can figure out that this is wrong, it will tell you.
If it cannot figure, it is going to give you the wrong pointer, and your program is going to crash.
So When to do exactly static
cast? do casting using static casting
if you are really sure that this is a proper conversion, otherwise you are risking with your
program, and this is where the dynamic has to come to the scene, you just replace it with dynamic cast
here and start to use the same syntax.
If it is a valid conversion, the compiler is giving you a valid pointer.
If it is an invalid one, there would be no compiler errors because the answer to this one happens in
the runtime.
There is something that called runtime information.
So in runtime, we go to this and make sure of the original pointer.
If it is correct one, we're going to cast it.
If not, we're going to give you a null pointer.
So if you double-check, if this is a null point or not, then you are in
the safe side. If you are unsure about the conversions that are happening, then you should go with
dynamic casting. Remember, using both the static cast and dynamic cast isn't healthy most of the time.
If you have to do it, probably something wrong with your design, you may better take time to think
how to make your design more propper than just doing dynamic casting or static casting.
Do not use the static casting unless you are sure that this is a propper casting, otherwise, go with just dynamic
casting,
and double check is it a null pointer or not. That's it.