In this video, you would know about what is happening behind the scene in polymorphism using something
named virtual table.
This video has no effect on your programming skills,
It just more understanding what's happening behind the scenes.
Remember, we once in early begin, we took these A, B, C, D, E classes and we started to do tracing to
this virtual, virtual,
who is virtual and what is it?
and then we started these
functions here to decide which function really is going to be called on the runtime,
so we can easily guess that.
We just don't know because if you know the classes exactly types, you can actually
know who is going to be called eventually even in a compilation time,
right?
but we know the actual behavior would happen in the runtime itself.
So what happened behind the scene is the combiner actually is going to read your classes and determines
the following:
It goes for every class in your inheritance hierarchy, and for every function is going to check
which is really the actual function that we will
call in a case of polymorphism.
So let's say you have four virtual functions, it is going to create a table of four entries and put for
every virtual function which a function is really going to be called in the polymorphism time.
Now, each class has an internal pointer to this table.
We call it vptr,
It is in the base class and protected, so inherited by other subclasses.
So now, your class has a hidden pointer vptr to this virtual table, and this virtual table has a number
of entries equal to the number of virtual functions in your classes.
So if you have five classes that are virtual, then you have five tables, and every table will have a number
of virtual function corresponds to its total number of virtual functions.
For example, in the runtime, if we have a function d1, f1 as you see in the code, the
first thing the compiler says "Is a special function?" then yes, it first get the pointer that we have
inside the D's table because it is inherited here and then gets the function D f1 from the table to
see which one should be called and then just calls it.
You have to do nothing with any of that,
the compiler is doing all of that for you.
So here is little understanding of that.
I want to mention that virtual table takes a little extra time in memory,
so it's now time to know why this happened.
Let's say that we have class A that has a single variable.
Notice that this class has nothing virtual here.
If you tried to print the size of (which is an operator to get the size) of A is going to say typically
four bytes,
It depends on your operating system,
but anyway, let's say four bytes.
They are mainly four bytes of this number.
Now, class B has only also single number, but it has a virtual function.
Now, if you tried to print to the size of B, it's going to be greater than 4. Why?
Because this class has a hidden pointer.
Let's name it vptr. It is to the virtual table that involves where are my hidden functions.
So now this is why there is little extra memory here because that extra pointer here, and also there
is another table that has an entry pair a virtual function.
One final administration for that.
Let's say that you have a class base with two functions f1 and f2, and D1 is extending from
base and D2 is extending from the base.
Now, these two functions are virtual
so we will have three tables.
So we have here table one, table two, table three,
and this is class one, class two, class three.
Now, thinking about D1, if we are calling function one and it's virtual, then function one is
going to call D1 function one,
but if we are calling function two, D1 has no function here, so it has to go to
the base class.
So now in terms of the actual performance in reality, so ..., here is D1 class,
and here's its table.
If you are calling for the function one, it is going to call the function one
of the class D1,
but if you are calling function two, it has to call the base function 2. In a similar way,
Let's say you have D2. D2 has no f1,
so the actual performance of f1 is going to the base f1, but the actual performance of f2 is added to D2.
...
So now here is the virtual table of D2, and here is the table of the class of the D2.
If you are calling function one, it has to call the function one of the base class.
So the pointer of function one is pointing to this function, but the pointer function two is pointing to this
function.
So anyway, the moral of that is we have a vptr pointer in the base, which is inherited in these
classes. We have three tables, and we have three classes, and each table has a number of entries equal
to the number of virtual functions,
and each function is pointing to what is going to be called really in practice.
That's it.
I hope the arrows don't confuse you, and you have nothing to do with this.
It's just all the compilation time.
That's it.