I wanted to share with you something that you typically don't see in books and courses, but it's
more of like coming from my industrial perspective. So we can see the polymorphism in some of scenarios
for the APIs and frameworks.
So the first thing is what is an API?
The word API is application programming interface.
The word interface here has the same context as when we were talking about the interfaces of our classes.
Let's define it in a formal way.
The API is something that intermediary.
It's something in between two things, two applications that would like to communicate together.
Let me give you an example of that.
Let's say that there are facebook guys who have their back end and their backend has like, say, 200
functionalities.
The Facebook guys would like to provide your mobile application with capabilities of communicating with
their systems.
So here is what it is going. They are going to define
two things.
First, they are going to build what we call a messenger API, for example,
and this would be, for example, let's say have 20 functions out of only the 200 functions in the
backend.
So now this api is an interface of only 20 functions.
Now, they are also going to build a mobile application on Android and iOS, and Android is going to contact
the API and the API is going to facilitate your queries or transfer your queries to the backend.
So as you see here, the API is in the middle between two things,
your application here, who is calling this guy.
So this happens a lot
in reality. Someone has a service, very big service, and then it provides you with some interface
to contact to make a call like Google, for example, you might have an application API that allows you
to contact Google to get some say, some research results, and so on.
This typically with remote APIs, you have to make a communication,
you have to send a request and you get a response saying JSON or so.
So this is a simple figure to represent that.
This is, let's say, the data sources server, server with some processing for Facebook.
...
This is a provided API.
So the API is now like a gateway like an external world.
This is your application
code.
You are contacting the messenger API, which is contacting the backend, and then we are returning back
the response to the customer.
So API is something in between two applications in the middle to facilitate communication.
We don't let people access directly all of our functionalities.
They use this API, which is providing a few specific functionalities.
Now, let me highlight for you two popular cases
when it comes to APIs. The first is a payment APIs.
So let's say that you have maybe a website for shopping for some superstore or some supermarket online
for some items to ship, something like Amazon or so.
So the user eventually have to pay money.
Now, there are a lot of banks, and you have your own credit card.
So there are two paths here.
The first one is I'm going to build my own code to contact bank HSBC and another code to contact the
bank of TD blah, blah, blah, and so on, to do these payments by myself.
So now the problem here is that this is very time-consuming.
Now, there is another idea.
There are companies who provide some payment APIs.
So by that, they are providing you an interface that you can contact to say, please withdraw from this
user information, credit card information or so,
this kind of money. Behind the scene, they are implementing their own software to contact whatever
to get money, or retrieve money, and so on.
Now, the idea here, you as your code, don't need to worry about the hassle of payments.
You just contacted the API of one of the payments, let's say Paypal or I think it's named Stripe,
and just to use it.
In terms of services, these APIs are going to charge your company something like, say, if you are
using Paypal, it will tell you that with every transaction I am going to take zero point
one dollars per transaction,
for example. Thinking about the functionalities of these APIs, you will notice that all of these
payment APIs will typically be very similar.
They need, for example, your customer, user's information like a credit card, name, expiry, and so
on,
but they might have different API styles because every one of them is defining his own API style.
So this is one example.
If you go to here, you can see the top API services.
Another popular example is airline APIs.
If you go to something like Expedia.com, and you give it like I would like to go from Cairo to Vancouver,
you will notice that Expedia is listing airlines trips from everywhere, like maybe from Canadian
Airlines, Turkish Airline, Lufthansa Airlines.
So how does Expedia retrieve back these results?
Expedia behind the scene is conducting the API of the Turkish Airlines to get the information for your
trip and contacting the Lufthansa API to get the information of Lufthansa. So I'm calling the website
of Expedia and the Expedia is calling many websites and APIs getting results their server and then presenting
them for you.
Now, thinking about polymorphism and APIs.
Now, let's say I'm going to save my own time, I'm going to depend on
Paypal, for now, to allow paying money through my website.
Now, if you decided to directly start to use the API of Paypal in your code, let's say that suddenly
Paypal guys got crazy, and they made it like one dollar per transaction.
So now they are really seriously very, very expensive.
OK, so the guys from Square API are providing something with zero point two dollars per API, or even
they are providing faster APIs.
Now, I would like to switch from using Paypal to use Square or Stripe or whatever.
Now here is the problem.
If you coded your code to depend on the Paypal code, it is going to be very coupled with it.
...
So you have to do a lot of code changes to facilitate the payments.
So here is the idea.
You are going to define your own internal interface for payments like let's say we are our company and
we are going to just provide some abstract interfaces for us, and let all of your code depends
on these interfaces.
Now, define internally some implementation that inherits your interfaces and just implement
Paypal communication and other interfaces for Stripe that calls Stripe and a third one for Square
API that calls square.
Now, if you would like to switch from Paypal to Square APIs, all you have to do is to get now a
new object of type Paypal, which is internally calling the Paypal operations or Square operations, and so on.
...
But the moral of that is your code depends on your internal interfaces,
it doesn't depend on the API of the Paypal itself.
So now you decoupled your code from the dependency on the Paypal API.
Your code knows nothing about Paypal and knows nothing,
I mean here by your code, your website, your part that needs the payments,
It doesn't need to know about Paypal,
It doesn't need to know about the future added payment service, it just knows about its owner interface,
and you are providing different implementations for these interfaces.
Think like you have a shape class, and now you have a rectangle,
in the future you have a triangle, then you have polygon,
but your process function knows the shape, it doesn't know about the rectangle, it doesn't know about
the triangle,
knows nothing about them.
This is how we provide a generic code. In the homework and the project, there will be administrations for that.
The last thing to inform also about: there are other terms that you might hear in the career like library.
Think always in the library like in STL so in STL like you have data structures and you have functions
that is ready for you, sort, vector, map, and so on.
There is also what we call SDK. SDK is a collection of tools,
all of them are gathered to you together in one unit.
Now, what I want to highlight here is the framework.
A framework is a group of libraries typically involving what we call inversion of control pattern.
I once highlighted this inverse of control.
Remember, in the shape class, there was a compute area function and the compute area function was calling
the child class that it knows nothing about it.
So here is what happens really in framework.
The framework is typically a big pipeline of different steps of classes or operations.
Let's name them A, B, abstractC, D, and E. The pipeline step of A and B, let's say they are classes
are well defined, they are implemented for you.
D and E are also implemented for you.
The problem, they cannot know what is C now. what happened in the framework is you are going to implement only
the C by yourself.
Now notice here, who is going to call
your C? the framework itself.
So who has the control.
The control is in the hand of
the framework, it is going to call A, then B, then your code C, then D, then E.
This is what we call an inverse of control, and the default code, your code is like the master.
So typically, let's say your code is called a library
so you are in control here,
but on the other side, the framework is calling your code.
This is the inverse of the flow.
OK, so this is what is a framework.
it's also a bunch of big libraries, but it has some flow, and you are somewhere in the middle.
You only implement this middle step.
So in practice, that's why the frameworks and web frameworks and backend frameworks are very strong and
very popular because you write like 10 percent of the code, and all of the remaining pipline is common
and shared and ready for you.
That's it.
A more relevant word for the word interfaces is the user interface.
We also here see like there are four interfaces, web interface, mobile interface, desktop
Interface, we call it GUI. This isn't our job in the market to do UI/UX,
but also this also involves the word interface
so you provide interfaces for the people. That's it.