So going back to the composition and inheritance issue. Once mentioned the inheritance
and how many troubles could start to happen, especially with the multiple-inheritance. Composition
as I said before, is a way to go in the industry.
If something is doable with composition, then just go ahead.
Now, we know about polymorphism, interfaces, and abstract classes.
So the proper way to do the composition in the market is more of the composition with interfaces.
So it doesn't depend on a composition of a specific object
like you have a car, you don't say just car has a class of engine.
You say a class has as an object of type interface of like let's name it IEngine, and there will
be some different implementation for this engine.
So we typically utilize the composition with the interfaces to resolve the dependencies and to avoid
inheritance as possible,
but when you tried to switch a lot of things that are more involved with composition to inheritance,
it might not be like very intuitive.
The good news is the more you learned design patterns, the more you will notice how things might
be switched from some inheritance hierarchy to some composition style.
For example, the decorator pattern can help us to avoid the explosion that we saw before in the class hierarchy.
...
So still there is something about it,
the negative side. We typically have to write more code for two things: we have to do more code to
handle the composition itself as a logic, maybe more wraps, and delegates.
In addition, we have to write more code to create instances of our intermediate classes,
and this is where something named factory pattern very simple and intuitive comes to the scene.
So that's all,
just keep in mind, try to make things with more composition as you could,
and this would typically involve some interfaces and polymorphism. Polymorphism itself
needs some inheritance, but when we tried to build  proper polymorphism specifically with interfaces,
we don't intend to make very deep hierarchical inheritance or multiple-inheritance, it is more of something
that allow the polymorphic performance and behavior.
Finally, I would like to share with you something like the design intentions when I design class and mark
a function as a non-virtual function.
I'm sending a message to others that this is almost a mandatory implementation,
do not overwrite, OK, but I still can override and call it.
This is true, but it will fail in polymorphic behavior.
So if you do that in polymorphism, you are going probably to lose it.
The worst is you will not notice that you are losing it,
so it would be more of like a bug in your code and you don't notice that.
So if someone is providing a non-virtual function, do not implement it, just use the given implementation,
Otherwise, make sure this will be called in polymorphism  set approach,
typically, It will be hard. As a better tip
also, mark this function with final, if you would like. If you are the creator of that, mark it
with final to prevent such mistake for others like you are telling them, hey, do not override
this one. On the other side, when you provide the virtual function, you are sending
a message like this is currently a default implementation,
but you as a child class you are welcome to write your own implementation. For
a good coding
also, you are suggested to write virtual and overwrite keywords in this function.
If you provided a pure virtual function, you are sending a message also like, hey, I don't know how to
implement the implementation of this function,
for example, the area in shape class.
Sometimes you are just acting more like an interface function as we said before in interfaces
like properties, for example, or even any interface.
You just telling like you know what you have to think
and implement this by yourself.
That's it.