For the second set of homework in the Baltimore office, which might be a little hard for you, the
first one is an extended company payroll.
Remember, we had a previous assignment about the company.
Now we'd like to add validation rules.
I understand that your background may not help you in that in practice we may need to verify invoices
like let's say there's an invoice that is right now is now out of date with some of our views, like
we have some deals with suppliers.
And when it come to the time of the invoice, it's actually turned out to be invalid.
Invoice board, for example, the Texas computer for the invoice is wrong because there are some advantages
in this country that the invoice didn't take and why.
So you can think there are several validation rules and in future there could be even more and more
validation rules.
So we need to verify the invoice using a set of rules.
And we need generic handling because the future will be more and more religion groups.
Let's say also there is something we call it very little group, which is a subset of the available
available validation rules.
For example, let's say we could add 20 different variations.
Good.
There might be like a mandatory validator that is just running the three of them.
There might be another one like, let's say the complete 180 or just run all of them and so on.
So there could be different subsets and invoice must pass all the validation rules.
And one of the little group.
So let's say the current system is configurable to use the for example, the mandatory creditor, which
is three rules or so, then the invoice will have to pass this three validation rules.
I would like you to try to develop those that involve the additional rules that might grow over time.
Let's say every one of them has some very good function that return true or false, something like that.
If you feel something is missing, just try to guess there is nothing, nothing.
Just I'm trying to help you to like.
I don't feel that this.
Expedia websites, so Expedia, a user, can create several itineraries and each eternity, it consists
of several reservations.
For example, you might have zero or more flights, hotels, cars and so on.
An example of that would be like I have four flights and my two uncles and two cousins.
Reservations for now for simplicity.
Consider all the flights.
That's just one way without transit.
And consider also hotels.
There are no cars cruising all of that at the moment.
So any sugary item which I have, for example, a flight would have some relevant information, like
it's a total cost.
For example, if it is a hotel, then we have looked, for example, the total night times, the price
per right.
Or so the cost of an itinerary is the cost of every item.
So here we have this itinerary.
We have here four items, two items.
It would have like eight items in total.
The total cost of the volatility is the cost of every reservation that we have here.
I would like you to design the set of classes for this system.
You only need to think about the reservation, but you are going to implement the video side if you
are unfamiliar with Expedia or what might be, I would suggest to you to go and to do some like bling
with it.
So try to develop the reservation classes that would give us eventually missionary and we can get its
total cost.
They miss service, so these guys are supporting classify classified ads as very popular Web site,
and as you know, there are many popular alibis for implementation, for for payments, for example.
That could be like one of them is one dollar per twenty five payments.
And these rules might change you.
And we might would like to switch to a different Ebeye systems.
As we said at the moment, the developers wanted to support daybed and Strib ice.
In future there could be more cyber, so we might want to switch the site.
Could the code good, should independent specifically by the kitchen.
What is bad.
What's right as we discussed before.
So when we go to the big bad website to see their eyes, we found the photo.
We find a class that's named the credit card B bad credit card with the following information and they
have an API function that takes the point across the card.
OK, so we would like now to use this, if I would like to call them.
I need to prepare an object of this type and call it what this is tied to get back the payments.
I need to set card information first, then call, I make payment.
This is the interface with bad.
This isn't our code.
We cannot change it.
We only can call it on line remotely.
Also, the guys has information.
They have an object that named user information, another one card information.
And this is why they are using a static function.
So and then you said that you call one function with the Strib user info card info and the money notes
that the structure of this API is different than the structure of the different.
The previous code, however, they are eventually very similar information because eventually we have
to take some payment information.
This is our website and is have some function to be.
It takes some transaction information.
And this is mainly the transaction information, which is very similar to what the eyes need.
You have to follow the code here so that you allow the payments, but without being dependent on a specific
API.
Once you are done with the previous homework, if you could only check out my code, we are going to
extend it with one more.
The guys from the squid, I have the following structure.
They have a static function also with a string and query.
So instead of sending a lot of parameters, you're going to send just a query.
And this is how are using query format is I asked you before to learn how to use JSON.
So now it's time to support this API with this JSON processing.
OK, so one more company role, but think of it as a bit separate from the previous company, Berel.
To make it simple, recall that we went into the Embley and invoice payable because we are paying them
for simplicity.
Consider that we have just one class employee and has an incentive, nothing more.
We would like to stress the idea of the pervert's interfaces, so Bable class should be cleanable,
printable and compatible.
And also the company Berel, which is eventually collection of payables, should be printable and sortable.
Sortable means we can call some function to order all the items in this collection to sort the collection.
Each type should be grouped together.
For example, if you have employees and you have invoices as a collection of Babits, you are to sort
them like, let's say embrace a bit first, then invoices by the end and immobilise by self-assertive
and invoices are outsourced.
It is what you expect in the main function.
You have a company B roll.
It's adding a table for the family.
So it's I think Embley here, which is a label adding another invoice and be able and so on.
Then as it is sortable, you can call, say, Adut order item in some some interface named sortable
for example, and has function order items and then you can print to them.
If you looked here to the printer you notice the employees come first, the invoice come in at the end
and police are sorted by salary first and then by name, and the invoices are sorted by the total cost.
And here I am printing the total Baid.
Here is this submission.
So you have to develop something that allows such overhead.
That's it.