Let's administrate more on the polymorphism syntax. In this example, we have four classes. Take
a moment to just read all of it.
So Class A has a virtual function void f1, class B is inheriting from A, and it has f1
f1, f1.
Now remember the rule,
if there is a virtual function, every child class is also virtual in this function even if it
didn't put the virtual function.
So now f1 here is virtual, f1 here is also virtual, but there is no virtual keyword, but it is virtual.
F1 here is virtual, f1 here is virtual too.
Now, f2 here isn't a virtual function, but f2 here is starting to be defined as a virtual function.
Every child of B will be also virtual at f2.
So this f2 will be virtual, and this f2 would be virtual.
F3 here isn't virtual function and here isn't virtual function, but f3 here is now a
visual function, so it is virtual here and also virtual here.
So this is number one.
Now, let's make some tracing to make sure
how does this help us to understand the polymorphism behavior.
We are defining two D pointers, one of them assigned to a B class and one of them assigned to the
A class.
So starting from the B class, the d1 is calling f1
so we go to class B, which is here, is f1 a virtual function?
Yes.
Then call based on the actual object. To the actual object is D.
So what's going to be printed
is d f1. Now moving to f2,
going to B. Is B f2 is a virtual function? Yes.
Call based on the actual object, which is D
so d f2 is going to be called.
Now, calling f3, go to the B. Is it a virtual function? No, make a call based on the pointer type which is
going to print B f3. Let's administrate more. We are creating now class D, and we are using an A pointer. Let's call
f1, it goes to A. Is f1 virtual?
Yes.
Call based on the actual object.
So it's going to print d_f1. Call f2. Is f2 virtual? no, call based on the pointer type A_f2.
Call f3.
Is it virtual?
No, call based on the pointer type.
So which is A_f3.
I hope by tracing this example, you now exactly know the polymorphism behavior that will happen from
the different course. That's it.