Starting from this video, we will start to see why polymorphism is really a very strong feature.
So let's define a shape class.
We have a shape that has some name and has some area function and get_name function and a destructor.
As an advice,
whenever you create a virtual function, you have to provide the virtual destructor so that the actual
destructor of the object will be always called.
Now, thinking about the virtual area as a side note.
What is a virtual area of the shape class?
We actually don't know
so maybe we can throw an error.
We can return -1 for now, but in the future, we'll see a better treatment than that.
So we don't want to implement a function that we know nothing about it.
We definitely can return to the name,
but do we need it as a virtual function?
The answer is no.
What does it mean when you make a function not private?
It means the actual object will be called here.
OK, so as a designer, if I design a function that isn't virtual, I am seeing a message that I expected
that this parent class would be called.
If I'm providing a function that is virtual, I'm giving a message that this function should be overridden.
...
Now, here is a rectangle class.
It has its own name, width, and height parameters, and calling the constructor of the above class like inheritance,
and now defining its own virtual function area to return width times height.
Now, let's think about what exactly the virtual function gives us in terms of compile versus runtime behavior.
Let's say we have a function that named process shape. The function knows nothing about the
shape.
It doesn't know which which kind of shape,
Is it circle?
Is it triangle? Is it rectangle?
Is it polygon?
It is what? it doesn't know.
So the printing here, cout the name and then cout the area.
Now we created a rectangle, we send it by reference to be a pointer, and then it is used.
Let's say that we provided this function to someone who extended the shape to polygon and called the process function.
When we implemented this function, we didn't know about the polygon,
...
and we didn't know about the future data types.
All we know that it has an area function that is virtual.
So the power here is that what happens in this function is actually determined by the runtime, is actually
determined by the runtime.
Only in the runtime, we will know exactly what will be the area of the class. On the other side, the
get shape function,
this is well known from the compile-time because this function isn't virtual.
So we definitely know the shape parent class name function would be called,
but the area is virtual.
We have no idea which function is going to be called.
So this actually defined a compile-time behavior versus runtime behavior.
The real strength in polymorphism is the ability to be more dynamic and that we can extend a lot of
the code functionalities without making changes for it. As terminology,
the non-virtual function,
we call them compile-time polymorphism because we know in compile time
the answer. Also called static or early binding.
The word bind refers to like a connection,
So we know that this get_shape_name is connected with the shape parent class.
The virtual we call it run-time polymorphism
because what will happen is mainly determined in the runtime.
We call it also dynamic binding or late binding.
It means later, at some point we will connect this area
shape with the actual object that we used it.
So this is how the compiler runtime is determined
in general. The word polymorphism means we have many forms.
So if you have a chain of K classes in inheritance, in runtime,...
a pointer calling function either would base or derived
so you see here we have two forms.
That's why we call it polymorphism. This dynamic binding is the core feature of how polymorphism provides generic code.
The process shape function knows nothing about the exact children
so this provides a very, very powerful key for extensibility and for flexibility.
In return, the runtime polymorphism is a bit slower and little extra memory than the standard
binding.
Let's administrate that with an example.
We already provided the homework for the package delivery service, and when we checked out the solution,
you'll notice that there are different package types.
Every one of them is added to the code. Old card types added the code.
So the code was flexible.
This is how we had here a set of packages of credit cards
but when it came to the shipment, we have to make a vector for the standard package, vector
with the two day package, vector to the heavy package, credit card for this guy, and debit card
for this guy, boolean for which card is used. We have to define a function for every time, we have to set
every credit type.
If the company decided to add one more package type, we will add another function
and we add a vector.
If they decided to add prepaid cards, we will add a function here, will add an object here.
As you see a lot of extensions to the code with minor changes,
we change request.
So how polymorphism is changing all of that?
You define a package class which is just virtual function to total cost and destructor, and then
your standard package, two day package and the heavy package are extending from this class.
In the shipment class, we have vector of package pointer.
Now thinking about that, we removed all of the vectors here with a single vector only for the package.
We removed all the credit cards types here with a single card here.
We removed all the add functions
here with a single function here and one function here.
This class has no idea about the packages or the payment card types.
If in the future we have one more package type or payment card type, we aren't affected at all. The total
cost function iterates every package and says package total cost and that's it.
The customer have vector of payment cards also
so it just using it as pointers. I hope you started to realize how the polymorphism is making our life
much easier when it comes to the generic code. That's it.