Let's see more examples to demonstrate the power of polymorphism.
Remember this system, we want to give it to think about its implementation
details. I think the most critical part was that the image editor needed to have shapes.
So if you tried to implement it in the normal way, you have to have a vector of rectangles, vector of
circles, and so on.
But the way that the polymorphism is going to help you is just you need a vector of shapes.
What are the current shapes?
We don't care. What are the future class that would be added like, say, a polygon?
We don't care.
This how polymorphism is mainly going to help us when it comes to these shapes.
Now, there is a bit minor concern that I would like to think about it.
This editor will probably need some function like add shape.
So we are providing it with add_shape shape-pointer for maybe a rectangle or for circle.
Now, remember, whoever created the pointer has to delete it.
So someone is calling add_shape with shape pointer.
Now, the one who called with the shape pointer has to delete at some point to delete this object.
If the image editor took a shallow copy of the current
pointer, the pointer
after little time is going to be invalid.
So it now vector of shapes that are invalid.
OK, then let's make a copy of the shape pointer.
Now, we are facing a problem.
You cannot make a copy of the shape pointer while you don't know about it.
OK, let's cast it to a rectangle or circle to make a copy of it,
but if you make a cast of rectangle and circle, you now know a lot about these sub-details.
So now the code is again not generic one more time.
So this isn't helpful.
So the question here is how to make a copy of a shape pointer to a complete object from its type, which
could be rectangle or circle.
We don't know.
Meanwhile, all what you have is shape pointer.
You cannot just make new shape.
You need to make like new rectangle, a new circle, but you cannot make that in the image editor.
This is mainly a critical implementation details.
...
I would like to stop the video for a minute and try to think about the problem if hopefully, you understand
it.
So this is the point class, just a standard x and y with some setters and getters and to_string
function that converts it to a string. Moving to the shape class, it should have some virtual function
compute area and another function that's named draw.
So we are expecting someone to implement them. As you see the virtual function,
we don't know how to compute area at the moment.
So this is not the best logic.
The draw function is as following: it saying like drawing a shape of area, blah, blah, blah.
So this is like a default implementation for drawing.
OK, maybe the child class is going to draw to write the generic message
first and then drawing it. This is something that is very, very, very interesting in this
code. The compute area function isn't this one.
In practice, there will be a rectangle that has some compute area function. Wait a second,
The parent class is now calling the child class, and he doesn't know which is the child class.
This is something we call inverse of control.
What's happening? In normal cases,
you have a child class that inherited from a parent class.
...
By
logic,
the child class knows about the parent class and about its functionalities,
but the parent class knows nothing about the child
class, right?
So this is how the logic like
the shape doesn't know whose is a rectangle, whose is a circle, but surprisingly here using polymorphism, the shape class
is going to the compute area function which exists on one of the children that the shape class doesn't know
about it. Now, the parent class is calling the child class.
This is an inverse of the normal scenario.
In a normal scenario, a child class is calling something on the parent class, but with polymorphism,
we can also inverse that.
OK, so there are many frameworks in the high level like in frontend and backend is using this inverse
of control trick.
When you are going to use these frameworks, you will get better sense of understanding polymorphism.
Now, there is a weird function here, something I'm calling a clone. Clone like make a copy.
So the function clone is returning shape pointer.
What is the point behind this function?
It is the issue that I just mentioned from a few minutes.
We are going to ask the rectangle to make a copy of this clone function.
OK, so it override it.
So now that rectangle is going to, here, the rectangle is going to override this function and write new
rectangle-asterisk-this, and do some computation for its compute area.
Here, It's going to call the parent class to make some base messaging and then drawing its own
self.
But back to the clone idea, why this class here is returning an object for myself, which is calling
the copy constructor.
So think of this like a virtual copy constructor.
The trick here is in practice when we have a shape pointer, we can call a clone.
So it's returning an object from something that we don't know
Its exactly type.
So this is solving our problem in the image editor. This is a circle,
very similar logic. It is returning here in a new circle. Now going to the shape class,
here is the issue one more time.
The image editor has a vector of shape pointer, and it has a function that says add shape, give me some shpae
pointer or some shape references.
In the normal case, you can say, OK, shapes dot push back, reference of shape, and that's it.
So we are pushing a pointer,
but the one that gives us this object will be destroyed,
so we need to make an object from a shape which could be a rectangle or a circle.
The shape
dot clone is our way to go around all of that.
Shape dot clone is going to return a shape pointer.
We don't know which shape, but in real-time or run-time, it will be maybe a rectangle, maybe a circle.
This how the clone is going to help us solve this annoying problem. There is here a draw function for
the whole image editor so it iterates all the objects that we have and just draws them, and now we can go
over in the destructor over all our shapes and just destroy them. Once you are done with destroying
them,
clear the whole vector.
So this is how we solve
our problem for the image editor.
In practice, you can have your function to initialize the editor like, say, creating some rectangle,
circle,
then you are adding them one by one.
That is it, so these are more examples for you to get more context of where polymorphism may appear like they
are eventually just inheritance cases, as you see, although we say that composition is
preferred over inheritance, but the way that we use it in inheritance is mainly related to polymorphism.
So a site can have a user or a customer or an admin. Parking could have a vehicle that could be a car, trunk,
truck or motor, and each one of them with needed
its own spots. In parking, there could be permits for students or faculty. In payment, cards can be
credit, debit or prepaid.
Customers sometimes are individuals, sometimes they are corporate.
let's say you are modeling Expedia.com website.
You could have a reservation, which could be for a flight, car or hotel, or itinerary. In a game,
You have a monster. A monster could be fire-monster,
water-monster, stone-monster.
You have a game of player.
Someone is an escaper, and another is a catcher or a soccer player and baseball player.
So as you see, there is some base logic where polymorphism can help us to generalize a lot of code.
That's it.