In this session, I want to highlight some generic motivate your code to could like safer code. The first
thing is the override Keyword. Let's say you have a function integer area. You didn't put in
the class here override
so you probably mean that you don't want others to override it because you didn't put virtual
here.
So a better tip is you put the word final.
When you put the word final after the function, it means no one can override it.
So say class square is extending from a rectangle.
It cannot now override the function area.
So if you are going to provide it with a virtual, and you know that this isn't going to be virtual, so
no one is going to inherit it, provide with final so that you can directly prevent
others from failing in this mistake.
If you are overriding a method also, right for yourself, here, the word override.
OK, so the compiler when see the word override,
he understands that there should be a parent  class with the same function so that you can override
it.
But here the function perimeter doesn't exist in the shape class, so you are not actually overriding
it,
there is no parent class to override it.
So this also, again, another compiler error that helps you. Remember, if you have a virtual function,
provide virtual destructor,
otherwise you may fail in a memory leak.
If a function is virtual from some base class, also provide it with virtual keyword like we know here,
the integer area is a virtual function, even if we didn't put the virtual word,
but the virtual would be like very triggering for others that this is a virtual function
so this is like a good coding practice.
One of the potential mistakes is as following:
This is a parent class that has parameter X
with a default argument of 1. This is another class overriding this function with a default argument
of 2.
If you are creating an object of Type B, you are thinking that it will have an initial value of 2.
Surprisingly, it will always have the parent class of 1, so never override function with some
default parameters,
they will not be called, only the parent default parameters will be called.
So be careful from that.
Also, if a function isn't a virtual function, don't override it,  although it
would be good with normal objects, but in practice, people will tend to use things with pointers.
So they would expect a polymorphism behavior, but it will not be a polymorphism behavior because it
isn't a virtual function.
If you see a function isn't virtual, do not override it.
OK, that's it.