This set of homework for the polymorphism is the following but first, consider the following node:
Always try to apply polymorphism, try to think about depending on some parent class to minimize
the dependencies and coupling between classes.
So, for example, the image editor doesn't know about the rectangle, doesn't know about the circle, doesn't
know about all of that
so we are removing dependencies between classes,
It just know what is a shape and so on.
So Polymorphisms is helping you in that.
In the first homework, you are to read this UML diagram carefully.
It's for an ATM machine and then just describe it.
That's it.
In the second one, we have a fresh software engineer who wanted to implement a new class for square
as a shape.
So he thought as following: we have a square which is inheriting from a rectangle.
A rectangle is a class that is very heavy with a lot of implementation.
The first question is, why do you think the guy thought this way?
Then think, why is this problematic?
What's wrong here?
and provide a tip to avoid such a mistake.
Also, how to fix this design like we would like now to still have a square class,
but we don't want to face the problem that we did here.
Remember, the rectangle class is a heavy one. You would like to make use of these functionalities.
We would like to develop a set of classes for a company and its payroll specifically we have people who are
either volunteers or employees, both are working in the company.
The employees are either hourly based or salaried based.
So the hourly-based guy would just be paid based on the number of hours.
There is also a commission salaried employee.
This guy takes commission extra based on the number of sales that he did.
So this is like a third category that we have.
So this is one category
the payroll has to pay money for it.
There is another source to pay, invoices.
We have invoices, let's say as simple as each invoice has a set of items, item could be like a book,
food, whatever.
Each item has its own details, like maybe for a book it would be the book author name.
So like a different fields I mean.
The payroll should determine and pays money for whatever payable. Payable means in like something that we
have to pay for it.
Here is the employee or the invoice.
So you have to do something that expresses the company payroll here.
We would like to represent the company payroll and some of  employees type that we have in this
system.
Assume after we developed the system, after a few months, we have the following:
There is one new type of employee, which is labourer employee. the labourer employee is an hourly employee.
...
However, at the moment there are no extra functionalities or variables that are for the labourer employee.
The question is from a design perspective, should you add a new class for a labourer, for example,
extending from an hourly employee, but just an empty class, or just make use of the hourly employee based object,
just make use of it as a representation for a labourer
at the moment. Which one is a better choice?
Think and design it.
In the fourth task, you are to study a library named JSON. JSON is a standard text-based library,
It's very common in industry, so it's good to learn about it.
You will study this very basic C++ library.
I by myself downloaded the library file and changed their examples to be better ones.
So I would like first to run and read the code then guess the text structure.
So first, just to read and just guess what is that. After that, try to find materials in web about
JSON.
I'm attaching here one video.
YouTube has a lot and Google has more is easy.
The guys has also some interfaces of the different functionality here. Please, read carefully.
In the future, I will have some assignments and projects depending on JSON, so I would like you really to do
this task.
There are other popular market formats to know about them, like XML and YAML, so check them out.
Also, they are good to learn for yourself.
That's it.