Starting from this video, we're going to elaborate more on some details relevant to polymorphism.
However, the core idea of polymorphism is done in terms of understanding and even in terms of practice.
So the more we go is highlighting more different angles about polymorphism.
So here is one of them relevant to the abstraction.
But remember, the abstraction was more of hiding details and showing essential details in the context.
So when we have this kind of class, we have several implementations for these methods that we have separated
them in a different file.
An interesting question is what if for some function we aren't unsure of the implementation of it at the
moment?
So this is, again, a case of abstraction.
Specifically, remember the shape class.
We have this area function.
If I asked you what exactly the area function? What is the value of the area function?
We have no idea. In the past,
we just were trying to through some exception or return -1,
but this didn't make sense. In C++,
if you don't know how to implement the function you just write equals zero.
So the equals zero is named pure virtual function.
Now, this class is saying, hey guys, I don't know how this function was implemented.
If you are a rectangle, please implement it as a rectangle. If you are a circle, please implement it as a circle.
Now the class that has at least one pure virtual function is a class that we named abstract
class.
So the shape here is an abstract class.
It has something that's very high level, and we do know how to implement it.  As a result, given
this class is an incomplete class. Incomplete means you cannot have an object from it, because if this
object is trying to call the area function, it can't find an answer for that. In a similar way,
if some class inherited from this class, he has to provide implementation to this function or is going
also to be an abstract class.
That's it. This is a new syntax only that you know in this section.
So the abstract class, or ABC, describes the behavior of an incomplete class. Future derived
classes have to implement the missing functions.
If the class has more than one pure virtual function, then it's called ABC.
Now, there is a question here, which is better, is it to provide the virtual pure function or just a virtual function
or pure virtual function?
The point here is if you provided the default implementation for a virtual function, then you saved
everyone else time like it just available for everyone else,
right?
So all the subclasses see my implementation, but if the function isn't implemented, then everyone
has to implement it. in the area
case here, definitely,
we don't have any answer
even so we just let others (the children) to implement it,
but sometimes we can provide some implementation. In practice,
still multiple inheritance with even abstract classes may cause problems.
So what we said about the problems of inheritance is still valid with the pure virtual function, it is still
can cause problems,
and this takes us to the concept of interfaces, which is very common in a language like Java and
C#. In Java,
there is no inheritance and multiple-inheritance, there is what we call interfaces like the
class has no implementation at all,
so this means that all functions in a class are pure.
So if all the functions in the class are pure, we call it interface. Here the word interface like say you
are going to a building, you see how a building looks like. or using an ATM machine,
you just see what is a building, what is an ATM machine.
You know nothing about the details.
So interface is like you are telling people this is what you have to provide,
but I'm not going to tell you anything about the interfaces.
There is still a chance that you fill in the diamond
problem with interfaces, if you started to do like some different angles, like interfaces with
different angles that have something that now common. The good about the interface idea, it gives
you a sense of view like this class is printable, comparable runnable.
We will see an example of that in the end of the lecture.
If all the inheritances in your system are from interfaces, this now will be very similar to Java,
now you are avoiding a lot of multiple inheritance ambiguities.
So remember, we discussed several cases about multiple inheritance and how it is very problematic.
If all of the inheritance is in your class, in your system, are from just interfaces, then probably
would be avoiding many of these problems.
In terms of terminology, if you are just inheriting from an interface, we better call it like 1A interface
implementation.
Now, I would like you to think of the interface idea as a contract you are providing to others
to use it
like let's say when you try to use, for example, a database, you will be provided with some interface
to use it.
So interfaces where others are depending on us,
we need really to be designed and tested in a very careful way.
So in terms of the interfaces compared to abstract classes, as we said, the interfaces have all
of them a pure function. In abstract classes, some are pure functions, and some others are implemented.
The problem here is the abstract classes has a high chance still like failing in the same issues with
multiple inheritance,
but if everything is more like interfaces, then you are in a more safer way.
A little more about the interfaces
guidelines like you are doing an interface and providing it for others, like the chip class or whatever.
So think of it as a contract because everyone is going to implement his own version from your code and
is going to like just follow what you said. When we started to change something that we are providing
to the public to use it
other teams, then breaking it, will fail everything.
To understand a more context of that, let's say that you are in Amazon, OK?
And we are building a logger component, for example, and we are providing people
with the interface for this logger.
Now, there are like 1000 teams who are using our interface for our logger class.
Once you made a change in the class in a way that breaks the compatibility with others, then there are
hundreds of projects that are going to fail because of such change.
You should provide only the minimal public functionalities. In interfaces you don't put
private functions, you don't include
your like some common functionalities. Remember, just more of your public section,
just you are telling people that you know what, if there's a shape, you can compete and compete
perimeter.
That's it.
You don't put anything that's an irrelevant or potentially private function.
There is what we call the principle of least surprise.
When people are using your interface, the most cases, it will depend on the function name and
they will not read documentation.
So make sure that when people like just do such a behavior, everything will be OK, that no surprises
in your code. Try to think from the client and user perspective.
What are their needs? like
make the usage of your interface very intuitive,
and so on. I would like to go back to the idea of interfaces as properties.
This is something that we see a lot in something like Java. In a typical inheritance thinking way,
you think like, oh, an employee is a person,
so we have a class person and we have a class employee.
This is the inheritance idea. With interface,
you might think of properties like, let's say this class is printable so and also, comparable, cloneable,
and so on.
So what does this mean to be printable class?
It means that probably this is an interface here that has a print function.
Cloneable is an interface that allow cloning.
So now the person class is inheriting from printable and cloneable.
So now we see the person is printable and cloneable. It means that it support this print function and this clone
function.
Now, the employee is inheriting from a person who is printable and cloneable.
So this is the idea of the properties.
When you think about it, about this kind of inheritance, this isn't like a circle is a shape.
It has a different sense, a sense of properties.
So this is something interesting about the idea of interfaces.
You can have an interface that refers to some properties, then you can inherit from multiple
properties.
So now this is a bit different sense than the normal inheritance.
We don't need to think here like in mammals and mammals types and so on.
It doesn't need to do that.
As you see, all the inheritance here is going to just interfaces. This is what we mean when we provide interfaces
that make sense for the people.
Be careful about what's really the function here and just inheriting from interfaces.
Remember, if some class is visible from serval paths like, let's say printable class is visible
in the employee, and then you are inheriting from something else
that sees also the printable class.
So the printable class is visible from two different paths,
then the compiler will say, oh, this is ambiguity. How to solve it?
We add the word virtual, for example, instead of a public person here, we use a virtual public person.
We mentioned that in the homework answer for the diamond problem.
One of the topics of concern is virtual function versus templates. When to use each one of them?
Here is a template use case.
This is a function, let's say process.
It takes a vector of data type and going to sum the values of this vector.
In a normal case, you have a vector of double and returning double.
If you would like to make it a generic function, you can use templates and say vector of type returning
type and use here type type type.
So in runtime, if we have a vector of integer, it returns a sum integer, vector of double, it returns a sum double, vector
of long-long, returns a sum of long-long, and so on.
But does the behavior of a vector here iterating and summing is different?
The answer is no.
So the rule is if the data type doesn't affect the behavior, then this is actually not a
polymorphism,
this is just a template style.
So when we get a sense of that this is polymorphism.
If the behavior itself changes based on the data type, like the behavior here of shape based on a rectangle
is different from a circle.
So with a change in the data type itself, we have a change in the behavior. This implies
that we have to make
..., we have to make a visual function. That's it.