One more practice with polymorphism. In this practice, we would like to highlight the idea of the
device driver, something in the operating systems.
Let's say that you put some camera, and you started to plug it in your system, which you could be ubuntu
operating system,
It could be Windows 10 operating system, and so on.
So now the camera guys, when they provide you with a camera, they also provide
some implementation for what we call a driver.
The operating system knows nothing about the specific functionalities of your camera.
So a driver is something that we typically install to let the operating system be able to communicate
with the device. With every hardware that you plug in, the operating system has
to figure out a way (the driver) to communicate with the device.
For every complicated device, these guys has to provide different implementation, like they provide
implementation for Windows 10, provide an implementation for Ubuntu, for fedora, and so on.
So the driver is something between the operating system and device.
There are also the applications like let's say I would like now to run some program on my machine that
would start to get frames and images from this camera.
Now, the application itself shouldn't depend on the driver like shouldn't depend
I am on an operating system of Windows, and i am on operating system of Ubuntu, and do a lot of stuff that's very dependent
on the driver.
So if you noticed here, an interesting thing is the behavior eventually of the camera itself is very
common like a function is going to start, to stop, give you a frame, and so on.
But the implementation of it from this perspective is different from Ubuntu than Windows and so on.
So it seems like we have one interface of generic functionalities here, and then we are going to have
different implementation for the drivers.
And also thinking about the application itself. The application shouldn't be depending on the ubuntu
or depending on the windows,
It should depend on some generic interface,
and then in runtime, someone needs to give me an implementation of that.
This is typically the operating system.
So the process goes as following:
The application here is want to run. This application knows that it has to use some functionalities
of camera device,
but what is the current implementation,
Is it third party, even, by the way, on Ubuntu,
there can be several drivers.
Some of them are fast, some of them are slow, some of them are buggy.
So this application doesn't want to depend on the specific implementation,
It just depends on the interface.
The operating system has some installed driver.
So when you requested the device, the operating system gets an object of this type of driver and
return it back to you.
So now you are using the interface, which is using polymorphism is implementing this device driver.
I hope the overall idea just makes sense for you,
but anyway, let's see code for that.
So I'm defining here, first of all, a very generic class.
I am calling it IDevice
like, remember, there can be a lot of devices, we are now trying to implement the whole cycle of the
operating system itself.
So we don't just have camera devices, we have even general devices.
So the class IDevice is just for whatever generic device. It should have
virtual destructor here,
I forget about that.
The ICamera device is now is an IDevice, and this is its interface.
So remember, this is an interface,
All of the functions are here
equal zero,
It means that this isn't implemented.
Remember the guys of the camera itself,
they thought about a good interface to provide to the public,
they don't get crazy in the later time and rename this start function to say a run, for example,
if you named it start now, keep it start, otherwise,
all the applications that depend on your interface as a camera provider interface are going to fail
in the future.
We then start to provide implementations.
So let's say that they provided a default ubuntu driver open-source implementation for this camera
device.
Someone found that this implementation on Ubuntu is very small and decided to provide another implementation
that is very fast.
The guys in windows 10 also wrote a definition for it.
All of them eventually have to do this camera device implementation, but they are just different implementation
for different operating systems or even different implementations on the same operating system.
Now going more, let's say that Ubuntu system or the operating system would like to model the application
in the system.
So also there should be some generic functions in an application, like, for example, we can run it
or we can shut down it,
So this is a generic interface for what is an app. Now, let's say that we have two camera applications.
One of them is named cheese,
this is on Ubuntu,
and the second one is named kamoso.
So every one of them is now inheriting from the public application.
So notice here now,
this one is a genetic app to be used by the operating system.
The more important thing here is,
this application is has a constructor that takes a camera device object.
So now someone is going to create an object for application cheese and provide it with the camera device
object.
Who created this one?
I don't know,
and I don't care.
All I care about is to give me some object that I can use and make some calls using it.
So now this is what's an application. Moving to the Ubuntu operating system itself.
Let's say Ubuntu is going to have a vector of devices and also a vector of applications,
and if you would like to shut down your Ubuntu system, you iterate on all application and just give them
a call to shut down.
If you are done with the system here, you shut down the system, remove the applications, remove the
devices.
Now, let's say that someone double-clicks the cheese application.
So we called the operating system with the get_camera application for the cheese.
The first thing is that the ubuntu system is going to have a specific driver installed on the system.
So let's say that it knows for now that the driver is ubuntu driver open source.
Now, it's going to check the application name.
Is it cheese or komoso, for example? If it is cheese or komoso, iterate object based on that and pass
for it the driver object that we have here.
So the camera app cheese or camera app kamoso
know nothing about the specific driver implementation,
we just give it for it.
This is how we reduce the coupling in the code itself.
Then you add the device to the devices and application to applications. This is definitely like very silly code,
I'm just highlighting the the generics of the
of the poloymorphism here. Going back one step,
Yes, this is a virtual function, good, OK. So in the main, you have your operating system, someone
double click the cheese,
so your OS gets the application and just tells it to run in a very generic way.
So you get your camera running.
I hope you get the example.
The last thing to highlight here is the coupling issue. The coupling means dependency.
If I'm defining the camera app cheese as dependent on the ubuntu driver windows 10, this is the
direct dependencies. In the market, we always tell people to depend on interfaces.
So now here I am having a camera app cheese that has a I, I for interface by the way, Icamera device.
It depends on this interface.
It knows nothing about ubuntu, knows nothing about Windows 10,
it knows nothing about all of these guys, OK.
It know nothing about them.
So this one is more generic,
we can change this implementation,
we can add more implementation,
So this one is very flexible, but this one is very tied to a specific driver.
So always when you have two classes, think about the dependencies between them and ask yourself, do you depend
the interfaces or abstract classes or you depend on a specific code implementation?
The more you depend on code implementation, the more troubles you will face when you would like to change
your code in the future.
That's it.