Everyone, welcome to this lecture of inclusion exclusion.
And in this lecture, we'll see how inclusion and exclusion problems can be solved in code forces.
And we will see that what different types of problems are there?
Right.
And we will also see it.
Why is Ford required, right?
So that's the most important part.
The device will actually be a whole lot of coding, a whole lot of word manipulation be required and
inclusion exclusion.
Well, let me start with a very simple division.
You all must have gone through the gone through discrete mathematics or simple mathematics, and we
know we have said to iterate.
Well, we know there's activity and to it, we know we have some things they said contained some elements
in them.
So let's say I have a city with some numbers in it.
And let me just give some random numbers to it.
Well.
I have a said to be looking again, give a very random numbers to this.
Well, so that means I have to search here, which is a and B and as the name suggest inclusion and
exclusion, that means I think Louis fields few of the things and I wouldn't exclude for few of the.
So I'm taking a very simple example of usage rate and it's just a quick revision rates.
And then we will keep on increasing the number of search and see how actually it works.
And then we look at some very nice examples and then we'll call them full.
So if I were to find out what is a Union B, that means.
And with the number of OK, not the number of elements, let's take this set.
OK.
The suits, which are in both A and B, the numbers which are both in B and how do I find this?
So we all know this, it is equal to air.
I'm just writing this eight names plus b minus e.
Intersection B eight.
What does this mean?
How does this work?
We all know, we all know this is very simple.
Let's say the society is said to be so.
Right now, a vital thing that means I've included all the elements in there.
Eight wild thing be that means I've included all the elements in there to include all the elements in
be.
And if I include all the elements in A and B to what are the elements here, we have one three, five,
10, 50 and two for five in a hundred and forty.
It will be all this.
That or does a certain set does not contain some identical elements to all the elements and said are
distinct, so no duplicate elements are there and separate.
But here we can see if I do it.
Blessed be that means if I join and B into one set, what will I get?
I'll get some duplicate elements.
What are those elements to name them?
We can have five five babies two times, also 10.
Any of the two names, eight and two for fifty one party and 100 great known elements has a good race
here.
Eight.
What is firing down here, firing and not actually into Section B?
That means.
I have included the elements which are common to what E and B twice late, so if I want to remove those
elements, what will I do?
What will I do?
I simply remove intersection B elements one number of times it just one day not.
I'm not saying remove them twice.
I'm just saying remove them once fired because they have been counted here.
Grace Barnini and one Inbee who just moved them once and will get all the elements.
What is a intersection B two intersection B in this case, as we can see, the common elements in both
N.B. and those elements are five and an eight intersection B Harris and in five, basically.
And if I remove an invite from this set, it means I'm doing a minus intersection B.
Never will I get I'll get this particular.
That but this side is equal to a union.
I hope this is very clear, it's very simple, and we have already started this fight, so this part
is a Union B.
As you can see, no element has been counted.
Why is it?
And if I want to find out the number of elements in the liver I can do is I can see number of elements
in a union very close to a number of elements in there, plus number of elements in B minus number of
elements in a intersection.
B, The how much will this be?
How many elements that are in there in their file?
Plus how many elements in B?
We have one two three four five six elements.
And how many common elements to sue?
What is the total number of elements here?
Nine.
So we have nine elements in a Union B.
I hope you got this part.
Eight.
It's a very, very simple example.
Very easy to understand.
Eight.
Now, let's move on to a slightly different example.
What if there are three sets, eight and one, for example?
I would like to take up a problem.
Let's do that in the next part.
OK?
Let's meet in the next few.