Hello, everyone.
So let's generalize all of it to in the previous video we saw, how does it go for two point and we
saw that in the audience and I just, you know, coming up really quick before the reset, how does
it happen?
How does it work?
It's very simple.
It's ABC.
I've already done them and we know what is a common be a intersection C and B intersection C.
Right now we have a third thing, which is intersection B, intersection C, which is common to all
three A, B and C eight.
For example, let's take the below example, which is numbers which are less than 15 and divisible by
two.
So we can see those are two four six eight, 10, 12, 14 eight.
And what is B numbers, which are less than 15 and diesel by the late?
Finally, we have numbers of what you see, which is Diesel five, which is five, 10, 15.
So I'm seeing less than or less than equal to here.
Now what is Eagleman B?
Eight.
So what is in this case, he was able to and B it is.
But the it's again, we see that a common B is nothing but which are divisible by six.
Eight, because those would be the breeding rate, because the one which are used by six are already
sold by two and three.
We have six and 12 here, but we have 10.
Why?
Because two and five the humans and and four B and C, we have 15 those which are December 15.
What about which are diesel by Altria area and C we have.
No, right, so this might be a common knowledge to all of us that how do we calculate this, how do
we calculate aiding in beating A.?
Very simple rate, which is we say OK, we include air include being Lootie.
And we don't include Eagleman B in the S.C. and being D-S.C.
And then what we realize is that.
There's a certain part which we have actually not included, which got included three times in ABC and
got subjected three times in a BBC, NBC at eight will include included again to understand this.
Let's keep on adding things here, right?
If I'm including air, that means I'm doing a +1.
If.
So that plus one means that we have included this, that's one plus one.
So in all the parts of EA, in all, these are parts of AAA and these subsections, I just added +1
because they're included.
Now let's include B.
The to include B plus one plus one will be here also again and again, that means these are the parts
which will be included when include B.
Now if I include C, so c included plus one here.
Plus one here and plus one here.
Now what I what I was trying to do.
We are trying to remove a common B ito.
If this is a this is B and this is C, then e common because we all know what it is.
Despite the audience, Bartlett.
Let's subtract this part, so what where this subduction means, I'm doing a minus a day to do a minus
around is remove unpleasant, so minus one and minus one, that means this has been included.
So in the end, what we want to do is we want to include all of these.
Exactly when they made.
So now what knowledge subject a common be?
A common wisdom knowledge object, a common see and then become A..
So a common see we have this part in Eagleman sees a let's remove vine from here and one from you.
Well, that means we have removed this.
Now let's subtract bekommen.
See, one day right now you when you can easily see that you get this whole part is included.
This hole is included.
One, So that's good.
This part is included.
This is also included, and this is also included, that is also good, but what about the middle part
here, right?
It was plus one three times and then minus one three times eight.
So we need the included separately.
That's where we have less a common be common.
Right.
So let's move forward.
And I also, yeah, let's talk about Ford, OK, so we have seen how this something in three states
work before, Ford said.
What we have is we have we are adding them individually, then we are subtracting them.
When we are taking them in pairs, then we are adding them again in triplets and then we are again subjecting
them in.
All right.
That's the burden that you can observe read.
We add.
We subtract, we add, and then we subtract and so on.
Right?
So how does it become?
We add the odd elements.
What do I mean by broad benefit contains odd number of.
That's in them, right, so this is a state which is unique, which is the intersection of even number
of states.
This is a state which is intersection of our number of states.
Eight.
If it is all we are, including it, we're adding +1 date.
Otherwise, we are subtracting it so it becomes minus one.
It is to the public if NW is hard.
If any, even state, if any, is even then it becomes.
But action, if an is art, then it becomes outdated and need to begin.
I mean, you can easily derive this formula.
It doesn't interfere.
No.
OK, so that was off for right when we have four sets, we add, subtract, add subject to how many
elements are there.
We choose one one one in them.
We have four one element.
We have four see two elements.
We have 43 elements and we have foresee what elements.
So similarly will happen in its 05.
I want you to write it, although there will be many sets here.
Because I will be including a weakened individual element and will be subjecting a B, e C and so on
and then will be including ABC.
And then we'll be subjecting a record above things.
And then we will be again adding ABC.
E!
Well, so this is how it works, so how many are how many individual elements, five seven.
How many in fields five c two five six three five C for five C.
Right.
So how many total are there?
So if you take this sum, if you remember this, this is nothing to restore.
The power and brand is five in this case, minus one.
If you add all of them, it becomes two to power and minus one.
And also, if you take five six zero, then it is this really about eight eight.
This is how inclusion exclusion works.
Great.
So when we have our number of elements in our particular intersection, we added otherwise we subjected,
well, I'll be using this in the next.
A problem discussion and also in the cold video, right?
We'll see you there.
Thank you.