Welcome back.
I have this first example that I want to present, which is a find eternal number of permutations of
zero two nine eight, so we have all single digits and the total number of permutations, which contains
one three.
OK, so let's say which.
Does not contain and will do otherwise, resulting in total populations of 0.9, which does not contain
13, 49, 34 or 23.
OK, well, no problem.
We can do the does not bite also, and we can do the other part too, right?
Let's do one part and then come to the other one.
So how many permutations of 0.9 are possible?
We have 10 numbers here, so there are 10 factorial permutations which are possible today.
So this is total number of permutations which are possible.
So there are OK, how many permutations are there, which contains 13?
So as we know that there can be many permutations which contain certain right, there can be many permutations
which contains 49, 34 and 23 eight.
So how do we solve this?
And of course, there will be many permutations which will contain both 13 and 34 eight, like one,
three, four and something.
Let me give you some examples.
First.
So let's let's call up a mutation, which just contains one three eight.
That means it should not contain other elements.
So let's call it 13.
And let's straight forward here nine here so that it doesn't intersect and two here.
Cool.
And it's just fill it at seven.
Five six.
And zero eight.
So this is a population which just contains 13, and it does not contain 49.
It does not contain 34 and it does not contain 23.
Similarly, you can make other permutations, which contains 49, 34 and 23.
But let me give you an example of accommodation, which contains both 13 and 49.
So what I can do is it's very easy to make it just bare them 13 and 49 and just fill the rest of the
digits.
It's a zero two three seven four five six seven eight and nine is already eight zip zero mutation,
which contains thirteen and forty nine point eight.
So this does not contain 23, and this also does not contain 30 foot, as you can see.
And similarly, you can make other examples, right?
There can be of a mutation which contains 13 and 34 like together, like I mean this way.
Ain't the how can I do this if I are going to find out whether a permutation contains 13 and 34, it
can contain it this way.
Right.
That means it has 13, also 34.
There's a difference.
Guys up there cannot be of a mutation, which contains 13 and 34 separately named because it can only
be used once in a mutation if it contains both.
One three four it has to be together.
Eight.
Yeah, two, one, three four.
And similarly, fill the rest of the digits over here so that there are no other permutations watchable.
So how will you solve this problem?
As we can see, there can be some combinations of these.
Numbers inside the permutations, right?
I will find out the total number of permutations which contains 13 and these these these.
So as I know, there are 10 factorial told by Malaysian trade.
So again, I will simply use inclusion exclusion over there, and it's not a very tough problem.
Eight.
And also this won't be required that this problem won't required much to could also aid.
But let's find out the total number of, let's call it b b.
And if I did like 13, that means there are no permutations, which contains 13 13 means.
I mean only 13.
Nothing else.
Eight.
And.
Then we can find out the total number of permutations, which contains 49 permutations, which contains
34 permutations, which contain 23 and so on.
So.
So how many more mutations are possible, which contains all these elements, we can see 13 plus 49
plus 34 plus 23, right?
That means.
All the permutations which have been included till now, which contains 13, but I'm not sure about
others and whether it may or may not contain 49, 34 and 23 in it.
If I include P. 49, that means it contains 49, but we are not sure about whether it contains 34 22
you in with it or not, and so date.
So this is the individual contributions of these elements.
Now let's subtract readable part of it.
That means.
Let's find out the permutations which contains.
Putting 49 in them, right?
Village break be 13 and 49 with this, let's celebrate B.
13 and 34 with this subject P. 13 and 23 with this subject B.
49 and 34 with this be 49, 23 and B 34, 23.
I hope you're getting the major point here.
And how will you figure out what is a certain number of elements here?
OK, we'll do that later.
Now, after this, what we'll do is we will need to add them individually.
That means permutations which contain 13 as well as 49, as well as 34 plus permutations, which contains
13 as well as 49 as well, is 23 eight.
And how will we find this out?
What are the total number of these permutations?
I'll tell you.
We'll figure that out.
And the second one can be 13.
34 and 23.
Right.
And the next one can be be 49, 34 and 23 will.
And the last one is simply subject, which contains all four of them, if possible.
Eight.
How do we do this?
How do we figure this out?
How can we calculate what their total number of elements?
It's very simple.
It's normal combinatorics, which is how many permutations are different.
The line which contains 13 in them.
So what you can do is speed up 13 together.
And what we have is we have either how many elements are left.
If I bring up other elements are left rate, which is zero point two.
OK, no one.
No one one two three four five six seven eight nine eight.
That means if I build this up, if I find out all the permutations of these numbers, that means, you
know, I live imitations of these numbers.
How many numbers are there now?
We have only nine am with eight because we have taken to them two numbers as one, because we are kind
of grouping them between all them relations.
One in three will be together.
The total nine factorial permutations are possible nine factorial possible, nine factorial possible,
nine factorial four days and nine Victorian for this.
Similarly, how many are there possible?
Four, 13 and 49 just.
Entertain and 49 together, if you're betting and voting in together, we have the rest of the remaining
numbers, which are zero two five six seven eight.
How many total number area?
One two three four five six seven eight eight two.
I have to tell it elements in this.
And if I pursued these eight elements were delegates.
I'll get eight factorial permutations in all those infected by mutations, 13 will be together and 49
will be together.
That means I got all the populations of 18 49 that together.
Eight.
And similarly, we can find out for this.
This, this, this, this similarly for three, we can.
Pair them together, so so in this case, what we'll have is we'll have one.
Three.
Warren nine.
Together eight and then only responsible 13 with 34 with 49.
It's it will just bind them together like all the other numbers and which is zero to.
Five, six, seven, eight, eight two, how many are there now?
This will be counted as one two three four five six seven two seven factorial such permutations are
possible.
Well, Emily, you can find out for others and do it too late, so I hope you understand how inclusion
exclusion elders in solving these same problems.
You can take an example of three of them, four of them or five of them.
You already know how it works for any of them, right?
You can do is use a Brakebills Datablitz a break in force.
Add in five subject and six and so on, it will keep on going, Dylan.
Eight.
OK, now let's go on to another example, and this is the example, which we can, right, because right
now I'm taking very less numbers, which are 500 and just 48.
But when when will call will take very big constraint.
So those constant will not be so easy to be solved using.
And we will we will have to call them.
The next problem that I took is it's a very again famous problem, which is find a total look to total
numbers which are less than 500 and diesel by the first four prime numbers.
So I would just want to find out.
The total numbers, which are less than 500 and by differs for prime numbers are going to do this.
So what are the first four prime numbers, first of all?
Right, so let's call prime numbers as B and the first four numbers are two three five seven.
So how many?
Again, I'm taking an example of food, OK, let's let's burn it down to three or implicitly eight.
So total number of numbers, which are less than 500 individual by first three frames.
We can also do it for food.
It's very easy.
No look.
So what nobody will lose are divided into individual, said Aito said.
It contains or let's say.
And that means the most, which is about over less than 500, so how many of them are there?
Right now, I'm not including zero, OK, so let's call them natural numbers.
So how many are there?
Very simple.
It's 500 by two, the right 250 such numbers, or it is NY three.
That means 500 by three.
That means if I divide one by three, what what will I get?
I'll get one, six and six again.
Later, there are 160.
Fix them.
Yeah, 166 numbers which are divisible by three and less than 500.
Well, and and by five, it'll be 500 by.
Right.
And so here I have 100, 100 members out there, which are less than 500 and whose.
I hope this is very clear.
No, what is and two three here?
Now must be introduced by both three and five.
That means the numbers which are divisible by six.
Eight.
If if the numbers are disturbing to all three, although that means the numbers are usually by two three
six.
Right.
Because two and three does not have anything.
Means the cobra, I'm late, so if I wanted to find it Elysium the least common multiple of two three
and it will be six eight.
So how many numbers are diesel by?
It would reveal just six, which is it goes to and six, which is equal to 500 by six eight and this
will be.
OK.
Eight and 20 will give me three, eight, I think did three is correct.
What is +2 five?
It is nothing but and then eight, which is nothing but 500 by 10, which is 50.
And the final one is N3 five, which is N15, which is 500 by 15, which is three and three.
Well.
Now, finally, what we need is we need all which individual right to three and five.
So this is nothing but at a team of two, three and five, which is the three and five, which is 30.
Cool.
So how many of them are diesel by 30 and less than 500?
We have.
Fifty by three, and it gives me one in it.
Well, now we have all these numbers, eight, and I want to find out the total number of elements which
are less than 500 and usable by just first three planes, so I cannot add all I can take individually.
That means 250.
166 plus hundred.
Because they're individuals now subject 83.
Fifty three.
And then finally, add it in.
It this is nothing but inclusion, exclusion for picking individuals, a breaking event.
And then again, taking out.
All.
This was an example of three, right?
What if the constraints were, let's say, 10 to the power rating?
Instead of 500 and let's say, 10.
And there were 10, I mean, how many numbers are less than 10 to the power rating, which is divisible
by first and prime numbers.
How would you do that?
So that will become a very tricky for us to solve, right, because we have to make to do the power
10 different combinations.
As I already explained, rate individual prime numbers, then we'll take them twice and then we'll know
raising force and so on.
So this is not very feasible by doing it, doing it by hand.
So I just wanted to give you this example.
So then we can call this out.
And in the next tutorial, I'll just go this particular example, which is will take you into less than
this, which is of the first interregnum.
Well, oh, thank you, everyone.
And.
In the next part.