Hey, welcome everyone.
And.
In this part, what we'll do is we'll try and code this problem that we discussed and we discussed it
for the first three frames.
And.
508 as a number, and but now what we'll do is we'll try and call this problem for them, and we sure
will fill out.
And let's call it.
OK, let's take this as an important.
Eight.
And let's take the first and prime numbers.
I'm just taking them and then we'll discuss how do we call this out, how do we make individual elements
out of them and take their seems right?
So it's not necessarily the daily claims you can pick any of those numbers, right?
But do remember when you're considering their Elysium's, then you will have to divide by their new
series.
OK, so just remember this part.
I'm just taking planes, so they're in a team.
I just multiply all of them and not divide anything in their.
You know, communities will find the ultimate.
One of the first frames are two three five seven.
Eleven.
Thirteen.
There.
I don't know, my calculations have become very big after I completed my bachelors.
It was good.
Does everything right so.
I've stopped using mine.
Yeah.
These are the primes.
The first eight frames made.
So we want to take 10.
Let's take 10 or 23 is a prime number, according to me.
And 29 is a premium, but then eight.
So what I need to do is I have to make all types of sex now, right?
So how do I make all types of sex?
We have already gone through the manipulation section.
If not, there's a big manipulation section in this code.
You can go through it.
So how do I make all this sets?
Let's say I have three numbers A, B and C, and I want to make all possible sets of these three.
Then what do I do?
Just.
Quickly going through it said zero means not including anyone.
OK, let's write binary of zero eight.
So I have three elements that means I'll start from zero and go to the two to the bar with three, minus
four and eight.
How many elements are there from zero to seven included?
We have to delete elements.
Eight These eight elements that actually the number of sets we can make from A B and C I have zero one
two three four five six seven eight nine the binary zero zero zero.
This is one's binary.
It was binary.
These binary or.
Five.
Six and seven eight.
That means at the time when we have one will simply consider that eliminate the Indy rules by Indy,
there is no one that means it's an empty suit.
Here we can't see to see here we consider be here.
We consider B and C because B and C rate B and C are we are getting this.
So now here we consider e who we consider AC, a b and a B and C.
So here you can see I was able to derive all these sets using some bit manipulation.
If I just iterate from zero to two to the power and minus one, then I'll have to roll to the debout
end numbers later.
How many total sets we have to retrieve our end sets?
All those numbers can help us generate all these sets.
In theory of an element.
So this is what is already described to you and just quickly revising it.
They will generate all sorts of these fame numbers.
Right.
Yeah.
OK, so as I said, ill, which number do we have to go, we have to go still to do the power in minus
one day, so we just simply left shift one endings and will simply get rid of the power and they and
we are moving less than that.
That means so I'm starting from zero so that you don't get confused because zero is actually not needed
here, but still no problem with it.
And.
If I take a Pfizer, which is zero, that means how many elements are you using to buy that?
So there isn't any eliminate.
What else to do is I'll simply start with one.
So let's start with one and let's try and make all the possible subsets first.
Well.
Let's call it in its May Day Go, Darling.
So if the jet a bit of elite element is said liquidated.
Then included.
That's what we did.
So how how will it check if the G8, the bit of ice element is certainly or not?
I'll just regift idea names and end with one.
If this is true, that means the G8, the weight of eight elements that if it is said, I would simply
sit out right now, I'm just printing it so that it's very clear to all of us.
I read and it said they'd.
OK, OK, sorry.
And is the total.
And is the number in which we are going to find a date or we just have to find these subsets of this
primes?
Victor, let's take em as prime start place.
Very sorry.
Sorry for that.
Yeah, let's take em here, Norton in.
And so Mr.
Right.
And we'll simply say, Scott Primes do.
Well, after this and I simply.
Brent.
Now you can see that we are generating all subsets in two three two three five two five.
We have three also, we have four also there.
And if I just keep on going down, we will see many more.
To the and this is the last one, I guess, which contains.
All the elements in disarray to how many are there 1023 eight?
If I have 1200, that means which one have I not included?
I have not included.
Zero zero.
I'm always so.
OK.
I think I just changed my.
Notifying.
OK, so this way we can just generate all the possible subsets of.
Ms.
Now what I what I need to do is instead of printing them, I just have to find their LC ms rate.
So let me again be recalled, Tim.
Let me get equal to one.
And whenever I'm finding any number eight, whenever I get a number, what will I do?
Let me.
Well, so whenever I'm.
When I including a number in my state, let's just multiply them because I've considered only prime
numbers and I don't have divided loyalties, I say Altium in two equals two this times.
Yeah.
So if that bit is said, the wins included prime number include means just multiplied into the.
And now what we'll do is we'll have a.
Final answer.
That means how many of them were actually included?
How many do.
How many so.
I do I do this.
It's very simple.
If the.
If the number of OK, just give me.
I'm sorry for that.
Now, what we have to see is that if the number of elements included, but.
Even then, subtract them or if they were all at them.
So there's dysfunction we all know about this, which is building popcorn trade, so.
Yeah, built, built in.
Funk, what does this do?
I just I just pass into it, and this will tell me what is the total number of Dead Birds in eight eight?
If the number of said Virginia is even that means it is doable by two, then employee excluded.
They'd want to exclude anybody else, him it is in and is the number we'll provide, let's provide a
very big number right now.
Where does Elysium, which is nothing but the multiplications of all the primes and.
Biomass objecting because there isn't even said that which contains even number of frames and other
ways, I simply add it into my LTM the odd frames.
Well, and after this is done, there's nothing much left.
So we'll just see out answer.
So there are these many numbers, which are lives in the first ten frames, which are less than this
particular in data, literally 200.
Let's take if it works or not.
It before and if I do 10.
So there are total nine numbers which are usually by the first in primes.
What is the number which is left?
It is when one is not used by any of these great.
Filled in, so I hope this court is very clear to you all, we didn't do much, we just calculated all
the.
Upsets and welcome greetings, absurd, we just checked that.
We just found out the him if the number of elements in the set was even suppressed them, because that's
what we noticed, right?
That's what we noticed if you went to break them, if it's ordered them into one.
So as we can see here and missed any rate, what if and was more it, what if 31 was also here?
Admits and was equal to 11.
But this this particular court work, according to the 11th IT subset, it will generate all possible
subsets of these 11 prime numbers and add and subtract accordingly.
So this is where computers help us aid and towards the complexity of the code.
So this particular for loop goes straight to the the program, which is in the middle of crimes.
It has 11 brains are destroyed, about 11 in 211.
It just goes to land only.
And this is nothing we're just checking and this is alternating just over.
Brilliant.
So we have some brilliant popcorn functions if you do not know about them.
You can refer to the brain manipulation section in this particular course or by searching for them online.
So just find out some building functions, which comes very handy during the contest.
Otherwise, you'll have to make another function parsing data to check the number of.
Which certainly state just.
Move ahead and find some interesting building functions in C++.
Well, so that said, guys, in the next part, I hope you understood how it is.
Inclusion Exclusion Bug eight.
Next part will be a little advance in which I'll be explaining what is Mobius function in number 30,
which is all to use for inclusion exclusion.
But that's very advanced.
So just get your hands on this practice few problems regarding inclusion, exclusion and then move ahead.
Thank you.