In this section, we start to something that's completely different perspective from what we were
doing.
We started the course with learning about the variables and about making expressions, precedence.
Then we learned how to make a flow, using if-statements and using loops.
Then we started to know how to create many, many instances in easy way, using 1D and 2D array.
The function isn't about more syntax
items involving extra feature, it is more about organizing the code.
So function is one of these great things that help us to organize the code in a very efficient way.
So let's remember, how can we do a task like the following?
Let's sum the numbers from 1 to n, we read the number, we write sum = 0,
We iterate on all numbers, sum it and that's it.
Now, if you thought about it, it's easy task, but it's very repetitive task.
What if you would like to provide it for the programmers to use it, or like you are in your
project, you don't like people to keep repeating the same task.
How can we do that?
We do that through functions.
Here is how we code it as a function.
OK, this is the first time we start to learn what is this (main) that we used to see?
OK, let's try to stop the video for a minute and read this syntax in a very slowly manner.
The first thing that you notice here, that line 5 to line 8 are the same numbers that we were
doing the same logic for summing the numbers.
What about (int n)?
we find it here, OK, in a very weird syntax.
OK, let's decode it step by step.
This is called a function,
The function name is (sum1_to_n), the function needs two things.
It needs input parameters and it needs a return data type.
So this function takes from me (int n) as a request and returns for me an integer as an answer.
So for example, if this function took a request of 5, it's going to iterate here from 1 to 5,
sum it.
Once we are done with sum, we make (return sum).
So return sum is related to this data type.
We are returning a variable of type integer and this here an integer data type.
So again, we can think of a function here as a separate module that consists of the following items,
first, a function name, second, a function parameter, something that the user is asking for us,
Third, a return data type, forth, some computations,
Finally, a return statement with the data type.
Let's read here what's happening, we define (int n),
then we say  (cin>>n), let's say the user entered 5, then
here we say it's (sum1_to_n) and we give it between
these parentheses the variable n, which is 5.
The compiler once saw that, it goes to line 4 and tell here, hey, compute for me your answer.
If the input is just 5, I go and do the five steps to compute the sum and then I return the sum
which should be of the same data type as here or convertible to it.
once we are returned here, the compiler gets this expression value which is now 10 and assigns it
to the left hand side.
So as we see, this is now handled as an expression, this expression is going to be evaluated and
returned a value for us, notice here also there are these braces here for the body logic inside the function.
And now it is a very good time to know what this (main) is, the (main) we said before, it is a function.
when you run your computer, when you run your C++ program, the compiler goes and finds the main function.
The main function is the first entry in the program.
And as a function, it could have parameters here, which is nothing.
And it has its own braces and it's returning some integer.
we usually return 0, 0 means that we are telling the compiler we are done
in a successful way.
We can also return some other values;
but this is out of scope for now.
So this code has two functions, function
number 1, named main. Function
number 2, named (sum1_to_n). this function takes a parameter (int n), and returns result int.
One interesting thing here to notice is the scope, the variable sum, remember the if-conditions and
loops, the variable sum is defined inside these braces,
right?
So you cannot here, say let's (cout<<sum)
You don't see it.
It is a local variable; local to these braces, you cannot see outside the braces.
So, again, a function is: name, some parameters to request, and some result.
yeah, that's it for now,
Try to familiarize yourself with the syntax that we saw today.