Let's do some practice on functions, remember, we already took the Employee program and we already saw
these functionalities and these screenshots, now we are going to take our old code for the employees
and we are going to make it using functions.
I assume that you already practiced this program and you read my code and you thought about it.
Now, the first thing that we can do is the system itself.
We are going to create a function named "Employee_system", we call it here from the "main".
So the "main" function is calling the "Employee_system", which has a while loop and it's calling another function
called "menu", the "menu" will list the menu for the user and it is going to take a choice from him.
And then based on the choice, if choice number one, we call "read_empolyee", choice number 2 "print_employee",
choice number 3
We "delete_by_age", choice number four
We "update_the_salary_by_name".
So if you noticed about the logic here, we are making our life much much easier.
So now let's see what are these functions that we are calling.
first, let's make our life easier,
We are going to define something called
Global variables.
This is defined under the "#include" and "using namespace std;", the local variable is something
that is inside our function, such as "main" and yours.
The global variable is defined outside the function.
This makes it visible for all the functions that are exist in this cpp file.
That's why we call them global, that everyone is calling them.
We call these ones local because only their function is seeing them.
So I'm defining here my variables as global variables,
So everyone is just seeing them.
This is a "menu" function, it gives a while-loop it list the choices, it asks for the choice, if the choice invalid,
it just keeps trying again.
Once the user entered a valid choice, it returns it.
the "read_empoyee" is just taking nothing, and we have this global variable "added" and we read it item by item.
the "print_employee" is just iterating all the employees that are global and just printing them.
"delete_by_age", is reading the start and end and just iterating to delete it.
"update_salary" is again iterating and updating the salary of the user. notice that these already are the code
blocks that we did before,
We just move them to a function to make our life much easier.
That's it.