The homework for the functions, the first function is a function that computes max of six values, actually
up to six values.
I would like you to create the following function, "max", that takes three variables, four variables,
five variables, six variables,
OK, so just implement them.
There's a question here,
How can the function that takes one, two, three, four variables utilize the function that takes the
three variables and so on?
Think about the utilization between these functions.
Reverse a string,
You are to write a function that takes a string and just reverses it.
As you see, I'm putting here "const" reference "&", so you cannot change "str",
you have to return a new one.
Calculator, is a simple program that gives the user an option to add 2 numbers, subtract, multiply, divide.
This is simple program, but we would like to make it more functions.
First of all, define a function that read two double numbers and make it by reference.
Define four functions, one for every operation out of these four operations.
Make sure that you don't divide by 0 in the division, then display for the user the choices,
read it and then based on the choice, execute the program and so on.
Keep going, once that program ended,
print for the user how many operations that he already did.
So the user keeps going in this menu until he ends the program. Is Palindrome Array,
You are to read an integer "n", then n integers, call a function with the array to check if this palindrome
or not, We already did this before.
We just would like to move it to an array. Set-powers,
The function "set-powers" is as following,
This is the function, like we call it the declaration of it,
OK, so it takes an array, it takes length which is by default 5, and it takes M which is 2, OK?
the function will fill this array of length with the following,
The ith position will have the value of (m^i) which is "m * m * m..." i times.
For example, if I give you length = 6, and M = 2 is going to put the values to be 1, 2, 4, 8, 16,
32.
OK, so notice here 8 is just 2 * 4, 16 is 2 * 8 and so on.
The same for the value here, 4 and 3,
It's 1,3, 3 * 3 is 9, 9 * 3 is 27.
So the ith value has m multiplied i times. after return of call, print the array to make sure that it's working
well, try it with different default values.
Implement the two functions,
The first is, "is_prime", takes a number and returns true if the number is prime.
The second function is "nth-prime", it takes an n and returns the nth prime for us.
So if we give you 6, return 13, let this function call this function.
Replacing sub-string, it might not be easy.
So we are to define a function "replace_str", it takes "input" and "pattern" and "to", and returns a string, the
input is lower cases and "pattern" will be always greater than zero,
But "to" can be zero and more.
Here is the replacement,
What I mean with it, if the input is like "aa" blah blah blah, and you would like to replace every "aa" with
"X",
So you see here this "aa" will be "X" and this "aa" will be "X" here.
OK, if I asked you for this input with "aa" and 4 "a"s; this "aa" will be expanded to 4 "a"s and this
"aa" would be expanded with 4 "a"s.
If I asked you to replace "aa" with empty string, then you see we are removing
it.
I would like you also while coding this one to make another function called "starts_with", it takes an input
and pattern and takes integer position,
It returns true only if the pattern exists in input starting from this position.
For example, if we have this function, aa bla bla bla and we say does this pattern exist
starting from position zero? here is true,
But from here, at position one is false, this function would be helpful for you in developing
the pattern function.
That's it.