Let's see the homework of the functions.
The major goal of the functions homework is mainly the functions partto learn how to pass parameters,
how to get the output and so on.
So in the first task, we would like to get the maximum of six numbers, and we would like to provide
all of these variations of the max functions.
Now, there is a question here.
How can function like the max of all, like a one, two, three, four parameters, use the
function of the max of the three parameters.
The goal of that is to learn to utilize things.
You shouldn't start to build everything of that from scratch.
We can actually build it in a trivial way.
So here is how we can do that.
First of all, we know that the standard C++ provides us with a maximum between two variables like
a & b.
Now, I would like to implement function between maximum of three numbers.
But is an easy way.
First, we will compute the maximum between the two of them, like, let's say the b &c.
Now, this code will return for us, the maximum between them.
Now, compute the maximum between the first number and the result of the maximum of these two numbers.
Let's give an example.
Let's say the numbers were five, two and seven.
So first, we compute the maximum between two and seven, which is seven.
Then we compute the maximum between five and seven, which is five, which is seven.
As you see this way, the maximum function of the three variables didn't introduce any logic to compute
the maximum of three numbers.
All what it did is utilizing that we can use the previous max function.
And as you know, in C++, we can have a maximum function with the same name.
But the parameters should be, for example, different.
Now, moving to a maximum of four numbers, we will follow now the same logic exactly.
We will first compute the maximum of the last three numbers.
For example, if we have like a 10, 5, 2, 7 then we ask here for the maximum of 5, 2, 7.
After that, we compute the maximum of 10 and the remaining of the number. In a very similar way,
we can do that. In a very similar way we can do that.
As you see, we can utilize the previous functions in an incremental way.
We can also have like a different styles of implementation.
Like, for example, you can compute the maximum of the first three numbers,
the maximum of the last three numbers, the maximum among all of them.
or you just follow this nice structure.
I hope you found that this is like an educated problem.
In the second task, we would like to reverse a string.
The string is passed with const and with reference. Const means it will be fixed & reference means
we are passing it to look to the original caller, which is very efficient. In C++ APIs,
you will notice this structure a lot. Now let's see how to implement that.
In the reverse function all what we need is, first of all, I take a copy of the current string and
then I have two indices.
We call them in algorithms pointers also by the way,
but not the pointer stopping.
But anyway, so we have here,a  start equals zero
and in the looking to that last index in that string.
So, for example, if we pass a string to like abcd, we will have 'a' start at zero and it ends
at three.
Then we will go like halfway as long as the start is less than end.
We will do the following.
This is swapping for the initial start and end positions.
So, for example, let's see here.
If we have the abcd here in the first step, we will swap the a and d.
So it's now d and end is 'a'.
After that start to move one step and go backward one step,
so start at 'b'
and end at 'c', now we do one more swap,
so now this will be 'c'
and this would be 'b'.
Then start to go to the right and end go to the left.
Now, the start will be at position 2,
but end at position 1;  this means we are done with processing. The logic here of
start less than end is as following.
I have a string.
I would like to reverse it.
So I have reversed it; the first to last and the second to the second to last
and so on.
When I reach to the middle of the string, I am done with reversing.
What if we have odd number of characters?
'a' will be swept with 'e', ' b' will be swapped with 'd'.
And then start and end would be looking at 'c'.
So this is again a good time to stop.
So this function actually does the hub of the string of processing only. In every step,
it's swapping the two characters and stopping at this stage.
That's all.
Let's proceed to the third homework, which is more like a calculator, we would like to develop a bunch
of functions adding numbers, multiplying numbers, reading numbers, and there are some requirements
here, like you read two numbers, but by reference, you will develop four functions for each operation,
but don't divide by zero.
So this is a more or less an implementation task.
The first one here is a menu function, which you will see it a lot in the projects.
I have a menu which will return an integer, which is a valid choice.
And now I start with choice -1, because we are waiting for the user to choose.
And as long as the user didn't provide a valid choice, we will do the following.
You can skip this
if it doesn't have value here. You will print the five options and then you will read a choice.
If the choice is not between one and five,
we will say this is invalid.
Assign the choice again to -1 and then wait again for the input.
We definitely the user can make the corruption to the program, for example, by entering the string,
but we don't care at the moment about this kind of validation. For this
if condition, if it's confusing for you like this part, what does it say?
It say the choice is valid.
Choice is greater than or equal one and less than or equal five.
And notice how I'm writing it
like mathematically, this is as same as you want to write something like one less than or equal choice
less than or equal 5.
So you see how I code it in a nice way.
So keep it this way.
Now, what does this condition mean?
It means if choice is valid.
So you can read it like if not a valid choice.
This is how we can understand this line of code.
Once we are done here, if the choice is valid, then the condition will be broken and we can return
to the current choice. The 'read_2_num' read 2 numbers by reference and read them.
Then after the return of this function, the 'a' & 'b' will be initialized correctly with the values that
will read.
Then we have very straightforward
add, subtract, multiply and divide.
The only thing in the division is it checks if 'b' equals zero or not.
In general, we shouldn't compare doubles with a number in this way.
But let's keep it simple for now.
Finally, we have here the main program, which go as following.
while true, we will keep going.
Then it asks for the menu to give us a choice, which is number from one to five, if the number is
five that we
know that we need to break.
So we break the function.
We increment the total operations and read two numbers based on the choice, we decide which function
to call.
Once the program is ended, we inform about the total number of operations that we are done by this
program.
That's all.