In this one we would like to write Is Palindrome Array, but as a function, we already implemented this
logic before.
So it's more or less about writing the function itself.
Here is the code.
We have a function that we call 'read_array'.
So it takes an array of some big length like we define an array of big length.
And the function do the two things.
First, it will read the array content and it will read also here to the array length and return the array length.
Remember arrays are passed by reference anyway.
So you didn't need to take care like a reference or so if you read an array here, that array here will
be definitely updated.
OK.
This is different from the normal variables that you need to pass by a reference.
The second thing is the 'is_palindrome' function, where you take an array and its length.
You have to pass the length and in a very similar logic to the reversing function. You have start and
end positions.
You go half of the distance.
Compare the first with the last.
And if they are not equal, you break.
Otherwise, you keep going one step to the right and one step to the left.
If we are done, would have processing and everything is good.
You just return true. An example of that:
Let's say we have an aabaa for example.
So first we have a pointer at 'a' and 'a'.
Let's make it different.
Let's go to the adbda.
Now it first compare the 'a' with the 'a'.
Good?
Good.
Then now start at one and end with 'd',  compare 'd' with 'd'. good?
Yes.
Go.
Now at 'b' & 'b', they would be equal with no need to compare.
Stop.
So it means half of the distance.
We were good to go.
So this is a palindrome string.
This is all about the is_palindrome function.
Homework number five, Set-powers, we would like to take an array, and this is its length and m is the
value, the base.
And I would like to compute like all of the different bases, for example, 2 to
power 0, 2 to power 1, 2 to power 2, 2 to power 3, 2 to power 4, and so on.
So how can we do that with an array?
We would simply we can use the history, like let's say that you would like to do for
the base m equals 3 ,this is three, then the next number here is just three times three, which
is nine.
Then for the 27? it is just the three times nine and so on.
In a similar way here, if you have the eight multiplied by two, it's 16, multiplied by 2 it's 32.
So you can utilize your history here.
So let's see how to implement that.
We first of all, we have an array, we read its length, we read the 'm', then we call 'set_powers'.
After that we print the given array. 'set_powers' said the first number was one because 'm' to the power
zero is one. Then starting from one, it do the following:
It says that array of 'i' equals array of 'i-1', which is the history times two.
So let's see an example.
Let's say we'd like to make it for m=3.
Three.
We first initialize with m=1.
Then array of one would be array of zero times three.
So it would be now 3.
Then array of two will be array of one, which is three times three, which is nine.
Then array of the next number will be the previous, which is nine times three.
It would be twenty seven times three and so on.
So this is style is very similar to the Factorial style.
Remember a  factorial style that we were using the previous number.
So it's the same exactly.
Here.
So this is mainly about setting the powers.
What's next? Get the nth-prime.
We would like to develop two functions.
One of them is to compute the prime number and another one is to compute with the nth prime number.
And the nth prime number should use the is_prime number.
So let's see how can we develop that.
Firstly, let's develop 'is_prime' number, the is_prime logic we wrote it before
if I remember correctly. We take a number.
So the function would turn bool if the number is less than or equal one,
This isn't a prime number.
Otherwise, we can start from i=2 up to the number itself.
But without equal then plus plus. Every time we check if the number is divisible or not.
If it is, then we return false.
Otherwise, we return to true.
For example, if I give you a number like 11, then you start from 2 up to 10.
Every time you check does 11 is divisible by two?
No, divisible by three?
No. Divisible by four? No. Once it ends
and none of them were like divisible by i
so we know we are good to go.
This is a prime number.
Now, the next challenge may be the real challenge and the problem is the nth prime number.
This function will return us the nth prime number.
For example, if I give it number six, it will give for me 13.
So how to do that?
The idea is simple.
We will start from equal i=2.
And we have a counter, let's say six will keep searching the numbers starting from two.
Every number that  is a prime number,
we reduce one with us.
For example, we start with...,
We know that n equals six, we start at n equal 2. Is 2 prime number?
Yes.
Then we are searching now for the fifth
prime number. Is three prime number? Yes,  then searching for the fourth prime number
starting from here. Is four prime number?
No. Is five
prime number?
Yes.
Then we are searching for the third prime number
but from here, there are like the other three prime .
numbers.
Is six prime number?
No, no, ignore.
Is seven prime number?
Yes.
And we need like other three numbers.
Then now decrease it,
now we have two.
Is 8 prime number? No
Is nine prime number?
No, is 10 prime number?
No.
Is 11 prime number?
Yes.
Decrease it.
Now we are searching for a single prime number.
once we found it
we know that prime number. Is 12
prime number? No. Is 13
prime number? yes.
Now n equals zero, which means we found six prime numbers.
If we found six prime numbers and n equals zero, it means we are done.
We found it here.
So this is the logic here.
We start from 'i=2'.
And every time if this is a prime number, then remove one prime number.
We found one prime number.
We will keep searching, searching, searching. Once n == zero,
it means we found all of the numbers that we need.
So I must to be the prime number of interest.
So again, please use this example and try to trace it.
And the final loop here is just printing all the prime numbers from like one to 19, just the printing
of them here.
I hope the logic of the function is clear.