The next function is about replacing substring, you would like to take this input string and this pattern,
every time you see the pattern, you replace it.
But this example here is giving us an important message we see here three 'aaa'.
One might ask, should I replace this 'aa' and this 'aa' from the example? No.  This 'aa' would be completely
replaced by four A's.
Then the remaining 'a' would be just added here because there is no match.
And sometimes when we would like to develop a function, we can notice that we can develop other functions
that make our life easier.
An example here 'starts_with'  function which just checks if the string input at this position
has this pattern or not.
So let's see first how to make use of this function, how to write it.
The 'starts_with' takes
the input pattern and position. There is an early condition here that says if the position plus pattern size is
greater than input, then no way to find it.
Why?
Here's a simple example.
Let's say we have this string of five letters.
If I give you position like three.
Now, three plus the pattern, which is 2 is 5. Is 5 greater than five? false.
Which means we can match this string here, maybe.
Now, what if the position is 4? When you look to it
the remaining is only a single letter, and this is two letters.
So there is no way that this one would match it.
This is what the condition is
meaning. If the pattern needs to go beyond the current string, then there is no way there is a match.
Now, what if there is a match?
We start to compare the input string from this position comparing to the
first character of the pattern, for example, let's say the position is three.
Now we compare pattern of zero, which is 'a' with this input of three
which is this 'a', correct?
Yes.
Move to the next letter.
Compare the pattern of one with the position of four, which is 'a', correct?
Yes.
If the loop ended here, it simply means we had a match for a complete pattern from the begin with
the given string, that simple.
So now we have a start function that can help us.
The function here now is very simple.
It says as following: iterate on the input string step by step.
In the early of every string, we would make a check.
Does the current string start with the pattern here?
If yes, we replace it with the 2 patterns.
Otherwise, we keep going.
If yes, we add to the result, the whole pattern.
And then we jump after the pattern size.
Otherwise, we add the current result.
Let's see an example.
Let's say the pattern is 'xxxx'.
Now we go at the first character and say, does this string start with 'aa' from position zero?
'aa' from position zero?
Let's pretend that there is an 'f' or 'd' here.
Does it start with 'aa'?
The answer is no.
So we append here in the result the character 'd'.
Now, after that, we go to position equal one.
When does it start with 'aa'?
Yes.
So first we append there is 'xxx' here to the number, and then we move the position with the
size of the pattern minus one.
The size of the pattern is two,  two minus one is one.
So we jump it to
we were at position
One was one.
We jumped here at....,  let me double check.
We have here one.
And then plus one is two.
So we are this 'a'.
I have an impression that this minus one shouldn't be put, let me
double-check, position equals zero; we add it and move now....,
Oh, there is an extra plus here.
OK, so this minus one is actually corresponding to this plus plus here.
So here is the logic we would like to.
The logic is if we replaced the current pattern, let's say the pattern is five characters.
Now, if we replace the five characters, for example, we would like to jump after the five characters.
So we should actually say position plus equal five.
But I'm here
saying position plus equal four because there is an extra plus plus here.
OK.
Which made the code for a while
not that understandable.
But if I would rewrite this code to be better nicer, I would remove this minus one here
and add a position plus plus here.
Anyway, let's go back.
We were at letter index one.
Does it match 'aa' ?
Yes, it match.
Then we added four X's.
Then we jumped two steps.
So we jump at letter 'b'.
Now, does 'ba' match 'aa'?
The answer is no.
So we add 'b' to the result.
Then we say does 'aa' match 'aa'?
Yes, we add another 'xxxx'.
Then we jump after it two steps and then the string is ended.
So this way, the overall result is computed.
The major lesson here that I would like you to get it that sometimes with having such utilities
your life is much easier.
Sometimes you need to decompose your program to different parts
that would make the processing overall is easy and adorable.
That's all.