Let's play with more examples to administrate functions, we would like to help our team by creating
a function.
The function is called (absolute) the function, do as following:
If the number is positive, it returns it as it is, if the number is negative it returns it with negative
value.
So the first thing is define a function name, it is very close to the variable name, for example, you don't
start it with an integer,
You don't use dashes "-", you don't use the spaces.
So we define it as (our_abs). You need to define what is the input for the function and what is the
output from it.
So the parameter here integer n, represents the input to this function.
So we are going to give it an integer N and the result is going to be another integer. here in the logic,
at line 5,
We say "if (n >= 0) return n;" otherwise here we are returning -n.
So there are two return statements here and very similar to the return statements in the main.
Once you are returned, you are done with the function,
You don't complete any more.
So for example, if we requested the answer for 5, it says 5 >= 0?
Yes, return 5.
But if we ask it for -5, is "-5 >= 0?",
no, we jump to line 7, return -(-5), which is now again 5.
So again, you see we have a function name,
We have some parameter, we have some return,
We have some logic and return statements.
Let's say we have another case, let's solve a maximum function.
You would like to create a function that takes two inputs, parameter a and parameter b and returns
integer representing the maximum of two of them.
So we go as following, the max between 2 and 5,
So the value "a" will be assigned the value 2, the value "b" will be assigned the value 5.
Now what is the maximum between 2 and 5? if 2 >= 5
this is false.
So we go here to the "return b", which is just 5. On the other side,
If we sent 2 and -5, so is (2 >= -5)?,
The answer is yes, so return 2. again, function name, two parameters here, or two inputs and they call it also
argument, so here, inputs, parameters, arguments, and we are returning integer.
Let's make something that's little more complex, you are to find the maximum of absolute of two numbers.
What does this mean?
Let's say I give you 2 and 5.
So find the absolute first, then compute the maximum. 2 and -5 ?
Find the absolute first, then do the maximum.
So we have here our previous absolute function.
So now our max2 is calling the 2 and 5 for our max2 here.
So "a" is 2 and "b" is 5.
Then I did something interesting,
I here at "a",
I called the function, we call it (calling the function).
I called the function "our_abs" with "a",
So "a" is 2.
So I'm calling now another function,
So the main function is calling our max2 function, and our max2 function is calling our absolute
function.
It goes as following,
"our_abs" is called here with 2.
We know that this function if took 2 it returns 2, so "a" is 2, and then "our_abs(5)" it goes 5 and
returns as 5.
and then we are comparing for maximum value.
What about 2 and
-5?
"our_abs(2)" is returning 2, "our_abs(-5)"
returning 5,
Then we are computing the maximum of them.
So we notice here, function "main()" is
calling max function, which is calling another absolute function, so we can make such a lot of calls.
That's it.