In this video, we will learn more about some variations in the functions, the first thing is
looking to this function
"lucky_number".
This function has no parameters,
We already saw this before.
So the lucky number is a function that has a return but doesn't have a parameter.
We can also have here, you see function main2(), but this isn't what the compiler is going to call, the
compiler will call the function main().
There is a third case that is very interesting,
This function has two parameters "a" and "b", and it is going to print them.
But what if you don't want to return something from a function that just doing something like printing?
In this case we use the word "void",
"void" means empty, we use the word void and we return nothing from here, so we can have a function
without parameters,
We can have a function that doesn't return something.
What else?
There is something very interesting in C++ called the default values.
The default values is when you provide some default values for the parameters.
If you use the parameter, it is using your current value otherwise it is using the default value.
For now, let's first see the "our_pow" function, let's say, it is integer n, Integer b and just braces, forget
about = 3 here.
Then this is our normal function,
We take result with 1, we go p steps and we multiply with *n and the result is done we return
the result.
Now I'm giving here something, say
Int p = 3.
Now look at the main here we are calling the function once
with 2,
If we are calling with 2, then this 2 goes to the n.
What about the p? the p takes the default value which is here 3.
Otherwise I'm calling with 2 and 3, and 2 and 4,
So the p here will be 3 and the p in this case will be 4.
This is what we call default value.
So if you didn't set p, is going to be set as a default value.
Please notice the following,
The first is if you decided to use a variable with default value, the variables after it or parameters
must have also default values.
For example, you cannot have a function like the following, "int a", "int b = 2",
"int c", once you defined a default value, all the values after it must be default values.
Think about it.
The compiler will not be able to know what to assign, which is b, which is c,
OK. so how to do it,
It can be "int c = 3" or you define default value for b and c,
OK. and definitely we can have several default values, like "int a, int b = 2",
"int c = 3"
So be careful about that.
It isn't a mistake,
It's like more of a compiler error.
The compiler will not allow you to do that.
Casting, casting is interesting here in functions, so be careful about it. this function "add" has
an "int a" and an "int b", we called it with integer a, integer b, so far so good.
But what if we called with 2 and 3.5, a casting will happen, so 3.5 will
be converted to an integer, so it would be 3 also.
So be careful with function that allows casting this way.
The last thing here to mention is the "overloading", overloading is a very critical concept in C++.
Overloading happens when we have several functions who have the same name.
For example, you are calling here
"add" and "add", we have here 3 functions
Each one of them is called "add", now how the compiler will differentiate what you are calling,
by the parameters.
Are you using different parameters or not, either as a data type, or even as a number of parameters.
So here we say "int add",
that takes int, int.
Is this different from this one?
Yes, because it has double and double.
Yes, because it has three integers, but you only have two integers.
So function overloading is when you have several functions with same name, but they have different
parameters,
OK. notice here, the return isn't considered, like you cannot say "add(int a, int b)" returning integer, and
"add(int a, int b)" returning double, the return isn't considered.
What is considered is only the parameters.
OK, how the compiler differentiate?
If you called here 2 and 3, it's going to find which one is the most suitable for your function call
which is here 2 and 3, if you call 2.0 and 3.5 is going to call this one because
it's most useful.
If you called "add(1, 2, 3)" is going to name this one.
So this is how you can think logically, how the compiler can differentiate which one to give a call.
That's it.