In C++, when we pass an argument to a function, it could be passed by value or by reference.
Let's know the details about that, but I would like to make a clear distinction between what we call a parameter and
what we call an argument, because sometimes many programmers just like use them in the same way.
And I even during the course, sometimes I do that.
But this isn't an accurate.
So I would like to make it very clear distinction here.
The parameter is declared only in the declaration.
So here in the function, we declare it with variable "a" and "b", "a" and "b" are called the parameters of the function "print".
So the parameter is about the declaration itself.
Now when we are calling the function, what we are calling with are the arguments.
So if we define here x = 2, and call it with x and 5, x is an argument corresponding to "a", 5 is an argument
corresponding to "b", "3*2+1" is an argument corresponding to "a".
So parameters are about the declaration here, arguments about the passing, the passing here.
Now let's go back to our topic.
We are passing values through what we learned so far by value.
There is also another way to pass them by reference.
Let's see the details of that. We have here a function "change" which has an integer "a",
This is normal.
We have here something we call it integer reference b "int &b", and the reference always is related to a memory address.
This is called the ampersand "&" operator, we read it integer reference b and we would like to see the
effect of this reference. Here,
we have a function "change" that takes two arguments "a" and "b", so this "a" is going to
be assigned to this "a" by value.
This means the compiler in the runtime is going to take a copy, memory copy of this variable to assign
it here.
So when you pass here 1 to this int "a" is going to be here "a", now if you incremented this a++,
It is
local change.
So when you come back here and print a, it is going to be 1, because this "a" is very different from this
"a". memory wise,
We have two boxes, one from them for this local function here in the main, and another from them for
this one here.
So we have two copies.
So if we started to change this one, this doesn't affect this one.
On the other side, passing by reference means that this variable is going to share the same memory
location as this one.
So now both the function "change" and the function "main" are looking to the same memory location.
So we are passing here the value "b1", with its address to this "b" and then when you increment b++
and you come back here, you will notice that this "b" now is 2.
So the core difference between passing by value and passing by reference; passing by value creates a
new memory
copy, but passing by reference is the same memory location.
And as you might be able to guess, this might play a big factor from one side to simplify the code,
the other side to minimize the number of memory copies that we are doing.
For example, the more copies you are doing, the more memory you take.
It might be like basic when you are using primitives like Integer, but as we will know in the end of
the session, it might be sensitive in other scenarios.
Here is another case for a demonstration,
We have here a string name and we have a function that's going to read for us "a", "b" and "name".
So the "a" corresponds to x, but by copy. "b" is going to be by reference for "y". "name" is going to be by reference
for "str". Now when this function reads the "x" and "y" and "str",
We will notice that the value of "a" will not be changed, it will remain as 1, but the value of "b" and
the value of "name" will be changed because they are passed by reference.
So this is mainly what is passing by value and passing by reference.
The interesting thing about passing arrays, they are always passed by reference, so if you have here,
some array of 6 elements and you called function to sum array and you give it here length of 3
elements, and then we iterate on the first three elements to iterate over the array and sum them
and returning the sum.
This array here is the same as here.
So you can read it and you can write it and you can change it and it's going to affect the main.
So the array is passed by reference.
So as you see, we didn't have to put the "&" here because it's already passed by reference. As an another
observation,
We didn't need to put the actual size of the array here.
We can just drop it for 1D arrays.
One more thing, let's develop a function to compute if a string is lower or not.
So we have a function bool return type, it is tacking string and iterating on the string and just checking
if the character is between 'a' or 'z' or not, if yes, it's returning true for all of them, if any of them is
a violation, it's returning false.
Now, is this passing by value or passing by reference?
This is passing by value.
OK, the passing by reference, by default is only for the arrays.
Anything else by default would be by value.
So now this is good.
But remember, if this str, let's say is a big file of one million characters, in the runtime the
compiler has to make another copy of one million characters to the function as "str" here.
So this is a big waste of memory.
The best way in this case is to pass it by reference.
But remember, also, when you pass something by reference, it means they are sharing the same memory.
So this function might corrupt your "str".
So this is a risk of that.
There's one way to solve this problem, using "const"; if you use "const string &str", then
from one side you made sure that "str" is by reference,
So no more memory copy and also it is const,
So this guy doesn't need to change it.
does
a guy who is coding is_lower function have to change the content?
No.
So the proper signature for this function is "const string &str".
That's it.