In the previous videos, we learned about the functions, but there is also built-in functions.
A built-in function is a function that is ready and implemented for you to use.
So that saves your time.
So the C++ provides us with these built-in functions, to save our time.
And we in the teams, build the functions to save our team members' time.
So the "abs" function,
Remember, we did it by ourselves.
The "abs" function
takes a number and returns a positive value for it.
The "fabs" is the same, but you can provide it with a float absolute number so we can do it with a double.
the
The "ceil" is something that takes it to the highest positive integer and the "floor" takes it to the lowest
integer. The "round"
function is function that's going to round it up or down based on which one is closest.
So we see here, 2.4 is closer to 2, 2.5 is closer to 3, 2.6 to
the 3.
Now what about -2.6, -2.6 is always closer to -3, -2.4
is also closer to -2.
Notice here, "ceil" and "floor" are very tricky functions,
They are tricky in math,
So you should be careful about that.
Remember, the "ceil" of 2.4 was 3, which is the closest to it.
But what about the "ceil" of -2.4, the "ceil" of -2.4 is closer to -2,
not 2, 3 as here.
In a similar way, the "floor" of -2.4 is closer to the -3, not to
-2.
OK, so try to think about it.
When we have a -2.4, we know that we are in the negative,
So after -2 is -3, -2.4 here is closer to -3,
not to -2, OK, because -2 is going up and "floor" is about going down.
But here in 2.4, what is after 2.4 is 3.
Sorry.
What is before.
What is before
2.4, is 2 what is before -2.4, in scale is -3.
OK, square root 16 is definitely 4.
So where are these kind of functions.
You notice here
we started to make "#include", "#include" and this is a good time to know about
the #include.
We used to use "#include" but "include" means what ?
"include"
means include for me the built-in functions already, for example, the "#include" is going to
include for you these nice cmath functions that we have, when we "#include", it includes for
us the "cout" and the "cin", that allow us to read and write.
I would like you to go and explore this "cmath" function header.
It has a lot of C++11 and C++17 new functionalities.
Also "stdlib", go ahead and explore it.
You don't need to memorize this function.
They will be helpful over time just to use them from time to time.
Let's see
Other interesting kind of functions, the "is_alpha", "is_digit", "is_upper", "is_lower" cases, so you can double
check using these functions.
You don't need to say oh is this letter between 'a' small and 'A' capital.
There is an "is_alpha" function or "is_upper" , there are also "to_lower" and "to_upper" functions.
So you can use them. Notice here, the "is_upper" and "is_lower" functions,
They don't return necessarily true or false.
They actually return 0 for false and return some integer for true.
OK, so be careful,
This is more of an integer value.
It typically will not cause a problem for you.
You can also call "max" function and "power" function and "log" function and "log10". the difference between "log2"
and "log10",
"log2" is about binary log,
and "log10" is just about 10th log.
If you aren't familiar with the log function, no problem.
There is also you can create some random number, for example, the "rand" function, the "rand" function
returns some number between 0 and something called "RAND_MAX".
So if you divided these two by itself, it's going to give you some number between 0 and 1.
This isn't the best way to do a random function, but just good to know at the moment.
Let's go back to the "is_lower" function,
Remember when we said "is_lower" and we said we better send "const" here, string &str.
Now if we would like to know if the whole string is lower or not, we can iterate on it character
by character and then calling the stdlib "if (!islower(str[i]))" you return false.
So now what
happened, you simplified on yourself.
So what is "const"? "const"
means a variable once initialized, it will not be changed, if you thought about the logic of "islower",
we aren't supposed to make a change to the "str".
We are just supposed to use it to judge if it's lower or not.
Now we know if we sent "str" without a reference "&",
It's going to just take more memory and more time to make a new copy in the memory.
So we need to send it with reference "&" here,
OK. so what does "const" mean? "const" means that this function will not change
the "str". Think of it like I am a caller for this function and I'm sure it will not corrupt my data.
But why I must put "const" here!, the reason behind that, that this is
a variable that doesn't have a name and there is a rule in C++, if you would like to assign some variable
-temporary variable- to a variable with reference "&", it must be "const".
So this is a rule in C++. your turn, we can really make a lot of mistakes using functions, try to create
as much functions as you can, for example, make mistakes in function names,
Forget to return, try to call with the wrong data types, try to call function that doesn't exist,
and red the compilation error.
This would be very useful for you.