There are three important types of variables, what we call a global variable, local variable and a
static variable.
So remember the local variable,
we actually we're using it all the time.
It is this variable inside your main function, a variable that has a scope,
braces, once the braces are done, the variable is destroyed.
You cannot use it outside of braces, say outside if-condition or outside the function.
Now there is on the other side what we call a global variable, and this is variable is defined outside
all of the functions.
So you see here, we have here the #include..., "using namespace",
We have here some function "main", but from line 4 to line 10, we have some variable defined in the very
public scope, in the very general scope.
You see them, they are here.
So this kind of variables we call them global variables. similar to the local variables, if the variable
is defined at line 5,
It is visible only for the lines under it.
So this is where you can define some global variables.
You cannot come here and say, "cout<<global_val", you cannot do that, but you can define and declare
them here in this scope.
So this is mainly what we call a global variable.
There is also a case where you can make it global and static.
We will discuss this later in the headers and "include" topic.
So there is also another very interesting type, what we call a local static, a static variable let's call it
just a static variable.
So you see here, we have oh, by the way, I want to go one step back here,
If you didn't initialize a global variable, it's by default would be initialized to zero.
So like in this case, it will be just 0. Going back to here,
this is your local variable,
here we are initializing it to zero,
This is good. Here,
We didn't initialize it to anything,
So this is garbage.
Now we have here something we call "static int si",
Now, this is a static variable, the static variables
are allocated only once in the first time they are called, and they are visible, and the same variable
through the whole content, they will be visible from the same place.
So only the guys here inside the "fun" function can see "si", no one else.
Now the interesting is every time the function is called the variable is using his last value, it isn't
initialized from scratch like a local variable.
This is the difference between them.
For example, let's say we have here "i1" with 0, and "si" with 0, every time we try to increment "i1"
And "si", and also we try to increment the global variable with 10.
Now let's call the function "fun" three times.
The first time you noticed here the printing of
"i1", forget about this,
this is a mistake, "i1" would be 1 1 1.
But when you see the "si" printing, you will notice it will be 1, 2, 3, wait a second,
Every time this guy has a value 0.
Why it is once 1 and then once 2 and once 3!
The reason behind that is the the last value of this variable will be used, this way the static is
defined only once and the same through the whole program.
So in the first call is "si" defined and declared? no,
OK, give it value zero and increment it, print it,
So it's 1. in the second call,
The function would say is "si" defined?
yes, what is its
last value?
It was 1, increment it,
It is now 2, print it, so it's now 2. Call function
number 3, is "si" defined?
Yes,
What is the last value? 2, increment it, 3, and so on.
So you notice it is a very great advantage when you have a function that can maintain an information
through its history.
The global variable here also visible in the public.
So every time you increment it, you will notice that its value is here visible.
It's visible from the global variable, visible from the "fun" function.
And we can increment it.
But there is difference here, the variable "si" is visible only from inside, but the global is visible
through the whole program.
That's all, the global and static variables are initialized to their default values, which is zero.
There are later topic named pointers,
So the value of pointers is null pointer. a global variable as said: visible from where we declare 'till like every
line under it.
In practice, we don't use static local variables
or global variables.
This isn't good practice, but however, it's good to know about them.
That's it.