Hi Everyone, in this lecture we will talk about mathematical expectation and which is an important concept
in probability theory.
And it is always good to learn about this concept because in programming also you might be facing
some problems which are related with calculating the expectation of something. OK?
So let us talk about what is this term expectation.
So expectation is kind of a weighted average value of a random variable.
Now you may ask what is a random variable?
OK, so a random variable is one of the outcomes of phenomena or a random event
you can say. OK So random variable is one of the outcomes of an experiment. OK?
So now you may ask what is a experiment.
So let us denote.
Let's take few examples of a random experiment.
For example, you throw a coin.
OK, you throw a coin in the air.
And that coin may get a head or a tail as the outcome. OK, so we can say X is  random variable
that can take the value head or it can take the value tail. OK.
Or maybe another example could be you throw a dice and this is a dice with six sides and you can get
the numbers in the range let's say one to six. OK.
So x is a random variable that can take the values one, two, three, four, five and six.
Now I hope you understood what is a random variable.
.
So what is the expectation? we will calculate.
What is the expected value if you throw a dice.
OK, so it's kind of a weighted average. so we'll see how we can calculate this average.
So mathematically, for a discrete variable x. ok. now let me also talk about the difference between
a discrete and a continuous variable ok. so
random variable come in to syllabus.
They can have discrete values or they can have continuous values. OK?
For example, let's say X is a random variable that denotes what would be the temperature of today.
OK, the temperature for today.
Today is a cold day so maybe I can say the temperature is around 10 degrees Celsius.
OK. but it can be 10.1.
It can be 10.2.
It can be 10.25.
.
OK, now you can see X denotes the variable temperature for the day and it is a random variable and
it can take continuous values. OK?
It can take continuous values so we will say X is a continuous random variable whereas in case of throwing
a die, X can take only one of the fixed values.
OK. so one of the values in the range one to six.
In this case, we say it is a discrete random variable because the outcomes have discrete values. OK?
The outcomes have discrete values so I hope you understood the difference between a continuous and
a discrete random variable.
Most of the problems that we would be discussing they would be based on the concept of discrete random
variables.
OK.
So mathematically, for a discrete random variable X with the probability function P of x the expected
value it is denoted using E of X is given by summation of Xi into P of Xi where P stand for the
probability of that particular value.
The summation runs over all distinct values of Xi, the variable can take.
OK.
So basically, if I have something like X. what is the possible values of Xi?
Say so x.. X can take the values zero. sorry In case of our die it can take the value one.
It can take value two.three four five and six.
So what is P(xi)? P(xi) denotes
What is the probability of each value of Xi.
OK, so if this is the ith outcome. the probability that this die will throw one by three, assuming
it is a fair die. OK. assuming it is a fair die. like every side has an equal probability of showing
up.
So we can say this probability is nothing but one by six, one by six, one by six, one by six
and one by six.
So each of the side has an equal probability.
That is one by six.
And how do we calculate the expected value?
That can show up on a die.
So that is nothing but summation of Xi into P(xi).
OK.
That is nothing but one multiplied by one by six plus two
Multiplied by one by six
Three multiplied by one
by six plus four
Into one
By six
Five by six and six by six.
OK.
If you just find out this, it is nothing but one by six common. one plus two plus three plus four
plus five plus six.
This sum is what?
So this comes out to be 3.5.
OK. so now what you can say is 3.5 is the expected value.
It's some kind of average value that you can expect when a die is rolled, let's say infinite number
of times.
OK. so this is the expected value that you will get.
And this is not equal to the most probable value.ok.
It is not equal to the most probable values.
Expectation is not same as the most probable value because on a diet you can never get a value three point
five.
But this is kind of an average.
If you do a lot of experiment of rolling die, the average would be close to this result.
This is what you can expect in the long run that your sum of values divided by the number of dies throws
would be close to 3.5.
This is what an expectation is.
Okay, so I hope you are able to understand what is the meaning of expectation.
Let me also talk about for a continuous variable with the probability density function P(x), since
a variable is const.. like it's continuous.
Let say the variable is like temperature and here we say.
OK?
Probability of having that particular temperature.
OK. so maybe it's a cold day.
So the average temperature maybe is around 10.
So maybe you might get this kind of a probability distribution curve.
So in this case, the expected value of E(x) or E of temperature is given by Xp(x) into the dx, so
basically you're doing this integration.
OK, so it is integration of xp(x) into the dx.
So this is nothing but this is again the area under the curve.
So its integration is also a way of summing up.
But this is used for continues variables.
So it's more into the mathematical side in programming.
You might not be needing to implement this integration formula in your code.
OK. it's going to be very, very, very rare.
OK.
But just to tell you that these two formulas are integration is like summation over the continuous
variable and the previous case that we just saw.
This is summation sign. it's for a discrete variable.
This can be easily implemented using for loop.You iterate over the values of X.
You should know the values of P(x) and you can find out the expected value of a given variable.
So that's all for this lecture.
And thank you.