Hi Everyone, so in this lecture we're going to talk about an important theorem which is known as linearity
of expectation.
So basically, it is a theorem that state that
the expected value, the expected value of the sum of two random variables.
ok, it can be more also, two or more random variables
is equal to the sum of... is equal to the sum of
expect sum of their individual expected values.. their individual.
expected values. Ok. so now you may ask.
Let's try to make it more clear.
Ok. so these random variables can be dependent or they can be independent as well.
Ok. so it does not matter whether the two random variables are dependent or they're independent.
Ok. so let me try to explain you with the help of an example.
So this is how you state this mathematically that E(x1+x2)  is equal to E(x1) + E(x2).
Let us discuss one example, suppose we are playing a game in which we take the sum of the numbers
rolled on a  two six sided dice.
.
Calculate the expected value of sum of the rolls.
Now you're throwing two dice
so what are the possible outcomes?
So you can..
You can see this matrix.
ok. so the first on the first die you get one, on the second die you also get one.
So the sum is two. on first die, you get one. on second die,  you get two. the sum is three and so on.
So you will have basically six into six.
You will have 36 outcomes.
OK.
And the probability of each outcome, you know it's going to be one by 36.
And now if you want to find out what is expected sum on the two die, so you will be doing OK one by
six, one by thirty six into two plus one by thirty six into three plus one by 36 into four.
OK.
So all those sums you would be iterating upon
this you would be doing. now
The rule of linearity of expectation states that
So all the statistics moves, you would be upon. this is the basic method that we are doing OK.
So but if we try to solve it smartly, if you use the rule of linearity of expectation, that is going
to basically say that this is nothing but equal to so we can say we want to find P(x1+x2)
So it basically says this expected values same as the expected value from the first die plus the
expected value from the second die.
So if you see this, this we have already seen that this is 3.5.
This is also 3.5.
So we can finally say this sum is seven.
So by using this principle we are able to simplify this problem a lot instead of iterating over 36
possible cases.
We broke down into these two values that we already know and this is a rule of linearity of expectation
is going to help us to simplify the problem
statement. Okay.
So... so you can see this is how powerful it is and that all.