Hi Everyone, so let us try to solve a problem using the rule of linearity of expectation.
So let us go through this question.
So it is a fair coin is true N times.
What is the expected number of heads that you can get to get?
So let us consider this experiment of flipping a coin N times.
And let us denote the outcomes of the experiment using this array.
So the first experiment outcome is let say E1, the second experiment is E2,E3 and up
to up to En.
So we want to calculate E(z).
That is nothing but E(e1)+E(e2)+E(e3)+
up to up to En. where E(i) what is E(i)?
So E(i) denote... it will take the value one if the ith experiment got the value head OK.
In the ith experiment, if you got a head.
This would be one or it would be zero if you got a failure.
OK, let's see if you got a tail.
So now what...
What we can say is that this can be written as E(e1)+E(e2)+E(e3)
And up to up to E(n). now we want to find out what is the value of E(ei)?
OK, what is the expected value of the ith experiment?
So we know that this can be written as Sigma xi nto pi, where Xi is the value that you got so Xi
is one.
What is the probability of getting a head?
That is half.
What is the probability of getting a tail? that is also half.
OK, so this comes out to be 0.5.
So what we can do is we can put each of these values as 0.5.
OK, so you are basically doing the summation of 0.5 how many times? N times.
This becomes N  into 0.5.
And this is equal to N/2 and you can see that this is the probability.
This is the probability of getting...
This is the expected number of heads.
If you throw.... throw of... throw of fair coin N times.
So basically it is half of them would be heads.
And that is also seems true
Logically, because of half the number of times you are, you can expect heads OK.
And I hope you understood this problem as well.
And that's all for this video.