Hi Everyone, in this lecture we will discuss how we can approach some more problems involving the expectation.
So let's go to through our first question.
So it says what is the expected number of coin flips to get a head?
So let's discuss the approach that we will follow to solve all problems of this kind.
So will assume that this expected number is x .OK and we want to calculate the x.
So we have discussed that the expectation x.
OK.
So or you can say  E(x), whatever it is?
So we want to calculate this value.
So what we are going to say? This is equal to summation of xi into P(xi), this is what we have
learned.
OK.
So what is p(xi)?
It is the probability of getting an outcome xi.
OK, so what can be an outcome in this case?
If you throw a coin, you can get a head.
You can get a tail.
So suppose if you get ahead. Ok. that means you got the success in the first throw itself.
So how many throws you needed, you actually needed only one throw.
So you needed only one throw.
.
OK.
And what is the probability of getting the head in the first throw?
That is nothing but half.
Ok. but what if if you don't get a head in the first throw, suppose you get a tail. Ok. let say you get
a tail. now
How many throws you would need to get a head?
OK.
So effectively you have already wasted one throw.
And you're saying the expected number of throw to get a head is X.
So effectively you would be needing X+1 number of throws.
ok. this is an important thing
you need to understand that you have already wasted one throw. ok. and you did not get a head. suppose
you got a tail in the first throw.
OK, that means you got a tail and you're expecting you will require X number of more throw to get a head.
So the total number of throw would be 1+x.
It would be 1+X.
Into the probability of getting a failure in the first  throw  that means the probability of getting a
tail in the first throw that is again half.
ok. So this is equal to X. let us solve this equations so it becomes 2x+1+1+
x.
This becomes the 2X-X.
This is equal to two.
And this gives us the final value of X that is equal to 2.
So yes, we can say we would required two number of throws to expect a head.
And that makes sense.
OK, that makes sense as well. ok.
So this is how you will frame kind of recursive relation.
And you will try to solve this equation to get the number of coin flips together.
OK.
So let us see one more example in the next lecture.