Hi Everyone, so let us move on to the next problem statement.so we have seen what is the expected number
of throws to get a head.
So in this question, we are slightly going to change the question. so the question is, what is the expected
number of throws that you would need to get two consecutive heads?
OK, so that means we want to get a head
Followed by a head again.
Ok. so now what may happen is let us assume that our that is equal to x. the expected number of coin flip
is equal to X.
Suppose you throw a coin once and you end up getting
a head.
Ok. so what would be the probability of getting a head one by two?
OK.
And suppose you again throw a coin you again and get a head.
So what would be this probability? one by two.
So we actually throw a coin two times and suppose we got a head and again a head.
That would be equal to one by two into one by two multiplied with two.
What could be the other case?
Suppose on the first throw you get ahead.
On the second throw you get a tail.
OK, so what would be this probability? Half.
And again, it would be half.
That means now you have wasted two throws and you again... you would require X number of more throws to
expect two more heads.
OK, so that means in total you would require x+2 t in throws this case.
So it would be one by two into one by two into the number of throws that is equal to x+2.
So what may happen in other case as well?
Suppose you throw a coin and you get a tail in the first throw.
And in this case, what you will say? you will say. ok, I will try my experiment again and I will require
X number of more throws to get two heads. OK?
So in this case, you have wasted one throw.
OK.
So you can say one by two into X plus one. any other case?
No, we have already covered all the cases.
So let's see how we can solve this equation.
So it becomes X equals two.
This two goes off.
It is equal to half plus one by four into X plus two into again.
Half into x plus one.
So let us multiply everything with four. it becomes 4x, it becomes four, it becomes four, and it
also becomes four.
OK, so this becomes two. this goes off and this becomes two.
Let's expand.
So four x equals two plus x plus two plus 2x plus two.
So effectively it becomes two plus two plus two six and this is x plus two x three x.
So four x minus three x is equal to six.
That means X is equal to six.
OK, so that... this is how you can solve this equation.
And what we are saying is we would... we can expect two consecutive heads if we throw a coin six times.
OK?
So I hope you understood this problem as well and see you in the next video.