Hi, everyone.
So let us increase the complexity of the question a little bit.
And instead of saying two consecutive three consecutive votes, we are going to write for the general
case.
What is the expected number of coin flips that are needed to get and consecutive it took?
So the answer will obviously depend upon the value of and so we need to analyze this and find out answer,
OK.
So let's see how we can solve this problem.
So what?
Let's assume that the transit is equal to X and we draw the line and suppose we get a failure in the
first row.
OK, so the probability of getting a tail is one by two, and we would required X more troops to get
in consecutive if I took it.
So it would be half multiplied with X plus one because we have already wasted one through.
So this is one case.
Another case could be that in the first rule, we get ahead.
OK, the probability stuff.
But in the next rule, we don't get ahead.
So suppose we get a deal.
So that means we have wasted two throws and we would regret x more throws.
OK.
So in total, we would be needing X Plus two throws to begin to get.
It is one by two in the one by two in the X plus two.
Similarly, we may have we get ahead, we get ahead.
And now we get a failure.
We get a deal.
The probability is one by eight into x Exmoor throws, so it becomes explicitly so I can see one upon
one, divided by two by whether it is explicitly OK.
Similarly, to keep on going in the worst case, what is going to happen?
We are going to say that suppose we get n minus one heads, OK?
And the net experiment gave us a tale, OK, in this case, what is going to happen again?
It would be one divided by two days to devouring.
That means we have wasted and number two and number of troops and we have to do the experiment again,
which would expect X number of tries.
So it would be X Plus and we're going to plus one by two, raise the dividend into X plus and a rate.
Then there would be a case in which we get a success.
Suppose in all the interests, we get heads, what is the probability of this happening?
It would be one way to raise the and into how many trials we needed.
We actually needed a number of trials.
OK, so that would be.
And so it would be plus one way to raise the dividend in two and OK.
So this is the case where we get all the needs in a number of trials because this is where we just get
a success.
But otherwise, even if there is one failure, then this would be the series that we would be getting.
OK, now let us try to simplify this.
How we can solve this equation so we can say X equals what if I take X common out of all the dumps?
It would be like X in the one by two plus one by four plus one by eight up to up to one by two rated
to.
OK.
Less.
What are these terms?
One by two into this one by four, into this one by eight into this.
So it would be less one battle, less two by or less three by eight less four by 16 and so on.
Less divided by and in duration.
Well, then less this term.
This term will carry a gun as it is and divided by the rest of the power.
And now you may ask, how do we solve this equation, OK?
So if you now look carefully this equation that we are looking at?
This equation is a dramatic progression.
It's a job.
So you know how to find the sum of in terms of GP.
It can be done.
What about this?
So in the denominator, this is deep in the numerator.
This is AP and this kind of a series is called as AGP.
OK.
So what you need to you need to find out the sum of in terms of the ultimate big geometric progression
that is again doable, that can be done.
And this term is a singledom.
And as you can handle separately, OK?
So I'm not going to solve this deep before you.
I'm just going to write down the result.
So if you solve this equation, if you simplify, then what?
You're going to get it having to get the value of X storage to the IT and plus one minus two.
This is doable.
OK.
This is the final result that you would be getting.
And you can verify if you put any equal or two.
Then in the previous example, for two consecutive heads, we got an answer as it becomes two plus one
minus two.
That is eight minus two.
That is six.
Yes, we derived this on that six in the previous example as well.
And that's so this this is the correct result.
We have not sold AGP 40.
We have no ideology before you.
So if you go back to your school level, maths are class 12 months, I think, then you should be able
to definitely able to derive this result.
Otherwise, you can just skip and go to the next problems as well.
OK.
So that's all for this we do.
And thanks a lot.