Hi Everyone, In this lecture will talk about Bernoulli's trial. so what is a Bernoulli's trial ? So an experiment
is called Bernoulli's trial if it has exactly two outcomes.
For example, an experiment may end up in a success state or it may end up in a failure state.Exactly
two outcomes and out of which one is desired. for example, flipping a coin
Exactly
two outcomes. a head and tail.
OK.
Selecting a number from one to 100 to get the prime or not prime. So again
two outcomes prime or not prime.
Or rolling a die to get a four. So exactly two outcomes getting a four or getting a non four.
OK?
So these all are examples of Bernoulli's trial and an experiment as a Bernoulli's trial
If the outcome can be represented using yes or no or a success failure kind of a state.
This is what Bernoulli trial is in simple terms.
And let's see at theorem that is associated with
Bernoulli's trial. If the probability of getting a success in Bernoulli's trial is P and the expected
number of trials to get success is one by P. effectively what we are saying is if we need it, If the probability
of success is P, then the number of trials we would need is one by P.
Let us look at one example.
For example, what is the number of trials you would need to get a head?
OK.
So the probability of getting a head is what ? if a fair coin is thrown it is one by two.
OK?
And what is the number of trials you would need to get a head?
So it would be nothing
But X would be equal to one by P.
so one upon
What is P ? It is 0.5.
.
So it is equal to two.
So you can say in two throws you can expect a head.
OK.
And what was the other method that we have already seen by making a simple equation so we can say we
can get. we can say x is the number of trials.
If you get head in the first throw itself, it is one by two into one. ok. Probability of getting a head
into number of throws.
Or if we get a failure in the first throw. Ok. that would be one by two. getting.... getting a failure.
And how many throws we would need, it would be 1+x.
So again, if you solve this equation, it is equal to 2x+1+1+x.
This becomes X equal to two. again, using this method or if you use this method, you're getting the
same answer.
So you can use either of these but this is more like a shortcut.
You can get the answer for events which are Bernoulli's trial in just one step.Ok. or otherwise you
can use the basic equation method that we have already discussed.
So this is Theorem one and Theorem two says the probability of getting success in a Bernoulli's trial is
P, then the expected number of successes
In N trial is N by P. OK.
For example, if you conduct multiple trials T1, T2 ,T3. Ok. T4  up to Tn. In any trial if
you are able to get success
With the probability of P then in N trial, how many successes you would have?
Again, it would be P P P, you're going to add all of them.
OK.
And this would be nothing but N multiplied with P.
So this is equal to NP. as simple as that. OK?
These are the two theorem that you should be knowing.
And from the next video, we will solve one problem on Bernoulli's trial.