OK, let us discuss this problem choose
Numbers. it says, N students are ask to choose a number from one to 100.
OK.
What is the expected number of students that would choose a single digit number?
So let us talk about a single student.
OK?
What is the probability of single student choosing a one digit number?
So between 1 to 100, we have only nine numbers so that means this probability would be 9/100.
Now we are doing this experiment not for a single student.
We are doing this experiment for N number of students, OK?
So if the probability of getting success in a single experiment has P OK. then we have seen from
theorem 2 that for N experiment or for N student.
This is going to be N into P. OK.
So we can see this is going to be 9P upon 100.
And that's that's it.
That's the answer.
This is nothing but a simple application of Theorem two of Bernoulli's trial. that we have seen in the
concept video.
OK?
So that's all.