Hi Everyone, so let's discuss this question of interviewing candidates.
So it says candidates are appearing for interview one after another.
The probability of each candidate getting selected is zero point one six.
What is the expected number of candidates you would need to interview to make sure you at least select
somebody?
So that basically means what is the probability of getting a success in an interview, in how many trials
a candidate would become successful?
That's another way of framing this problem statement.
If you use the concept of a Bernoulli's style. is this evnet a Bernoulli's trial ?the answer is yes. so
either person can pass in the interview or it can fail in the interview.
OK. so there are only two outcomes.
The probability of getting a success is 0.16.
So how many trials you would need?
That is nothing but one by three.
And this is equal to 6.25.
.
So you can in seven interviews. OK, you can down rounded up to seven.
You can say in seven interviews.
You can say
You will select someone. you cannot take 6.25 interviews.
You have to take seven interviews only.
OK, doing interviews  interviews, you're going to select someone, OK?
And if you want to solve this using the equation method, you can still do it.
So you can say X equals 0.16.
If the person gets successful in the first interview then or if the person fails in the first interview,
then you would require X+1 more interviews ok so probability of getting a failure.
That would be o1-0.6. 0.6 into x+1.
OK.
You can simply solve this equation and again what you will get?  you will get X equals one up one
point one six.
This is again 6.25.
OK?
This is method one, which is using  Bernoulli's trial.
And this is the standard equation approach that we have already seen.
So that's all for this video.
Thanks a lot.