Hi Everyone, In this lecture we're going to talk about a general type of problem, which is known as coupon
collector problem.
Let us understand this problem statement and this can be applied in question of this particular type. ok.
Let's see this question.
A certain brand distributes a coupon in a packet of chips.
The coupon is chosen randomly from a set of N distinct coupons, so you have N type of coupons. let say
a coupon of type one, coupon of type two, up to a coupon of type N. and any packet of chips can contain
coupon with the value x.
OK. I don't know what is this value x?
What is the expected number of packets that you will buy so that you get all the N distinct coupon?
So you want to collect all N distinct coupon?
And what is the number of packets you have to buy?
That is what you need to find out.
OK.
So another way to frame this question could be how many throws are needed so that you see all the N faces
of  a N sided die.
OK?
How many throws are needed?
To get
all N faces
Of a N sided die. For example If the die has six sides. in how many throws you will see, all the faces from
one to six. that is another way of framing this particular problem.
Let us discuss how we can solve this problem.
What we will do? we will say okay. let us say that E(xi) denotes
the number of pockets you will buy, denotes the number of bags you will buy
To get.
to grab the ith new, the ith new coupon.
ok, I'm not saying the ith coupon I am saying ith new coupon.
That means you have already collected I-1 type of coupon and now you're collecting the ith type
of coupon.
And what is the value that we want to compute?
We want to compute E(x).
That means we want to get all types of coupons which can be written as E(x1+x2+x3+...xn)
.
This is what we want to compute and we have seen that using the rule of linearity of expectation.
This can be written as E(x1) plus E(x2) plus E(x3) and so on E(xn). all of these
terms can be added independently.
Now we also saw that
getting a new coupon or getting an old coupon, so whenever this event is can be treated as a Bernoulli's trial,
ok so what is the probability of getting a new coupon ?so why it is a
Bernoulli's trial, because if you buy a packet of chips, either you will get a new coupon.
That is a success.
OK.
Or you will get a coupon that you already have.
That means you will get the old coupon that is a state of failure.
What is the probability of getting the ith new coupon?
Probability of getting
the ith new open. let us try to find out this probability. so this would be how many new coupon are
available.
ok. that is available
new coupon after you have collected I-1 type of coupon upon total coupons. ok.
upon total coupon. as simple as that.
The probability of getting the ith new coupon is going to be nothing but let's say this probability
is equal to N minus
how many coupon would be available?
Suppose you have already collected
I-1 type of coupon OK. and total coupon is N. how many new type of coupon would be available
that would be nothing but N-i-1
.
OK.
Upon total coupons that is N. so that means this probability P is nothing but n-i+1 upon N.
And then what is E(xi)?
Because
this is a case of a Bernoulli's trial.
OK, so we can say this probability is nothing but one by P.
The number of pack that you will need to buy to get the ith new coupon is nothing but N upon
N-I +1.
OK.
And what is the value that you want to compute?
You want to compute E(x) that is equal to E(x1).
So If you put the value of I is one what you get? you get N upon N-1+1.
So you can clearly see that in order to get the first unique coupon, you only need to buy one pack.
ok at buying one back will give you the first new coupon.
OK, what about E(x2)?
So you will add this term to put the value of I as two.
It becomes N upon N minus two plus one, which is N-1. E(x3) that is N upon N-2
upon so on....
To get the Nth new coupon what it would be? you will say N divided by N-I,
which is N+1, so effectively you can clearly see if you have collected N-1
of coupons, then to get the Nth unique coupon the expected number of packs that you need to buy
is equal to N.
so that is what this series is.
So if you try to simplify this to what you will get is, you will get OK.
N upon N. so if you take the term N outside, it becomes... it becomes starting from this thing.
So I'm just going to write the terms.
In this order, it becomes one plus one by two plus one by three plus up to up to up to this term.
This term becomes one by N.
So this is the final result and this is... this would be your answer ok. For any given value of N
You can easily compute this.
series using a for loop and you can finally output your answer.
So I hope you have understood this problem.
And that's all for this video.