Hi Everyone, in this lecture we're going to discuss a problem unique number.
OK, so what this question is, your given the 2N+1 numbers?
That means you have odd number of numbers. Ok. where every number comes twice except one number
Find out that unique number.
Okay, so let me give or take an example.
let's say a we have N equal to seven.
That means we have odd number of numbers because it is 2N+1.
And let's say the numbers are one, two, five, five and maybe one.
And let's say two.
Ok. let's say this number is three.
So what we are doing is? let's we also have a number six and we also have a number three.
We have N equal to let say nine numbers and we want to find out the unique numbers.
So clearly you can see there is one number that is coming only once that is this number six.
OK.
That is this number six.
So now how do you then approach this problem?
So the approach one could be what a brute force approach.
You can go to every number and you can check.
You can scan the entire array whether this number is coming or not.
Ok. if this number is repeating in the array again then obviously three is not a number.
Then you go two, do the same process again
You will find another two here.
You go to five, you'll find another five here.
OK, you go to this five, you scan the entire array and check, whether there is another five coming up or not.
Okay, easily,
This approach is going to take order(n^2) time and we do not need any extra space.
So it is going to take O(1) space. OK?
So input array is going to take space but that is not extra space.
Let's talk about approach two. In approach to what we can do is? we can maintain kind of a frequency
table. OK?
We can maintain kind of a frequency table or a hash map or a hash map.
hash map is going to be  unordered map.
And we can just put everything inside a hash map so we can go to three, we can say, ok.
Three is coming.
What? three is coming
one time. we go two. two is coming
One time. we go to five.
Five is coming
One time. we go to five
It is coming again to increment the frequency of five. we go to one.
one is also coming, one should also be there, OK?
One should also be repeating. One is coming one time, two is coming two time, 6 is coming how
much time? six is coming one time only. ok.
So what we can do now is we go to three, three is coming two times and we go to one,
one is coming two times.
Now if you look at this. Ok. if you look at this.
Then clearly you can iterate over the frequency table and you can check which number has a frequency
of one. so this approach is going to take O(n) time to build the hash table and then to iterate
over it.
And it's going to take O(n) space.
This is another approach. can we think of something better than this approach?
Can we use somehow bit masking. OK?
The answer is yes.
Let's see how.
OK, so what are you going to do is you know, you can take help of XOR  operator, OK?
XOR of two numbers which are same is zero.
So if you do five XOR five, you can get an answer zero.
So if it's like one zero zero one one zero one, if you do XOR, XOR of the same bit is zero.
And then you will get to zero.
What about if I do a XOR of numbers like a^b^a ?
And what is going to happen?
The answer is going to be zero.
sorry..., the answer is going to be B because the bits of A will cancel out each other. Ok.
Let me give you an example.
If I do five XOR six XOR five, it would be nothing but five. if  you do a XOR with six.
It would be one one zero and there would be zero one zero.
If you do.
OK.
Sorry, 011.
If you do a XOR with five again that is one zero one. the XOR of same bit is going to be zero.
So it going to be one one zero?
So you can see this answer is nothing but six.
So what I can say is if I have numbers like five, six, one
Five, six and maybe three and two. Ok. if I have these numbers and I want to find out this unique
number. what I can do? I can simply find the cumulative XOR of all the numbers. Ok. so what
I need to do? I just need to find the XOR of all these numbers.
Once you do this what your left with.
The bits of three will cancel the three.
The bits of five will cancel this five, bits of six will cancel the six.
And finally, in your... in your XOR what
you will have XOR of this one.
So you will have one.
OK.
What you can do?
You can initialize the initials XOR as zero and four all the numbers in the range
Zero to
i less than n. i plus plus.
you can say, ok.
My XOR should be equal to my current XOR till now with the current number in the array.
Finally in this XOR you will have the number that is unique.
So I hope you understood this algorithm.
Now why this is better because we are not taking any extra space so we are doing in O(1) space.
And how much time we will need we will just need to iterate on the input array that is O(n) of time.
So no hash table is needed.
And it is running in linear time.
That's why this approach is better than the previous two approaches.
That's all for this lecture.
In the next video, you will write the code.