So let's see the code for the problem unique number one.
OK, so what we're going to do? we are going to make a method int unique number.
And we can either pass a array or vector to this method and will return the unique number.
Okay. so n is going to be array.size() .
And here let's create a array, So vector of integers array.
And I give the numbers let's say one, three, five or
Three, five, three one five ok. the unique number is four
That's what we want to figure it out.
I will say, ok. cout unique number and I give the array.
So we discussed the concept is very simple so I can say, OK, I'll find out the cumulative XOR of
all the numbers.
Let's say the XOR is zero, for int i equal to zero.
I less then n.
I + +.
I can see cumulative XOR plus equals. sorry... equals cumulative XOR with the current numbers the
the current number is array of i.
That's it.
And once we're done with this, we can return the cumulative XOR.
And this XOR will store the unique number.
So let's build the code.
And we should include vector as well.
And you can see the code is built.
And if you now run this dot slash unique one, we're getting the unique number as four.
That means our code is working perfectly fine.
So that's all for this video.
See you in the next lecture.