So we will solve of this another problem. this time there is a slight change in the question, so instead
of having 2N plus one numbers, we are given actually 2N+2 number.
OK, so that means there are two numbers which are unique and rest
every number is coming twice except two numbers and we need to find out those two numbers.
Okay, so this is what the question is saying.
So let us take an example of an array. Ok and we need to see what how do we figure it out?
What are those two numbers?
OK?
Maybe let me repeat some numbers.
So three is coming later two times four is coming let say
Two times.
let say a five is coming one times, and let say six is coming one times and let say two
is coming two time.
OK, so water to unique numbers that we have.
We have five and we also have six.
OK.
So how do we find out?
What are those two unique numbers?
OK.
And let me just say, instead of six we have a number seven that would also be fine.
So that you don't think I'm taking the consecutive numbers,.so we have five and seven, which are unique
numbers. now as a very first step
What we can observe from the previous problem is if you simply do XOR of all these numbers, this repeating
numbers will cancel out each other.
So two XOR  three XOR four XOR five XOR four XOR three XOR seven and XOR two.
OK, so what?
What is going to happen that two is going to cancel its bits. three is going to cancel it
bits. four is gong to cancel its bits.
And finally, the result would be nothing but five XOR seven, OK?
If you do this bitwise XOR, five is like one zero one. seven is like one one one.
If you do a XOR, this is zero.
This is what ? this is one.
And this is also zero.
Now how do we figure it out
What are the two numbers that we have?
OK, so obviously we can use the frequency array based approach and then figure out what numbers have
a single frequency.
So we discussed that frequency table based approach takes the order(n) space.
But here we are, going to do it using the bit masking based approach.
OK.
And we will try to avoid any extra space that we're going to use. OK?
And maintaining the linear time complexity as well.
So now if you look carefully at this result. Ok if you give a careful look with this result, what
you will observe is that
If the two numbers are different. OK, if the two numbers are different, which are going to be then
this XOR will never be zero.
OK, so I am writing one observation XOR
2 unique numbers, OK?
Will be greater than zero.
That means there would be at least
One set bit, there would be at least one set
bit inside the XOR. OK. now, what are you can do base upon this set bits?
OK, so a bit when...when a bit is set? a bit is set
when it is present in exactly one of the two numbers when it is present
in exactly.
One of the two numbers. OK?
So in this XOR which bit is set that we can easily figure it out. which bit is set, it is
easy to figure it out, this bit is set that means it is present in exactly one of the two numbers
it is not present in both.
OK.
Basically, I'm saying it's not present in both.so what is the bit that is set ?
This is the bit. OK.
This we can figure it out at what position the bit is set.  what I can do ?
I can say ok.
This is a position zero.
What is this set bit?
It is zero.
This is position one.
What is the setbit ?
.
It is one. OK, what we will...we  will start from the right and we will find out
the first position or any position will work, any position where the bit is set that will tell ok.
this is set in only one of the numbers. ok. So this bit is set..
It is not set in 5 .it is set in seven. Ok. what we will do?
We will iterate through this entire input ok. so in the third step
we will say Ok, let's say we know the position of set bit. position of anyone set bit you can
figure it out just to make the algorithm more clear.
We will start from the right and we'll find out the first set
bit from the right OK. first set bit from the right. ok.
once you know the position.
OK, what you can do?
You can separate your array into two parts in which part in which there is a set
bit Ok. so if you talk about the numbers two, three, four, five, four, three, seven and two, OK?
One of, if you write the binary of this OK. so a binary of two is zero one zero, zero one one, one zero
zero, one zero one, zero... one zero zero.
OK.
Zero one one, one one one.
And what about two? zero one zero.
OK.
So what I'm saying is let us have we also have some more numbers like maybe six and six.
That that can also be there OK. let's say we have six and six if you have six and six.
Then it is like what? it is like.
One one
Zero.
OK.
And one one zero, OK.
So what I'm saying is if you try to separate these numbers based on the position of set bit.
So where is the setbits?
The set bits is there on the second position.
So all the numbers in which they have one set bit at position p. Ok. P equal to one
in this case. we will separate them out in a different set.
Ok, so this as a set bit Ok. we take it. this as a set bit,we take it.
This does not have a set bit, we ignore it.
This has a set bit.ok.
We are checking for set
bit at this p equal to one. Ok.
This has a set bit. OK.
This has a set bit.
.
OK.
This has a set bit. ok. This has a set bit.
ok.
So what I can say if I combine all these numbers in one particular set Ok, let's say that set is
A. OK, I'll just write it here.
So the set A is nothing but two
Now, what do you know is
In set you will have some numbers which are repeating twice so  A will be up to 2N+1.
And it will have one of the unique numbers because we are separating on this bit and this bit is only
coming in one of the unique members.
So A will be of the form 2N+1.
So if you just XOR all the elements of it so it would be two XOR three XOR three XOR seven XOR
two XOR six XOR six.
So what is going to happen?
6 goes off, 2 goes off, 3 goes off.
And what is A ? A is nothing but seven.
OK.
Now... now
You know what is the first number.
How do you get the second number?
OK.
There are two ways.
One is you pick all the numbers which are set B, which are not in set A.
So you call them as set B.
set B is nothing but four XOR five XOR four.
And It is nothing but five.
OK.
So you get the second number B equal to five or what are you can do is you can say I know the
XOR. XOR is nothing but five XOR seven.
And once you figure it out, figured it out.
What is the number A?
So you can do XOR of this result with A, that is seven.
So from here also you can get the second number, which is five.
OK.
Hence, we are able to extract the two numbers five and the number seven using bitwise operators.
OK?
So I hope you really understood this approach.
And in the next lecture, we will saw the code and this approach is taking O(n) time and
it is taking O(1) one space. Ok. Hence it is quite an efficient approach.
And that's all for this lecture.