Hi Everyone, in this lecture we're going to discuss the implementation for unique number two.
So let's begin.
So what we discussed, we are given the 2N+2 numbers and 2 numbers are repeating. oh...sorry...all numbers
are repeating except two numbers.
OK, we need to find out what is the unique number. for example in this array
We have four and we have seven.
These two numbers are coming only once so we need to find out these two numbers.
So we have this....
We have to complete this method.
The first step we discussed we will do XOR of all the numbers. I can say ok. I will store the XOR in a
variable called the result.
And I will iterate over the vector. OK I less than array.size().
can say ,OK.I
Let us do the XOR
then I can say result equal
result XOR  array of i.
All right.
What is the next steps? so we discussed that Ok. if you do the XOR. you will get us out of the two numbers
there's all the numbers will get cancelled.
we will effectively get 4 XOR 7, so four is like this one.
OK.
And seven is this like this one.
So if you do the XOR, you will get one one and you will get a zero here. we discussed we'll find out the
position... one position where the bit set is set. if we start from the right we will get this particular
position.
OK, so let's find out the position.
In this case, I can say int position equals zero and I can say while...
Let me just copy this resulted in a variable called temp, so temp equals what? temp equals a result.
I'm saying ok  this number is temp.
And while the last bit is not equal to one.
OK.
But while the last bit is going to be equal to zero, I can while temp and one. while this is equal
to zero, I will keep on incriminating the position and I will right shift my temp.
Ok. so effectively what is going to happen?  Suppose if the number is zero one zero one zero zero.
So you find this last bit it does zero.
Your discard it and increments position from zero to one.
Again it is zero, you're discard it and you increment the position two too.
At this point, we will stop and we will say ok, the position is two. Effectively
After this loop
we will know the value of the position variable.
Next, what we need is? we need to filter out the numbers from the array which have set bit at position.
OK, now how do we filter that out?
Again, it's going to be easy.
Let me tell you.
So based upon that, we will divide our numbers in to two set, let's say set A and set B. Both of them are
zero in the beginning. so for int  i equals to zero.
I less then again array.size(). I can say i++.
So what I can do, I will create a variable called mask that is nothing but one left shift position,
OK?
So if your number is like position as two then I'm doing one left shift two.
That means I will get a number like in the binary it would look something out this.
If you have a number, let's say zero one zero one zero. if you do a
AND of these two.
And if the final result is zero. so if position is two, I'm creating a mask like this and I'm doing
AND with some number B1, B2, B3, B4 so on...
OK.
So, OK. let me just write B1 B2. B1 B2 is bits the ith bits and
the zeros bit. ok. the nth bit.
If you have a mask which has one at ith highest position and if you do a AND here. So effectively,
all other Bits are zero, OK?
Finally, this number would be either zero.
This number would be zero if the ith bit is zero. ok. If ith bit is zero
this number would be zero or if the ith bit is one, this number would be some power of two.
That means this number would be greater than zero.
So effectively, what I'm going to do?  I'm going to check whether the ith number in the array has a set bit
at the position so I can do a AND with the mask to check if this number is greater than zero.
Yes, it has a setbit.
then I can say ok. set A equals set A XOR
What?  the number at Array of i, if this is not the case then I will just add that number in setB. So setB
equals  setB XOR array of . so finaly
If you print the value of set A and set B, they will contain the two numbers.
OK?
Why?
Because of the logic that we have discussed in the previous video.
So let me just build the code.
OK. this should be void.
We are printing the numbers, OK?
And this call should be like unique number two
And that's it.
OK.
We have built a code and now we can run it. I can say ./uniquetwo.
I'm getting the numbers seven and four.
That means our solution is correct.
If you want a dry run, we can do a quick dry run as well.
We have the numbers what? we have these numbers... one three five four three one five seven.
First, we do
the XOR.  So XOR is nothing but 4 XOR 7 which is like zero... one zero zero and one one one.
So we get the result zero one one.
We find out the position of the first set bit from the right.
So that position is nothing but zero
in our case. this temp and one. ok this is temp, temp and one is not equal to zero.
This loop will break and position will remain zero.
Now what we say? we say ok a mask equals one left shift  position.So mask is nothing but one
left shift zero.
that means it is nothing but zero zero one.
We do a
And with all of these numbers.
OK.
So with one we do AND of one, ok one and one. zero zero one AND one we get one.
Three is 011 and one. we again get one. With five
also we get one.
OK.
With four, we will get zero.
Four and one will give zero.
This will give one.
And this will also give one.
So all the numbers in this case are going to give one because they have all set at the last index.
So effectively, If you do XOR of all these numbers, so we see one three five, then three, one, five
and seven.
They lie in setA.
Effectively, all these get cancelled. seven is left and in setB we only have four. OK, because
with this it is zero.
So even if you have six and six.
And this would give zero and this would give zero.
So it would be 4 XOR 6 XOR 6 and this would be nothing
but 4. I hope you understood the logic.
And this is how we are figuring out the two unique numbers.
So that's all for this lecture.
Thank you.