Hi everyone. In this lecture we're going to solve this problem, unique number 3N+1.
okay, so this bit different from the problems that we have seen where the repeating numbers were
coming two times but in this problem, the number that is repeating is coming tries except one number,
which is coming only once.
OK?
So let us look at an example.
Now, this example is let's say we have the numbers five, two, five and let's say three five
Two and two. so you can see the number five
is coming three times.
Ok and the number two is also coming three times, the one unique number is nothing but 3.
The problem is... although we can do it using the frequency table but we need to think in terms of
bits, OK?
So the idea here is.
We somehow can we do XOR. the answer is No.
Ok, if you do sort of let's to five or five sort of five.
It will still give you the result 5 ok. so what... what you need is you need a way
so that you can
Cancel out
bits of repeating numbers. ok., a bit of a repeating numbers, OK?
Basically instead of a number when it is coming three times the bits should get cancelled for that
particular number.
OK, so how we can do it so let's come up with an approach.
OK, so what we will do?
We will now look at some of bits on each bit position.
ok. why this is important.
You will come to know very soon.
Let me just first write down all the numbers in in a single line.
OK?
In a single column. let say the number is what? the number is
Five. okay.
And I'm going to make three bit position ok. one
two two and three.
right now, I just assuming the numbers are small but otherwise we will have 32 bit positions.
OK, if it is a integer then five is nothing but one zero one.
What about two?
two is nothing but zero one zero.
What about five?
again One zero one.
What about three ? zero one one.
What about five?
One zero one. what about two? zero one zero.
What about two zero one?
You get what I'm saying is we'll find out.
The some will find out the sum along each column along each column.
Let's see what is this?
The sum for this is one, two, three and four.
OK, what about this sum for this one, two, three and four?
OK.
What about this one?
The what I'm saying is that some.
At each position, OK, some at each position.
Will be on the phone, Ryan, or it will be of the endless fun, OK?
So it will be three in four for the column.
We're the unique no does not have us.
OK, so it will be three.
And if?
Unique, no.
Does not.
I was say, OK, does not have a certain.
And you can verify for this calamitous.
It is three days of the farm train.
And here you can see the unique number that is three.
It does not have a set built in this column, so you see to see one and see zero.
OK.
And it will be on the phone to the endless one, we're unique, no, has I said.
OK, unique number has a Edward because every other number is coming three times, OK, it this tree
and will always be there.
And this one bit would be added because of the unique number, and it has led to celebrate here and
it.
And you can see the summit of the farm tree and plus one look at the summit of the palm tree and plus
one.
What are you going to do, what each of these positions you can do or more with three you get whether
the original as zero or one.
So if you do a morbidity, you will get three more three.
That is what, zero or more?
Three that is one or more.
Three, that is one.
OK, so now you are getting three words, OK, and now you get the binary representation of the unique
number.
So if you convert this into decimal zero multiplied with two squared plus one multiplied by two rows
to divide one plus one multiplied with to register to the bar zero.
This number is what this number is.
Nothing but the number three itself.
OK?
And this is how you can actually find the unique numbers OK.
And you can extend this approach for maybe numbers of the Form five and +1 or seven plus one or four
and plus one, whatever.
And this approach can.
This resolution can be extended for those kind of numbers as we looking.
So I hope you really understood the solution.
OK, so Warren, Glusman, you you can simply do this odd think for five and +1 because it is all you
can use this kind of approach as well.
OK, so I have no showing you the most common approaches for solving these unique number type of problems.
And in the next lecture, healthy the code for this particular approach.
That's all for this video.
Thank you.