Hi Everyone, in this lecture we would be discussing the implementation for the problem unique number
three.
So let us begin, so first of all we have this input array  that we want to...
From which we want to find out the number which is repeating only once. Ok. it is of the form
3N+1 where every number is occurring thrice and only one number is unique.
So we need to find out this unique number. ok. that is four.
So let's see how we can do it.
So what we discussed is we discussed that we will add numbers.
ok. but what we will do? we will do addition along the column ok. so for one, it is like zero zero
one sorry..zero zero one. For three , it is like zero one one. what we discussed.
We will add all the bits along this column, this column and this column.
And finally, we'll get some sum. Ok. let say this is S1,
this is S2 and this S3.
And then we will take a modules with three to get where
so this Mode three will remove the bits which belong to the numbers which are repeating thrice.
And if you get a number like zero one zero, then this is what the number is. OK.
Or if you get zero one zero zero and this number is nothing but four.
So something like this we are going to do.
So let's see what are the things we will need.
So we are passing the array here. Ok.
And now what we will do? we will maintain the count array. ok. so I will say OK, vector of int, this count is...
or maybe the sum array you can make. In the sum array, we can say we have 32 bits and everything is initialized
with zero.
So this is the fill contractor, so we are making the array of size 32 because integer in this
case takes 32 bits and everything is set to zero. OK?
What I can do, I can do for int i equal to zero.
I less than what? I less than 32. I plus plus and I can check what if I given the number let's
say the number is seven, so it will have lots of zeros followed by one one one.
I'll find out what is a bit at each position and it will add to the counter.
It will get added to the counter.
So maybe I can say. Ok.
And maybe I can move this logic into a separate helper method as well.
ok. so
Let me... let me do it.
So I can say ok. let us iterate over all the numbers that are there inside my array so I can say
I can also use a for each loop. so for int a number X that is there inside my array.
I can let us set the sum array.
OK.
Let us update the sum array or maybe I can make a method update sum.
So in the sum array, I'm going to pass in this sum array and I'm going to pass in this number x.
OK.
So let us write this method.
Let us make a helper function.
So maybe void update sum
So we are getting this sum array.
This error must be passed by reference so I can say vector int and array. Ok. this is a vector object
and I'm getting a number.
Let's see how we can do it.
So first of all, I need to extract all bits of X so that I can do easily. For int i equal to zero.
I less than 32.
I  plus plus and I can say ok. tell me, what is the last bit?
The last bit that we are extracting is or maybe let's talk about the ith bit. ok, the ith is nothing
but
It is going to be x
And we can do the and with what? one left shift i.
We are finding out what is the ith bit.
And I can check
If I ith bit what? if ith bit is set then I can say. ok. sum array of i++.
So effectively you are saying. ok. let's talk about the zero th bit.
If this is one the sum array becomes one. if this is one it becomes one. if this is one, then this
number sum array becomes one. next time..
Let's say you have a number four. Four is represented by lots of zeros followed by one zero zero. So extract
this bit. it is zero. sum does not update.
extract this. sum does not update. extract this, at this point
the position is two. In the sum array at the second index we increment this as two. ok. So we are storing
the bits in this or zeroth column, first column, second column and so on.
This is what we are doing.
So this is going to update the sum array for all the numbers and we have called this update sum method
for all the numbers in the array.
So finally, this is going to give us the array of sums. ok.
And once we have this sum ready we can divide... we can take modulo with
Everyone. I can say for int i equal to zero, I less than32
I plus plus. at max, we can have 32 bits in the sum array. so I can say sum array of i equals
sum array of i.
And take a mode with three.
That's it.
So this is going to give us.
an array of bits. an array of bits. Because each position will be of the form zero or one because
we discussed in the sum array every sum would be 3N or 3N+1.
If you take a mode three either you will get bit zero or you will get one.
So finally, what we need is from array of bits we need to convert it into a number.
ok. so maybe let's make a helper method that converts an array of bits in to a integer. ok.
So maybe I can say return sum function. let's a number from bits and I give the sum array and
here I can make a method int number from bits I'm getting array of bits.
So how we can convert this? it's pretty easy.
So I can say the number is zero.
And I will iterate over all the 32 positions and I will multiply the corresponding number with powers
of two.
I can say number plus equals what?
So array of i multiplied with power of two so that is nothing but one left shift.
And finally, we can return num.
So let me tell you if you're confused here.
So we said. Ok. we have one zero one one and so on.
So this is 2 raise to the power 0.
this is 2 power 1.
This is two square. this 2 cube and so on.
What I say.. I say, ok. let's multiply one with two raise to the power zero. So one left shift i what ?
two raise to the power i.
OK?
plus zero multiplied by two power one.
OK.
Plus one multiplied with four plus one multiplied with eight.
This number is nothing but one plus zero plus four plus eight.
This number is 13.
OK?
So effectively, if you want to read the binary it is one one zero one and this number is 13.
But in the sum array, we're storing it in the left right order.
And that's why we are making the power from two raise to power zero.
That is one left shift i.
till the thirty first index.
OK?
So this should return the number. OK.
So finally, If i call unique number three.
This should return integer. so I can say return integer and i can say cout unique number three.
OK.
This should be what? this should be sum array.
All right.
The code is built.
And now what we can do? we can try to run it.
So ./unique_3
And we are getting four as the output that means our code is working perfectly fine. ok?
So I hope you really understood the logic.
And this is exactly what we discussed in the theory video and you can dry run it yourself and I
hope you understood the logic as well.
That's all for this video.
Thank you.