Hi Everyone, in this lecture we're going to discuss how we can compute all subsequences of given string
and we are going to use a bit masking based approach to solve this problem. OK?
So generally speaking... there are two ways in which we can generate subsequence as a whole given string.
OK?
One is using a recursive approach where we know that each for each character we have two choices either
it will be included in the substring or it will not be included in the string.
Ok. so then we can say OK, if we do this, we have two options for A.
We have two options for B.
We have two options for C.
That means we can have eight possible sub sequences, OK?
So what we want to do is we want to print all possible sub sequences. so effectively
If we do not include anything Ok that would be like null string.
If we include a single letter that would be like either A or B or C or if we include two letters,
then it would be either AB or it would be either AC or it would be BC or if we include all the
three letters, then it would be ABC OK.
So you can easily see that this are eight possible sub sequences that we can generate.
Now how we can do it using bit masking.
So one thing we are going to do is we are going to write the numbers from zero to seven that are eight numbers.
Ok. so zero, one, two three, four, five, six and seven.
So if you look at the binary representation of these numbers so you will observe a pattern, OK?
So zero is what? zero is zero zero zero.
What is one?
It is zero zero one.
Then what is two?
It is zero one zero.
What is three? zero one one.
What is four? one zero zero.
What is five? one zero one. what is six? one one zero and
what is seven? one one one.
OK.
So effectively, if you treat these as a mask, Ok?
And if you try to overlay your string ABC over these three numbers, you will find out that OK.
Zero means do not include that corresponding what ?character.
OK.
So if you put zero zero zero over ABC, you can see nothing is included.
That means it is a null string.
Zero zero one means OK.
Let us overlay this over ABC and you can see that OK, if you want to include C, that means this would
correspond to the output C.
OK, what about two
that mean, it is nothing but B.
What about 1 1?
Include B and C.
OK.
What about one?
Just include A.
What about this? AC.
What about this?
AB
It is nothing but ABC OK.
So again, what you can see here is you're able to generate... you're able to generate all possible sub
sequences because for...
OK.
Because the bit pattern is such that it can generate all possible subsequences.
OK, now the question is how do we know that we need to iterate from zero to seven? okay so we know for
a string of length N, there are two raise to the power N possible subsequences. Ok.
So subsequences.
Now  the question is, if we have a string of length N then I can easily iterate from zero
till what ? two raise to the power N-1.
This is the range and this range will give us all the combination of bits that we can overlay on the
given string and find out what the string is. OK?
So now one thing you may ask is Ok, how do we know, how do we how do we do the filtering logic.
OK, how do we filter. Ok. so if the number is  let say six, six is what? one one zero
How do we extract the digits A and B OK?
Effectively, what I'm going to do is, I'm going to extract the last bit.
So let me tell you.
OK, so what we're going to do? we're going to find out the last bit if it is zero.
OK, so we would do it in a reverse manner so we will extract the digits from right to left and we are
going to iterate over the string in the left right order, OK?
If it is zero, we say we're not going to include A.
OK A is dis gone.
If this is one, then we are going to take B.
If this is one, we are going to take C.
So effectively, the order of picking the later it is reversed.
That means in the output of this is one
So instead of taking C again, I will take A.ok.
If this is B, I will take B.
This is what BC, I will take AB OK.
Then if it is what? if this is one then I will take C. OK, if this is one zero one, I will again
take A and C.
This is one one zero, so I will take what BC and this is one one, i will take ABC.
only change that will have is the
outputs are produced in a different order and you can store them in a vector and you can also do the
sorting based on length or based on lexicography order.
That.... that is easier, easily doable.
So in the implementation of filter, I'm going to extract all the bits of the number from right to
left one by one.
And if the bit is one, I'm going to include the corresponding letter from the string that I'm going to
read from left to right order.
OK?
You can also read it from right to left.
That is not an issue.
You can modify the logic accordingly as well.
OK, so that's all for the theory.
And in the next video, we will see the implementation.