Hi everyone, so let's look at the implementation of finding  all subsets or subsequences of a given string.
Ok, so I'm taking the input in a character, you can also use the string as well.
That is also fine.
So let's write a function void generate all the sequences.
And here's what we're going to do?
We're going to accept the character array.
And here first we'll find out the length. length is strlen of array
Now what you can do?
You can say ok.
For int I equal to zero, so we saw we need to go from zero till what? two raise to the power N-1.
.
OK.
This two raise to the power N can also be written as one left shift N.
because it is faster and minus one will come as it is.
So I can see I less than...um
Two raise to the power N that is one left shift N and I can do
i++.
All right.
So once we are done with this, we can say OK. For every number, I need to filter the bit. Ok.
so maybe I can make a method void filter
Or maybe I can say overly. overly a number on string array
that is our array and I'm getting some number that I need to overlay on this particular array.
So here we will overlay the number, that is the number as I and array is array.
So this will actually print the subset.
OK, if needed you can store them in a vector or array.
But right now we are just going to print it.
How do we do it?
Let's say the number is six.
And the array is ABC.
So we are going to extract the last bit.
We are going say ok it is zero.
That means we will not print A. So I can say while this number is greater than zero
Find out the last bit.
so the last bit is what? number AND one. if the last bit is set, Let us keep a variable J.
OK.
Um.
Let's keep a variable.
let say J that was initially zero that means ok, we are not going to do any wor. int J is equal to
zero.
If the last bit is one then we are going to print this character at the jth index. so I can say cout
array of J.
That's it.
Otherwise you go to the next position. so you say ok. J equals J+1 or J++ and  you
also discard this bit. so you can say number equals number right shift one. that's it.
And now we can print and endl here.
And it seems like we are done. what is going to happen next time on this bit is gone.
So we extract the last bit, which is this one. And J is one, so if this is one we print array of J, so we
print the number B then we discard this.
We go to the next position J equal to 2.
And here we say Ok. this bit again one so we print the letter C.
And after that we print the new line and this is printed as a string in a single line.
OK.
Similarly, we do it for all the numbers from zero to two raise to the power N-1.
And hopefully they should work.
All right, so we are making this function call generators  all subsequences and now we can test our code.
So let's run this ./subsets.
Let me give a input ABC so you can see we're getting Null followed by A, AB, C and so on.
And finally, it is like seven and we are getting a b c. so maybe I can run with the different input
as well.
So you can see in this case, the length of the string is four and we are going from zero till what ?
15.
The 15 is in binaries like one one one one.
And you can see four one one one one.
We have a B, C or D as the output and for zero
We have NULL string as output. for zero zero zero one
We have only this one which corresponds to this A.
ABCD.
OK.
We are iterating in this particular order so that's what we get A as output. for two we have zero zero
one zero.
so we are getting B as output. for three, we have zero zero one one.
So we are getting AB as the output and so on.
OK.
So I hope you really understood this part and this is nothing but we are finding out the position
of the set bits and correspondingly we are picking a character from our array as well.
All right.
So that's all for this lecture.
Thank you.