Hi everyone, in this section we will talk about traveling salesman problem.
So it is a problem that helps us to find the shortest round trip cost.
Let's see what is the meaning of shortest round trip cost.
And it also has applications in last mile delivery systems, vehicle routing problem.
I will give you one example.
Let us think of an example of let's say, a delivery van
OK. so the delivery van has let say a certain number of orders that it wants to deliver and it starts
from a warehouse.
OK. so let's say there is a warehouse from where this van starts and let's say it wants to deliver
orders to certain customers which are located at let's say   different locations.
What it wants is? it wants to design a route.
Maybe it wants to figure out in what order it should cover the cities and come back to its original
location so that the minimum cost is optimized.
So this van is going to start from this location and it's going to..
go to different locations. maybe in the first step.
Maybe it goes to this location, maybe from here it goes to this location and maybe then goes here
then goes here, then goes here, then goes here and then maybe comes back.
ok. what we're doing is we are actually.
Traversing the entire set of nodes by forming a cycle. ok. so it's not a path from one location to
another, it's actually a cycle.ok.
So we are coming back to the same node from where we started. ok?
And what we want is we want to find such a route that minimizes the cost.
ok. so there could be multiple possible options maybe from A you could have gone to this location.
Maybe from here you could have gone to this location.
Then like this, maybe then like this, then like this, then like this and then came back. ok. so
this could be another route.
So there can be a lot of possible routes and we want to find out a cycle that has the minimum cost.
OK.
So it is given we know the distances between every pair of nodes it does given. OK.
We know what is the distance between any two nodes.
That is given. so you can assume that the input is a kind of adjacency matrix.
It's a V X V matrix and we know what is the distance of each node to other node. ok. So from every
We know what is their distance and we want to find out what is the minimum cost of this particular tour.
OK.
This is also known as Hamiltonian cycle so their goal is to find out the minimum weight Hamiltonian
cycle and this is what this traveling salesman problem solves.
So that's why it has applications in vehicle rooting, supply chain management because if you come up
with a route that is taking longer time that means it will take more fuel.
So people want to reduce their shipment costs.
And one more thing about this problem is it's a NP hard problem.
There is no quick solution and adding every node increases the complexity of the problem so we will
see when we will discuss the bruteforce based solution.
It actually has an exponential solution.
We don't know in what order we should cover these nodes so that the total cost is minimized. ok.
so it's a NP hard problem.
OK?
So what is a brute force approach?
Later on, we will also add DP to this approach.
OK.
The first let's try to explore recursive solution.
So I will start with a small example.
Let me draw a small graph.
Let's say I have A, B, C and D. as I said
We know the distance between every two pair of nodes.
let say, this is 20, this is 30, this is 10, this is 25 and this is 34 and this is 42.
Ok. now from every node you can go to every other node.
OK?
And you can start from any node the answer will not matter.
For example, you come up with a tour in which from where from A you to B, from B you to C,
from C you to D, from D you come back to A.
OK.
So I'm talking about this particular cycle.
You can also start from B and you may get the similar too so B, C, D, A and B.
Ok. so these two are exactly same.
Ok. it doesn't matter.
We start from A or from B because these two are these two represent the same cycle.
OK.
But there could be different tours as well.
From A you can go to C, then you can go to D, then you can go to B, then you can go to A. maybe
from A you can go to C, from C you can go to D, from D you can go to B and from B, you can again
come back to A.
So this is effectively the source from where we started.
OK.
So we start from source we end up our source and all these edges we need to add. so effectively speaking
if we talk about all possible permutations.
Ok. so we can have given N nodes, we can have N factorial permutations.
Ok. but we are saying we are fixing the starting node.
We say we will always start from the zeroth node. let say
That is A.
Because even if we start from any  other node, we can get the same answer. so effectively by considering
this fact that we will always start from A, we have a little bit reduce this complexity to
N-1 factorial. but it is still OK.
It is still bad.
And as I said this problem is actually takes a lot of complexity to solve and it is a NP hard problem.
Let us discuss.
We can solve this problem in a brute force method.
OK.
So let us discuss brute force.
So what we will do? we will start from A and from A we know, we can go to three different nodes.
We can go to B, we can go to C, we can go to D.
So we will make three recursive calls.
One for B.
One for C.
And one for D.
OK.
And from B, we will try to go to the neighbors that are not yet visited because we're talking about
this.
But we know from B, we can go to C and we can go to D because they are not visited.
OK?
Talking about C, we can..
We know that we can only go to D because in this path the ABC has already visited D is not visited,
so we will make only one call at the D. Talking about D we know we can only go to C.
OK, so this is how the recursion tree would look like.
But let us figure out what would happen in the base case.
OK.
In the base case, we know that we have visited all the cities that are there.
What we will do? We will return the cost of reaching the source node back from D to A.let's say you're
standing at the D, Now what you should return at D? you should because at D we want to do is when we are created
this path, we said ok. from A we got to B, from B we go to C, from C we go to D and from D we go
to A.
D should actually return the cost of moving from D to A.
OK, what is the cost of moving from D to A?
.
So this cost you can see 25. so D is going to return 25 to C.
OK.
What is C going to do?
C is going say ok. from C to D
the cost is 10. it is going to return 10 + 25.
So it is going to return 35 to B. what is B going to return? B going to return
from B to C
The cost is 30 so it is going to add 30 to this cost.
So 10 plus 25 plus 30.
Ok. and what is A going to return? A is going to actually... each node will also check what is the answer
I'm getting from this branch and it will actually take the minimum.
So let us assume that this answer is minimum.
So it is, let's say.
75. ok.
Sorry... this is 55+10. yes, this is 65 and from A to B. A to B. ok.
So what is the cost?
The A to B  the cost is like
this cost is 20, so A going to add 20 to this cost, so A has one option in which the cost is
actually 85. 10 plus 25 plus 30 plus
20.
So this cost is 85 Ok. and similarly we will also compute what is the cost from this branch?
What is the cost from this branch?
So let let me just draw all the branches.
Let me just draw all the branches.
When we go from A to C and from C we can go to the nodes which are not visited.
So they are B and they are D. ok. from B we can go to only one node that is not visited.
That is D.
And from D we can go to only one note that is B. OK. and at D, similar thing is going to happen.
We can make a call on C and B and we can make a call on
B and C.
Now, this is how the recursion tree would look like.
So your idea is to compute the cost of every route to leaf node and take minimum of all these costs.
OK?
So what A will get?
A will get option one from here.
A will get option two from here and A will get option three from here.
Ok. plus.. .what...
What would be the cost?
So this would be your first option would be the cost of going from B
Completing the round trip and coming back to A plus the cost of the edge A comma B. OK?
Option two would be the cost of going from C, then coming back to A plus the cost of the edge AC.
A to C. And an option three would be the cost of completing the tour, starting from D the coming back A.
plus the cost of the edge A to D.
Ok. so this is.... this is the recursive breakdown of this particular problem.
Now you may ask how we can implement this brute force solution.
So in the base case, we can check if all the cities are visited ok, we can simply say return the cost of
Going back to source
from the current city. OK from the current city, whatever is the current city. let's say in this
case, the current city is D. current city is C D B B C. we will return the cost to the source that is A from
the current city.
Otherwise what we will do we will find out the minimum cost.
OK.
By taking the minimum of over all the options that are available.
OK?
So maybe
We can say cost of going to some node, let's say we are going to some node I from the current Node
C plus
the recursively we can say we will call the same function that will compute the cost of coming back to
the source node starting from the ith node.
OK, so something like this we will need to do.
So this is the brute force solution of this problem.
So that's all for this lecture.
In the next part, I will tell you how we can implement it and we will also optimize it using DP.