Hi Everyone.
So now we have discussed the recursive solution.
Now I'm just want to talk about why you can use dynamic programming in this particular problem.
I suppose you have N number of nodes.
OK.
You have N number of nodes.
And let's say you have something like ABC.
Let say this is the current path that you have explored. and you also need to add N-3 nodes in this
current path.
OK?
Or maybe the current path might look like ACB and you may still have N-3 nodes which are left
Ok?
So if we talk about n nodes then 3 nodes I have depicted here N-3 are in this going...
are going to be in this particular path.
what does this sub tour represent?
I call it as sub tour.
OK.
This subtour represents the
the minimum.
OK, so there could be multiple possible subtours.
Maybe if we have some not like DEF. the sub tour may start from
D, the subtour may start from E, it may start from F. let's say we have computed the optimal
sub tour once.
OK, let's say we have already computed once and the same sub tour can be part of this solution as well,
why?
In this solution, what we are expecting? we're expecting that we will
We have already used the nodes AB and C.
We have already used the nodes AB and C and then from
this tour, we will start from some node. Let's say we will start from some node and we will traverse the remaining
n-3 nodes
And we will come back to A.
OK.
The same sub tour can be.... can be the optimal solution here as well.
We'll start from some node which is same as this one.
We will end up at some node, which is same as this one and we will end up at A.
OK.
So what I'm trying to say that if you know that you have already visited ABC or ACB, so what are the
set of states you have visited?
OK for this and for this.
OK, we are going to... we're going to make a call on multiples of sub problems. Ok. for let's say ABC tour,
you make multiple calls and then for ACB too, you make multiple calls.
What I'm trying to say is if you've already figured out what is the optimal answer for this path you
can reduce that answer for this part as well.
OK.
Because the set of set is you have visited is same and in this set you will have the same as it is.
like this one?
OK?
Because if DEF are left and they want... they need to be covered in a specific order
the same order can be used here as well.
OK.
That is the whole idea of using dynamic programming in this problem.
So what we need to do is we will see that we will dp will have two states.
One state will depend upon what is a set of cities that we have visited ok. we have visited ABC.
So that is a set of cities and there is a clever way of doing this.
We will see it can be done using bit masking and we will also talk about what is the last city we
are at.
OK, last city we are at?
the current city we are at. Ok.
We will do... so this will become more clear as we go through the implementation video in the next part
first we will discuss the recursive solution
And then we will code it out.