Hi Everyone, So let us look at the DP based solution for  traveling salesman problem.
First we will do recursion and then we will optimize it using DP.
So let's begin.
So firstly, I'm going to create a function.
It is called as let's say in TSP
And here we are going to pass in the graph.
The graph is now represented as a 2D vector because we said we know the distance between every
pair of vertices.
This is the data structure that we will required.
And apart from it, we also need to know the set of cities that has been visited. so I will create
one variable.
Ok. I will call it as set of cities. it's say integer and I will tell you how we are going to use it.
OK?
So let me just tell you. set of cities, what we are going to do?
We are going to represent it using integer because it would be easier for us to use this in DP state.
So let's say we are at A
We want to go to B.
Then we go to C.
Then we go to D.
And from B, we go to D and then we go to C and so on.
So this we have already seen. so what I will do.
So initially this would be zero.
But when I am standing at A. I will make it as one.
Ok. so one in binary looks like this.
When I come to B I will mark the second bit.
Ok. so this represent city A. this represents B.
This represents C, and this represents D.
So we are talking about bits. bits of this number. when I come to B I mark it as one.
OK.
And from B, when I come to C I mark this bit as one.
And from the C I come to D. I mark all the bit as one.
Effectively, when we reached the last node, all we will have last
N bit as one that means we have covered all the cities. From here we will return the cost coming back
to the original city.
ok. so one more thing we should have here is. the number of cities we have. Effectively,
I can say the base case would look something like this if set of cities if this is equal to, ok.
what is this number?  for N equal to four this number is equal to 15. for N equal to four,
This number is equal to two raise to the power four minus one, which can be written as one left shift four
minus one.
And for a given value of N can be written as one left shift N-1.
OK.
So we can check if this is equal to one left shift N-1 then that means we have covered all
the cities. ok.
That means return the cost
from the current city that is position or maybe you can just call it as city. From the current city
to the original.
So the original cities are at the index zero.
So I can say return.
The distance from the current city to the original city.
So original city is A.
So that is going to be zero.
ok. so this is what we return. so we return the cost of going from D to A.
This cost is returned back to C.
Otherwise, what we need to do?
Otherwise, we can say try all possible options.
Ok. Try
all possible options.
So I can say I have a choice
From city zero till...
choice till N, choice plus plus. I have multiple choices. ok. and I need to check... need to check if the city
is visited or not.
ok. cities is visited or not. how we are going to check?
So we are going to check it like this if set of cities, let say set of cities is
a number in binary. ok. so we can check whether a particular cities is visited or not by checking
if the I th bit is set or not.
Suppose I want to check for C. ok. from B I need to to make a call on C. C is not visited. D
is also not visited.
So I can make a call here and I can also make a call here. so I can check by doing AND. so I can create
the mask
Like this zero one zero zero.
This is my choice index.
This is choice zero choice one.
choice two.
I can do one left shift choice.
OK?
It will give me effectively number like this zero one zero zero and I can do a AND with this one.
If this AND
Is equal to zero.
That means this bit must be zero and the city is not visited, the city is not visited.
So let us try to do. The AND
With one
Left shift
choice.
OK.
If this is equal to zero then that means this particular city is not been visited.
We are checking whether it is visited or not, so we can compute the sub problem.
So sub problem will have a solution that is equal to. so let's say.... let's say at B, we come to know
that C is not visited.
So we will add this edge that is the distance of B to C, So  the distance of city to the
city that we are going.
That is choice.
Plus, the recursive call so that recursive call will be nothing but TSP of distance.
Now we're sending a set of cities, so set of cities
was 0011.
We need to send the updated set of cities.
OK.
The updated set of cities would be.
we need to set this particular bit. so we have 0011. we have to set this bit as one, so we will do a OR
operation with this particular mask variable that we have created.
So it is going to be zero one one one.
So what we are going to do? we are going to do
city that is the original city that we are sorry.... set if cities that we have and we are going
to do a  OR operation with the current chosen city.
Okay, so the current choices is choice the one left shift choice.
OK.
And finally, we can give here the final parameters is city 2 which we are going so that it is now choice.
And is N equal to n. ok. so I'll just erase this one.
And I'lll tell to try to explain you what we are trying to do.
And here also we will keep a global answer that is int because we are taking minimum of all possible
options.
We can say the answer is minimum of whatever answer we earlier computed and what we got from sub problem.
That's it.
And finally, from here we can return the answer.
So this is actually the recursive call
To solve this problem. Now some of you might get confused with this and this, I'll explain what we
are doing.
Once again, we have A, B, C and D.
OK.
And from here we can go to C, D, C and D.
OK, so I'm not going to draw for this part because it is going to be very similar.
But a, we are going to say we have already visited City so it is zero zero one. From here,
When we come back here, we say we have visited B.
OK.
So at A we are going to make three calls because we have three zero zero.
OK. choice is equal to zero one two three four.
So when the choice is zero, we will see that this bit is already set.
OK. so one left zero is one.
And if you do a AND of 0001 with 0001, yo.. nothing is going to happen.
So this
If condition will not true.
So A will not make a call to A. but we will make a call to B, C and D. so we'll make three
calls. So firstly we made a call on B. so when we came to B
Oh, what we did in the... in the particular call from when we made a call from A to B, we said the new
set of cities should add one more city because we have... we are visiting B.
Ok. so the original set of city is was zero zero zero one and one left of choice because this index
was one. one left shift one
is nothing but one zero. and this new set of cities now becomes zero zero one one.
This is because of the call.
When we arrived at this particular node we get zero zero one one as the mask.
OK?
And at A was the city and this was the choice.
But when you came to B, you have B as the city and you have these two as the choices.
This is choice.
OK.
The choice would be from A to ABCD everything, but only two choices are
where we will make a call. C and D because they are not yet visited. similarly from B
When you come to C. we say okay compute the answer for the sub problem.
And tell me how much cost it will take for the subtour to complete and get back to A.
So this returns some cost which will tell B.
And then B makes another call on this branch.
It returns some cost and then B takes.
OK.
Given option one and  option  two. what is the minimum?
Whatever the minimum returns back to A. now A makes call on C and the same story repeats.
So C return some answer here, A makes a call on D. The same story repeats and they return something
back here.
Ok, now the interesting thing to appreciate in this question is we have represented a set using the
integer and this is going to help us
in using DP. ok?
And using DP.
OK, because it would be easy for us to make a integer state in the DP. so in every call you can see,
what are the variables that are changing?
So one is this set of cities that is changing.  another is the current cities that is changing. ok.
So we are replacing the city with choice and set of cities with this updated set of cities.
So we are adding one city every time.
And this is just checking whether city is visited or not .visited or not.
Here we are adding a city and you can see these are the two variables that are changing all the time.
So we can use to 2D  DP here because of the overlapping sub problems property that I have already discussed
with you in the previous lecture.
OK, so let's first run this code on try to see.
So I think the answer for this problem should be 85.
So for this test case. so I can say cout TSP of... what ?
we have distance, we have set of cities.so Initially it is zero zero zero one, which is one. the current city
the current city is zero, A is at zero and number of cities we have is four. ok.
We are going to build this code.
Yeah, there should be comma.
OK.
So let's run this one.
So we are going to run a traveling salesman and you can see the answer is 85.
That means it is correct and
our code is working fine. ok. so in the next lecture, we will add the DP based logic for the same.