Hi everyone, so let us look at DP based solution for this problem.
What they need to do?
We had two states one is set of cities and one is cities.
Now this set of cities, we have four cities.
There are two raise to the power N states that are possible for this one.
OK.
As we saw that for N equal four, we have from
Zero zero zero to  one one one one.
OK.
talking about these we have two raise to the power 4 that is 16 states starting from zero
till 15.
What we will need?
We will need to create a DP array, which is of the type 2 raise to the power N into the city.
So we have N cities.
These are the possible states that we need to fill in the DP array and this would also form the time complexity
For this particular problem. OK?
So for each state, we are doing a loop of size N. maybe you can multiply it with one more N
To get the overall time complexity, OK. this is still exponential?
So let me... let me try to show you.
So we will create a DP array.
And one rai... the number of rows would be one left shift N that is 2 raise to the power N.
each row will be initialized with a vector of integers which has N columns and each column is initialized
with minus one in the beginning.
Because we don't know what is the shortest distance. In Tsp we will send this DP matrix.
and here we need to accept this DP matrix as well.
And here we need to pass in this DP matrix as well.
What we can do? we can check if DP of a particular set of cities and current city if this is not
equal to minus one.
That means the state is already computed so we can return DP of set of cities and city.
And if it is already visited.
oh, so if it is already visited then we return it, if it is not visited, then we will first compute
the answer like we did.
And we will memorize this answer in this particular DP array.
and we will return the ans.
So I think that's it.
That's what all we need to do.
So have applied top down dynamic programming here and let build our code and let us try to run
it.
We're still getting the answer 85.
That means our DP based code is also working fine.
That's all.
I hope you understood this problem now.
Thanks a lot for watching.