In this project, we are going to take the old project that we already implemented, the askme1,
and we're going to apply object-oriented programming.
This would require from you two things.
The first thing, refactoring. Refactoring is a keyword in the industry.
We mean to take the old code and start to restructure it in a different way.
For example, make sure that the model is model no printing there.
Make sure that the viewing is about viewing, not about logic, and so on.
The previous code also just focus on struct with encapsulation,
but there are no other OOP concepts that were applied. In this project,
you would have to rewrite to consider that provide private sections, public sections, and classes.
Think about setters and getters.
Make sure that you don't force outsiders to make a lot of gettters.
Make sure your class is doing its own job. Use const as possible in functions and in parameters. Minimize the
dependencies as possible between classes. Don't use the friend function, friend classes,
you don't need them. Separate the view from the model,
as we said. Feel free to optionally split it in different files,
but this isn't needed. After you are done with your own project,
compare it with my project.
Compare my old code with my new code so that you can see the differences. Also as a practice for you,
drew the UML diagram.
That's it.