In this section, we will highlight some of the fundamentals of the language that I intentionally skipped
in the beginning of the course because they just cause puzzling for the students and don't have a big
value.
So we'll be discussing a wide variety of of different things.
The first thing is very fundamental about the bits information.
So typically everything in computer is built with zeros and ones.
This means in the very, very low level of of the computer systems, there are just zeros and ones.
And this is mainly for the simplicity
like it's easier to build a computer this way. Zeros and ones more about like..., think of them, for
example, like the electricity on and off and things like that.
So this let's develop some ideas about the binary system.
The word binary, as you know, refers to the 0&1.
There are many system representations when it comes to numbers.
We typically, as humans, use all the time what we call the decimal system. The decimal system is referring
to the system of 10 digits from 0 to 9.
So when you have a 1 digit, you can make 10 numbers, right, from 0 to 9.
If you have 2 digits, you can make 100 numbers from 0 to 99.
So we can represented like 10 to the power 2.
If you have 3 digits, you can have up to 1000 numbers from 0 to 999.
So in general, if I'm telling you we have a number of k digits, it means
we can have up to 10 to the power k numbers in this range.
Please make sure you understand the logic here.
Now, there is a correspondence in other systems.
For example, in the binary system, if we have a single number, ..., if we have a single
bit, we call it bit here. If we have a single bit, which is just 0 or 1.
So we have 2 numbers, but if we have 2 bits, we have to 2 to the power 2 numbers, which are 0
0, 01,  10,  11 .
These are the four different numbers that we can have.
If you have 3 bits, we can have 8 numbers, 8 different binary numbers, 000,
001, 010, 100, 111, 011, 101, 110 .
So these are like 8 different numbers when it comes to 3 bits.
So in general, if you have k bits, which every one of them is just 0 or 1 , we have up to 2
to the power k
different numbers.
OK, so as you notice, in general, the base here represents  the number of different digits, which are
2 here in our case, but 10 here
in this case. We also have something we call it a byte.
The byte is 8 bits.
So it is just we are giving some name to a bigger unit.
And if you have 8 bits, you have 2 to 256 different possible numbers that
we can generate.
What if I have 4 bytes?
4 bytes are 32 bits.
So this means we have up to 2 to the power this number.
OK, what if we have 31 bits,
we have this number.
These 2 numbers are very important.
The 32 case and 31 case I would like you to have your eyes very
familiar with these 2 numbers. In general,
here's a table of all of the different cases, and I would say the first column here is very important
to memorize.
Also, the last 2 numbers here are important to memorize and also it's good to remember that 2 to the
power 20 is around one million.
OK, so let's take it one more step further, if we have 4 bits, we have up to 16 numbers.
How many numbers from 1 to 16? 16 numbers.
But this is one based.
What about zero based?
It's from 0 to 15.
We have 16 numbers. So far,
this is good.
But notice that when we refer to that, we are all the time referring to positive numbers or 0 and
positive numbers.
So we have from 0 to 15. If we would like to develop something that would allow us to represent positive
and negative numbers, we can divide this range to two halves, one half from 0 to 7.
And these are 8 numbers representing positive numbers and another range from -8  to -1
representing 8 numbers.
I would like you to think from the perspective of the people who are designing the language, like let's
say you are saying, oh, here we are using 4 bits to represent numbers, but this is just from
0 to 15.
We would like to give people positive or negative numbers. I would like him to say integer x equals -10.
How he can do that?
So we can say take our maximum capabilities from 0 to 15, divide it to 2  halves and say what
is this use to have these numbers to allow positive and zero and the other half to the negative values.
Try to make sure that you're familiar with what I'm saying.
If we have 8 bits, then 8 bits are 256. If we would like to support positive
and negative, we can divide to two halves.
So one half from 0 to 127 and another half from the -128
to -1.
So the overall range is like from n-128 to 127.
So always keep in mind this style. This number is like one plus this number if it's a positive
number.
Let's make it further, if we have 32 bits, so if you have 32 bits, you have this very big number.
So if it's unsigned, which means there are no sign. Then we have from 0 to 95, notice
this 95, but the number is 96.
If it would like to support positive and negative.
We have from 0 to the half here and from this negative number to this one.
So again, this is a complete range here and notice that this is 47 but this is 48.
If you would like to provide 64 bit, then you again have this very big range to this range.
It's also good to familiarize yourself with this very big number.
That's all.
The moral of that is how many numbers we can represent when we have some k bits and dividing them to
two halves to represent some positive numbers and some negative numbers.