One of the important topics is about how to handle the Imbert, if it had been a mistake from the user.
But before that, let's say motivated in a different way, I would like you to read this program and
imagine that the user enter the 10.
What's going to happen in the flow of this program?
You are not the following you entered the value ten and then indirectly printed the intervening message,
then your each message.
So the problem here, it seems that line twenty six as it was, and use that as if there is no value
from line twenty six.
Here it is.
What's going to happen behind the scene.
Exactly.
You're right, you're on the program and then you enter ten for the age.
So when you enter ten you are actually enter two things too far.
You enter the ten and you entered that backslash in the end.
Right.
So now the edge is going to read the ten, but the getline here is going to read the end.
That's why the program will not wait for you to enter the getline and it will not.
It's actually is going to read your backslash end.
So age is now ten, but your name is now backslash and no one is waiting for your input for the full
name.
So to solve this problem, there are two ways.
The first way is to use Getline twice.
So one of them, you know, it's going to read the enter from here and the second one is going to read
that what you really want to enter there is another way to do that, what we call a IT ignore.
The scene ignored is a function that its purpose is to discard or ignore the impulse.
Well, two things could happen.
The first one is you provided a number of characters to ignore after it, just us to be ignoring.
The second is to give it a character to stop over it.
Typically, we use the end for this scenario.
So there are two uses scenario for it.
The first is a reading.
This extra backslash in the second, as you will see, is ignoring the invalid input.
Let's see an example here.
If you here to switch it up.
Terzian each if you added the line for the end of the ignore 256 and backslash.
And so this means please ignore up to two hundred fifty six or if you found the backslash end.
So now we would see an edge then backslash in the next character directly would be backslash end.
So this line is going to ignore the backslash end and now you can read your full name directly.
So the moral of that, as I said, is either ignoring the up to up to this number or if you found this
backslash and you can use another character, you can use a bigger number as you like.
Let's go to our topic directly.
The validation so far, we were assuming the user would be a good boy and would just enter the values
as we expected from him.
However, the user could easily provide wrong data.
You asked him for an age and he entered his name.
So the program is going to crash.
How to handle that?
CNN has has what we call CNN did fail, send it fail for simplicity.
It's just going to check if something is wrong.
And what we were reading was not the same.
Ignore can help us to skip the remaining of the line because something wrong happened with both of them
who can handle invalid.
But it is an example.
Let's say I need to make a program that a couple of numbers, a couple of entities.
So I'm sending them here by reference.
And I started to read X and Y.
If the user did something wrong in X, then this is now become invalid in Brookline.
You can also provide something wrong with Y.
So let's say that he entered two numbers, X and Y.
But he did something wrong in itself if he did something wrong and in the end, reading the this year
did feel is going to return.
True.
So we think we can do something like that.
If CNN did fail, if something went wrong.
We can ask a visa to enter again.
Then we do a couple of things.
First, we call the clear function, which is going to clear the mistake that happened inside the CIA
and we get ready to read new values.
The second thing we are going to ignore to tell the end of the line, we don't expect to.
More than two hundred fifty six characters, typically up to backslash in character, which is typical
would happen.
So if these are entered into something wrong at X, we are going to ignore the X and the remaining of
X line, which typically have the Y.
So here are a bunch of trials.
I started the program with entering Mustafa and then Mustafa is in an interview.
So the program will either entertain of Field and me feed ten point four and twenty four.
This is going to fail.
What is the failure here?
Notice that the X is going to return and I stopped by the DOD because its character, the Y will find.
Good point for this is failure for the White House is expecting any integer.
Now it is a tricky case when you.
Twenty four.
It's going to return the X when you write the ten point four.
Ten is going to be to the way.
The problem though is going very well because it's really written to to an integer.
But noted that your stream is that has this point for I'm not going to handle that here, but I'm pointing
out the problem so that you be aware of it.
There is no other way to read this email, by the way, which is using oyster industry.
Oyster industry, as you remember, can take a complete line, a string, and just you can read from
the line as you like, just the one side of a string stream.
It is a very slow function, but in a way that the logic here, I'm going to read you rule number and
try to read the two numbers for me.
If I failed, I just try again.
Rootsier.
I need to make a clearing for the function.
I don't need to to ignore the remaining of the function of the line.
I don't need to do that because anyway, it is a temporary stream so we don't care about it.
One more thing to know about it is white spaces.
We do this piece.
We also know that tab, which is like four spaces.
Typically there is the other type of of of of of spaces and C++ call of all of them what we call a white
space.
There is internally a function is a space to check if a character is one of the spaces or not.
So let's see if we can foresee squibbing or not giving for the white spaces.
I mean, defining a string of three spaces.
One, two, three attempted taking care, skip white spaces.
The three character ABC.
What I see is kibbitz basis and will take any spaces at any depth and just ignore them.
Then reading the three letters, ABC would be one and two or three.
Now let's say that I would like to to, I would like to not, not, not skip spaces.
Look to this line of function here like 13.
I say I with six zero six is causing it.
If, if you notice here, we already read ISIS six characters.
We are done with reading.
If you try to read anything more, it's like no input in the city.
Ciggy Zero is returning the reading till the start of the program.
We said ciggy one.
It would be from the second from the second character here.
Sixty two it would, it would read from the.
So this is zero.
This is one, this is two to three and so on.
So in a way you can ISIS from the scratch telling you one more functionality is leading you to move
to the beginning of the stream.
You can use it, use it also in files.
So here what I care with more is the no, skip the.
So if you say it, the US, it means very don't skip characters, don't skip white spaces.
So here, here there are actually there are two spaces on here.
There are two spaces.
So character would read the space character building the space characters, you will read one.
If you read to them you will have a space space one.
So the more of that is with the skip the US or skip the books you control more what you would like to
do with the spaces and tabs and carriage return and so on.
This is mainly Morreau, this is what really I wanted to say about the workspace, that's all.