In this video, we would like to highlight some more notes about the fires and extremes that either
to hear the first thing is about the music that you can open the file that we already see, the eye
in the mood to read it.
Only we saw also the outward which allow us to write only.
There are actually more modes.
For example, the four have been obtained the means to add in the end of the file, which is also ICE
eight, which means go to end of go to ending in the file opening.
So you just go to its end.
There is what is called binary file.
I will highlight it after a few seconds.
There is also the trunked here, which is going to remove the whole content of your file.
There's also the interesting thing here that you create and replace when we create it means that you
are going to feel if the file doesn't exist, then your place is going to fill in.
The file already exists.
So the moral of that is they are providing you with different statuses for different situations.
Generally, you typically don't need most of them and you typically need the in and out and you either
need either the trunk or a OBINZE.
It depends on your keys.
If you just need to enhance your file more and more, you typically would use.
The building is one of the functions in the streaming is what we call in the file.
If the you if it's telling you if if are you done with reading the file or not.
So as you can, as long as a file is in the file you can just keep reading it.
If it meant that you are reaching the end of file, you cannot read anymore.
The Getsy function here is a function to allow you to get a single character from the street.
We saw a lot of see in the field, which is a flag internally, if any error happened while the reading,
remember, let's say I'm reading an integer, but you give me a string, then the fail or the fail would
be will be true.
So you see here we have three kind of mistakes, actually.
Four that we have here, the end of file, which we just described, meaning are we done with reading
or not?
And we have the feel, which is indicating if we have a problem in reading something or not and we have
the bet, the bet is a bit trickier.
The bet is is much bigger and general error than the failure.
The math indicates that something heavy happened with the stream you cannot read anymore.
Let's say you were reading from a file and then maybe somewhere in the middle, the operating system
restricted access to the file.
So you cannot read or write anymore.
For example, you cannot write them.
You don't see it if you are asking for the bad bit is going to check two things.
If there is a failure, general failure or some issues about complete reading, write that you cannot
do it anymore.
There is also what we call a good bet, the good bit is checking if there is no error at all that is
mean.
There's no endophytes, there is no failure, there is no bad luck.
Sometimes guys think that the good bit is the opposite for the bad bit.
But this is a true rootsier.
The bad bit doesn't check the end of flight.
So if this was the opposite for that, we need to find this as true, true, true.
This isn't the case.
So the good bit is an update to the bedmate.
Practically speaking, you typically use the failure only as we see in our examples.
Sometimes you might need to check the end of flight.
Typically you need more than that.
But anyway, I just wanted you to be aware that there are different things to check in the status of
the binary file.
When you have something like the image, for example, Google doc or so the orange takes to find sticks
white are just normal files using the normal letters and characters by the files are written internally
based on zeros and ones.
If you try to edit to the text, you would not be able to [REMOVED] the specific program that can read
them according to the way they were written with the text file are normally natural text.
If some character in the text file is corrupted, you can still open the file and you can even find
it by your eyes, which is a mistake.
But however, they are typically bigger in size and their size depends on the platform.
So from a platform to another, the files content may have different sizes.
On the other side, the binary files allow us to write, text file and allow us to write.
Include something that's very binary, something that is and is invisible, for example.
Like it, like the normal characters, remember, there is more to this world, a capital to is it capital?
We have specific ranges.
Sometimes we might try write something even bigger than this rage.
Every time there is minor corruption in your file, you probably will lose your room.
While this is what is with the verified, if you tried to obtain an image and just remove a few a few
things from it, you typically will not be able to open the image again.
Typically the file sizes are smaller and it doesn't depend on the platform size.
In most of the cases, if you would like to open a file in a binder, I would use it as binary.
So this is what you add here, mainly into the elbow to indicate that you are going to open it in a
binary mode.
It typically, when it comes in infrastructure courses, you will have a chance and reasoning to write
and read in a binary format.
So you need to do that.
At the moment, there are also functions like a physical effort that we highlighted the last time.
They allow you to move in the file itself.
In the file structure, of course, it would be more like how people are implementing databases, which
is typically in binary.
So we're learning more about how to use it.
That's it.