I would like to highlight a bunch of different things in this video.
The first one is the switch statement, remember one would like to do and if statement let's I would
like to do this program.
If number is one, then just say what number one is the number one hundred or one thousand, just print
one hundred thousand.
If it's 200, print this guy l'esprit this guy this the standard Felsen ninety nine point nine percent.
You'll be using it this in C++, what we call a switch statement.
So you do a switch on the variable and then you start with case, case, case case which is going to
have a value here to to check if the number is value, one number is value and so on.
In every case, you can have a break here, which is once you achieved a condition, it just to break
it.
I would like to try to sense a comparison between both of them.
So it's going to say is, number one, if the answer is yes, is going to be print one and going to
break.
So we go to the switches statement.
If there are no quick isn't one jump two hundred.
If it's a hundred or one thousand, go here.
Is it one hundred and the break we go outside.
If it's two hundred you go brainteaser but there is no break so you go to the next one.
This is a default.
Something correspond to the variables here.
So you are going to beat the guy.
So you see it's going to move one by one like here if y if it's going to check if there is a break or
not, if there is a break, it's something that just go outside, something like the Elseworlds else.
If there is no break like this hundred year, it just keep going also to the next one.
So this is more of like other condition.
So here a hundred and one thousand is like more of the hundred one this condition.
So sometimes it's useful, but most of the time you don't really use it.
The other thing is what we call a do while remember in while loops we we use have like a while over
some condition, then somebody into while we have the reverse, we do the body first, then the condition,
the syntax is like you do the work to do and you open to the buttresses and you put the word condition
here.
So the difference between both of them is which one is starting with the body and which one is starting
with the condition.
The way they do while is very important or very useful if you have to do one.
But the execution at least.
So you are going to do this, but the execution, then you are doing the verification.
But in wire loops you have to verify the condition.
The declare and the define most of the time in the course we write a function directly like here what
we are doing here, but in C++ we can actually split, split the declaration from the definition.
The declaration is like the following.
You have a semicolon here.
There is nobody.
The declaration is more about what like you are saying.
We have a function named factory.
The ticket integrated returnability how that would be having.
No one knows the function, the definition you are going to now Ubuntu places and you put all of your
body logic.
This is very useful and sometimes especially like it is a case, let's say you have to function if one
or if two, if one is calling if two and if two also is correct, if one, how to put something cyclic
like that.
This is a problem.
Now, here is a way to handle that.
You can't first declare this to function if one and if two, then you function.
If one is calling if two and you'll function if two is calling your one.
Now this circular behavior is doable through this forward declaration.
Mind functions, airline functions.
So here is your normal function, if your function is really very small, you might want the word in,
though the line is giving a hint for the compiler that you might be able to optimize this good.
For example, you are quoting here the functions that one with Max between X and Y, it could happen
that the compiler would go and could be the content of the function as it is here and put it here.
And then in your actual code that has been compiled and run, there is no function named the max.
It has been removed and its content has been copied and pasted in different places with the max function.
Is calling your advice D then don't function in two cases.
Specifically if the function is very short like here and also we are going to call it very many times.
So it's much better to just align it in the code to make it like very fast in the code.
Also, truth telling you that in an industry we typically document our functions, a good function would
have a name that really express what it's going to do.
So if I'm saying salary data, this is a function that expected to read for us.
Some data is typically some documentation that start with a definition or like a statement or what is
this function going to do then?
For every input parameter we say, what is this parameter?
And for every other parameter we say, what is our parameter?
And so on.
The style of the function and the state of the naming is something that varies from a company to another.
But generally speaking, it's good to provide some documentation for your function.
And even better than that, your function, name and parameters are very expressible.
Like when you read them, you know, the intent of the programmer behind the function.
Also, we have something called if I define something like good in color, red, green, blue, the
red will can be used in the program here.
Its value would be zero and green would be one and blue would be two and so on.
You can say all colors are equal red and you can print it is going to print red with value zero.
You can say here are equal color of two.
This is going to be the value of one of the blue.
You can define it with different is starting to say.
If you say the equal one, every one consecutive will be committed by one.
So one, two, three, four.
If you define here February of two, then the next one will be the value of the previous plus one it
will be three.
But here you back again and define fourth.
So the more of that, it just helping if you would like to define maybe some consistency style, but
in an easier way.
So it might be one way to do that.
Locality of reference, this is something interesting and you study more in computer architecture courses,
I hope I like to highlight something about it here.
Let's say we have a huge to the matrix like that and we have to function.
One of them is attriting heavily on The Matrix, but RuBo and another one is creating biometrics.
But call them the Baycol.
The question for you, like how many operations that this guy and this guy is doing?
Exactly the same.
We are doing the same iteration, same hexing.
So Operation Wise, we are the same.
But speed wise, you will notice in most of the computers, the first one is much faster than the second
one.
The reason behind that is relevant to how we how we stood the to the arrays in memory and to the array
is a stored rubyfruit.
So if you have four rules in the array, the memory will have the first rule.
The second rule.
The third rule.
The fourth rule are all in the memory.
Now, when you try to exit the array, there is something called cash in your processor.
The cash is going to check if this number exists in the cash or not.
If it exists as part of a block, it's going to return it for you.
If it doesn't exist, it's going to probably remove some space from the cash and could be another block,
big block from you to the array.
Now, the good about having it written with array rule by rule is when you try to access the first element,
the first rule, or some of it is going to be copied to the cash.
When you try to access the second element, it's already in the cache.
Third element in the cache.
Let's say that the element number one hundred and one is in the cache we're going to bring to the next
block.
So 100 what exists, 100 to exist and so on.
Now, the problem with the order is as follows.
You access the first element in the array.
It doesn't exist in the cache is going to be the first through, for example, for you.
Now, we would like to access the second rule first, the value.
But this isn't in the cache is going again to drop the cash value and bring another rule for you.
And then you are moving to the third rule.
If you just hear it behind the scene, this good is causing a lot of get to the cache, remove fumigation,
get from the cash flow through the cache, which is going to be very slow.
If you didn't understand what I'm saying, this is totally OK.
Doesn't affect your coding.
I just wanted to tell you that Ruby rule iterating is too much faster than going the right column iterating,
that's all.