C++ differentiate between what we call signed variables and unsigned variables. So, the unsigned
range is something that doesn't have negative values.
For example, for 8 bits, it just from 0 to 255.
...
Signed variables are on the other side are allowing negative numbers, but to allow this negative
number from our maximum range
here, we divide into two halves, one half to represent the negative values and the other half to represent
it from the positive values.
And remember, if you would like to support 255, it isn't like -128 to positive
128.
Remember there is a 0 in the middle.
So it is actually dividing this range to two halves.
It would be
-128, +127.
So always notice this difference because of the classical mistakes for beginners.
Through the course, when we define integer number equal -10,  notice the integral variable,
it allows negative value
so we call it actually signed. Typically in C++,
the every integer you define is 4 bytes, which is 32 bits.
But notice that this is something that's platform dependent.
So the laptop that you go and buy to your usage would have different aspects from platform
to another and so on.
So assuming 32 bits here, this is the range that we noticed before.
Remember, we said before if we tried to use the number  after this number,
we get an overflow and we try to use a number before this number, we get underflow.
This is now the time to understand for you why these ranges; like why this very specific number.
This is mainly because the integer is 32 bits.
And within this limitation of the maximum number that we can represent with 32 bits,
this is your maximum when it comes to supporting the positive and negative value.
On the other side,
C++ also has more data types than we have just learned. Through the whole course we were using integer
which is typically 32 bits.
But here I would like you to know that we actually have other data types.
We have what we call short, which is just like typical 16 bit, and we have what we call Long long,
which is 64 bit.
But there are actually other some few names.
But for now, I would like you to know that we have more data types than we saw.  Notice here that
64 by 8 is just 8 bytes.
So if this guy 64 bit, it means it's 8 bytes.
There is also a good note to know that character is internally
1 byte or 8 bits. That's why we said that we internally handle the character as just integer but of
0-255 range, actually
-128 to 127
OK, so in C++ we can define the variable as it signed or unsigned. So we can say signed integer or unsigned
integer or signed long long.
So there are two information here.
The time and the signing status; this defines your big range.
So here is some table that give you some sense of ranges.
We already discussed this before.
If you have a character is typically 1 byte, short typically 2 bytes, integer typically 4, long
long is typically 8.
This is also what we call long.
It's just 4 bytes.
Most of the time,
I would say just make more use of it. So notice here in a 32 bits use, which is also different than
64 bits for use, like notice here, for example, the long here if it is only 32 bit, it's just
5. But on the 64-bit CPU,
it's just 8.
It is a more formal table coming from the reference of the C++. Notice here something interesting, we have
here all of the types that you can define.
You can say I have integer.
This is the one that we deep used all the other course.
If you wrote integer or signed or signed integer, this is all just the integer.
So we have many other data types here.
You have short, we have long, we have long long.
We can use it signed, we can use it unsigned and so on.
If you didn't use the word signed, then it means signed and it means supporting both negative and positive.
Looking here to this C++ standard column, it says at least 16.
What does this mean
at least? The C++ standard guarantee only for you the minimum number of bits that can be used here.
For example, if you define an integer, the minimum number of bits would be to typically minimum 16.
If you noticed here, there are different setups for 32 to 64 architectures, most of the time
the integer would be 32 actually bits and in one case is just 16.
And if you notice here about the long long, the long long is at least 64.
And all of these cases just 64 bit. Looking to the long, the minimum is 32,
most of the time is 32, except in this case, it's 64.
You don't have to memorize these numbers.
All I want you to know that the number of bits is actually platform dependent and C++ guaranteed the
minimum, but nothing else.
OK, let's see some code. We can say here, short short_var1 to -10, this is as same as if you
added the word signed and use it.
If you try to use the size of operator, it can tell you the number of bits or bytes that are used in
the memory.
So if I say I short_var, and say out the size of short_var, that is going to print here 2 for 2
bytes.
Remember the short is 2 bytes.
You can also print the min and max values like, say you print SHRT_MIN  and SHRT_MAX , it is going to
give you this range.
If you try to add one here, it's going to overflow.
So if you added a value of one to the max notice here, the max value is this value.
If you added one max value, it's going to be negative, this overflow.
But notice here is something interesting.
The plus one moved the 67, back to the 68.
This looks like a circle like these numbers here for some reasons about the internet implementation
of that,
it's circulating.
We'll see that again here.
Let's say we define unsigned integer short.
OK, so now instead of signed, use the word unsigned. This means its minimum must be 0.
What about the maximum? We call the USHRT_MAX here to get the value.
So it's now 65.
Now, let's increment to this number for one
step.
What's going to happen?
It's going to overflow because you are going after the limit.
The interesting part here is the overflow is going to be back to zero.
So, again, this is jumping.
Think of them like circle.
Like if you have 3 numbers, it is like0, 1, 2, 0, 1, 2,  circle.
If you have that number is 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, ..., 9, 0, 1, 2, .......,
If you try to go beyond, it circulate to the beginning.
What about if you try to assign a value of minus one?
This is underflow, but notice again it is going to circulate in the circle.
So -1 is going to jump to the maximum, -2 is going to jump to the max-1.
So it's actually like wrapping around, circles are wrapping around it.
You don't need to care about that.
I'm just telling you something interesting about what's happening behind the scene.
Um, uh.
This is what we just were saying.
OK, so....
And if you looked about the previous code, the long long, the long long was like the white strike,
like it was supporting a very huge number.
So one, we could say, OK, I would like very big numbers in my system.
I'm going to use every little data type as a long long not an integer.
But this is actually wrong.
Why?
Because the more bigger datatypes, the slower the system will be.
So be very careful.
Do not use just long long because it allows more bits.
So it would be very big.
No, no.
Most of the time you would find people are using just the integer.
So this is a standard in usage.
You should think about what is the smallest datatype that you can use for your system because it
means less memory and less size. For the long long, you can define it here long long var or unsigned long
long, or unsigned long long int and so on.
All of them are very same. This is a long long and these two are the same as unsigned. If you try to print
the size of one of these variable, it will be 8 bytes.
There is also one interesting thing, the what we call the literals with suffix. So a suffix is something
we are adding to the end of of a word.
For example, here, if you say 2, this is just an integer. In C++, if you write '2u', this mean this
is an unsigned u. If you write '2l', this means long. If you write 2'', it means long long.
OK, and this is a bunch of like constants that is defined for you for this outputs.
Now, when I try to print something like, say out this number, what is
the datatype of this printed number?
C++ is going to check the compiler.
What is the smallest type of integer, long or long long, that represented this number.
So notice this is fit in the integer.
So the available of that is just integer.
Now, if you try to use this big number, this one fit now in long long, OK, if you try to fit something
bigger than that, there would be a compilation error because it's greater than long long.
Notice here,
C++ doesn't try to check unsigned long long, its maximum is long long.
OK, if I would like to force unsigned long long?
The best way is to start to use the literals here, the prefix litterers.
So I can say this number and say long long, this is now unsigned long long. This very big number but unsigned long long.
So without this one, you would get a compilation error. There is something also that to standard that
I wanted you to be familiar
and know about it
This what we call the 128 int. The unsigned long long is 8 bytes.
This one is much bigger in memory.
So you can define a variable in what I think compiler, you can increment it, but you cannot print it in
a direct way.
OK, you don't use it, you shouldn't.
But just I want you to be aware that this exists; 16 bytes one.
Um.
So for the bike representation, for signed and unsigned variables, if you have assumption that we are
using 32 bits and unsigned integer, we use all of them to represent 32 bits.
But in the signed integers, we use one bit to represent if it's positive or negative internally
and use the other 31 bits for representing the value.
That's why the idea of division of our number to two halves is coming from this reason.
If you have 8 bits, we take 1 bit to the signed and we take 7 bits to the value.
So it is seven, then 2 to the power 7.
It is 128.
That's why we divide it two halves this way. In the future,
this is something relevant to what we call 2'complement, which is something that you should know about it.
That's it