Let's talk about some of the details for the double numbers or the floating point numbers in general.
The first thing we would like to talk about is the scientific notation.
The scientific notation is just a shorthand for writing very lengthy numbers.
For example, let's introduce that. If we have something like 1.2 times 10 to the power 4
we know that this is like 10.000; 10 to the power 4  is just 4 zeros.
And then we multiply it with one point two, we get this big number.
The 1.2 we call it a significant and 4, we call it the exponent of the 10 here.
What about 5* 10^-3?
This is as same as 5 divided by 1000, which is just 0.005.
What about this number times 10^24?
It is very huge number.
Thinking about the left style and right stylem,
we notice that this left style is easily readable, compared to this one, and also is easily to be compared to the
other numbers.
OK, here is one more thing.
If we have this number that times 10^4, it is the same as if this number become
but we divide here by 10, or become 6 and we divide it by another 10, or 7 and we divide by another
10, or 8 and we divide it by another 10.
So here is the notation.
The notation of 1.2e4 means that this is 1.2 times the 10^4
OK, which can be represented as 1.2e004
So 'e' here which is referring to the exponential or exponent, it means 1.2e,
when you see 'e', you're replace it with 10to the power and put this number is, 004, is like
4.
That's OK. For this number here, 5*10^-3,
We can write it like 5e-3.
So it means 5 times 10 to the power -3. For this number here,
It's written as 1.2387e8.
For this very big number,
we can write it like5.97 blah blah blah e24.
So the scientific notation is writing this number in this style.
You have the significant and you have some power to 10.
Then you write it this way.
It would be easy to read and easy to compare.
How to build this scientific notation?
This is an important thing.
Generally speaking, you have to restructure it to be one non-zero digit then 'e'.
So there is always the scientific notation, that is only a single digit here, non-zero one,
then you have something here.
This is the details of how to compute that.
Feel free to read it.
It's very logical to think about it.
You would like to give the first digit here so you keep moving the sign like you say,
7 would like the 7 to be here in the beginning.
So you need to keep dividing here to get it here and so on.
So in terms of scientific notation, you see that this number can be written here. I'm just providing
more examples. If we would like this 7 to jump here to the beginning, then we divide it 3
times.
That's OK. If we have 600 here, and then we would like one digit on here to be 6. ,
so we need to multiply with these 2 zeros.
So you see, if I'm moving left, I'm dividing.
If I'm moving right, I'm multiplying.
And notice also here something like 6.7,
We can write it like 6.70000e+00 .
What does this mean?
It means as following: we have here
the 0.7000,
This is as same as 0.7.
So don't get confused about that.
And 'e00' just means 10 to the power zero, which is just 1.
So make sure that when you read such a number, you don't get confused.
This is what we call it, trailing zeros.
Here are two values.
OK, here is your turn. Try to think about this one.
Give yourself like one minute how to make it with one digit only here in the beginning.
Something like 3.4,
probably this is wrong.
So for the 123, it would be one point.
So we need to multiply with 2 to make this shift.
This number, if we put here a point, then there are 5 digits that you need to multiply
with them.
If you have something like that 0.8, then you need to divide by e-10 to get this
number and so on.
There's something here relevant, but I don't want to get in details.
It's just confusing what we call the significant digits.
So thinking about this number before the 'e', we have up to 6 significant digits.
But it isn't that straightforward.
Like for example, here in this case, it's just a 3  significant digits
although we have 6 before the 'e'. Feel free to go to this link to read about the significant
digits, but I just wanted to give you a sense of when people refer to significant digits, they refer
to some digits here before the 'e'.
It is more tricky when you have some trailing zeros.
But for example, here in this case, we have like 9 digits.
If you have something that involving the 8 here, like all of these zeros would be ignored, then
we have only 8 here
so it would be one significant digit.
It isn't a big deal.
I don't need you to understand it at the moment, but just in case, then feel free to go here.
But when we say significant digits, we are referring to something before the 'e'.
This is what I care about it at the moment.
In terms of code: if you try to print this number, it would be pretty normally, but if you try to
print this big number, it would be printed in this notation.
That's why it's important to understand the scientific notation. In C++, you can even force printing
of scientific information as following.
This is what we call, a setf  function so we can say setf(ios::scientific).
setf(ios::scientific)
Another way is to say that I would cout scientific this way and now if you try to print these two
numbers, both of them would be printed in the scientific notation or these two numbers would be printed
in the scientific notation.
There is also in C++, what we call precision.
The precision is forcing how many digits you will need after the point.
So if you say here precision ten, if you try to count here, one, two, three, four, five,
six, seven, eight, I guess this would be this would be 10 or so.
So now mixing the precision with the scientific notation, this isn't very useful, actually.
What's more useful is just use it with the with the normal representation.
So let's here go back and set setf.
ios::fixed, ios:: floatfield. It might look weird for you.
Just use it as it is.
You are now getting it back as a normal printing; the standard not the scientific notation.
Remember, the precision was set here to 10, so if you try to print to this number here, it is going
to print 10 digits after the dot and here it is going to print also 10 numbers after the dot.
Notice that in C++, if you try to print 100.0, it would just print 100.
But if you say here 'showpoint', it will force typically point putting the point here.
So why line 27? It is just forcing the point here and printing. What we're using here is something
called
ios three manipulators which will have a separate video for them. The moral of them is you are
affecting the stream
output here to behave in a way different than the default style.
So the default style is to print this number without scientific notation.
When you tell him, hey, I want you to put this flag, it is going to printed in a scientific notation.
If you said here, hey, I want you to this precision, it is going to print all of these numbers. If you
say, hey, when I want you always to show point, it is going to always print the show point and so on.
So this is called istream manipulators.
We will talk more about them later.
That's it.