One of the critical topics to know about the floating point numbers is the rounding errors.
Recall we once highlighted about the double comparisons.
If you have here a number, like a= 3/7 and you incremented 1 here and then you subtracted
it. If you tried to compare these 2 numbers, surprisingly, sometimes it would not be the same one.
Here we have 5 and 4.
And if you try to print them, surprisingly, you might find that this 4.99999 is printed as 5.
But if you try to compare, they are not equal.
So the reason behind that, as we highlighted before, is C++ is using an approximation for this floating
point or read values.
And the lesson was you should not compare directly.
So today we will learn a little more about that.
And we learn one way to make a comparison.
But before that, I would like you to take the chance, read this program and tell us what is the output
of this program.
OK, so probably you guessed some of them correctly, this one is going to print 2 stars. We have
we have 0,5, so it's going to increment twice. we're going also to print 5# because
0.2 is going to be incremented like 5 times.
Surprisingly, the third one is going to work for infinity.
If you tried this on your computer, this would not be printed 10 times.
It would be printed as infinity numbers.
So what's wrong with such a very simple equation?
The 'r' not equal just one.
What's wrong with that?
The wrong is here in the 0.1.
So let's introduce two things about C++ and the math itself. In math,
if you say 5 divided by 2, this is just about 2.5.
Nothing wrong about that.
If you divide 1 by 10, it's 0.1, so far so good.
But if you try to represent 1/3, in math, you would notice it is 0.33333333
3 forever.
We can write this in a shorter notation and say 0.(3), which means that 3 is repeating
forever, but about 3/7?
If you tried in the calculator, it would be also repeating forever.
So we find that this pattern 428571 is repeating forever.
We are going to put it in parentheses () to indicate repeating forever.
If you thought about it, if in math these two numbers are going forever, then we cannot represent
them in limited storage.
That's why C++ eventually have to approximate this number.
It cannot just use it as it. It can not just represent it going forever.
So this is one reason why C++ eventually or any programming language would have problems will come representing
floating numbers.
But it is what's more tricky.
Let's think about 0.1.
It looks like very, very straightforward in decimals.
But remember, everything in the lower level in C++ is just zeros and ones. When we try to represent
zero one in binary representation,
and I know that you don't know how to make that, then you find it represented as following.
It is actually 0.0, then 0011 is repeating forever.
This means that although the number 0.1 is very straightforward in math and in decimal
systems, but in binary it's also going forever.
So 0.1 would have to be approximated also
so it would not be accurate.
That's why in the slide here you are incrementing with 0.1 which is internally approximated.
So this one, when it comes to 'r' and one, this one will not be actually one.
It would be something like 0.9999999.
So the comparison will not work.
OK, let's have some fun with the IOI manipulators, if you include 'iomanip' to see the precision.
Let's print the five and six.
Fair enough that the .0 is removed. If you try to print 0.1 or  1/3.
let's set precision with 20, we want 20 digits.
When you see the 0.1 printed, you will notice there are some numbers in the end here.
So some numbers are here.
If you say the 1/3, it will have some numbers that are not just 0.33333
...
So these two cases are cases where C++ is going to approximate your numbers and they cannot represented
in completely appropriate way.
As a side note, the precision can help us to do some rounding to the numbers. Let's use here's some
number like c=3.14, and then try to print a precision like, say, if you printed
9, it should print 9 numbers, but it didn't print 9 numbers.
Why?
You have to use the 'fixed' also with C++.
So every time you are using the precision, please also use 'fixed'.
Now if you try to use the fixed here and printing the 9, it is going to print this number with nine
digits.
So far so good.
I would like you here to highlight the rounding of a number approximating a number.
If you say it for this number up to 7, then it will be a couple of 00. For 6, it's 0here.
Five is OK.
If you say that I want to print it to 4, C++ is going to make an approximation.
So this 8 is going to be approximated and give us 1 here.
So now 66. If you tried to approximate to 3,
This 6 is going to be removed and this 6 is going to be 7. Approximate more of the setprecision (2),
it will be 7 go to 1 here
so it will be 2.
So, you know, in math, if you like to approximate, you see
if the digit is greater than 5, then you increment to the one before it.
OK, this is just math.
But be careful.
Let's say here you are approximating this number to 3, so the 8 will make the 4 to be 5
and the 5. Should the 5 make the 6 to be 7 or not?
This is something that repeat. Here in our case, the 5 doesn't increment the number only if
the number are 6, 7, 8, or 9 and you are set precision, it's  going to increment to the number before
them, otherwise it would not affect it.
So the moral of that, you can actually have some control over the rounding of the printed numbers.
Comparison:  as we know now, direct comparison is wrong.
If you would like to compare number, here is one way. You can think of the difference between two numbers.
What happens if we have two numbers that we think they are equal, but there might be very minor
differences in the value?
If we so substracted the two numbers together, the difference would be something like maybe 10^-9
, 10^-8,  or 10^-10, something very small.
So if you would like to check for comparison, we might start with comparing if they are very, very
close or not.
If they are very close, we consider them equal.
Otherwise, we just can compare normally.
less than or greater than.
So here is how to code that.
I'm defining a function that takes two numbers a and B and some EPS.
This EPS represents the error gap between the two numbers, the potential one.
And here I'm saying float absolute "fabs" between a and b, remember "fabs" is getting the absolute which is
a positive sign, but in a float representations.
So if we subtracted the two numbers and they are really very, very close, like one
and one point something very, very small.
We know the difference should be less than this EPS value.
If it's less than EPS value, we return 0 to indicate they are equal, otherwise they are not
equal.
We can now compare normally less than and greater than. If a<b, we return -1.
Otherwise, we return 1.
So this function is returning either 0, 1, or -1. 0 for equal,  one
if the first is bigger, and -1 if smaller.
Now we are defining here our a and b like 3/7 and this one I'm making here 0.1
to make it more problematic as an internal representation.
If I compared a ==b, it would be 0.
But now if I say double comparison to a and b, is it ==0? , is it equal?
It would say yes.
One.
Now, let's see why this might be also very careful, very, very dangerous function. If you try to
compare1/3 with 0.33333, and you say it is ==0?
It will be answered
Yes.
Now, if you tried to use less precision here, like you say, this just number here, ==0?
The answer is false.
Why?
Because the difference of these two numbers is greater than 1e-10. You notice here
if you try to think of the difference, it would be greater than 10e-10
...
So now this EPS value is now a problem, like what is the right very small difference.
This is really a very challenging question.
Let's play with that.
I'm going to use the same number, but using ten to the power -9,
...
That is going to work out.
So although the idea of comparing two numbers using the difference is a good idea and I hope you got
it, the risk is what should be the value of the EPS value. Typically something that e-10 also
is going to work well
in most of the cases. The moral of that even this problem, even this way is still problematic.
That's it.