Similar to the integrated five, so there is also the types in floating point that we never introduced
so far, but there are two other data types in C++, one of them named a float and another one the named
Longido.
So the longer float, the minimum size is typically fold for the double is typically eat the along,
the double sometimes is eight, sometimes is 12 and sometimes is 16 times more of a platform dependent.
So there is no guarantee that Longyearbyen is better than double.
If you would like to define them, you define double X like we did or float Y and you put here F or
the double and you put here the El Capitan.
Generally speaking, as we'll know, we typically use in our in our applications of the X as double.
We never really use a fluid.
And also we are very careful about doing double as potentially might be more competitions or more memory.
The first question here is about the range of of of floating and floating buoys.
Look what we know, the maximum value of integral.
But what is the maximum value of Dubon when it comes to the double?
There are two components, not just one with just the range recoded, the range and the precision.
The idea here in double representations, we can't allow much, much, much bigger values.
But on the contrary, it would not be.
I would be very accurate.
So in this way, we have here this position one, so, for example, looking to the to the double,
for example, the doubles range is you see here up to ten to the power.
Three hundred eight.
This is a huge number.
You imagine up to three hundred zeros, for example.
This is very huge.
But the significant digits for us are around an average 16 for the float on average is typically seven
for the.
For the longest of all, it could be it depends on the implementation like here in some case it could
be like 33 digit up to thirty six digits.
Remember, once I highlighted the significant digits in an informal way, I just wanted you to know
that this, this, this, this just before the E let's let's make it that informant just we call them
significant digits, so up to only seven digits and flute, which is four bytes.
That's why they're using the fluid is a very, very bad idea.
Using the the double is up to 15 to 18 digits.
This is typically a lot in terms of real life practice.
That's why the dubbin is a standard, the type that we are typically using in in in our usage.
It's also important here, like it might be that the heartbeat fluting type has the same range as the
16 byte.
Like we're thinking about.
The estimate was 16, 16 is is different.
So why these two have exactly the same range, although they are different in sizes?
Because, again, remember that also there is also the significant digit.
But so it isn't only about the range, it's also about the significant.
Significant about.
In terms of Gooding, let's set a position for up to 19 and let's try to bring to flute and double and
longlong unit is the float here in a very early stage is starting to give very wrong representation.
You will notice the double is surviving much bigger range, but on the double is roaming much, much,
much more.
If you not if you have something very strong up to that.
That's why the double is usually a very good representation.
But the float is very is very dangerous because in a very early stage, let's count here, one, two,
three, four, five, six.
So you see it after like six or seven digits.
It started to to feel that this is very risky for real life applications.
Let's even see some problems.
Let's define a float value.
If one here with a maximum of the integer, that's good.
So far, surprisingly, if you try to use it something like a different value, you printed it wrongly.
Even it has less value because of the number of significant digits.
Anyway, way of of of of fluid is just seven.
So there is no guarantees in such numbers.
It's going to work.
Well, you see here, it's printed even strongly.
That's why we we typically don't use the float.
The the the double has like fifteen or so significant digits.
So this number is a small for it, it just has insignificant digits if you try to count them.
We have the numbers for one more night.
This is nine and the zero also counted here.
So we have like ten significant digits.
So overall, you see the double is surviving with something that is decent for our usage.
The internal representation of fluid and how it's supporting such a huge range and how it's approximating
it is a bit complicated at this stage, just like you know that internally say we have 32 bits, we
divide it to two.
But one part we call it the mixer and another what we call it the exponent.
And we use one point, one bit for that.
But using this representation allow us to have a bigger range, but is less accurate.
So this time it is about using two to the power.
Thirty two.
We are using it in a different way.
The double in general has sixty bits because it's 15 digits on average for the precision and it is double
what we call a double precision because we're using sixty four or sixty eight bits and could try to
hear the fluid is just 32.
I forget it.
No, it should be seven digits and we call it single precision.
If you notice, we call this double precision because it is double the float value.
One other concern to talk about is C++ define two variables specific to cases.
One, could we call it ñan, which is not a number.
And then over another value is infinity.
Remember, when we divide over zero like five, what, zero or negative five were zero.
This is infinity.
Could be positive infinity like in this case and negative infinity C++ we printed the word enf.
OK, on the other side, what if we divide it zero by zero?
This would bring to an end.
So this is another number, which means the mathematically invalid it is.
One more interesting thing.
What is the output of this condition and line it in that equation that this line will not be printed?
This is the only case when you compare something in C++ by itself and it doesn't bring in a very funny
case and has some usage in what we call dynamic programming, but out of scope for now.
Some tips, all of what I need from you at the moment is to just keep using double as we used it to
reduce the food, to reduce long double, as long as we don't have a good reason for that.
You might read this here for some for some for some minor cases for them in general.
And as long as you are far from the financial or currency applications, you are on the safe side.
But in some of these applications where the precision play a big factor and might affect the competitions,
you have really to understand how floating point numbers ebooks never could bear fruit directly as we
did in the last time.
But remember, also competing with difference is a bit problematic.
These articles here are very important articles, but it might be a bit advanced at the moment.
What I care here is before being a software engineer working in the market, it is very important to
read them and to understand them.
There are a bunch of advices here in this great article by myself, which is a key figure into the community.
He is writing a bunch of information about double's and in a very nice way about some of the mis wrongdoings
and misunderstanding of people about the real values.
So in a way at this are worth reading.
But but you can skip that for now.