One of the important topics to know about this is a type conversion, once you start to know that there
is the intent, there is a fluid and there is a double long double signed and signed worth about the
type conversions.
So there are two type conversions, what we call implicit and explicit implicit is happening behind
the scene.
And it's very risky.
If you don't understand it, if you if you are defining a boolean status here and assigning it some
value.
So where you're assigning any to your value, but this is boolean, then an implicit conversion has
to happen from an integer to a bullet.
If you put the value like a positive or negative, it would be eventually true.
The only case for a conversion in Boolean to be false is to assign the value zero.
Otherwise it would be true.
Some guys might have the impression that the negative value would give false.
But this is wrong.
Let's say you have something like a double salary here with one hundred point six.
If you try to put it in integer, you are going to lose the point.
This is what we know.
What if we try to put something else like what if we try to put something like an integer inside a shortage
that you should expect most of the time to get and overflow?
And in our case here, it will not happen because just a hundred something.
But let's say that the Senate is 100000, then this is going to make an overflow.
So you you have to be careful about that.
There's an interesting thing that you would not be able to understand.
It's Internet at the moment.
If you if you declared insane character blood to read the value of minus one, this will be its actual
value would be two hundred fifty five.
So this is a bit special, relevant to the very deep representation of the bits.
So let's just give it the one.
But I wanted you to know about this information.
If you if you try to cast something to something, I probably will face the corruption in the value.
For example, if you have seen it to get X negative 100 and it was assigned to unsign the variable,
this is negative.
So this is underflow.
So it will cause a problem.
In C++, what we call promotion, if it happened that you have an exhibition that have mix of data types,
so C++ have some rules to handle that they have what we call a promotion.
We have this list.
And and this order is very important.
If we have a mix of data types that C++ is going to find the end, then I have to say that the one that
is coming from the lower that exists of them, for example, does the expression, let's say the exhibition
has integer and unsigned, long and double.
C++ is going to start from the eleven.
Does it have longer does it have bubblicious convert everything to double?
So let's say here integer, unsigned, long, long and so to integrating int it started for me.
Do we have a long double double.
No fluid.
No unsigned longlong.
Yes.
Convert everything in this equation to unsigned longlong.
So the way that C++ is handling an exhibition that involve a different data types is converting all
of them to one in this list starting from the end the to the beginning.
But, but notes that there might be a lot of corruption in the data that might happen from here.
So every time you have an expression that have mixed set of data types, think twice and you have to
remember this list and you have to remember what's going to happen behind the scene.
You might wonder why you have this list.
If you have interest to read about the logic, you might check this link.
It might be useful to have that.
Let's do some good if we bring 20, minus 30.
This is very normal.
There is no implicit conversion into your mind fear.
But if you try to have an insight into your MBA was 20 and 30 as of them, this will not work.
There's no conversion here.
But I'm warning you from that.
Let's say we have the financial or the excuse.
Then if you say X plus 90, remember, the type of 90 is going to be searched among end and long and
long, long.
So 90 would be long.
So it would be no shorter plus.
Long story, short end.
So this is going to be the X is going to be converted to a..
If I have something like X plus 85 plus five point one, all of the all of the expression here would
be handled as a double.
So this one would be handled as double and this one would be handled as double if you tried to bring
the two million plus two million.
This is going to overflow.
But if you added here Longlong, for example, in this part, then this out of these two sides is going
to or this is longlong so agreed.
This one, too, also to look at them, but into familiar as longlong.
So be careful if you have such equidistance, it's Aliette like prefers to put suffix literals here
to facilitate the printing in a similar way.
You can take this submission to Z if you would like to have it in a variable.
It is one more thing.
Let's define longlong d as some longlong maximum even minus something.
So far so good.
If we try to do one minus zero point zero, this one is going to be converted to double and the one
minus hundred is going to be converted to double.
Surprisingly, when you try to break the both of them, they might be equal.
And the reason behind that is the double has a precision on average of 15.
So it might fail to handle something like Longlong.
So be careful from that.
It is one more interesting thing.
Let's say we have character C character Max, which is now one hundred twenty seven.
Remember the character Max is moving from minus one hundred twenty eight to one hundred twenty seven.
If you add see it should be No.
Two fifty four which is beyond the character limit.
So it's going to be overflow.
Surprisingly it will not y because C++ do a direct promotion for short values and character values to
to integer or translate into other divisions.
So if it's character or short it will be upgraded to integer.
And if it is unsigned, the short or the character or circular, it will be upgraded to unsigned character
and unsigned short.
So the moral of that is there will be an upgrading for this value even before the competition.
So this is kind of an exception to the rule.
So this will not overflow, as you expect.
A few tips, remember that unsigned integer can be very problematic, so be very careful, something
like X minus Y, if the result is negative, the results will be corrupted in the convergence, like
some integer would be converted to unsigned the entire there would be corruption.
So you sign the integers unless there is a good reason for that.
There's also what we call an explicit conversion here you are converting by yourself and C++ provide
you with several ways to cast, including the old sea styles.
So in the old cystine, if you have something like Xixi to integrate this way or cost it to integrate
this way, I would be using this site all the time to avoid using this style.
But although it is OK in in the normal custom here, so the proper way that people like more is what
we call the static custom C++ like a static cost of index that the static cost is going to as you see
when you read it here, it give clearly the intention.
What do you want to do?
Clearly you are saying, I would like to also associate a good forecasting.
It would be easier than searching for the code here.
I think Zober in both of them.
But searching the code for this one is easier.
The advantage in the static cost, if you are trying to do something wrong, encaustic like with pointers,
the static cost will dictate in the completion error.
For example, let's say you have character see here and you have a pointer here.
If you try to come to the character, see to integrate pointer, it would work well.
But if you try to offset the cost, it will.
Koblin Why?
Because character is just one byte and integrities for byte.
You cannot make such a conversion in the memory.
So the good about the static cost, especially when it comes to Beutler's, it can help you with this
competition.
So please try to push more yourself to use a static cost, at least if you are trying to use pointers.
There is also other modifiers.
In C++, for example, the code is the cost because the cost can remove the code to modify it.
Please don't do that.
Like this is something that we use in a very, very exceptional cases.
Don't do that.
There is also the reinterpret cost which can cost whatever integer point or whatever waterpipe to another
time.
Again, we do not do that.
So what we use is typically static cost.
That is something good.
Something as psychodynamics.
We will see, we'll see in the Olby.
But for now this is explicit costing the sties.
Your turn.
I would like you to read this program and guess the output of it.
OK, so the first thing in the orbit of this program is is going to bring to this very big number.
This is very surprisingly, the victor is empty.
So the size is zero zero minus one is zero.
What happened?
That's why you have such a big number.
The reason is the function size is returning what we call our size and our security, which eventually
is just unsign the number either outside of India or inside the globe.
The problem here is if we have zero minus one, then zero zero is unsigned.
So this expression would be converted to inside.
And as it is negative, one is going to be underflow to such a very big value as a result.
This for Lub here is going to work for infinity because this is very big value.
The right way to be more severe is to Casta the vector, the size or any size coming from Israel to
integrate here is more.
Practically speaking, the size says the security was used because it might be the vector is very huge,
but this is actually very, very, very rare.
So it is more severe to discuss it, to integrate here and just walk over it.
So anyway, be careful from such a such a minus one.
Yeah.
As a trick.
If you would like to avoid the custom, you can take this minus one and plus one here.
So it's no wonder Zadvydas says it would not make a problem.
Even if it did, it cost the city.