One of the topics in C++ is about what we call extreme manipulators and manipulator is something that
changes the format of the many of the stream itself.
For example, remember we used in Fluting when we something would fixate on scientific and point.
Remember, the rule mainly was to change the output format itself.
So we use scientific you start to see some some scientific notation.
This is what we mean by changing the format of the parameters here.
For example, if you also use a key word like our case, there is more will be printed.
Also one, we want to mention the word alpha.
When you citable the Alpha, the value of the word is printed as true and the value of Foulds is printed
as a zero.
So this is also when a change to the Elbit itself.
So today we are going to know about little other manipulators.
One of them is called the Schubas.
Schabas is just forcing the same.
Well, if you printed the hundred, it's typically printed without a plus sign.
But what if you would like a sign for it?
When you use a city, your position is going to show the sign here.
If you'd like to cancel it, you can say, is that a no show position?
So now it is going to print without it.
They said CW is one of the most important ones to know about them when you try to bring something like
that one, two, three, four, with two brackets here, it just printed as we expected.
What if you would like to bring it in a field of any characters?
But if you do, we mean think of it like any different slots.
For example, here, if I say said W5, it is going to set a window of five spaces and then when you
write one, two, three, four is going by default to write them to the end of the five slots here.
If you have set of six out of six, the characters are here and then you put the four characters here,
seven and so on.
What if you would like the printing to be on the left side, so I know say said, but I come here first
and said it is Flagg's to left now when you try to print, it is going to print them in the left side.
This interview is very important in when you have a printing, say, for tables or so, I would like
the other to be very organized.
So S.W. is your way to do that.
There is something called business.
We know about the the DISMEMBERS and we talked about the Minorities' before.
There are other types of abuses like what we call Octagon and hexagon.
You do know about the hexadecimal.
You do know about these types at the moment.
But just I wanted you to know that we can bring to the numbers in different ways in Boynton's, because
you will notice that the numbers are always printed in this hexadecimal format.
If you read the text of the deal, it's going to bring to the the the number.
This way, if you use the other case, it would be printed this way.
If you don't understand that, this is totally OK.
OK, there is one interesting thing here.
Sometimes when you on your program and there is a crash for it, let's say you divide it by zero.
And there was a lot of how would you expect to see in the console.
But you look to the console, you don't see the output.
This is one one of the bothering, puzzling things for a for a newcomer for gaming.
What is the issue?
The issue is in the sea out object.
When you write your data, the actually not printed directly to the console, which is internally buffer,
they think of the buffer like an internal array of characters with every time you bring to something,
the combinat is just in the runtime.
They put this out in the array of characters printed.
And this array has a limited size, let's say a hundred character or eighty characters.
Every time you reach the end, the limit of the array, let's say you print it.
So far, 80 characters is going to print it, print it wants.
What is the point.
So it is writing to a console or writing to a file is very slow operation.
So the behind the scenes they would like to minimize the number of writings.
That's why they keep putting in the content in an array and the printed it.
It's all of it felt the problem was behind the scenes crashes.
The crash happens, but the real content is imprinted so far.
That's why it could happen that there is a crash and there is an output buffer that is imprinted.
So you didn't see what you already wrote.
Now, here's an interesting fact.
What if I would like to force the printing to heaven directly without being put in the buffer?
You would the would the flash.
So the model of all of what I was saying, if you would force an elbow to really come outside of the
once you did writing, you just put the word flash.
Once you put the word flush it go.
And the force of taking the output of the buffer so far and just print it.
So if it happened that you have a crash and you don't see all of the L would try to put a flash to force
you feel free to here more.
There's also another thing that I would like to know about through the whole course.
We were using the out for printing, which is actually two other things.
One of them, the named Serhan said, is abbreviation to console error.
When there is some kind of errors that you feel in there, could you might use the third A.D.s in eclipse.
You will notice the third is printed in a red color.
So the interest in here, if you send a message said, does it have an internal buffer?
So it's always the flush.
It's always printed.
You do need to put a flush with the Wesser.
So try to use see our concert to see maybe cut difference.
What is it, what is the like the consequence of flushing a lot.
As I said, writing is an expensive operation.
So if you are trying a lot of writing, this is very slow.
You would notice that if you are writing a huge amount of it, that's it.