Through the course twice, we have talked about the compilation process. We knew about what is
the compilation part,
we learned a few things about the linker part,
and in this section, we would like to go in little more details about the compiler and the linker.
A full understanding of this issue, especially about the compiler things,
would require three different computer science courses.
The compiler course, the assembly programming language, and the computer architecture.
With these courses, you can have a very deep understanding of what is happening and about the
details.
There were many programming languages that have been there, and it was like an evolution for the languages,
so we have here our hardware typically implemented using just a bunch of the zeros and ones.
The first the programming language
and the only one that the hardware understands in our context typically is the machine code language,
which is just zeros and ones.
You can imagine how hard to write zeros and ones.
So through zeros and ones, we can tell the computer every kind of instructions we would like to give.
Remember, every programming language eventually is a set of instructions.
When we go to a higher level, we get what we call an assembly language, and the assembly language is
kind of one-to-one mapping between this language and the machine code language.
The assembly is still like a low-level code, but it's much, much easier to write compared to the machine
code.
And now in the development of languages, we go one higher-level like Java and C++ and Python, and these
are very high level languages.
We can write programming languages in a very easy way.
Some of them are compiled like C++ and Java, and some of them are interpreted like Python.
Later, you can know what is interpretation in a python course so.
...
So if you tried to go to this website and you wrote such a very simple code, which is a high
level code and you wrote a square function this way, the website will give you a translation for this
code to the assembly code. If you tried to read here, you would notice something called square int.
So you can guess that this is a square function.
So as you see, we are going to do mapping that this code is going to be converted here.
So we have here also the main function, and then you start to find the commands or instructions like push,
move, move, pop, ret for return, and so on.
So the main function here, you see in line 14, we have a call for a function named Square that takes
an integer and this square is going to take an integer,
and eventually would be computed and return here with the ret.
So the assembly is a bunch of instructions in this way that have very specific meanings.
So overall, we write this kind of high-level code like C++ code or Fortran code, this higher
level and then this high-level code is going to be converted to assembly language.
This is mainly happening through a compilation step. After this code is converted here to assembly,
we are going to convert it to another level, to a very low-level code, which is the binary
code. From the high level to the assembly,
we do that through the compiler. From the assembly to a machine language,
We do that through another program called the assembler.
So this is how we go step by step to the target destination from the high level to the machine level
code.
The assembler is just another program that you don't see, which is converting your code into assembly
language.
Finally, when you double click on your executable, which is eventually a bunch of instructions
in zeros and ones, these instructions are loaded into the memory,
then there is what we call a fetch-execute cycle, which simply takes the instruction executed, then
take another instruction executed, fetch another instruction and executed, and so on.
So this is the whole cycle that involves, as I said, the compiler and the assembly and also the
computer architecture here.
So overall, behind the scene, we have the compilation.
Remember, we talked about the preprocessor which goes to parse every line that starts with the hash, the preprocessor
directives, and then is going to be compiled to give the assembly code and then the assembler would
give us what we call object files,
and these are bunch of binary files.
We also learned about linking, which has a major goal of combining the bunch of object files that
you have together in one executable program, and then you may face some resolve reference, the linker
also is going to resolve the references, which means searching for implementations. if it didn't find
the target implementation, it says an undefined reference as we will show in the next lecture.
Finally, execution: we load instructions in the memory and do fetch-execute cycle.
This is a big picture of steps that happens mainly in the compilation process.
So we have the source codes, in the compilation,
they go to the assembly and with the assembler, they go to object files, and the linker is going to take all
of these files together with all of you will say std files or libraries, push all of them together
to give you that executable file.
This is for now about the big picture of the compilation process. That's it.