Let's go into more interesting details about the compilation process, as you see, there is nothing here
that you are going to do eventually, but it's good to understand something about what is happening.
This is a big picture as we talked about them.
Now, I would like to go with you with some examples that help you to clarify a bit of things.
This is the directory of the files.
We have three CPP files,
each one of them has a header file, and we had a 4th dot_cpp file, Test here, which has a main. I'm doing a simple
hash-defined Mostafa, which is just defining constant Mostafa, and another constant saad here, and
a constant Ibrahim here, and a constant hello here.
Please give a minute to familiarize yourself with the code.
Interestingly here, Fun2 is referring to Fun1, and the Test is referring to Fun1 and Fun2,
but Fun3 here,
there is no one is referencing this file,
so it exists, but it isn't used by the Test file at least.
So we have four CPP files in total. When we try to compile this code, we notice in the directory
we typically have five binary files.
Four of them for the O object files, and one of them for the executable.
Remember, we said that before the binary file isn't a text ASCII file.
You cannot open it with notepad and read it normally.
So in the code, we had three header files, three CPP, one CPP. Eventually, you have four CPP files.
So we have corresponding four object files, and we have one main file which would also have another
executable file. The compiler generates for us these four object files, and then the linking is going to
generates for us the executable.
So the compiler will give us these four dot_O files, but the linker is going to give us the dot_exe file. More interestingly,
here, the linker mainly only needs Fun1, Fun2, and Test_O,
OK.
Why it doesn't need Fun3_dot_O?
Because the linker doesn't see the main is using the Fun3, so it can be discarded normally like
simply can be discarded.
Now, let's go a little more in details, if you would like to view the code that is written in C++
or an assembly, you can do that with any notepad or eclipse,
but what if I like to view the code in the machine code?
This isn't very useful, but sometimes it would help you in some debugging.
You can search and download for Hex editor. If you are using Linux just search in the computer
software part some Hex editor. In Windows,
I think I forget the name.
Just Google for the Hex editor if you have interest.
Now, let's view the code for the Fun1_dot_O.
When you open it, it would be actually a bunch of zeros and ones, but the Hex editor would
do some combination for the zero's and one's and print it in this hexadecimal style.
More importantly, it will try to decode here some of what is seen here.
So if you tried to go to Fun1 here, you will notice the word
Mostafa here. Remember here back to the code,
the test here has Fun1, Fun2, and hello,
so Fun1 has only the word Mustafa, Fun2 has only the word Saad, and the Test has the word hello,
and looking Fun1 and Fun2. So now Fun1 has the word Mostafa.
What about Fun2? Fun2 should have the word Saad and also referring to Fun1 which had the word
Mostafa.
So going here to Fun2, for example, we noticed that it has read the Mostafa and noticed that it has
the Saad.
OK, so it actually contained both of them. Going to Fun3,
we find the word Ibrahim here, also exists.
Now, going to the Test, we find Mostafa and we'll find Saad and we'll find hello, but you don't find
Ibrahim here.
Why?
Because Test_dot_cpp doesn't include the Fun3.
That's why it doesn't see the word Ibrahim. In a similar way,
we find the similar three things in the test_dot_exe.
So as you see here, you can see how these files have a good dependency between each other.
Now, here is one more interesting thing.
Let's come to the Fun1 and add a header file for add A and B, and also here in Fun1_dot_cpp,
we have a function add,
but we have commented it.
I would like to ask you a question.
What happened if you tried to compile this project, and can you run it or not?
OK, if you tried to compile it, it's going to compile successfully, it is going to give you the three dot_O files,
and the dot_O for the test file.
So eventually compiled. This is a surprise because, oh, I do not have an implementation for that.
By the end of the compilation process, you are going to get a linking error.
It say is undefined reference to add int and int.
It means that when I tried as a linker to put all of them together, I was trying to search for
the implementation of the add, but I didn't find the reference for it
among what you give to me. That's why there would be no executable generated for you here.
There would be only the dot_O files.
Let's make this more formal.
The compiler outputs two tables in every object file, so it reads the CPP file and generates an object file.
The compiler identifies what exists internally and listed it in one table, and also identifies symbols
for what should exists externally.
This means that the compiler actually will compile successfully even if it doesn't see the implementation
of something.
OK, so it can see only the declaration in the header file.
If it's seen only the declaration in the header file and doesn't see the implementation, it marks in this external
table,
hey guys, I'm waiting later someone to provide this implementation,
but if the add function neither exists in the header nor in the implementation, it is going definitely to give
a compilation error.
But if the information exists in the header file that the declaration, but it doesn't exist in the implementation
part, it just going to mark it that I expect later that someone externally another dot_cpp file
or something is going to give me the implementation of that.
...
And here's the role of the linker.
The linker takes all of these object files together to link them.
So if dot_cpp1 is expecting a function and market it externally, it should exist in one of these other
files that we have.
If it doesn't exist in any of the modules that we provided together, then it is going to give you the
undefined reference that you have seen.
So that's why the compiler can work if you see something in the declaration but doesn't see the definition,
but the linker would like to get all of them together.
That's it.