Throughout the whole course, we depended on the IDE like eclipse and code blocks to compile, link,
and run our own code. Today and using our current  background, we will see how we can also use the
command line to do such a process.
It happens sometimes in your development that you don't have an access to an IDE.
For example, when we work remotely on other servers, then the only way to compile and run things
is to do that from the command line.
The command line is an important skill for any software engineer.
As we know so far, there is actually some compilation step, some linking step, and then we
double click or we execute something.
So we overall have three kinds of commands to give to some program to run them for us.
IDE was doing that for us.
So what does the IDE do behind the scene? it just does them. There is behind the scene when you go and
install the GCC or the g++. The GCC is a program that we use to compile and link the C files for C
programming language and the g++ is the one that we run for the C++ compilation
like say you are using some g++ for, let's say, version five, you can also
download another one, let's say g++ nine or so, to do the compilation for you.
So now let's open some terminal. If you don't know how to open the terminal, just Google it, how
to do it for your operating system, which is eventually some black screen. Try first to run the word
g++.
If you see good outputs, like if it doesn't say I don't recognize what is g++, then
you can see the g++ program.
If you wrote g++ dash-dash help, it is going to give you a bunch of options.
One of them is the dash-dash version which is going to show the version of your compiler.
Please, run this command. Two interesting commands among the big list the dash c,
and dash O, the two options. The dash-c is going to compile and assemble your code.
The dash_O is going to tell it the path for some output file.
Now, let's try to do the compiling, the linking, and the running.
If you'd like to compile your file, you need to do a compilation command, one for each CPP file.
As an example,
remember, in the last time we have four CPP files, then I would like to give four commands,
each one of them is going to compile my file.
So we see here the command is g++,
or maybe if you have another version, you say g++ dash nine or some version, then you give it dash c,
which means we are going to compile and assemble our code.
You are going to give it dash_O and then some path for the output file.
So I'm saying here, dash_O, my fun2_dot_O.
So it means please locally here, give me a generated file which is my fun2_dot_O, and then you
are giving here the name of the CPP file that is going to be compiled.
Now, I compiled Fun2, then I compiled Fun1 then, I compiled Fun3, and then I compiled
test dot CPP, but we here in the test dot CPP, I told him, please make the name Mostafa Test dot O.
It doesn't have to be test dot O.
This is the output file.
It's up to you
what is the file name?
Once we did these commands, we are going to generate these dot O files for these
dot CPP files.
This way we are done with the compilation step. In the second step,
it comes the linking step,
and in this time, we say also again g++
but this time we do without write dash C, we directly
say dash O. Again, O for the output file.
So this time we say, hey, we would like to output, say if you are windows, you say output program
dot exe.
After that, you are going to provide a list of all dot_O files that we will need
like I said here Mostafa_test_dot_O, Fun3_O, MyFun2_O, MyFun1_O,
and once you did this compilation, you get a program dot_exe file because
this is the name that we selected.
Now, go to your program dot_exe file and run it,
You are going to get 30.
Here is a question,
what if I just give it most_test_dot_O and myFun_dot_O only? It is going to fail to link because the
Mostafa_dot_test is needing something in Fun1_dot_O. It is searching
for the implementation of some things.
That's why you need here to provide a complete list of all the dot_O files that you need. With these
three commands,
specifically these two. This one and the previous one.
You compiled and linked your program to get an executable to run.
One more interesting thing, please go ahead and investigate the console screen in your IDE that shows
the commands area.
You know that you used to ignore it, but for fun, let's say looking to eclipse or even code blocks or whatever.
You should start to see these g++ commands here.
As you notice, we have four g++ commands and then other g++ commands.
We have here some names for the exe then the bunch of the dot_O files.
You see one O file for every file you. You probably would see extra choices,
for example, dash Wall is for warning. Dash_Wall means show me
every warning that you found in this scope.
dash_O for the optimizations.
As you know, the compiler is doing a lot of optimization behind the scene.
Dash_O_zero means it doesn't do any optimizations, but you can also have more choices,
for example, if you went to eclipse here, you notice that we have dash_O one, two, three,
and s. Dash_O3 is the highest kind of optimization that you can get from the optimizer.
So you can also add these dash_O commands, if you like.
There are definitely a lot of choices that you can have in your compiler.
Feel free to go and investigate.
I wanted you to be aware of the compilation's commands because sometimes you need to do them in practice,
although most of the time, the IDE would be enough. That it.