In this session, we will learn how to path arguments to your whole program. So far,
we were reading all with the input from the user and process everything within it.
In practice, applications typically are initialized with some of the initial arguments that we run the
program itself with them. So we don't pass them as reading from a keyboard,
but actually, we passed them as major parameters to the input of the program itself.
You can think of that like I would like to, for example, run my online book reader program, but I
would like to give it an initial path to the database itself.
You can think of it like we can run the program, and then we ask the user to enter the database path and
read it.
That's OK,
but in reality, this is more convenient.
We can run the program itself and provided it with the input at the same time,
or let's say you have a factorial_exe program, you run it with 5, so it gives you 120, and so on.
So you think of all of the needs, like maybe path of the database, path of the configuration file, number of
parallel workers, and so on.
So how to do that?
We will start for the first time to see a change to the main function.
You notice here we added two parameters.
The first parameter is of type integer.
The second is of type character pointer array.
This is actually an array of character pointers.
The argc is the number of arguments that you pass to the program and the argv is a list of character pointers
for this character pointers.
If you write this program and do nothing, just run it as it is,
you will notice the following:
The argc would be one, although we pass nothing to the program,
and then it's going to list  the value of the program itself, which could be typically
some relative path or complete path, it depends.
So even without passing anything into the program, there is at least one argument here, which is the
program itself.
So now we would like to see what's going to happen if we tried to pass more programs.
Let's say we went to the command line here, and our program is called ztemp (I'm here on this level).
So I'm calling it with debug slash ztemp.
This is where my exe exists,
this is on ubuntu, and then I pass the word Mostafa then 10, 20, Ali. The program said here, remember that
I am iterating on the number of arguments and printing one by one.
This is argv of I is the ith element of the array which would be of type character
pointer.
It listing the following:
It lists the program name itself, then Mostafa, 10, 20, Ali.
So I pass the four arguments, but the fifth one will be coming from the program itself.
OK, let's do one more thing. Let's say that my program is expecting two values.
The first one would be a path to something, and the second one would be an integer.
So I'm doing the following:
I'm first of all, checking if the user really passes
two arguments or not. To pass two arguments,
we know there will be an extra one for the program itself.
So I'm saying if the argc is less than three, print an error message to the user.
Otherwise, I am taking the argv (which will be a character pointer) and put it here in a string,
and also I am taking the second argument and calling my personal function (function to_int) which will
take a string and passes it, so the character pointer will be converted to string,
then I'm doing  i_string on the string and then reading it and returning an integer, and then I'm printing
both of them.
That's it.
So this is the initial logic of my program, expecting a path, expecting an integer, and using them
and to_int is our function to convert a string to int.
More interestingly, there is a library named stdlib, and noticed the dot_h, stdlib_dot_h, this library is from the C library.
This library has a function named a_to_i which can convert for you, to is to convert, I is
an integer.
It can convert for you a character pointer of characters to an integer.
So we can actually replace our to_int function.
We can actually use the atoi function and just passes to it the character pointer, and it will
convert it to an integer. This just a more short code if you would like, instead of writing a to_int function.
Now, let's see the usage of this program, I here ran the program and give it the path of
some file only, so it's one parameter.
So it complains and says, hey, error please pass a string and an integer.
Now, I changed my code and passed the path to the file,
and 20, it will give me the path and 20.
Now, here is a trick. Always in paths,
be careful from spaces.
So here I am giving another path, which has Mostafa, space, saad, bla bla bla, and 20
but this is cause a problem.
What will happen is the first string would be read as a path, and the second would be taking...
So the program here will understand that this is an argument of one and this is an argument of two and this
argument of three.
So this is now wrong. To pass a path,
or even a complete string,
You have to pass a double-quote for it from beginning to end. This way, the command line will know that
this is one complete string.
So this way, it will figure out the spaces. That's all.
Let's make a small demo.
So here is the eclipse program.
We learned already how to pass the arguments from the command line.
I would like to show you also how to run them from the eclipse itself.
If you
right
click here, and go to the run as (we usually click this guy or this button
but there is also something here called run configuration)
You click it when you go to the run configuration, you will find a lot of C++ configuration that you can
increment one or remove one and so on.
So this is the configuration of my program.
This first time for us to come here.
You will notice here we have the program name.
You can browse it here and you can find it from a project.
You will notice we have the build configuration here,
I'm using debug as an active one.
Now, this step is what we care about it,
It has the argument. As you see here, I put hello world and I put three
other integers. The environment is another important tab that we use it in real life.
If we would like to add something to the environment. Now, as you see here, the argument is well configured
for us here.
So let's run.
If we ran it, we see it
gives hello world and 20. The other extra things don't matter here in our program.
So this is how to handle in eclipse. In code blocks,
here is the same program, you go to Project, set program arguments, and then you select which profile you
would like to use.
So here in the debug I have hello world 20, 30, 40,
then again, you can just run the program here, and then you will have both of them here.
That's it.