Hi
So in this lecture, we're going to talk about big integers and how you can solve problems involving
big integers.
Firstly, we will see what is the meaning of big integer and then later on we will see what are the different
solutions provided by programming languages like C++, Java and Python.
OK?
So, In all of them.
There is a slightly different way of working with big integers.
The Java provides a big integer class, in C++
you have to use arrays to simulate operations on big integers and in Python they are handle like default
integers.
So we will dive deep into it.
But first of all, let us try to understand what is the meaning of big integer.
OK?
What is a big integer. So right now that we have learned is in order to store integers we have in C++ or int C
we have the data types like int or we have long long int. ok. these data types have
So when you create a variable using this datatype, it creates a box inside the memory of fixed size.
Let's say with int it is, let's say four bytes.
Or you can say it is 32 bits.
OK, let's say it is 64 bit box.
That means the maximum number of bits that can be stored inside this long long is limited.
And if you talk about unsigned long long, the largest number that you can form is of the order
two raise to the power 64 minus one.
And in this case, it is of the order two raise to the power 32 minus one. ok. so if you set all the bits
as one and if it is a unsigned int then this is the largest number that you can form.
Now, in terms of
decimal, it is of the order 10 power nine and it is of the order 10 power 18. OK. approximately.
That means if a number has more than 18 digits, it cannot be stored inside long long int.
That means that number is a big integer. it cannot fit in the primitive or the predefined data types.
Then how do we store such number. okay. so that means maximum an integer can have up to 18 digits.
It cannot have a number which is greater than 18 digit and that can be stored inside these data type.
for those problems in which you can get very large numbers.
We have to do certain operations like additions, subtraction multiplication division. so your regular
data types will not work.
Then we call those numbers as big integers.
And how do we store those numbers. OK?
So ultimately, we don't have a box which is greater than 8 byte and the memory required
The space required to store that particular number. let's say hundreds of digits, ok hundreds of
digits.
We can answer that number directly. ok. So one option to store that number is a array.
OK, for example if you want to store a very large number, what you can do?
You can say, OK. I'll create a array and I will store this numbered digit by digit. OK?
So  maybe five, three, eight, seven, six, two and so on.
OK. maybe you can create a very large array and each box of the array represents a digit of that particular
number.
OK.
Another option could be string. strings also a character array.
You can also use a character array to or String datatype to store that particular number. maybe five
three six two four eight nine seven one zero five two. whatever it is.
So these are the two options that we can clearly use to store those particular numbers, which are very
large.
But now the question is how do we perform various operations. such as addition on this particular string
or on this particular character array?
That means we need to come up with an algorithm.
OK.
like we do it on a notebook, a similar kind of technique.
We need to come up and implement that addition operation on this array or on a string.
so this is going to be a our first problem.
We are going to give two big integers.
We are going to take input and we are going to add them.
So let's see how we can solve this problem in the next lecture.
OK.
So that's all for this video and in this section will be solving more questions like big multiplication
and the Java big integer class and working with bigger integer in python.
So stay tuned.