Hi Everyone, so let us build our first algorithm involving big integers.
So The problem that we are going to solve is larger addition that we are given to large numbers and we
need to add them.
So this is what we need to do.
So given to large numbers, the numbers may not fit into long long int hence the task is to add
these numbers OK.
So that means we cannot say. OK, we take input and we will just output the number A+B.
OK.
This will not work because the numbers are very large and they are not going to fit inside long long int.
So maybe one option to take input these numbers as strings and we can write an algorithm that adds
two large strings and those strings must be treated as numbers.
So let us look at one example.
So let's say we have a number one which is I'm going to take it as a small number. let's say N1,
which is let's say 938. OK. because the algorithm will also work for small numbers. OK?
And let's say N2 is 65.
So let us see how do we do this addition on pen and paper and how we can convert this into a very simple
addition algorithm.
So we have 938. OK. and we have 65 and this is how you do an addition.
So you say 8 and five 13. one carry.
This becomes ten. one carry. nine and one is also 10.
so you put zero here and one comes here.
ok. so what you can see is when you're doing additions. OK?
If you treat this thing kind of array. OK. if this thing is a array and if this thing is also array then
it may happen that you have carry. ok.
you have a carry.
And this final result may expand on the left.
OK. but in array we know that if if this index is zero. OK. if this is zero, this is one.
this is two or if this is zero, this is one, this is two.
You cannot expand on the left side of this particular array. ok so what we can do is what we may have
a array which may have a lot of space on the right.
OK.
So when we're filling this array, we're filling in the left or right fashion and we don't know how much
space we would need.
So we we generally fill the array in the left to right fashion.
So what you can do is, if you want to build this addition algorithm on an array and you want to do the
filling from left to right. OK. because this digit may not fit inside the output array. what you can
do is, you can actually reverse these two numbers and then you can start addition from left to right.
OK?
So one thing we can do is, we can fix.
OK. one of the numbers is 938, so will reverse it.
So we will say. OK. we have.
What? we have what? we have 65.
So we reverse it.
It is written like this 56 and we have nine three eight.
So again, we are going to reverse it.
It is going to be eight, three and nine.
OK.
So this is your array one.
And this is your array two.
And maybe your output array is is a little bigger array.
And you have reserved little more space in that.
OK.
So this is array1.
This is your output array.
so What you can do is,
Let me just tell you. you can start adding from left to right.
In a similar manner.
OK. so you can say OK, let us go to the zeroth index and add the two numbers.
So we are at zero.
It becomes eight plus five.
The sum is 13.
What we do? we put sum mode
10.
We just want to put the digit that is sum mode ten here. ok. sum modules 10.
so three will be stored here.
ok. and this would be copied in the array of I. ok. so instead of writing digit.
I can say in the output of I, just put this value and for the next position generate a carry.
OK, by default the carry is zero. for the next position the carry is going to be
What?
sum by ten. ok. sum by ten.
So 13 by 10, the carry is what?
This is going to be carry. ok. so carry is what? carry is equal to sum by 10.
so carry is sum by 10.
That means you are going to add one here so at this point, what you're going to do? you're going
to add the Ith number, Ith digit from N1, the number one and the Ith digit from number two.
And the carry, so it becomes six plus three
plus one which is ten.
OK.
Again. now you have the sum as 10. you put zero here and you put one as the carry. OK.
sum divided by 10. so one will go as a carry for the next position.
This position, what you can see is that the number N1
is finished.
We don't have anything from here.
The number N2 still has the number of digits.
So what we will do ? we will just add carry and the digits from two.
So that means we'll add nine plus one that is 10.
Again, the the sum is ten. we will put what? will put zero here and we will make...
We'll make forward
carry has one.
So at this point, the number N2 is also finished and the number N1 is also finished and we can
check if the carry has some value.
So the carry can be either zero or it can be one because when you are going to add three digits.
OK, so the largest number it could be nine plus nine plus one. ok the largest digit can be nine.
the largest digit can be nine.
And the largest carry would be one.
OK. so if this carry is one then what you're going to do? you're going to put a one here and this
is what is going to happen in your output array.
And finally, you're going to reverse.
You are going to reverse this result.
OK.
And in order to get the final answer you will reverse it and the final answer would be one zero zero.
This is the very simple addition algorithm that we are going to see. Now
one thing that may happen is, there are three special cases.
So first cases when the number N1 is finished. OK?
The case one, when N1 is finished
we will not add digits from N1.
case 2 is when N2 is also finished.
We will handle the case of carry separately.
OK.
These are the two cases that we need to see.
And case three is when N2 is finished.
We just need to look at what is the value of carry.
Now it may happen is, sometimes you might get a number like 56 and one three eight zero or
maybe you may get one three eight zero followed by 56.OK.
In order to just make our work easier, we will assume that the second number is always the largest.
OK. that means if you have two numbers A and B. you will always make sure the second number is largest.
This will actually help us in building the algorithm and not looking at the case when you have second
number as a smaller number.
ok So this is a case you can swap them.
You can just swap the numbers.
OK. so if it is A comma B, you make it B comma A. OK. this will we will see while writing the code
that, it is going to be helpful because we do not need to put the conditions on both the numbers.
OK, so just to simplify the algorithm, we will do a swapping.
If number two is smaller than number one. we will make sure that the larger number is always coming to the bottom.
OK?
So that we can look at ok. when this number is finished, we can only work with this number.
OK.
So this is the idea of swapping the two numbers so that the largest number is at the bottom
or you can keep at the top as well.
ok that's also perfectly fine.
So I hope you got an idea about the algorithm.
In the next video, we will see the implementation of addition.