So we have already seen the algorithm to do addition
and now what we are going to do? we are going to build that algorithm in the code.
So let's see how we can go about the algorithm.
So first of all, what we will do? we will take input two numbers and then we will write algorithm. OK?
So since they are big integers, we cannot take them input as
a integer, we can take input them as a string.
OK.
So i can say
I have a string S1 and strings S2. then I can read those strings cin S1 and S2.
All right.
And maybe I want to output my result inside a string array.
Or I can say there is a method
Add numbers. S1 and S2.
So this method is going to return a string.
So let's create this method.
So I need to create string add numbers.
I get string N1 number one and string number two.
That's what we have.
And we can compare these two numbers to make sure that N2 is larger.  N2 has more number of digits.
we will keep it at bottom.
So if N1 dot length is
greater than n2 dot length.
We can say  ok. let us just swap these two objects N1 and N2. and that's what we do.
And here we will form the result.
So result is there is a empty string in the beginning and every time we are doing addition. for example,
we have let's say, 56 and three zero four five.
What we will do? we will say five plus three is eight.
OK.
And in this case, the digit is eight. we will put here.
So we will what we will do? we will push this inside the result array. we will push this inside the result array.ok.
And this number should be actually 65.
OK.
If the number is 65, we will first reverse it.
And the another number is four
Five zero three.
OK. these are the two numbers and after everything I've written in the left to right order.
OK. so that I can do additions from the left. OK. we can do additions from left to right so that
any carry that is generated can be easily appended on the right of the particular string.
OK. so this is how we are going to build it.
So what we can do is, we can
Since we have assumed that
our N1 is smaller.
Okay, so first thing is we need to reverse the numbers as well. so I can say, I can use the inbuilt
reverse function and N1 dot begin to N1 dot end. So this is going to reverse my entire number.
OK.
So it's a function that is available in the algorithm header file. N2 dot end.
All right.
And now what we can do is, we can add digits. OK. up to N1.length because N1 is a smaller
number. OK. so that means we will iterate
only till this particular part and we will say OK, what is the output after adding these two and
whatever it is carry is generated, we will start adding it to another number that is N2.
Ok. so this is N1. this is N2.
So I can say int I equal to zero, I less then N1.lenght because it is the smaller number. I++.
.
So we know what is the digit.
So this digit, we need to extract.
So it's a character. Ok. it's a character. so I an say int digit one.
So maybe I can make a function character to digit.
So I want to convert this character into digit and I given, I can give N1 of I. int digit2 I can say char to digit
of N2 of I.
I get the second digit from here.
I want an integer.
OK, so this char to digit we need to define, how do we convert char into digit.
It's pretty easy.
So let's make a method that accepts the character and it returns the integer value of that. OK?
So for example, if you have a character like five. if you subtract zero as a character. OK. maybe
it has ASCII below 45.
It has ASCII 40.
If you do the subtraction, it is going to give you five as a integer. OK?
so I can say return ch minus zero.
So you subtract something
You subtract actually... actually zero to get the corresponding integer value. OK?
Similarly, if you want to do the other thing, if you want to convert a digit to a char. for example,
if you give int digit equal to five and if you add a zero as a character here and you you typecast this
into a character then
It is going to get converted into a character. so maybe you can say return digit plus zero.
So let me let me tell you, if you're not clear how this works.
Zero has certain ASCII value. OK. maybe let's say this ASCII value is 40.
I don't remember the exact number but let us assume it is 40.
So if you add a five to it, it becomes 40 plus five.
That is 45.
And since we are typecasting this into a character, it would be interpreted as this particular five.
because all these characters, they have ASCII values in a particular series. OK?
So if it is 40, then it is 41.
It is 42.
It is 43.
It is 44.
and so on. ok.
So something like this.
So I hope you are getting this conversion.
OK. so now we have, we know what is the first digit from the first number.
What is a digit from the second number.
What we need is? we need to find out the sum.
So for sum
we should also know what is the carry.
So in the beginning, the carry is zero.
OK.
So I can say the sum is nothing but D1 plus D2 plus carry.
And in the output
OK, in the output, so output digit that we want to store is nothing but sum modules 10.
and the carry would be nothing but sum divided by 10.
sum divided by 10.
And now we have to store the output inside the result string.
So the result is a string. so we can use the push back method to push something in the result. OK.
So to push a character inside our result.
For example, if it is let's say 56 and let's say three zero five.
So five plus three is eight.
So by default the carry is zero.
OK.
So we are converting this five and eight into integer.
This is five.
This is three.
This carry is five plus three plus zero.
This is eight.
So your result...
Your carry is going to be sum divided by 10.
So carry is going to be zero and result dot push back.
So what should come here, it should be 8. OK.
So I can say I will use this method.
I have a digit eight. I want to convert into character.
And this is nothing but output digit.
So output digit is 8.
ok.
In the next iteration, we will go here.
The carry is zero.
It becomes six plus zero.
So we will push what? we will push six here and we are done. OK.
So we'll stop at this particular point because we have reached the length of the smaller string.
Now we have this left. OK. maybe some more digits which are left here. So whatever carry has been generated
will be added to this number.
OK?
What I can say is, I'll put another loop.
I'll put another loop for this part. for int I equal to starting from this particular point.
N1 dot lenght.
OK.
I less than N2.lenght.
I + +.
So what I will do? I say OK, my sum is nothing but I need the digit D2. OK so my digit
D2 is nothing but char to digit of N2 of I.
So The sum is nothing but D2 plus carry and similar thing will come here, so I can say output digit
would be nothing but
sum divided, sum modules 10 and my carry would be nothing but sum divided by 10.
OK.
And in my result, I can push back.
What? I can push back Digit to char of output digit. OK.
This is what we do.
So we have done a similar thing.
Instead of adding to numbers, we have just worked on the second number.
And if there is a carry which is coming from behind, we have handled that as well.
ok.
So this will serve the purpose for the second part.
OK, one last thing is left.
OK, so finally, if a carry is generated. OK. Carry is generated.
For example, if I give you this example of 938
Or maybe 988 or let's say 938 plus 65.
OK. how we are going to handle it. we are going to reverse it 839 followed by 65. 65 is like five
six.
We are going to add it. 8 and 5 is 13. one carry. six and three is nine and one 10. one carry.
Now this is done using this loop.
OK.
Nine plus one.
OK, we are iterating from N1.length. from here till here.
Nine plus one is what? ten. So this is done using the second for loop.
and now again, finally what we have? we will have carry
OK. nine plus one is 10.
And if there is a carry, we will append a one here. finally if the carry is left, I can say result
dot push back.
What? one. or one like a character.
Now you may ask why, why we are hard coding one because the largest value of the carry can be only
one in this particular case.
OK. so the maximum digits that you might be adding is nine plus nine plus one that end up to 19.
That means the carrier would be either zero or it would be one.
so if it is not zero then it must be one.
Or either you can write it like this.
or you can say OK. digit to char.
So this will work perfectly fine. OK?
And finally, what we can do is, we can reverse the final result.
so I can say reverse result.begin() to result.end().
and I can return result.
So now let us test our code.
OK.
And
Let's go here
and I can say dot slash big addition.
Oh, OK. I need to build the code first.
And I need to run it.
So maybe I give one zero or maybe let us try with small numbers.
938 and 65.
ok. we get one zero zero three. which is fine if I get a lot of
big number. ok.
OK, it's working fine.
so one thing we can do is, we can
do with integers also and see the difference
what happens if you add big number into a integer. OK. I'm going to give the same numbers as integer
also.
Let's say we have
One one one one one.
And may be two two two two two.
OK.
And maybe we can copy the same
here as well.
Now you can see this is the integer.
This is
handle using string and this is handle using integer. OK.
You're storing them as integer and you're adding them.
So what you're getting is, you're getting a very small number because this number was not able to fit
inside a integer box and hence there was an overflow which made the number as negative.
Ok. so that's why this will give you a wrong answer and this addition will give you the correct answer.
OK.
So I hope you really understood how to perform addition on big integers.
And this is the algorithm that we have written and it's pretty much simple. although it's a bit
a lot of code but I hope you really understood the algorithm.
OK, so that's all for this lecture.