Hi Everyone, so let us move on to the next problem that is about computing a large factorial. ok.
So in this problem we are given
integer.so the input is not a big integer.
It would be a a normal integer but the output that we want to produce that is the factorial of this
particular number.
It may be very large and may not fit inside into integer. for example, 100 factorial. OK.
So this is the value of hundred factorial and you see it is a very large. it cannot fit into a long
long or something like that.
OK.
So what we need is, we need to look how we can do multiplication.
OK?
And again we need to come up with an algorithm for multiplication and we will store all these digits
inside a array.
ok. we will use a array.
Each index of the array will store one digit and let's see how we can build this particular output.
So first of all, we need to know what a factorial is. so if you want to compute five factorial then it
does nothing but five multiplied by four factorial. ok. what we will do? we will compute the answer to this
particular point.
Again, using repeated multiplication. and let us say this answer is 24 and will multiply this with
five.
What we need is, we need this again would be computed  multiplying one into two, the into into three this into four.
So we need to see how we can perform multiplication between two numbers.
So let's say we have a larger number on this side, a smaller number on this side.
So first of all we'll write this. OK.
The pen and paper method. how how we do it. we say OK.
Five multiplied by four is 20.
we say 2 carry. 5 into 2 is ten.
plus 2 is 12. we put two and we put one carry
and this one will come here. OK?
so this answer is 120.
Again you can see we are building this in the right to left order
but since we are storing this inside a area. the array can be built in the left to right order. ok. the array should
be build in a left to right order. because in an array we have vacant space on the right.
So any additional digit like this one
they can be easily accommodated on the right side.
so What we will do? we will reverse this number. we will reverse this. we will write four and two here and we will multiply that with
five.
OK.
And let's see this output is being stored inside a array.
Ok. we we have a large array here.
we say five into four.
That is 20.
So we'll multiply this number with this digit. so five into four is 20. we have
this number. We extract this digit by doing. OK, whatever the product mod 10 that would be stored here.
So zero comes here and two gets carry. two gets carried  of. five into two is 10. 10 plus carry
that is equal to 12.
so what we do? we put two here and whatever is left, it gets carried of.
And since we don't have anything here this Kerry would be put here.
So you can see this answer is also 120.
The only thing is you need to reverse the array to read this answer. So if you reverse it, you get 120
as the answer.
OK?
So let us look at one more example of doing multiplication.
OK, so let's say
the number is 922. OK and we want to multiply it with 15.
So how we're going to do it? Now in this case, you have a bigger number here.
It's not one digit it's two digit.
So let me tell you, how we're going to multiply this number.
So we have 922, which is again an integer.
So we reverse this.
It becomes 229. OK and we have 15 here. OK?
And we are going to do multiplication.
So in this case, I've only reversed this number and not reversed this number.
This number is as it is.
So we'll multiply.
This digit. ok. This digit.
so this is inside a array because the result of multiplication is going to be large.
So this is going to be kept inside a array.
OK.
This could be a bigger number as well.
And the result would be stored here.
OK.
The result would be stored here.
Now
because when you're doing something like this. one  two two into three into four into five into
six into seven into into, let's say 15 or whatever, then this result would be very big.
but this number would be small.
So this we will store inside a array.
and this we will store this inside a int.
OK. so this is what it is.
So 15 into two.
It is what? it is 13. we put zero. three gets carried of. 15 into two is 30. 30 plus 3 is 33.
We have three. three gets carried of. 15 into nine is what?
135. so what
we have? 135 plus the carry
That is 138.
OK, what we put here? we put 8 here and what's
gets carried of.
13 gets carried of.
OK.
get carried of.
So how do we accommodate 13?
We say OK. while this number is not
zero.
We extract one digit out of it.
We put that digit here and we reduce it by a factor of 10.
OK. so this number now becomes one. extract the last digit put it here and we reduce it by a factor
of 10.
So this becomes zero.
so the final answer that we are able to look at is we are going to reverse this.
OK?
And after reversing this, we will see it as nothing but one three eight three zero.
OK.
I have a terminal shall open.
So one three eight one three zero.
This is the output.
OK.
If I show you the multiplication here. so 922 if I do 922 into 15, it is giving me an answer
of one three eight three zero which is same as this one.
So this output would be stored inside a array.
OK.
This concept of multiplication explains how you can multiply a large number which is stored inside a array
with a particular integer.
And we are going to use this concept to compute factorial of a number.
Ok. so all we would need is, we will need is to
OK. so what we will need is, we will need to write a method that multiplies array with a particular number.
OK?
So if we have this method, multiply
an array with a particular number then very easily we can calculate our factorial by reading a
loop for I equal to one, I less than equal to N, I++. whatever array you have
you multiply it with that particular I.
OK.
And yes, this is how we're going to compute the factorial. so let's see the code in the next lecture.
And that's all.