Hi everyone, so let us write the code for computing big factorial in this lecture.
So first of all, I'll write the main. In which we are just going to take input something.
OK, so we have in integer N. we'll take that as input and may be we will do write a function that computes
the Big Factorial. OK.
Or the factorial of N.
OK, so now we need to compute this.
write this method. void big factorial.
We get a value N. So what we discuss is
we will create an array and in that array we will try to store the output of each multiplication that we are going
to do.
OK, so first of all, we can create a array or we can also either use a vector or we can create a
array. both are fine.
I'm creating a vector of size let's say 1000 and it is initialized with values zero.
So that means I'm assuming in my output, I will not have more than 1000 digits. OK?
So
OK. so either I can use pushback to expand this Victor but right now I'm assuming that I won't
have more than a thousand digits.
So this you will know from the constraints given in the question because I'm just reserving the space
of one thousand and each of it is initialized with a value of zero. ok.
In the beginning, I will initialize the answer for one factorial. that is going to be one
so I can say A of zero is one.
And another thing I will need to know is what is the actual size of the output?
Okay, so if you reverse this it might be
So you will also store up to what position we should print the output.
OK, so we should only print the output before index one. ok so I will note what is the size of the output
that has been generated so far.
The size of the output is one.
Okay, so maybe I'll take a variable int size that is equal to one.
OK, now from two onwards for int i equal to two. I less than equal to whatever it is my number or whatever
is my N.
What I need to do? I need to multiply.
OK, I need to multiply my array.
OK, I need to multiply my array
With a number I.
And I also need to tell
up to what size we have stored the answer. OK. so as we multiplied with two, it will become two.
Then we multiply it with three, it will become six.
then it will multiply with 4.
It will become 24, so once it becomes 24.
The size is going to become two.
OK, then we multiply it with five.
The size is going to become five.
OK, so 24 would be stored like this.
OK?
Then multiply it with five.
It becomes 120.
OK?
So 120, 120 would be stored like this. size would become three.
So inside this multiplication function we need to update the size as well.
So this is the main function that we need to write.
And once we're done, we we need to print
the result in the reverse order. OK?
That means starting from size minus one.
to Index Zero.
That's what we need to print.
So first of all, we are going to write the multiply method. so void multiply, it accept a vector.
OK, and it must be passed by reference because we are going to modify in the same vector and it is
also going to accept the value I. The number which we are going to multiply.
OK.
And we are also passing the size
the size is also being passed by the reference because we are going to update this particular size.
OK. OK or you can return the size as a integer from this method and you can take it here. that is also
fine
but let's see how we are going to do it.
So when we are doing the multiplication again, we would have some carry and we would have
something else as well. So for int I  equal to zero. I less then what?
I less than size. I plus plus.
So let me tell you for example, if your number is what? if your number is nine two two multiplied by 15
so we discussed it would be stored in the array like this.
two two nine and it will be multiplied with 15.
OK, so it is stored in the reverse order.
SO the size of this is what? size is three.
We are going to iterate from zero one two.
We are going to iterate from zero less than size.
Yes.
So first of all, we will form a product between these two. 15 into two.
So we'll say, OK. this product is nothing but array of I multiplied with number plus whatever carry we have.
So in the beginning the carry is zero.
And now from this, we need to extract a digit.
Ok. so your digit would be stored in array of I again. array of I would store product Modules 10.
OK, so we are going to overwrite.
OK, we are actually going to overwrite this array
At the same time. So this two becomes now zero. 15 twos are 30.
And three gets carried.
carry is three.
into two is 30 plus 3.
next iteration. ok.
So carry is nothing but carry is what? product by 10.
So for the next iteration, we know what is the carry and we are already updating the results.
So we put
33. so three gets carried. 15 into nine is 135 plus three. 138.
And what we have is, this addition is over.
And finally, we are left with a carry that is what? carry is this divided by ten.
So does this 13..
So this is left.
OK, so to handle the carry, we need a separate loop.
So I can say while this carry is not zero, so I can say starting from what? array of size, what you
will put inside array of size? we are going to put carry model size.
OK. so array of size is this index, we are putting what? 13 models 10. we are putting three here. OK. and
we are going to reduce this carry by dividing it by ten.
Ok, so we can say carry equals carry by ten
And and since we are actually using extra space here now we are in incrementing.
We should increment the value of size.
OK, the size should move to the next index. so I can say size equal to size plus one.
All right.
And finally, when we're going to return.
We are going to put one here.
This size is going to move to the next index.
Size will come to the five index.
And it also tells us that OK. inside your array the output is stored up to five positions. OK?
The output is like one three eight three zero.
All right.
And this correctly updates the size.
So what we need is, finally we need to print the result. so I can say for
either you convert this into a string or then return or simply print the output. that is also
fine.
I greater equal to zero.
And I do I minus minus.
And I can say cout. array of I and that's it.
And finally, we can say cout endl.
OK.
We should include
vector.
And you can see build is successful.
Now we're ready to test our code.
So if I say dot Slash Big Factorial. I give five.
I get 120.
If I say if the input is 100 then you can compare that this answer must be
same as this one.
OK.
Nine three three two six two one.
So here nine three three two six two one and forward by lots of zeros in the end.
So you can see this actually
looks correct and this is how we can do a multiplication between a big integer and a number.
And this is how we can compute big factorials in C++.
So I hope you understood the concept of basic addition and multiplication.
and we will see some more things in the next lecture.