Hi Everyone, In this lecture, we're going to talk about the Java big integer class and this is a
good thing about Java that it provides us in build class that works on very large integers. OK?
So.
We will see how to use this class and how if you are programming using Java, how you can solve problems
involving big integers very easily.
So this class provides various actions to be performed on big integers.
Some of these actions are like more automatic like addition, multiplication, modules, base conversion.
ok you want to convert a number from base 10 to base two or from base two to be a 16 or
16 to base eight.
So you can convert any large number from one base to another base.
Third is power a calculation. you want to do a big integer A raise to the power B.
You can do it easily.
It also supports bitwise operators on
large numbers and there are also methods to find out whether a number is prime or what is an ex prime
and so on.
What I would recommend do, so in this one tutorial we won't be feasible to cover all of these methods
if needed
you can go and look at the Oracle documentation of this class and you will see there are lot of methods.
For example, one of the methods next probably prime.
OK. so it returns the first integer that is greater than this big integer and that is probably
prime.
And you can see there are a lot, lot of lot of functions. so there is a method to strings which convert
this big integer into a string representation of that. there is a method value of which returns
big integers whose value is equal to the specified long.
So you can also convert an integer into a big integer.
So we will see how to use some of these methods.
And there is a constructer which
provides a way to construct a big integer object. okay. so when we're dealing with Java.
OK, so the data that we store in variables.
This these variables can be of two types.
One is primitives. for example, a variable like int. or  another thing you can have is objects.
Or you have object references. ok. when you're using
when you're creating objects to store... store your data and the syntax that you need to remember is
for primitives you you do it simply like int x equals to 10.  for objects
What do we do?
For example, you want to create a paintbrush object. so you will look paintbrush B.
This is equal to new paint brush.
The paintbrush is a class that is predefined or that is user defined as well.
In our case, we would, we would be creating a big integer, so we would be writing big integer
My integer or whatever we want. this is equal to new big integer.
Now, what is the advantage of creating this object is that
So here we are creating a big integer object and this is the object reference that is storing
the address of that is referring to that object. ok.
So whenever you create object like the big integer object. so this all comes with certain methods.
If I give you an example from the documentation, one of the method we just saw is next probable prime.
OK.
What we would be doing? we would be using these methods on the big integer objects to do our work
and so on.
Let us jump into the code and look at the exact demo.
How to you use this?
And in order to use this class, you have to import this statement.
java.math.BigInteger.
So let's jump into the code and then we'll see.
The firstly will make an import. Import
Java.math.BigInteger. ok.
Now let us try to create some big integer object.
There are multiple ways.
OK. so one ways to contract this big integer from a string representation. OK?
So for example, if I say a big integer B1.
This is equal to new big integer. and I give let's say five as a string.
And I can say ok. it as system.out.println and I print this B1. So print, print method already
knows how to print big integer and it would print the number five.
So we get the output five.
OK, or what we can do, we can also say I want to convert.
I want to read another string but as a different base.
For example, I'm defining the number one zero one one and I specify the base.
OK, so
this redix is the base, so we defined one value as a string, another is the base.
It translates the string representation of big integer  in the specified radix into
big integer. so I say ok. read this number as a base two number.
So what would be the value of this number?
Let us see.
So let's see the output.
Clearly, we know that this number is nothing but if this number is written in base two then this it
presents to power zero, two Power one, two Square and two cube.
So you add eight plus zero plus two plus one, this number is nothing but 11.
And that is what we get.
Exactly here.
SO that means this is another way of creating the big integer object.
Similarly, you can try out other ways as well.
but now I will jump into how do you take input. ok. So in java in order to take input
First, we need a scanner object, so we will create a scanner and we'll say.ok.
We have new scanners and this is capable of reading from the standard keyboard input.
And now this scan object has various methods.
OK.
So one thing you can do is, you can read it as a string and then you can convert it into a big integer.
Or you can directly say that, OK I want to read the next big integer.
So I can say ok big integer B3 equals sc.next
next big integer. ok.
We call this method and maybe I want to specify some value, which is a very large value. let's say
one two three one two three one two three four five six four five six four five six four five six four
five six seven eight nine. let's say.
So clearly it has having more than 18 digits which is beyond the range of long as well.
I can say OK. we will read this as an input from the user and maybe I want to print this value. so
I can the sytem.out.println and  I can say ok. print this big integer.
So I get the same output. OK. Now I suppose I want to do an addition. OK. maybe I want to do an addition.
So let's look at the method.
What is the method available to add?
OK.
There is a method add.
So what happens
you call this method add on a big integer object and you supply a value that needs to be added and
it returns a big integer whose value is the current object value plus the value that you supply.
ok, for example I say OK. I want to add something to the B3.
So I can say B3.add and I need to give another big integer that is B1.
And this is now going to return a new big integer. Either you update it into a new object.
let's say B4.
You can do it in the same object like
B3 equals B3.add(B1).
.
In this case, the result would be returned and it would be stored in a new big integer object B4.
And may be I can say system.out.printl
and I print the result B4.
So you can see
You can see  eighty nine plus five is 94 and hence we are getting this result. similarly you
can do it for multiplication and all. may be let us look at one of the methods for working with bit.
there is a method bit count.
OK.
It returns the number of bits.
that differ from its sign bit. so maybe let us look at this method.
So a bit different from sign bit.
So let me
take this number let say B2. OK. let me take this number B2. so B2 is a positive number
so the number of bits, positive number would have zero as a sign bit
and that means how many Brits are there which are  different from zero.
So they're actually three bits. I can say okay
system.out.println.
And I can say B2.bitcount.
B2.countBit().
It is count bits. yes it is bit count actually.
It is B2.bitcount.
So if you use intelligence, you would automatically get suggestion
what methods are available.
So we have three bits which are different from the sign bit.
OK.
And you can also convert an integer into a big integer.
For example, let's say I have a number.
Int to BigInt. let's say I want to maybe calculate factorial and I want to initialize my initial number
as one.
Let's say. but I want this one to be converted into a big integer so I can say ok. big integer one
this is equal to big integer dot value of.
And here I give the number. OK.
So whatever is the number that is int or long that would be converted into a big integer.
And I can say one.
This will give me the big integer object corresponding to the value one.
There are also a few other ways to initialize some common constant. for example.
If you look.
This. ok. so there are...
there is bigInteger.zero. there is bigInteger.one. there is BigInteger.ten.
So you can also create this one.
By using this statement. So big integer with value one. So you can say ok big integer
One.
Or maybe one one like this.
This is equal to big integer.one.
So it also creates a big integer one object OK. So  this number can be any number, this could
be 56.
And you can say ok. a Num and this could be num and this could be one.
And.
You can say ok. system.out.println and one.
OK.
In this case, you're converting this number 56 into a bit integer  object on which you can do a
lot of operations.
And here is another way of creating big integer one objects.
So this is applicable for one zero and ten. you can use this syntax as well. right?
Let us look at some other mathematical operation like you want to do.
Let's the power of two big numbers. OK?
So maybe we have
Some number. let's say
big integer A that is Bit integer dot value of
let's say I  want to do five raise to the power. let's say.
Six. big integer B that is big integer 6.
and I want to do A raise to the power B.
So now one thing to note is, if you look at the power method. So it accept integer as exponent. Okay. so
we should we do not need a B.
So you can do big integer raise to the power some integer. So you can say ok system.out.println.
.
And here you can say ok.
A.powerof(6).
This will give me a new big integer. which is five raise to the power six. which is one five six
two five.
OK, what is five power five?
It is three one two five. OK. which is fine.
That means it is working perfectly fine.
There are also the mathematical methods like gcd.ok.
so suppose you want to system.out.println
And maybe you want to find gcd of
the number A
which is the number numb. you can say
num.gcd
And maybe you want to do the if gcd with
Let's say
Number 11. right?
So that number 11 is what? that is B2.
So you can say ok. with the number B2.
So 56 and gcd of 11 and 56. So that should be one.
Yes, we are getting the gcd as one.
Similarly, you can explore all other methods that available by yourself and use this class as per the requirement.
Now why we discussed this big integer? even the people who are coding in C++, if you are getting a
problem which clearly involves the use of big integers. either use Python or Java because the inbuilt
libraries are going to save a lot of time of yours. OK?
If you want to save time, especially for the big integer problems. you should be using either Python
or Java.
Because if you start coding this functionality from the very ground up, you will end up wasting a lot
of hours and your time might get over. ok.
So that's all for this video.
Thank you.