Hi. So you have seen how to use the big integer  class in Java and now in this lecture will solve
one problem that is the factorial problem using the big integer Java class.
OK. so let's see how we can write the code for the same.
So first of all, you need to make import.
So the big integer class is part of Java.math package.
So we have imported the class.
And now what we need to do? we will maybe take input
Some number.
OK.
So scanner sc equals to new scanner. system.in and we create a scanner object.
And using this object, we will take input.
So maybe I want to read input which is a integer. so I can say sc.nextInt.
All right.
And maybe we will define a method to compute the factorial. OK.
So this is going to be a static method because it's not associated with any particular object.
It's it's common across all object. ok. Static big integer factorial.
OK. return type is big integer and the method name is factorial and we are passing it as a integer N.
So in order to compute factorial we know the result would be stored inside a big integer class.
OK?
So you can say int result, this is not correct. why?
Because the result of a lot of multiplication is going to be a big integer. OK?
So you can initialize this result as one so you can say new big integer and you can give a string value
of one.
Or you can simply use the initialization using a constant that is big integer dot one.
So once we are done with this what we can do next is, we can say. Ok. for int I equals to two. I less
then equals N. I + +.  OK.
So why we're using integer here because n is an integer. OK, so anything that that is less than N
that would also be an integer. so I can say
the result should be multiplied with itself. Ok. so result equals result dot
not, not itself but with the current value of I.result dot multiply what?
So here you can see I is a integer.
Okay, you cannot write I because this multiplier expects a bigger integer. so you want to convert this
integer into a big integer and we saw for converting integer, the method is known as value of.
we convert I into a big integer and then we can multiply to big integer by having the first
object. calling it multiply method followed by the second number that you want to multiply and that
should be type casted into big integer.
OK?
So we can say return result.
That's it.
So now what we can do? we can verify our output by saying system dot out dot println.
and we can call factorial of N.
And so this println method already knows how to print a big integer.
So maybe if I give a small input five, it should give me the factorial.
OK.
If I give a large number like hundred, then also it should work.
So yes, you can see it's it's working. it's working and it's giving me the correct output.
So that's all for this lecture.
I hope you understood.