Hi So in this lecture, we're going to talk about big numbers in Python.
The best thing about Python is you actually don't need to do any extra work to work with big integers.
OK?
No extra work in Python.
But does that mean Python automatically handles big integers.
The answer is.
Yes.
So yes, if you have a number which is beyond the boundaries of integer. OK. so in Python, we do
not define data types explicitly.
If you have a number which let's say goes beyond the boundaries of int. let's say there is a 32 bit box.
ok. which store the integer in Python.
But suppose there is a number which is bigger than this boundary.
Then what happens? ok.
Internally the interpreter is going to check if indeed it is big enough that cannot fit inside a int type of a bucket.
Then it automatically uses an efficient array like representation to store that particular number.
OK?
So maybe internally it's going to use some kind of array.
Let's say we have a number, let's say one two three four and so on.
Lots of digits.
OK.
So does it.
Does it mean that OK, if we convert this into array, one box of the array or one cell of the array will store
one digit?
The answer is no.
OK.
Because this kind of representation will become inefficient because one box is of 32 bits and in order
to store just one digit we are just wasting too much of memory.
OK?
So what happened is, it will convert a bigger number. OK?
It will convert a bigger number into a base 32 number.
OK and then that number will be stored here. OK?
It will be treated as a base 32 number. so maybe you're storing a bigger number inside this something
like this. OK?
Five, six, seven, eight and so on.
So it's actually a bit of a complicated or bit of a efficient representation.
So I have a attached a doc. that you can read to understand how big integers are stored internally.
But for the programming part, you... you can simply work with them like regular integers.
OK, if, for example, if A is a number one one two two three three five and B is the number two three
five six seven eight nine 10 11 and so on.
And you want to multiply these two numbers so you can simply say print A into B.
And this will work as
expected. OK. so you get an output. OK?
You can also do. OK. I have this number.
I want to do A raise to the power of... A raise to the power B. so you can say A raise to the power B.
And it will give you the correct output. OK?
the only thing that will happen is, in some cases OK. when these two numbers are very big. ok. very
big that means right now it is also very big. OK?
You can see it is beyond the range of a 64 bit number.
The output is definitely needs a lot more bits to store store the answer.
OK.
But sometimes it is very, very, very big. In that case
the time taken to multiply them or the time taken to do the power will be a lot more.
And you might get a TLE but that kind of input is generally not expected because we didn't get
an output because the program timed out because of time limit exceeded OK.
So such multiplications
You will not.. or such power bomber operations you will not find or you will have a more time limit to execute
them. OK?
But the idea that I wanted to convey was you can simply work with big integers in Python without doing
any extra effort. OK?
For example, if you want to compute a factorial, you can write a method factorial that takes input
value N and you can say ok my result as one and you can say, for I in range.
One to N plus one.
OK. so this is this look will go from one till N. and you can say result equals result multiplied by
I.
And finally, you can return the result.
So let's return the result and let's call the factorial of 100.
And we want to print it. so we can print it.
So maybe I can just call it inside the main method
and it should work fine.
So you can see we are getting the 100 factorial as our answer.
And that's it.
That's how you can work with big integers in Python.
No extra effort.
Just the regular code and you're done.
All right.
So thank you for watching.
See you in the next video.