Hi Everyone. in this lecture, we're going to solve a challenge from the online platform that is a SPOJ.
And it's a very simple problem that deals with big integer operations.
So let us look at the problem statement and then we will try to solve it.
OK. so let's say. so the Julka is given by her teacher is the very simple puzzle.
There are two friends and they have 10 apples together.
OK.
And
one of the girls has two more apples than the other girl.
How many apples they have?
OK. so this is a simple example.
The actual question is here.
Let us first look at the example, then we will look at the problem. In the example it is given ok
one girl has
apple x, another girl has y number of apples.
The sum of the apples is 10.
That is X plus y it is 10 and the other girl has two more apples
then the first girl. So y is having X plus 2 apples.
So if effectively you can say. OK. Y it's nothing but x plus two so x plus x plus two.
This is 10.
That means 2X is equal to 10 minus two. eight.
It means X is nothing but eight by two
that is four. the value of X is four.
And what is the value of Y?
That is X plus two that is 10.
So you can see this is the number of apples the first girl has.
This is a number of apples the second girl has.
Now the question is let us make the problem a little more difficult instead of saying they have 10 apples,
so the teacher is trying to check that
If it increases the value of some of apples then whether they can solve it correctly or not. ok.
the teacher wants to continue asking the question but with big numbers. OK. so help the teacher to write
a program which will tell her the right answers. so what we are given?
So we are given
that X plus Y is now not 10 but it's a big number. OK?
And it is also given that the second girl has instead of having... ok.
So it is given that the second goal is having K more apples than the first girl.
OK, so if you go through the problem statement, you will get to know. In the input you're given
every test case consist of two lines.
The first says how many apples both the girls have.
The second line is how many more apples the second girls. OK and both are the positive integers and the value
of the integer is of the order 10 power 100.
But that means you cannot fit this number inside the regular integer.
you need a big integer. ok.
So every test case should output two lines. and first should contain the number of apples belonging to
the first girl. second should contain the number of apples belonging to the second girl.
All right, so this is what we have.
So let's see how we can approach this question now.
So if I say, it is given that OK. let us assume the first girl has x apples.
The second girl has Y number of apples.
It is given X plus y is what? X plus Y is what?
It's a big integer N. OK. and it is also given that Y is K more than X.
OK, so I can say x plus x plus k.
This is equal to N OK.
That means 2X plus K is equal to N.
And N and K is input. ok. the input is given. input is N and K.
And in the output, we need to find the values of X and Y. so we can simply say X is nothing but N minus
K by two.
All right.
And what would be the value of a Y. Y is nothing but x plus K.
OK.
So using this formula, we can find out values of both X and Y.
And what I would suggest is you try to write a program on your own, which works with big integers.
OK.
So what is what we are doing here?
We are doing a subtraction.
If you use Java, you can use the subtract method on the big integer object.
OK.
And here you are also doing a division, so you can use the divide method.
And one thing you need to notice if N and K are big integers then you can easily do subtraction.
But this two is an integer
So maybe you have to convert this to into a big integer object and then you have to divide it with two.
Okay. so you can say something like OK. let's create a big integer using this two.
Something like this.
So we will see in the next video, how you can write the code.
And this is what? this is nothing but addition operation.
You're again adding a big integer X with a big integer K. and you are done.
OK, so let's see the code in the next lecture.
But before that, I want you to try this problem on your own and try to submit it on SPOJ in Java.
OK?
That's all.
See you in the next video.