All right, so let us dive into the solution of the problem.
So first of all, I will start by taking input. OK?
In the problem, I'm given that there would be a certain number of test cases.
OK. so I will scan the inputs here.
OK.
And I would also create a few big integer object, so I need a big integer to store the value
of N and K.
Let's see.
We will take those as inputs.
SO I need to create a scanner object to read those inputs. so I can say system.in.
And also I have a number of test cases.
Okay, so if I go to the problem statement.
Let's look at how many test cases we need to take input.
So
OK.
We have
the number of test cases. we have actually hardcoded number of test cases there are 10 testcase. OK.
So what I will do? I will simply say OK. the number of test cases I have is 10 and I can say while
this test case is greater than zero, I will keep on solving this problem.
test equal testcase
Equals TC minus one.
So I will be doing this problem solving this problem for 10 testcases.
I'll read the value of N using SC dot next.
OK, so one thing is you can if you want to read something as a big integer, there is also a method
which scanner
that is SC dot next big integer.
You can use this method to directly read something as a integer. OK?
Otherwise, you have to read it as a string and then convert to big integer.
and K is also a sc dot next big integer. so we are directly reading that input as big integers.
And let's say we have a method which is known as solve and which solves for given value N and K. and it prints
the output.
So what I will do? I'll create this method
solve.
OK. I'll say static void
static void solve.
And here we are going to solve for big integer N and and big integer K.
OK, now we know that X plus Y is equal to N. so that means if sum of two numbers is a bigger integer,
then these two numbers would be also bigger integer.
OK. so what we can say is, we have a big integer X and we have a big integer Y.
And from the formula that we derived, we saw the value of X is what? The value of X is nothing but N
minus K divided by two.
This is what we have seen. so we can simply say X is nothing
but from the n you have to subtract the value of K, so you can say  N dot subtract K. OK. and
then you have to divide it with two.
So X is equal to X dot divide.
And you cannot say two because two is not a big integer.
And this divide method accepts a big integer, so you can convert this
integer into two like this and we are done.
And finally, Y is what?
Y is K more than x.
So Y is X plus k.
So you can say, the first object is X. call the add method and then give the K as a big integer.
So you can say X equals...sorry. Y equals x
dot add K and you're done.
And finally, you can say system dot out dot println and  you first give the value of Y and then you
give the value of X because in the output, the bigger number is expected first on SPOJ.
And it looks like we are done. just for now, I'm reducing the number of test cases to two. I can say,
Ok. I have two testcase. one is 10, one is 20 and it is let's say 2 and it is four.
So let's see, what output do we get?
OK.
We we forgot to import the big integer class from Java.math package.
We are done.
And let's see.
OK, six minus four.  11 and minus nine.
Uh.
Let me just verify what we are doing here.
So let's see the inputs.
What are the inputs?
We have 10 and 2.
10 and 2 is a input.
Ok. oh, we do not need to actually give the number of test cases
that is hard coded.
So let me look now.
So yes, we have six and four for ten and 12 and 8 for   20, which is fine and the difference between
two them is four and here the difference is two.
So it looks fine.
Now only thing is, I have to make the testcase as 10 and submit this code on SPOJ.
OK.
So let's submit it.
And let's see.
So you can see that our code got accepted and we are done with the julka problem.
I hope now you understand how to work with big integers while solving online challenges.
That's all for this video.
Thank you.