So far, we were learning how to make basic and simple statements. From now on, we are going to take
more steps in creating more and more complex programs.
So there is what we call in C++, the flow, like the if conditions and the for loops and so on.
So this this is like a step in a bigger journey.
Let's say that you want to write a program and the program is going to read the salary of someone an
integer
And then if the salary is less than one thousand, you are to print: you are poor.
Otherwise you do nothing.
If you thought about it for a while, you almost don't have tools in C++ so far to do that.
This is where C++ comes to tell you "if conditions". The if condition is something that says the following:
If there is something that is true, do something.
Otherwise, don't do anything.
Here is the logic of it.
But here is the syntax of it, let's say we are reading integer salary and then cin the salary.
So far, so good.
Check out what is inside these braces for now, salary less than one thousand.
Let's say that the person entered here.
Five hundred.
So is 500 less than 1000
The answer is yes.
So salary is less than one thousand is true.
So now this weird syntax is like if true.
Then there is a statement inside it.
OK, so the if condition goes as following, you write here if two parentheses and put a condition.
If this condition is true, this line would be executed, otherwise it would be ignored.
So let's try the program you entered five hundred, five hundred less than one thousand.
This is true.
If true, we go inside the condition we print "you are poor", then we print the word "salam" and we end the program on the other
the other side.
Let's say the person entered ten thousand so ten thousand less than one thousand.
This is false.
If false mean that the condition isn't satisfied, this line is going to be ignored.
So this only would be printed so that if condition allows us to decide if somebody's logic will be executed
or not.
OK, please read and double check that.
You understand that.
Now, what if I just don't want to print a single line of code?
What if I need something that's more complex?
So C++ allows you to use the braces; to use more logic.
So let's say I'm reading a number and I would like to do more logic if a number turns out to be ten.
So if number is ten and now open in two braces, all the logic that we are writing here now is executed
only if this condition is true.
So if I enter ten is going to print 10 is
lucky number, also ten times two plus three, which is twenty-three.
So now with if conditions, we get inside the body either one statement like in the previous code or much
more logic.
This is one very critical thing here.
Now that we are going to learn something called the "scope" and local variable, a local variable.
It is something that has a specific scope when we use braces here and define this integer here.
Can I come here and say cout << x the answer is no, why? because this X is visible only through these two
braces, only visible through these braces.
So this is what we call this variable local variable.
We later will know more about something called global variable, which can be defined here in line
three.
So what is inside
braces, is invisible outside it.
So this is the scope of a variable.
That's it for today.
But let's know about some common mistakes.
Let's say that you define that integer "age" for 45 and you would like to compare if age is 45
to five.
Say wow, 40 years ago, something like that.
This is the right way.
There are two common mistakes that happen.
The first that you write it this way: if age equals forty, now equals forty is an assignment, not a
comparison
or a relational operator.
So what happened here that age equal 40 is assigned to age.
So the first mistake is the original value change.
The second mistake is.
Age equals 40 ends up with 40, if here is going to be executed, it is going to be treated as true.
Why?
Because it is only false if the value is zero.
OK, so the second mistake is this is going to be executed like here.
If you said if age, this is going to be executed because the condition is true if it's a value not
zero.
So be careful about the assigning and the mistake that it causes.
That's it.
Please make sure to practice that before the next session.