Let's solve the second homework set, we would like to find the maximum of 10 values, we started something
that should tell you how to do that with only two variables. The idea is simple.
We mainly need to keep minimizing over the same value.
So let's start here.
We have to read ten numbers.
I started by reading in the result the first value and remember from the previous homework, the
initialization of result was a bit tricky.
So here to avoid the initialization at all, I starting by reading the first number in the results directly.
Now we have other nine values to read.
So what I'm doing here is just I keep minimize all of them, read the number.
If result is less than it, maximise and so on and so on
and so on and so on.
By the way, you might write it like (num > result), this is OK.
, but observer here, I like to write it like the result is less number because I just change here
result equal number.
So like a more, more synchronized code.
Anyway, this is mainly the idea how to make two variable, take one of them and keep maximizing among
all of the other variables.
The other case is that you are given a variable number of variables, which
is N here equal ten. Later,
We'll learn about the loops and this should be easier problem.
But to solve it here, we are going to make a simple trick.
We are going to check from a step to another.
We'll read account and initialize the result.
Remove a count, let's say we read count with five.
So we read the first number.
Then now we have count equal one.
We have four numbers, I am duplicating here nine if conditions because I know we have a maximum of ten,
ten inputs.
So with every one of them, I'm checking if there are more inputs, remove the input, read it, do the maximization
and so on.
The code definitely isn't well structured just for visualization purpose.
(ctrl + shift + f) in eclipse will make
All of them well organized.
That's all.