The third homework set. we will read a number X, then 6 numbers representing three Interval
an interval is something that has a start and end, both of them inclusive.
For example, here in this image, I am showing you three intervals, Interval from one to ten here
starting at one, ending at ten and interval from five to six, starting at five, ending at six and
interval from four to forty,
Starting at four, ending at 40.
You will read the number X which is seven here and we would like how many intervals X is part of.
For example X here is a seven, seven is part of this interval and this interval.
So it's part of two intervals in this case.
Here we are reading number 10, and number 10 exists in these three intervals.
And also the last test case; we have a number 10, which doesn't exist in any interval.
All of the intervals would be given such that the start is less
than or equal the end.
So s1 will be less than or equal to e1, s2 will be less than or equal to e2, and so on.
In the second assignment, you will read 2 intervals and you have to print their intersections
if they don't intersect, print -1, for example, for the interval [1,6] and [3,8],
the intersection is the interval [3,6] because the interval [1,6] is the numbers
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6 and the interval [3,8] is the interval 3, 4, 5,
6, 7, 8,
So the intersection is 3, 4, 5, 6, which is [3,6]. For these four numbers,
[1, 15] and [20, 30],
These two intervals doesn't intersect,
So we print
-1, that's all.