Let's solve the third homework, actually, the first one is easy.
It was more like an introduction to the second one, for the first one, all what you need is to read the
number X and then start to read the three intervals I kept.
Just start and end here.
And then I read the start and end and increment the count if X is between the start and end.
That's all. you don't need more than that.So interval
Second, the third and counter. in the second one, we need to do the interval intersection and this might
be tricky.
And this is why actually you have this assignment.
So let's see here.
You might try to list a lot of different cases, which would be hard and buggy, but you eventually
can do it.
But there is a consideration here.
If you try to think a little more, you will notice the following.
Where does the intersection start and end?
The intersection starts at the maximum of the two starts and ends at the minimum of the
two ends.
If you tried that, it should be good enough.
Now, there is one trick here that would save you a lot of your time.
Try first to make sure that the intersect, if it doesn't, just get rid of this intersection very early
How to know
The two intervals don't intersect if one of them is ending before the start of the second,
which need from us
Two cases here to make sure that ...
If I am ending before his start or he is ending before my start, then we definitely don't intersect otherwise
with the simple observation, we can get that intersection in an easy way.
One good lesson from this problem is many problems can be solved in many ways.
Some of the ways might be easier to find, but very hard to code and some approaches might be hard to
find very easy to code.
Sometimes the approach is hard to find, hard to code, but is very efficient.
The moral of that is there might be several ways to tackle a problem.
Do not go with the first idea that comes to your mind.
Try to think deeper.
I also used to tell my students an important to track.
I used to tell them think on papers not on PC.
I mean by that when you have a problem, don't rush to the computer to code it because I believe the
coding make like a kind of bounding to your mind.
Your mind got trapped and it's boundaries.
It cannot find good solutions. when you have a problem go far from the computer, pick a paper and pencil
and start to sketch a solution, verify the solution.
Ask yourself what if there is another efficient way.
Let's try to see this problem from a different angle.
This how people in the industry come up with different designs for their problems.
The same problem can be solved with different ways, and every approach has some pros and cons.
So do not be that guy who just rush to the computer to write an idea.
Do not be the guy who just thinks the one way to solve the problem, try to figure out more than
an approach, try to figure out the different like qualities in a solution, that's all.