In this video, you will know about more advanced ways to use the "if statements" specifically. let's say
I need a program with the following logic.
If the salary is less than one thousand we print: "you are poor". If it is between 1000, but less than twenty thousand,
You have a good salary.
Otherwise, if you are greater than twenty thousand, you are a rich guy.
Now, how to do that in a syntax.
This is one question, but more interestingly here, far from programming, when you are an engineer,
a good engineer, think in good ways to test his good.
So this is introduce the word "test cases".
Test cases are the cases
where we are evaluating our program.
For example, a good software engineer might decide that I would like to test for a salary of zero and
five hundreds, one thousand, ten thousand, twenty thousand and maybe this very big number.
OK, so the logic behind this one thousand, ten thousand, twenty thousand, they are the boundary of
the conditions here.
So it's good to make sure that you are doing well on the boundary of your condition.
This is a very big number to make sure that your program is working well.
Also, in other cases, you might think, OK, can a user try a negative number? can you enter
my salary is minus hundred, for example.
And so on. Moving to C++, the C++ offers you what we call the "if, else if chain".
What is the "if else chain".
Let's focus about line 8 and 9 here.
Let's say that you enter the salary like three thousand.
So the line 8 and 9 is what we did in the last time.
We say if salary less than thousand: you are poor, this condition now isn't satisfied.
So we don't get inside line 9. now in C++, we can do more conditions.
But in this case we use the word "else if".
So now we say "else if" and then we give a new condition,
What was the interest in our second condition?
We wanted to know if the salary is between one thousand and twenty thousand, but less than it.
So this is our new condition, which is true in our case.
No, it isn't
true still. So in our case, this also false.
Then we said else.
So the else here is you are going to get inside it regardless of you were true or not regardless of anything
anymore.
So again, the logic is as following,
You start with first condition.
If it is true, you get inside it.
Everything else is discarded.
If it is false, you go to the next else if condition.
If it is true, you get inside it and discard everything else.
Otherwise, you go to the next else if condition and the next else if condition and the next else if condition and
so on.
As long as the condition is false, we are moving to the next condition.
We might end up with an else only without else if.
If this is the case, you just get inside it.
So here, if you thought about the logic, we say: are you less than a thousand, there is one handling here. are you
between one thousand and twenty thousand,
This is one handling here. else, we are here.
Notice, it is in a bit implicit here, but we know that this (else) happens only when you are actually
greater than twenty thousand.
So this how we handled that when greater than twenty thousand by ourselves.
You can still write here else if salary greater than or equal
Twenty thousand.
But we actually we don't need this condition.
Let's make a simple practice, let's say that you are reading an integer and you would like to print
if it has one digit, two-digit, three-digit, four-digit or more or five digits and more.
For example, if you entered five hundred fifty-six, you would like to say that this is three digits.
I would like to use what we learned to think in some code for doing it.
Here is the code, The logic would be very simple, we would say as following, if number is less than 10,
Print: 1 digit. 100, print: 2 digits. 1000, print: three digits.
10000, print: 4 digits.
Else we know it is definitely ten thousand or more; so it's 5 digits or more.
Let's move to a little bit more complex, although it's very logical, we said before that inside the
Braces, we can add whatever body we want.
So an interesting question here.
Can I put another if condition here?
Yes.
Can I put more if conditions?
This is what we call nested if condition.
We can put more and more and more nested conditions.
So let's see the logic of this
code. we say read a salary, if salary less than one thousand, we go to this big logic between line
11 and line 18, else, we do something.
So if someone entered, for example, 2000, it would just print "you are rich", otherwise it would be
here,
In the body of this logic. if the person is less than 1000, we ask him for his age and read it.
And then we tell him here, if age is less then twenty-two, you are still young.
What if the person is greater than twenty-two or equal?
Nothing is printed.
OK, so again here a line to 21.
Can we use the variable age?
The answer is no.
This is a local variable and not visible outside its scope.
So in summary, we saw three styles for if condition.
You either write a very simple if condition and body.
This body can be a single line of code or just two braces with whatever code that you would like.
And this can even be like more nested if conditions.
The second side is if else chain.
So you say if condition, else if condition, else if condition, else if condition, else if condition.
The third the case is you say if, else if, else if, else if, but you end it with a single else without the if.
To keep going in the chain if condition,
If it's true, you go to the body and you stop all of that.
If it is false, you go to the next condition and you execute it,
If it's true. if the condition is false, you just go to the next condition.
If this is false, you go to the next condition.
If it is true, you get inside it.
If it is false, you go to the next condition, which is just else without if.
So we always execute this body. here,
We just execute,
If we have an else if here,
If we satisfy this condition. The word "condition" refers to the relational operators of true or false.
That's it.