Let's practice on selection.
In the first program we would like to create a simple calculator that just do for us the basic addition,
subtraction, division and multiplication.
So we'll read two numbers and a sign between them and then just apply it.
So for example, if we read 7+55 it gives 62. 7*10, it gives 70,
stop the video for a few minutes, and try to sketch the code, and always try to challenge yourself
earlier, always challenge yourself.
This is much better for you so that you can give your trial then compare your trial with my trial. here,
this is a very basic program.
we would like to read two numbers,
We also would like to read the operation, which is of type character.
So we read two numbers. given that we would like to do the division operator,
So choosing double here is more wise choice.
So you read and just we need to start to apply our if else conditions.
If we thought about it, we need to check:
Are you "+" operation?
If yes, then we do the "+" operation. else,
Are you "-" operation? if yes, do the minus operation. else, are you the "*" operation?
If yes you do the multiplication. else, we can say if operation == division.
But if we are sure that the user is just inputting one of these four values, we can just write here else.
OK in another case if you would like to verify more the input for the user, you would write
here, else if operation == Division "/", then you would have another else only and tell him this
isn't a supported operation.
here,
We would like to read two numbers and print the minimum of them.
So if I give you 10, 20; you print 10, which is minimum. give you 70 and 5 you
give 5.
again, give a trial by yourself.
This is very easy program,
We can read the two numbers and then easily we can compare if the first is a smaller one, just to print it.
else,
Then the second is the  smaller one. in this program
We don't need any more to write here any other else if.
So this is very fair if-else program.
Let's move to a more challenging case.
You are reading three numbers and you are printing which one is minimum.
I would like to think in this could and there are really more than an approach to do it.
In the first approach here, we are reading the first three numbers, and here is the logic. We first
are comparing the first two numbers, is number one less than number two or not.
If so, then we need now to compare number one with number three.
If false, then, number one is definitely not the smallest one, but it could be number
two or number three.
So we are here doing the logic of it.
So the way we are doing it is mainly based on the comparison of the first two numbers and
and second two numbers.
So this one created for us a nested-if set up, as you see, compare the first two, compare the second two and
so on. in a second way, we got rid of the nested-if conditions.
We know number one would be the smallest, if it is smaller than number two and smaller than number three.
So we are making condition for every one of them, if I'm smaller than all of them,
Print number one. if not, then if number two is smaller than all of them,
Then number two. if number one isn't the answer and the number two isn't the answer, definitely
number three is directly the answer. here is a much more nicer way better than both of them.
We are taking some temporary variable, let's call it answer, and we put number one inside it, and
then if "answer" is greater than "num2", then definitely "num2" is a smaller than the current answer.
at this moment,
Answer has a minimum of "num1" and "num2".
Otherwise, if answer is greater than number three, then we can say answer equal number three.
Now, what is good about this approach?
This approach is easily scalable.
Scalable means we can add more values
And it works well, like let's say I would like to get the minimum of five numbers, using this logic
We can extend it easily, but the previous two ways weren't extendible.
It will be very tough
code.
And it will keep increasing in a complex way.
OK, let's go more.
Let's read an integer and we have the logic already, we just need to transfer this logic to code.
It says if the number is even,
Print last digit of it, for example, if you go 234, this is an even number
you print the last digit, which is 4.
If the number is odd, we do the following, if the number is less than 1000, we print the last two
digits of it, for example, 157, which is odd, and less than 1000 we print the last
two digits here, which is 57.
Otherwise, if the number is greater than 1000 but less than this million, we print the last four
digits of it.
For example, if this is the number, we print the last four digits of it. otherwise we print
the negative of the input value.
So if I give you this number we print the negative one, as you see, the logic almost exist.
We just need mainly to print either the last digit, last two digits, last four digits or a negative
value.
Write
a code for that.
Here we just to go ahead with the logic of the code, the first one, we need to know if the number
is even or not, which we can know that using just the mod 2 "% 2" is it == zero or not.
OK.
Otherwise, we go in the else and say, if num less than 1000, if then print the last two
digits. if it is less than this number, then we print these digits. notice here,
this condition has an implicit condition, in the request
It was like if the number between 1000 and one million.
But if we know that now the number isn't less than 1000, then this means it is must be greater than
1000.
So here we omitted a condition.
We removed a condition because it definitely applies.
Else, again, has here an implicit condition,
If the number isn't less than 1000 and it isn't less than one million, then definitely, it is
greater than or equal to one million.
So we don't need to put specific condition here.
This is more than enough.
Yes, let's proceed more. Last three digits,
Again, you are given the logic of a program here and you are to print it.
The logic here if a number is less than ten-thousand, you just say this is a small number.
Otherwise you sum the last three digits,
And then if the sum is odd of the last three digits, you say this is a great number.
If the sum is even, you do the following,
If any digit for the last three digits is odd, say this is a good number, otherwise say this is a
bad number.
Again, try to take the logic of the conditions and just write a code for it.
Here we go,
First of all, we we do the basic two cases,
If the number less than 1000,
Then just a small number, else we start to prepare our program. To make it easy,
I started to get the digits of the last three numbers.
So, you know, remember that mode 10 "% 10" can take for us the last digit and then division by 10 can remove
it.
So I took the last digit and then removed
It, take the second digit and removed it, take the next digit and removed it. this way,
If we have a number like say 330, then I have now the zero and the three and the three.
At this moment we can continue our logic.
I'm going here to sum the three digits and then if the sum is odd, OK, this is a great number.
else, we started to do the following three computations,
we know if every digit
of them is odd or even, if this is odd,
Yeah, we get the digits here either our three digits are odd or not, and then we just go
ahead and see if any of them is odd or not.
Otherwise, it's just a bad number.
So just go ahead and try to trace it here on these test cases.
If you notice, as an engineer, I'm trying to cover all the possible and important test cases. one interesting
thing about the comparison, you might think, if I would like to know if
the number is even, I can say if mod 2 == zero, and if it's odd I can say mod 2 == 1
I can also know for the odd
If mod 2 is not equal zero, which one is better?
Give a minute for thinking.
I would like to know if a number is odd.
Which one to say? "% 2 == 1" or "% 2 != 0"  ?
The "!= 0" is actually much better.
Why?
Because it works for even numbers and odd numbers. sorry, it works for positive numbers and negative
numbers.
Let's say that sum is -11.
If you took "-11 % 2", it will be -1, not 1.
So this is tricky.
You have to be more careful.
But in both cases, it would be not equal zero.
So this way is more valid for negative and positive cases.
So always when it comes to compare even, compare with zero or not equal zero.
Not with zero or one.
That's it.