In C++ 17, there is a nice change for the if-statement function to allow now an initializer.
Let's read this code here.
We are defining some variable X with 11.
Then we're checking if X is odd, we are printing a message.
Otherwise, it is even now in line 13, variable X is still visible for us.
Question here.
Do we really need that?
Sometimes, yes.
But sometimes no. If it is important to have it here, then the scope like now in
this area, is limited now because of the variable X like X is visible.
So it might be a problem.
C++ 17 is trying to help with this problem by reducing the scope a little bit if we have to.
Now look here we have in the new C++ style something like if initialize semicolon ";" condition.
So we know, we see we have two things and there is a semicolon in between.
In the first one here, you can initialize something and then you write your normal condition.
Now your code goes as normal as you would like.
The variable Y that you initialize.
Is visible in every if-else inside your if-else block here.
But the interesting part here is starting from line 20 after this if-else block the variable Y
isn't visible anymore.
So that is all, this is all what happened.
Instead of initializing something here, you can put it at the beginning of the if condition and.
then it is invisible in the remaining of your program.
It is only visible inside your if-else block.
This makes your code more like a more cleaner.
It would not be widely applicable for your cases, but it will help from time to time.
That's it :)