homework set number 1, the first problem you will read two integers A and B and based on being odd or even, we have
four cases, if both are odd, print the multiplication, if both are even print the division.
Feel free to assume that B will be able equal zero.
And if the first is odd and the second is even print the summation and if  the first is
is even and the second is odd, just print the subtraction of them.
And this is a case, for example, here, five and seven,
Both of them are odd so the multiplication is thirty five,
In the second program, you have to read three integers and sort them, sorting means order them, sort
them from small to large.
This is what we mean by ascending order.
The descending order is decreasing.
The ascending is from small to large.
For example, if the input is two, three, one, we will order them to one, two, three, observe
four given three integers here.
There are only three cases.
If they are of different values, if they are equal values, it will be less than that.
Then in this problem, you will read three integers and you have to find the biggest one of them, which
is less than one hundred, if there is no such a number, print minus one, for example, 22, 90, 115
observed here
one hundred and fifteen is bigger than hundred.
So we will discarded we have here 20 and 90 and both are less than one hundred.
The maximum among them is 90.
In this case, all of the numbers are greater than 100.
So the answer is minus one.
In this case, only 50 is less than 100,
so it's only the answer and so on.
In this program, you will read five numbers you will read- sorry,  you will read six numbers.
The first number is X, then you read other five numbers and printed the following.
How many numbers are less than or equal X and how many numbers are greater than X?
Is there some relationship between these two outputs?
For example, we return then we read these five numbers, we have two numbers, less than ten or equals
ten, which are the one and five and then 100, 200, 300 are greater than ten. That's all.