Let's solve the first homework here, problem number one, for the arithmetic of the two numbers, we
will read the two numbers and to make our life easier, we will have two variables is_even and is_even for
A and B and then based on the check of that, we can easily decide the output.
For example, if not even and not even for both of them, then this is an odd number.
So multiply both of them, if even and even, then we divide them, if not even
and even, then it means odd and even then the addition, otherwise the subtraction.
So this is one easy way to develop this problem. In the second
In the second
problem, we have to order the three integers.
And I would like to ask you if you have thought about the numbers, No, sorry, this isn't the
case, it is in the third one.
Let's see the solution here, to sort of the numbers we were going to make the following.
We have the three numbers A and B and C.
And I would like to verify first, if B is less than A or not, if B isn't less than A, then I'm going
to make sure that they are swept, so that we are expecting A and B. For seek of example here, assume
we have the numbers three, two, one.
So now A is three.
B is two. I'm
verifying, is B less than A? the answer would be yes.
So let's swap them here.
Now, if we swept them together then now this is two and three.
Now let's go with the second part.
If C is less than B itself.
So we are now comparing the second two numbers here.
If C is less than B, we again need to to make similar logic.
We need to push this together.
For example, we need to swap them.
Let's swap them here. Now,
One and three, so far seems good.
But the problem here is that this guy now is ordered relative to this guy and this guy, but might
not be the case between these two ones here.
So, again, double check again if B is less than A or not, if this is the case, we again are going to
swap both of them here. This is mainly how we can swap three numbers in the future, we will learn about
a mechanism that can help us to sort a lot of numbers in an easy way.