Let's continue, for problem number three, we would like to find the maximum, but it should be less than
one hundred.
And one question here.
Did you consider that the integers might be negative values or not, if you didn't,
then this is a wrong conclusion.
All of the examples here that I provided for you were only for positive examples.
But this might not be the case.
And it depends on your solution.
How good is your solution?
Does it consider something that might make the negative values wrong or not? For simplicity,
Let's assume for now that all of the numbers are greater than or equal zero.
I start here by initializing the result to be minus one and I have three if condition.
Every if condition is trying to maximize over the current result.
But I would like to make sure I'm maximizing over something that is greater than or equal to 100, is greater
than or equal to 100.
So we starting, is it less than 100?
If so, this is a valid number.
If it is greater than our number, then this is a good number, take it.
Doing the same logic with B and the same logic with C..
So the overall of that is we are maximizing, but I'm first making sure I am maximizing with a valid
number.
Where is the problem with this code? If any of these values like A is less than zero,
There might be some troubles for some negative values
because I'm stating here the result with negative one.
So maybe we'll get to give an example here.
Let's see what's happening if we provided
Something like minus 10 and minus 20 and minus 30, the answer would be minus one.
Why?
Because of my bad initialization here.
One way, one might decide to use a very, very, very small negative value here, something like the
the lowest integer value.
Then this code is going probably to be correct.
But here is a handling.
If we don't want to do that. just a one hundred, it's a bit longer,
But there is an idea behind it that
I would like to share with you, the idea here is as following, I'm going to check if any one of the
the three variables is a valid starting point or not.
So I'm checking if this is valid or this is valid or this is valid, if any of them is valid, I
just would like to to initialize my result with it.
If all of them are invalid, the result would be invalid and all of these conditions will not work.
If any of them is valid, then it's a good initialization one.
So the moral of that is the previous code has a problem with the initialization, like the way that
I initialized it isn't wise enough and this code is trying to solve this problem.
So this is one way. In other programming languages,
It could be easier to handle this problem.
Or as I said, you might use something that's very, very small value so that it fits with whatever inputs
here.
In the last problem, we would like to make a conditional count, which is mainly checking how
many numbers greater or less than, for a while you might think, OK, let's do some If else condition.
This is totally valid.
But I wanted to go in a different direction.
I just here initialized a counter and then a less than or equal X, a2 and a3.
Observe that this is Boolean, which is ending up with either one or zero.
So whatever is less than or equal X will be an added value as a word.
And clearly the relationship between the two numbers that this is count, then the second number is
five minus count.
So this is the relationship between both of them.
And you can definitely do that with an if else condition.
That's OK.
Yeah.