Homework set number two,
In the first problem, you will read 10 integers and you have to find the maximum among all of
them, but I would like you to try to do all of the code using only two integer values.
If this is hard for you, ignore it and just do it whatever way,
but try to stick to two integer
only, in the second program, you will read first an integer N, which will be from two to ten, and then
you have to find the maximum among them.
For example, here, you read,five for five numbers.
Then you read all of them.
The maximum would be four.
Here we have ten numbers and then we read numbers and the maximum is one hundred twenty-nine.
This is like same the last example here.
But just when the N is fixed to ten
That's all.