Let's continue our talk about the about the estate move.
I would like you to start reading this quote, which has some default constructor and Akabi and move
constructor.
And we have here a department E department cluster that has an E object.
And then in the constructor, we has also two types of constructor that receive an employee and calling
here the Buranda class with so like initializing the E with the parameter here.
I would like you to trace this good and figure out a bug in this could give you like five minutes to
do that.
The Depok is in the line 15 you are receiving here on our value difference, and then we know that this
guy will be destroyed soon.
When you when you try to initialize the with item, you initialize it with item itself.
But item here is an L value.
It's Zanin.
So the right way is like very similar to this.
Did you move this guy need to be marketed with an extreme move so that the construct to deal with it
as an R very different.
So the major difference here we need to do that is to remove function here in a very similar way.
If you have a copy constructor and move constructor to the class here and this this is this like constructor
related to initialize it's the proper way is you move the inability to the move function here.
Now, generally speaking, you need to when it comes to your good, you need to identify all of the
places that are using your R value reference and think if you would like to bust them, would move around.
This typically would involve some composition's in areas like care or inheritance.
You need to think about basing your object still in or value reference so that they can make use of
the fact that this is actually a temporary object that would be destroyed to.
Let's see one implication on the move function, let's say you have here, BE1, if you did a move for
BE1 and you received it to be R, this is this is tricky.
We are here to state and our values are very different, but the type is an L value added value.
Let's do something else if we try to push back here.
There we are.
This is a real value that OK, let's push back in a vector the move of B1.
Now, when this push back received b one market was move, which is a static cost, eventually it's
taking it very different.
So it's going to steal its memory using a move constructor or.
Yeah, using a move constructor.
Now, where is the problem if you if you if you try to do with it back back is a function of the return
of the last element reference and print.
It will print.
If you tried to print B1 to print, it's going to be a runtime error.
Remember that B1 was best to be stolen and its internal data is now has been taken.
So if you try to do beyond the print, this will give you a runtime error.
The only way is to maybe you reduce your pointer if you would like, like you say, set for a second
here.
Remember that our set sits second, for example, is able to create a new memory if needed.
But other than that, it's the it's just a and we want to say that the return of move we want here is
an X value.
And and the reason here is this B one is marked as movable.
So it's a date that has been taken.
But as we still has this identity of this address, we want we can take problems with it.
This why it is important to differentiate between what is an X value and what is a better value.
We having an address here is problematic.
So you need to be careful about that when we come back later to take some value in an explicit way.
It's also worth to to remember about the return, the Arborio reference is eventually just just the
difference here.
We have some global variable dysfunction is returning our value difference over a global variable using
the move.
That's OK.
There will be no runtime error here.
This is another case.
This only for educational purposes like let's say we are basing M.B to get the minimum of them and you
are returning either move away or move B to return as a strange reference reference.
But but this is a reference is reference to arguments, so, again, it will not cause a problem.
Let's do something else.
If you try to do something, you have A and B and then you are trying to return reference to them.
But this is wrong and we are now looking at variables.
They would be destroyed very soon.
As a general rule.
Do not use this to move on the return of functions.
Avoid that.
This is just very problematic, typically, unless you are sure that there would be no problems happening
from the.
This is some readings, if you'd like to do some readings, but I prefer to delay them after the world
section.