I would like to go back to the move constructor and copy constructor and learn a nice tricks that might
make your code maybe less a good size or less trowels.
There are two tracks here, the delegation and the swabbing this hour.
This is our copy constructor as it is.
This is our assignment as it is almost for now.
And this is, first of all, the move constructor.
There is an easy way that instead of Fiorita good in the constructor and the assignment and there is
a duplication, we can delegate from the constructor to the new assignment.
How to do that.
As simple as you start to use the equal here and then use it right here is the remove of the other object
here on your right and instead move for this object.
Then this value will be at our value and with this equal rigor, you are switching it to here.
So this way you don't have to write any good in the constructor.
You only have to focus over the copy constructor.
This is the delegation right now, the Swaptree.
Remember, in the last time in the constructor, we have to do two steps forward.
We say that we first need to delete my own data.
We second need to take Cobbe from the data on the other for me, and we then need to pointer the other
object.
Now, here is a track.
We are going to only swab my.
Object details is with his own object, it is within an internal swap function that is just as webbing
my pointer with his pointer.
Am I going to this pointer if I have more data like, say, integer X or so?
You're just describing them now.
After that, what happened?
Notice that I didn't delete something from my side and I didn't put another pointer on his side or what
I did is just I swear that my data was his data.
Then after the constructor go out of here or what's going to happen is this object will call its own
the structure and its the structure is going to do the normal deleting that we used to do.
So in this way, you are actually doing much less good in your function by avoiding to delete yourself
and not point to the other day, which might be problematic in a very systematic way.
Provider's work function that just to swab the internals of the object and this is what we call the
Swaptree.
Before the R value references, there were a different logic here that involved what we call a QB and
swap, where do you first make a copy of this object and return it here, but still sometimes even happen
in the move, in the assessment of the letter itself.
Let's say we have something like our own vector.
So I have a length of my array and he has a lens of his own array.
Then sometime you will have to create your own memory first before just taking the memory of the other
side.
So sometimes we might need to create using the constructor my own data, then swab it with the other
other guy.
That's why you're providing a separate function here is useful because both move constructor or assignment,
assignment operator or assignment operator might need to use this swap function.
These are very nice readings about the swap function.
That is like a discussion how to write a better swap function for more generic purposes, how to avoid
the throwing of exceptions.
And what about the QB and swap adiam?
But what you learn here is more than enough.
That's a.