I referred more than once to the value, and I think you had a good sense of it now, but it may be
time to make it more, more, more explicit.
Recall that Analia value is something that has an identity.
It has like personality.
It has a name or identifiable address.
And also we named the we are values, the bureau values here to be tamburri, something like the Electra's.
I learned also that kersting and value can generate an R value difference, which is there is more.
Now, going back to the diagram here, we say that we have three primary values.
They value their value.
And also there is this value and there are two different classes here, the value and our value and
every one of them is good and expression.
The value is something now between what is the R value add, between what is the value, something very
narrow.
So far we learned about it.
The X value is something that has an identity and also movable.
Remember that L values has an identity, but the current market, like with the casting operation as
movable, it means that they will expire or would be terminated their life at a specific time in the
normal way.
Now when we try to move in value, we convert it to our value reference.
Why do we do that?
When we do that, we have a message that this object will be stolen soon by some other guy.
It means it's about to expire.
And this should be always the reason that you try to move something, because after it has been moved,
you shouldn't try to make use of it.
Remember the session of the when we tried to use the object after it was use it because a runtime error.
So the moral of that is when a move on value, there is an intention that this guy, someone will take
its internal and it will expire soon.
And from here, the extra value comes, the extra value is an by adding value.
It's something that originally has an identity, but now it's about to expire.
So it's movable object.
This is the overall difference between the X value and other guys.
It it's something in the middle.
It's something movable because we we apply the custom over it.
But also originally it's something has an identity.
And and and remember one question about the difference between X value and be our values.
You have to be careful when it comes to coding like you shouldn't use it after it has been moved.
And this take us to this very nice diagram.
Every every one of the five types can be identified by these two properties.
Is it has does it has an identity or not?
And is it movable or not?
So thinking about the values, the value cannot move.
But he has an identity thinking about the we are values that implies they do not have an identity like
hundred, but they are ready to be moved and destroyed in the memory in a way only in the intersection
between something that has an L value and is movable.
We find extra value, which may only happen by taking an value object and casting it, for example,
to.
And this is one one one good way.
Now going back to the to the parenting classes and our value is something that is ready to move.
That is it in the diagram.
And the value is something that has an identity.
That's it in the in the diagram.
Let's see, some examples do have the value more in our in our minds.
So let's say we have an X here, which is 50.
This initial value we have here ulcerate value reference to 15.
But Exide itself is still Annell Value, which has a name, has an identity, hasn't addressed to me.
Is it simply in the memory?
It is a better value.
We know that so far.
If you could move on an L value, the return here is in value that is ready to move.
This is an X, but if you try to move X and receive it in Y, Y again, come back as a value because
it now has a name.
So you can think of X as something that is hiding the name for us because everything that has a name
is in value.
So the move here is hiding the name.
But the move here, we received it again in a name.
So the name is clear.
It is an L value.
Again, no thinking about here if it is a function that is returning our value.
This is wrong, as you know, because it pointing to a local reference.
But in a way, if it is returning an R value difference and we don't have an access to its name here.
So if one calling if true, this is an extra value example.
If you try to do something like integrate, you qualify to that.
If Y again is an L value.
And now I hope I hope you over all of that, you get the sense of marking something with an clustering,
something to reference reference, make it as X value as long as you can have a name for it like you,
you don't receive it in a name.
Now there are other two interesting cases.
If you try to use the subscript operator on an value, let's say here string stuff and then you exis
it with one, this become now an X value.
OK, so String Mustafa is an R value, but this subscript operator goes, it goes as to to have some
like pointing to something, some internal address inside it.
That's why we convert it from our value to an extra value in a very similar way.
If you use the good operator to access some temporary object, the name if it is an anesthetic member,
Zigged and Xibalba.
Now, one might ask himself, do we really need to differentiate between what is effectively a PR value
and highlight that there is now an identity?
They are in a way, you know, movable, and we are going to pass it to someone who is going to steal
the data from them.
There are differences.
The first one that we said here in the previous slide that you need to be careful about the dealing
with the values.
You should try to use them if you have an access to the identity.
And here is one more interesting difference.
You can cast the exact values to a difference here, because we know there is an address, but you cannot
cast a we value because you don't have an address identifiable for you.
So this is one difference.
And also in some of the readings, you will notice that there is even a physical difference between
them.
Overall, I hope you will still I hope you manage to figure out the differences in case here are some
useful informal rules.
If it has a name, then it has an identity, something like in the value nonconscious value reference,
the value difference and so on.
If it doesn't have a name, it is another value.
And then now there are two types.
Either we are values like the reference and the like like literals.
But these are and this.
Yeah, but this aren't they do not have an identity.
This is a mistake.
The second case, an exit value, for example, the very popular case would be the return of a esteemable
where the function here, the move goes to the need in the name to be hidden for us.
But we still have some identifiable address for it.
So overall, it's movable.
So the value is something that really has an identity identifiable address, but still movable one.
It also worth mentioning something about the big picture.
Now, when we try to bessen an argument to a function, there are mainly three value categories that
we have.
We canvas and value or be are value and x value from the function that receiving the parameter itself.
We have military cases.
It can like have a barometer for an hour value or value or add value, reference or value difference.
You can even think about the corresponding cases here.
If you would like to be very good in the proper optimizations of both of them, you have to remember
the many to many relationship between them.
For example, where we are three values and we have we are receiving here in three scenarios or even
five scenarios you have to have in your mind and you should be able to do that.
Now, for all of these scenarios, for example, in some scenarios there will be a comparison error.
If you try to pass a constant reference to the parameter, this would be a comparison, a comparison
error.
If you try to pass, for example, a variable to a function that has a reference, you are expecting
the function to be able to change the variable and so on.
Having the inmind these relationships is it is useful for the relationships and here some readings,
that's all.