Let's continue the perfect wording.
Let's go back to the forwarding problem, and this is as simple as now the solution using the forwarding
reference idea, instead of providing a constructor for every different case, we are going to use three
template parameters here, one for the full name, one for the nickname and one for the address, and
then one would like to initialize the full name.
We are going to use the forward with it.
Forward here.
This way, the constructor is able to receive the different types of up to eight cases because up to
eight cases are going to be generated for you.
The second with the forwarding function.
If you received here and our value reference, it will be assigned to this guy was a constructor if
it is available.
And if you received an elevated reference, this guy will be initialized with a copy constructor.
So with these two guys, we solved with the perfect routing problem.
One thing here to keep in mind, you have to use a different city, a different template parameter for
every case of them.
Why all of them are just a string because every one of them will be generated based on the usages that
you have here.
This one isn't a string.
This one would be generated maybe to string reference.
We could as the string reference, maybe string reference, reference, string reference, reference.
It depends on the compiler generation based on the usage cases.
And if you have a function that is returning a T, it will be also a separate template.
So be careful so that you don't get that comparison error.
By the way, you can use Otha instead of the template of just saving your time, something like auto
or to auto, but you might face this error.
I'm not sure if the feature is really applicable from now or not.
The declaration time, we will highlight it.
We highlighted once later, but it's just guessing the type of Wolny directly so it will know that full
name here is, for example, the string reference or so a declaration type of something in the in the
library that gas the pipe from here by itself.
Something that can make your code more generic if you are confused about this is like just skip it.
I would like also to say that in our example here, I believe that there the move was more than enough.
For example, let's say that you are going to receive all your parameters and just like without reference
at all, this isn't the best practice.
By the way, if you are receiving here like string for name, nickname and address and you just move
this parameter to here.
Now, there are two cases.
Either the caller is using an L value.
So it would make in a way, a copy constructor outside us and give it us to here we move it or is giving
us our value reference.
So we are just if it was an R value for us, then you will wonder if it's a real value, why this guy
would be good in moving.
We learned that in the next lesson about the competition, where there is the constructor will not call
an extra call here.
But this is something that's very compiler dependent and we will know about that in the next lecture.
Let's introduce you to another funny thing, let's say you would like to to create a perfect factory
function where the factory is coming from, design batteries, and let's say that we would like to create
a function that able to create any arbitrary object to to be able to satisfy such a crazy idea.
You need the following.
You need to function to be able to accept any number of arguments.
You need to be ready to accept a value or value.
You need to be able to forward a barometer to other guys as we wish for.
The last two things, you can use perfect forwarding with the forward function or the forwarding references
will follow the function and to supported a number of arguments.
Arbitrate.
You need the verdict, Hambly.
So let's see how all of them would get together.
The function would be as following.
Here we have the forwarding reference parameter that we have.
We have a return and we have equal parameters so that the return is deep and it is the parameters and
we are using here.
The very argument is that now the remaining is this is that which is a constructor of an object and
would like to pass the argument.
But remember, we need to forward it.
So you see here the syntax we forward do the args, which is going to do the casting, then we put the
three dots after it.
Actually, this is a Woodburn's of the example.
I wanted to show you how the verdict template was come would come in with the four words here.
Anyway, let's see about the mean.
Let's see first the stronger case I have here, a string guess I can call the Kiriat function with a
template string and bessus it is an L value so this guy will create a string of L value is another case
mussing a string of Mustafah.
So it's going to call the string class T would be a business and we will call Mustaffa as our value.
So far so good.
Let's say I could with something like create and I guess the two victor into and best two parameters.
Five and ten.
One thousand.
This would create a vector of five elements.
Each of them is custard with one thousand notice here with best two values.
Then the answer would be the two values.
So it's like creating here vector of integer with two values.
We can even in a similar way create a vector vector of integer ambassador content to you.
If you feel that this is very advanced, you can skip it.
I really wanted to show you this three arcs, but good to understand the example.
Let's also show you something interesting.
The emblazed function, the symbols function in the vector.
You can normally push back something like I have a vector of bit of interior string.
You can normally push back.
We say make pair of two Mustafah, you are just creating it.
The the emplace function is very interesting.
The function take for a position and iterator and you give it the parameters of the say here be whatever
here is just without, without the beer and so on.
You just send them here like in arguments.
If you have a if you have a class of constructor that take five elements, you just pass the five atmosphere
vertically.
Now the EMBLAZED is going to put it in this position, but if you try to open the C++ function for the
employees, you will notice it consists of the three things it consists of.
Predictably, it consists of the forwarding references and the forward function.
So this function is actually implemented using the three things together.
I hope at this moment you are confused about the difference between the move and forward.
But in case, remember that the move we don't call it with template arguments, OK?
And you can typically call it with an L value on our value.
But the result always is that our value differs.
When you use it to remove you have an intention.
You are saying that this guy is going to be X, Y or soon and it will be no longer used.
They send you forward on the other side can forward the value as an only value reference and the values
are value difference overall.
You have to be careful when you are using coding to move forward because the the guy here might like
after moving it would be expired.
So in the case.
So you need to be careful for not using it.
Some this here highlighting for sometimes you guys might use forward function instead of the function,
maybe by mistake or intentionally.
Do not use that because it will not give a compilation here.
So be careful.
And again, to optimize your code, you really need to identify the locations where the semantic overall
applies so that you don't lose the advantage of the or value difference.
These are a bunch of readings that it.