The illusion is an important compiler optimization track, let's say, let's read this code we have
here across my beer, which supported a copy of semantics.
We have a manager that have an object from Type B and we have three function get get one is returning
a temporary object here.
So it would be must be copied in the return.
Get to also is returning by value here.
Copy.
But from a local variable here that has a name and get three is returning a copy value, but from a
variable that is accessible from somewhere else.
If you try to function like get to that is a good chance that you don't see a copy of constructor.
And this would be very surprising thinking about that here and get to we have a variable that we must
copy to get it here.
But what happens is something called the Cobie Illusion, which means that the compiler can directly
construct this B1 here from this from this guy directly squibbing the copy or move to what is the logic?
This guy is going to be destroyed in a way.
So if we can just get it here directly, we can escape and copy.
So this way, we learned about two ways to skip Cubby's, one of them by ourselves using the semantics
and the are very reference and another one is out of our control is mainly using is by the compiler
itself.
So this is an optimization that the compiler does in C++ 17.
If you are returning something that doesn't have a name at all, the copy illusion is a master to happen
is a must.
However, if you return it a copy value from a local variable that has a name here accessible only from
here, it may be hubbins.
And this depends on the compiler.
This means that some compiler support it and some compilers don't.
If you are returning a local variable, if you are telling by value here for something that is accessible
from somewhere else, then the competition would never happen because this will corrupted this B value.
So we actually must return a copy or move constructor from this guy.
So this is a good story of the illusion.
It's a compiler trick in a way.
If you noticed, if the compiler can skip the move constructor with the copy constructor, then you
shouldn't have any side effects on your movable constructor, like very specific logic that effectively
ruled class.
In other words, you shouldn't assume that the copy constructor must be good for this heaven.
If you even if you anyway have to do something that has side side effects in your constructor that affect
the overall state of the object beyond just the moving or copying, then something is wrong in your
code.
The most technique for for the illusion implementation, which is good, return a value optimization.
And as I said, it constructed correctly the object in its destination.
There are two types of the return value optimization.
One of them is this guy tamburri here without any.
And the other guy has a name, the one without any.
We say it definitely reaffirmed the Cobbett allusion, but the one with name it may be.
Yes, maybe not.
Another case very similar is best by value, let's say that we have here a function that is receiving
the difference.
If I am calling this function with an object, there will be no Kobie constructor here because this
guy is referenced by this guy and this team also can be reflected by this guy.
So no call constructor here.
By definition, if we are passing an object to be here that we have a copy of, like a local reference
for it here and berthing the copy constructor must be good if we are quoting here the receive to function,
which is best argument by value.
Now, here is the tricky case.
If you are basing something that is very temporary from here to here now, the compiler know that this
guy would be destroyed anyway in normal cases, as we learned before you can.
But here are value reference to receive it efficiently.
However, it turned out that the compiler also will not call the copy constructor for this case and
most of the compilers and just construct it here directly.
So even with yeah, we'll know we'll know soon about that here, so I would say you better depend on
the move, move semantic to make an efficient come here like you can depend on the compiler, but remember
that every compiler supported this trick.
So it's better to depend on yourself.
But also, if you don't see the kokabee constructor code or the constructor, you should understand
what happened here.
There is one critical difference to know about this, this is style and this is style about this style
and this style, the.
The the when you call the function from here with this guy, this guy here, look, look to this function
here, receive one, receive one received the beebee, but it needed a local copy from it.
So it had to call the copy constructor, then assign it here.
Now when you call this guy, you don't have any copy constructor here.
So there is no more memory creation.
So a big difference between receive one and receive to that receive one.
Didn't call a copy constructor here, but have to call it here.
So there is an extra cabbing here.
But this guy here, he didn't have any extra copies inside the inside the function.
It's more efficient.
But what I would like to emphasize here is the exception bought this function is creating an object
it has to create if it needs a copy from it.
And this means this memory, for example, may give you some memory education problems.
But this guy doesn't have any memory education.
And this is a big difference between both of them.
This guy, anyway, is going to receive his object.
If there is an exception for any reason, it will have been outside this function.
It is it isn't the responsibility of received to 200 memory creation here, but this guy will have to
handle memory creation here.
So this is one big difference also between the two sides.
OK, here is one very interesting case.
If you have even your class without the move, constructor and copy constructor and the Ardlethan also
the compiler would do a copy elision Agaba illusion because this one is in a way is going to be destroyed.
So why to have a copy from it here.
Even if you don't have these guys, it will be copied in a blessed way, like it would be Sebti specifically.
And you will see later when you said the new computer, the unique pointer in response to pointers that
we can return a unique pointer, although it doesn't have a copy constructor a similar way.
So it should be for the OSTREM objects, for example.
OK, here's one more interesting thing.
In some compilers, you can stop the illusion for like if for whatever reason you would like to do that.
To do that, you just need to add an extra flag for that, which is this for that you either added to
the jobless plus comment here or maybe on your own, your idea in eclipse.
You need to go to settings in optimization and maybe you just write it here in in code blocks.
You go to the compiler settings to toolchain executables and you then you add the flag here.
I'm using C++ mine here to support the C++ 17 final notes.
Don't return amove object from a function.
This is going to prevent RVO.
Some guys think that if I am returning an object as a move, it's helping.
It's just causing harm.
Remember that all compiler supported the illusion and it's only created during the creation only.
So it's also very limited compiler like compiler optimization.
One more one more concern.
One might say, OK, well, we learned that we should parameter TARBY current reference as a good practice,
but we notice now if we pass by value, there is a chance that the compiler will do some good work for
us.
I would say still the best const reference is a Seiver technique and it doesn't depend on the compiler.
So it's better in passing by.
Differentiate by cross reference is a good choice and communicate clearly your intention.
So I would say I would guess that was the difference, but it's good to understand what's happening
in the compiler behind the some readings.
That's it.