In this situation, we will introduce the move semantics and the perfect for wording, they are part
of the modern C++.
This would section is mainly for one purpose, which is boosting the performance of your system.
Specifically, there are behind the scene a lot of constructor calls or copy constructor calls.
That takes time and we can avoid and escape some of them.
So the purpose of this section is in adding new features to the project itself rather than making the
project a bit faster.
If you skip this whole section, you will notice that you can write the same code, you can add new
functionalities.
However, if you wrote it, you will learn how to avoid some of the extra copies.
So this is the purpose of the of this section is building the processing in terms of dependencies of
the next sections.
There are some minor usages for the esteemable.
So if it having that you found that this this section is overall like a very overwhelming for you,
you cannot really learn it.
You might say what you will learn and keep going.
And maybe when you see this is to remove you just skip it or just do some Googling about it.
Overall, I would like to warn you that this is one of the hard and advanced topics in the language.
There are a lot of concepts, five specifically, and they are overloaded concepts that they have a
lot of like angles to understand.
You are expected to find it difficult.
I did my best to simplify it.
So some guys just oversimplify things.
But this end up that you don't really know how things are really working or you don't know how to really
optimize and use them when you are expected to iterate on the material.
And also you find me contrary to many other sections and providing a lot of reading links.
Do not follow the links after the section, after the lecture.
Just follow them.
Like when you finish the whole section, come back to them and try to follow them.
Some of them will be covered.
And what I was saying mean all of them will be covering some extra information, hopefully free to skip
as you like.
Just what I would like you to do, expect it to be a bit hard and typically you'd need some iterative
learning either of my material or maybe or other material that.