In this section, we'll learn about one of the modern features in C++, and it's a bit advanced.
We are going to introduce some concept related to what we call a value category.
Historically, when we say entire, your salary equal hundred back to the early days of C and C++,
we say that salary is a low value L for left and for right.
And we meant by that.
Left value is an identity that is on the left side of an assignment, and our value is a temporary,
typically on the right side of our assignment.
So you see here, here is the equal assignment.
Salary is on the left.
It's left to value.
Hundred is on the right.
Value salary has an identity.
So it has an address, for example, in the memory.
But it is something temporary.
We don't know how to get its address in the memory.
This guy can use the reference salary so that we can know its address.
So this is what historical was, what is left to value and what is right value.
We call them a value category, the kind of classification for an expression.
However, when the language is changed a lot, these definitions are no longer generally true.
It's still helpful to remember that l for left and out for right, but no more.
We don't say any more left of value.
We just say starting with the new C++, we have three primary new value categories.
L value X value for expired are value for pure or value and we have to be the categories here.
G.L. value for generalized value and our value.
Every expression in C++, which is eventually some abberation operators and Oberon's can be eventually
classified to one of these three primary classes.
And overall, as you see, we have now five different classes.
We are value now is is more complicated and involved.
More different.
More different in.
Two things to keep in mind, every expression has a tie and belongs to a value category.
So now when we say an expression like eight, for example, it has a tie and has a value category and
they are independent words, we will later elaborate more on that.
The value category is in a value.
The value category is a classification for the exhibition.
So it isn't a specific value like two or three for the classification classification to one of these
five types.
So when you have some expression, I say, what is the value category of this expression?
You say, oh, this expression is of our value, this expression of Xibalba.
And so.
Back to the value and our value, you actually learned a lot in C++ without knowing about the existence
of these kind of classifications.
However, when it comes to studying the topic of the semantic move or perfect for wording, we have
to do something about the value categories.
We will.
The whole story about value category is all about boosting the performance, so it specifically make
your code much faster.
That's also the whole story about semantic move is making your code much faster.
These are a minor bloss here.
You will you will understand some of the combined error messages when you know the value.
In the next session, we will highlight a lot of messages that, you know exactly which one will compile
and which one will not, but we will start to classify them to what is elevated and what is our value
when it comes to explaining what is our best value categories.
It would be very confusing for anyone.
I will try to provide some treatment for the topic.
I wouldn't say it's very formal.
It is still informal treatment.
We cannot provide a very complete treatment for this topic.
For beginners, impossible.
So take it easy.
Expect yourself to be confused in the beginning, maybe read the material, maybe read some article
and so on.
Let's introduce some terms that would be helpful for the next session.
The first one is the word identity, the word identity, like when we have an integral salary, equal
hundred salary has an identity.
You can think of that like, for example, the easiest way to think of it, it has some others may be
pointer maybe ability to determine if two copies of our variable, if two copies of a variable are identical,
or if you are confused, always remember that identity means an address.
This is a good simplification that would fit in all the time.
When we say something is a assignable, it means we can change it to value.
So Saturday equals 250.
We assign it to something now.
The second thing is the temporary 100 year is a temporary value.
It doesn't has a name, it doesn't have a name.
So when you you say your salary equals hundred somewhere in the registers, the hundred is going to
be created and then it's going to be copied to the salary, then the lifetime of it may end.
It is a reasonable thing.
Like we don't say a hundred equals salary.
This is comparison error.
Hundred is something that we don't have.
An X is a direct access to its memory address.
Salary isn't a temporary variable salary.
It is something that has an identity.
It has a lifetime that's just bigger than the equal here.
The word lifetime refer to the time duration where an object variable is in a valid estate.
While the school referred to the accessibility of it.
For example, let's say you defined a static local variable.
The lifetime of the variable is very big once you declared it till the end of the program.
However, you cannot exit from any function.
You have to exit from where it exists that the basis of it.
So the two key key words here that I would like you to keep in mind, identity like salary, temporary,
like a hundred to definition would help us in the next edition.
To make it easier for you in the next Titian's, I would like you to iterate on every line here and
think which one of them will compile and which won't if it doesn't come by, why they think it will
not come by then.
Then write the line in your computer and read the compilation message and double check.
If you really understand it or not.
This will make our life much easier.
That's all.