Let's talk about some examples that help us differentiate between what is an early value and what is
our value, or specifically then you are value type.
This is it, your salary is one hundred, we say that salary is a value and hundred is our value or
B, our value.
The as we said, the logic B in all the C things would like salary is on the left side.
It has an identity.
A hundred is on the right side is it is a temporary.
So salary is the value and hundred is our value.
What I would like you here to keep in mind, as we said in the last time, salary has identifiable address.
We can access its address using and the salary, the embassy and the salary and we can change it unless
it was consistent.
Every variable name is elder value.
Remember this rule because we will need it more than once in the next sessions.
Hundred here is a literal.
Every literal is a temporary variable.
Temporary value.
It has no name.
It has no identifiable address.
Notice that hundred exists somewhere in the registers in the the in the interim it definitely exists
somewhere, but it has no identifiable address.
This means with no where is this address.
It's going to be destroyed soon.
Also hundred is in assignable I can say here.
Two hundred equals salary.
If you try to do this, this line, you will get an error that say that any value required as left over
of assignment.
What does this mean?
It's interesting to know about what does it mean here?
This is the.
Assignment, the other end of assignment, and this is the left of the Oberon's now, this lefties is
complaining that this isn't an value.
Why is it complaining?
Because it needs something that has identifiable address to talk this century and put the value on it.
But 200 has no identifiable address.
So you cannot copy salary to 200.
You cannot do that.
This why this?
This error message is about the complaining about everybody.
Let's take another example here are defining variable names, A, B, C, and also the underlying ABCDE
languorously values.
They are names.
Names are values, the values of three to two times E plus B, the square root to revive here the CBB.
These are all be our values or our values.
They are all temporary.
If we did something like into a reference, if one equals B, we call this is a low value difference
in value difference, we could be honest or not honest.
So this is an unconscious reference so we can write something like one equal to any.
This is OK, because if one is addressable and also we can change because it is in.
Now, if you try to do something like reffed plus one equals four, this will give you a comparison
error rate plus one.
Here is a temporary exhibition at Imbrie Value.
You can go and address something with this expression greatest the integer ref reference to equal B..
This is Actionist, a value reference.
So it's really value because it has a name, it is identifiable address.
But here you cannot change the value of this reference because it is of course it is.
One or more interestingly, operators, most of the operators expect to be our values as their operands.
For example, Iblis be the plus here is expecting some other value and our value.
For example, it could be two plus three or here two times speak.
So plus is expecting in general our values or our values
what happens here.
There will be an implicit operation that will convert the E from a value to our value and convert B
from a value to our value.
This isn't that important for you to know about it at this stage.
But I would like you to know that operators in general expect to be our values.
It is one exception.
The assignment operator, the assignment operator like Refaat equal to any exhibit and the value on
itself, the site.
So it should be something like L value equal some expression.
More zombies, if you say the victor of integer, often this is actually a temporary value, a temporary
vector of 10 values, but it doesn't have a name.
So it's temporary and it would begin soon from the memory.
This is a temporary and this is a PR value.
You say double here and initialize it to zero.
This is also a temporary value.
We do not have any evidence for that.
I would like to provide you with a simple rule that help you always to identify, typically identify
what is in a value and what is it.
Ask yourself, do we have a name?
If you have a name, then it's a value like the salary, for example.
But if it has a name, it means it's identifiable and it has an address which you create an identity
for it.
But if it doesn't have a name, it means it's our value.
It means it could be something tamburri in the memory.
It is an identifiable address.
OK, most of the talk here, I say are value.
We are value fit.
Like I'm using both of them in the same way.
Actually, all what we say as our value is and our value.
But as you know from the diagram of the last decision, there is also another type under the other value,
which is extra value.
It has a very narrow cases.
So we will come to that later.
That's it.