Let's continue about the difference between l value and be our values.
Here we are making we have three functions.
One of them is receiving entier.
The second one is integral reference, and the third is into difference.
We already took these three functions before and we already know about their usage.
If you have something like if one integer here, it can accept three things here, at least it can accept
four from us, just value ten, which we know now.
It's just our value and it can accept from us X and can accept from us what.
Now, if you would like to call, if free to function with variable, with value, ten, ten is temporary.
So this is like you saying integer reference A equals 10.
This will not work.
Why?
Because then here is a temporary value and we are expecting the value reference, specifically nonconscious
value reference.
So L is the reference value reference but then is a better value.
So this is, this will not work for F to X..
This is going to work because X is that value and we are passing it to a low value reference.
And as we said, we can end or connect or assign the value of a value to an L value difference.
However, you cannot call if we do with y y here is a at a cost to integer.
So it is like like a constant value.
You cannot bother to just value reference, which is expected to change the content.
We know that because Melua is kind of.
But this isn't in the third case you have, you can bet the integral reference a four even and our value.
And this is a bit confusing, but this is how the Central Committee eventually decided that we can bind
some we are value to a value difference.
We can also definition the X and we can also send Y, which is by definition.
So this one is allowing us to serve the three ones here.
But there is a cost here.
The variable E cannot be changed in the function because it's cost on the other side.
We can send the year then X and Y to the variable, to the function if one and it can be changed.
But the cost here, X and Y are sent by reference.
They are sent by Kobie.
So it's taking more memory copies.
We already know of all of that.
Let's go more.
It is a class, it has a variable.
Embley salary is definitely an L value.
Then we have two functions.
Get one and get to get one.
Is returning y value get two is returning by reference.
I would like you to know these two rules.
If you are returning by value, this is a b r value.
If you are returning Bio-Reference, this is an eleven year difference.
Here is some about the logic behind that.
When you return a variable salary itself is an L value.
But remember that when this function is returning here to either get get one, this salary will be copied
to a temporary variable here.
So eventually what we have here on the right side is a temporary copy of salary.
That's why we consider the return to BBR our value, because what you have here is another could be
different from what you have here.
That's why this is a b r value, because this is temporary.
It doesn't have a name.
If you try to do something like E to get one equal fifty, this will not combine.
We understand that more when we come to get to here.
If you try to call it get to and you put the value in to this, this is to get to is a return to Bio-Reference,
so it is only value.
Why, because the value returning here is the same in the memory address as the value returning here,
but as well as here were having no difference, we are making a copy of it.
But still, this is still an individual reference more efficiently.
If it is something like integer reference S3 equally to get to when you do that, either get to here
is just the same address as a seller here and we are assigning the address of S3.
So S3 and celery are the same in the memory.
S3 is an alias for the seller.
If you change it, it's a three to 70.
The value of salary will be changed to 70.
It is a more syntax that we really used.
I can say either get to equal 50.
Why?
Because either get data is equal to integrate different salary.
So this line is exactly like you wrote into a reference salary equal 50.
This one is left value.
And remember we said that the equal need on its side and the value.
So this one is going to work because the value going back to this line in line twenty, it would get
one is returning by value.
So what is on the left side now of the equation is a better value.
That's why this guy will complain that it was expecting an value here.
Not we are value.
Here is one more interesting thing in the injustice here, at least if you opened the function, Max,
of tier two and three, you would notice the return of the function is the difference.
It's trying to return either the value of two or the value of three, but using it as reference.
If you try to write here into your reference, Max, two and three, this one is going to is going to
work.
But notice, this is an L value return.
This is an L value return.
So Max here is returning actually the reference I saw some guys who are saying that Max three are are
r our value.
This is incorrect, at least in D.C. This is different from scorebook function.
For example, the school function is returning by value.
So it's a better value.
But Max year is returning by reference.
So it's really value difference.
It's also in a very similar way.
Things in C++ like Getline as it is tier one equals or two plus plus it.
All of this one's an operator overloading or returning Bio-Reference.
So all of these guys are l value.
That's all.