Let's continue more details about the difference between them.
Remember, we went to an operator overloading, introduced to the class, my beer and what I care here
more about two things, the prefix operator plus plus and the most fixed operator plus, plus.
Remember the prefix operator plus plus would returning by reference.
However, that was the fixed operator was returning by value.
This means the return, as we said, from this function by reference.
So this return is an early value, but the return from here is a right value.
And remember the operator plus plus here.
Why is it returning by value.
Because it first take a Cobbe from the current class, then we are incrementally or internally incrementing
the object, then returning Akabi this return.
It is in the diskless.
It's a different copy.
However, here we do not have a cubie.
We are returning actually the object itself again to be used in further operations.
So overall, this is a return by reference is Anila value.
This is a return by value.
This is a we are value.
Let's define here variable EHP and then some C equals two times E-Plus five.
This is a normal expression, a temporary value.
So it is a b r value expression.
If I did something like sea equal air plus plus the ER plus plus here is a B R value expression.
However, if I did something like Last Plus Equal, then this is an L value expression, so this is
a mistake plus plus E is an L value expression y very similar to the logic of the class that we just
mentioned.
The E-Plus was here.
The boost effects.
This is returning by value.
So it should be R expression, but E is returning by reference so that if we changed the E here it will
be changed.
It is an L value expression.
Now, the value here equals then we usually do, right sentosa this way, because it is used to incremented
than assigning to 10, if you try to do something like abler plus equals 10.
This would be a combination error.
Why?
Because on the left side of of the equal sign, an expression that is B are value, so it will not come
by.
So the moral of that is A plus plus is a PR value.
However, plus plus A is a lift.
The value expression.
Let's see the difference when it comes to objects, not the primitives.
I'm defining my beer as V of one and two and then I'm saying here blood must be equal.
My beer of three and ten.
Now, this is a.
A return to Bio-Reference, so it is an 11 and I can see plus must be the Brent, so it's going to print
for and the and 11.
So not that he had this plus plus is useless.
So the actual actual value from here would be the three and the 10.
The plus plus B from here will be useful and then it would be incremented to quarantine.
So far so good, so straight forward.
This plus plus B is very similar to this plus plus eight.
It is a trick.
If you did something like plus B plus plus equals my bit of two hundred and three hundred.
First of all, it's going to combine.
But notice here, the corresponding one didn't come by in C++.
The the the the rule about the birth defects operator is for comparison error only for primitives,
but it's going to work for the objects.
As as you know, the plus plus, plus plus here is returning at.
Could be returning a copy of B. So actually the the the copy is going to be assigned to the 200 and
300.
This means it is useless and has no effect.
If you tried here to print that, we were going to close it again and then print the value would be
five and 12, not two hundred and three hundred and one again.
Why B plus plus is returning by value.
So what is return is something temporary in the memory is going to be assigned to 200 or 300 and just
gone in the memory.
So it has no effect.
So here is a bit confusing for for two reasons.
As I said, the first is it doesn't compile because the rules in C++ for the primitive is different
from the objects.
And the second one that this statement has no effect at all.
The only effect that you see here is that the original three and the ten, the original three, four
and 11 are going to be incremented.
But this assignment itself has no value.
The hint that I would like you mainly to get from this slide and the reason behind it, some expressions
on primitives might be different from operator overloading.
If you are if you overloaded operators, what might not combine in the primitives might combine it or
behave in a different way.
Let me give you an example.
If we wrote something like eight times for equal G, let's say that A4 and G are primitives.
This will not compile because eight times before is A is a, b r value.
It has no identifiable at this.
It will not work.
However, imagine that A is a is a class for example, that overloads the multiplication such that the
return of this statement is an object written by reference.
Now this statement is going to come by, so it could be an L value under the operator.
So the model of that, as I said, is just to differentiate between the behavior of primitives comparing
to the objects when it comes to operator.
The second thing that I would like to highlight here is about the arrays and the pointers.
Array names are not modifiable values.
They are a name.
That's why they are a value.
And as you know, they are they are not modified.
But you can adjust if you try to say array equal reference X. It will combine error because you cannot
modify the array.
Array is is is recidivate in the memory in a specific way.
And you cannot just remove it.
You can create a pointer B and assign it to the IRS.
Now, pointing to the value of your.
You cannot say B plus one equals three, because B plus one itself is an expression of A, B or value.
However, we can say as three B plus one equals 10, the extra is that the reference operator, the
TEQSA, the addressee it and go to the content, bring its address and be ready to assign something
of it.
Here are new cable rules.
The first rule is the extra recovery to hear the different single convert the B-R value to an end value.
So Nieblas one is and B are value.
The S3 could convert it to an L value.
That's why this line combines on the other side the difference.
Operator convert an L value to be our value.
So they are working in an opposite way.
If you define here and integrate equal ten and assigning the pointer to the difference of a itself is
an L value when you apply the difference over it.
The result of this expression is a b r value.
Here, if you try to say be equal, a reference of eight plus one, this will not work because E-Plus
one itself is a better value and the difference is expecting an L value to convert it to be a plus one.
So it's going not it will not work in a similar way.
If you try to say you reference equal 40, it would not work because reference to A is a B R value.
So keep in mind this couple of rules to help you.
If you try to say integer point or B two equal ten, this is would combine error because the pointer
here is expecting an address to be used, not a primitive this way.
The only exception for this rule, the only literal exception is a C string literal.
The old style of character applies here.
If you say character pointer equal, Mustafa is going to come by because this is string, although it
is literal, it is actually Internet NRA.
So it's very similar to the line here.
If you try to define a string reference erev to equal Mustaffa, this will not come by for the same
reason that we know about them.
Referred to here is an uncanny valley reference, but Mustaffa itself is a better value, so you will
not be able to assign them.
Remember, a string is a is an object.
Here we can definitely assign something like l value and we are value tokenized value difference.
This is a bit a special case.
That's all about the value versus the our values in the very simple case.
Remember that the LRR value, the dollar value, something that has an idea, something that has identifiable
address or in a very simple way, it's something that has a name.
The buyer value on the other side is something that is temporary and it has no identity.
Going back to the scene here, we have this or value that was in the past, as simple as what is on
the right side.
But now we we saw a lot of details that we could be our value.
Most of it is actually just our value because the value here it is the beer and the glass.
For these two things, we also reduced the value, which is mainly has a name X value is something that
is most much more constrained.
It also has an identity and have another feature that will talk about it later, which is the movability.
We can move it.
X value is for an exit buyer.
It's a very narrow type and it's here in the intersection of these two things.
Most visual value and our value are now like a high level concepts, but the actual primary values are
these three categories that it.