So far, we were using things that we already know and plus the integer or the value, the value difference,
the daily value reference, they are value.
All of them are actually what you used to use, what you can figure out by yourself if it will combine
or not.
Now, we are coming closer to the reason behind explaining all of these concepts about value and our
value that we do not see a real consequence for them.
So far, the R value difference is a new type of reference that has been introduced in the modern C++.
When we define something like Integer A equals 10 and then we take integer reference variable for this
variable.
We call this one and only value difference.
And one of our rules is the only value difference binds only to an entire value.
The word binds here.
I always like to think of it like connect or assign something.
So this one has to be an L value to be assigned here because this guy you need an address.
I can define an expression like integrity equal two times one D in value, two times plus one is A B
or value.
Now what is happening behind the scene in these three lines?
First of all, some temporary location in the memory is going to be created.
The value of two times E plus one will be computed and put in the temporary location.
And what is more important here, this value is going to be copied to the address of T.
After that, this temporary location will be lost and after some time it will be destroyed from the
memory.
Now, the stimulus was introduced and you reference what we call our value reference, which is simply
a reference also like this guy reference, but now to a temporary object.
We use this double ampersand annotation, which we call the R value reference operator.
Now, using the R value reference operator, we use something like integer reference reference, some
name equal two times the Iblis one.
This is now our value reference.
What does this mean?
It means that as following create in the memory some temporary location, compute your value to Iblis
one and put it in the term.
So far, so same.
Now, instead of cabbing the term value to our one, we are going to put the address of this Temba location
in our one without an extra Kobie.
And this mean we avoided one step.
Imagine that what was in the right side was a very heavy object.
In the normal case, we should copy the whole object from the right to the left.
But now, instead of all of this be all, what we are doing is pointing to the address location of this
guy.
So what is the intuition behind that?
If this temporary value is going to be destroyed soon, why just letting it be destroyed?
Why not taking directly its address and make use of it instead of doing the Koby's tab?
So this is the old model of the R value difference.
It is there to avoid us unnecessary copies.
Our value reference are all about the performance.
You can write your code in this way.
It just a bit slower comparing to this way.
So again, the model of that, this is a temporary exhibition and all this time we copy it to the left
side.
Now we don't copy it.
We just use its address and put it here in our one and we don't remove it in the memory this way.
We are extending the lifetime of this expression and using it here to be more bounded to the Erwan.
The neural here is the R value difference binds only to our values, while the value references bind
only to the value.
In other words, he doesn't value the right side.
Here must be an L value.
And here on the right side, the right side must be and we are value.
It cannot be left to value.
Remember, the whole goal of that guy is to look to this, to take this address instead of the cabbing.
So this guy already has an address and it is there with us.
But this way, its address and its content might be destroyed soon.
So let's just keep it with us for now.
This is a story about the R value difference.
Let's see the effect of that.
Let's say that we have two functions here.
If one and if two and we are overloading them.
And we have year X and reference Y and integrate X is a L value, and the value of that guy is a value
reference.
And the guy and this is a constant value.
But remember, X and Y and Z themselves are just L values because we have names.
OK, we'll come back to this point later.
Now, if we try to call, if one with X, if one with X X a year is an L value.
So it's going to match F of integer references.
If you try to call Y again, it will match into a reference.
Say, if you try to code with that again, it's going to match your reference.
So far, so straightforward.
If you try to call with ten, which is a p r value, it's also going to match with the reference A we
should which you should be able to recognize this by yourself.
It is good or it is we are value, it matches the Kooris division, otherwise it matches the reference.
This is these are the rules of C++.
It is a new thing.
Now, the difference between if one and if two, if it is supporting an extra function that the right
value difference.
So it has left the value difference.
It has consistently value difference and it has also a b r value difference.
Now, if you try to call if it was X, which is an L value, it will go, it will call left with the
L value difference.
If you try to call with Y, the Y is going to call the Y is reference.
Y is reference.
Sorry, this one should be the the, the second is the difference.
I guess so if you try to call with the Z, Z is.
Z is as sorry, it should call also the inter-group, why should the reference differentiated Caraco
the cornerstone?
Because it's incredibly valuable.
Z here is a cornerstone value, so it can be different.
So far, so good.
This three lines are the same as this three lines.
It is a different melody.
Line 19, a line twenty four.
If you try to call.
If it was ten then is a better value.
The function that will be called is a function here in line in this one with a B are very different.
So it is one more matching or binding rule in C++.
If you are calling a function with a R value, the one that will be match it first, if it exists,
will be the the R value reference function.
The question here, why is this new Y to give more priority to our value reference, because our value
reference can avoid us an extra copies.
So if you provided us with an overloaded version, the take or value reference are we are calling you
first because you probably have better handling for the temporary values instead of losing them, you
are taking the reference behind the scene.
So this is a model of this slide.
If you are calling a function with or value reference, it will match the first to the function that
has our value.
OK, what if there is no other value reference?
It will match one of what exists or compile it of this is impossible.
Now, let's go to a very tricky concern we have here in reference reference R-1, Equal 10.
So far, so good you can bring to our one.
You can bring to its address.
You can bring it to size.
Now, I would like you to notice the following.
What is the relationship between our one and integral reference reference R one, this would take us
to what we mentioned very early in the lectures when we say every expression has a type and belongs
to a value category.
These are two independent capabilities.
We have what we call a variable type and a value category.
They're the variable type of R one is value reference, but the value category of our one is L value.
Remember the rule, everything that has a name is er is an L value.
This is its value category regardless of its type.
That way many people don't get that is the because the all the time assume the variable type would be
like the value category.
So when you are seeing here integral reference reference are when you're saying oh this is our value
reference.
So our, what is our value difference.
This is wrong.
The type of our value R one is a variable type of r r value difference, but its category is the L value
value category is B's.
The unavailability of the expression which is here we have an expression that has a name.
So R one is an L value.
When when you see here, when I say integer string be equal reference of our one.
If our one is in value, this expression should then compile, it will compile because r one is er l
value, it's a value category is l value.
This is extremely important to keep in mind in a very similar way.
If you define here integer X equals one and you say integer difference Y equals X, the time of this
expression is L value difference, the variable type, but the value category of X is L value.
And before this is you never have a problem with that because in a way both of them are value.
So you didn't you didn't you didn't need to keep in mind that the are two independent probabilities.
But starting from this slide with knowing about the R value difference, you have to keep in mind that
the variable type is different from the value category.
Let's see some consequences of that.
Let's say that we have here for functions.
If one F2, F3, F4 and we are providing the possible for cases busingye value busingye reference using
the value reference or the R value difference.
Now we are defining variables here, X, Y and Z and W if you thought about that here, the X and Y
and Z and W, all of them are value categories of left value.
But the types are different, the type of this statement is integral here, the type of this guy is
like the interior, the type of this guy is the value reference, the type of this guy is our value
reference.
So let's think of that value and value category and value.
Why is the added value add value to make it easier for you?
What's really tricky here, zied is l-a value as very category.
Dabu is value as a value category.
Now let's call if one was X, Y, Z, W, 10.
There they are straightforward.
All of them will be called in.
Some of them would be Matchett.
As we learned before, if you try to call F2 with X and Z and W, it's going to work well.
But if you try to kill effort with Y or if you do it, then it will complain, as we already learned
before and in a very similar way.
If we already discussed that before, it is the it is what I care about it.
If you try to call was X and Y, it will not bind and this is also we know about that because X is an
L value.
And why is it relevant?
It also is an L value, so it will not bind.
But the error message here is interesting.
Their message is we cannot bind our value difference to the value.
Weight is indeed a difference in value difference.
No, it is only value only.
As we said, the more clearer case, if you try to bind, if it was debu, it would say cannot bind
our value reference to any value.
If you do not understand that variable type, not equal value category, you will never be able to understand
the error message of line twenty seven because it would be for you what this is all value reference
and why cannot you buy in.
Why are you claiming that W is an L value.
Because every variable name is an L value.
Every variable name is an L value because it has an identity and it is identifiable in the memory variable
type, the equal value category.
Let's test your understanding.
I would like to read this quote and to think and discuss the output of this could give yourself five
minutes thinking deeper to make sure that you got it.
If we try to go call, if we do with X, the value of X has an L value.
So if we do, X is going to normally call.
If we do straightforward, if we try to call, if it was ten, then is a B R value.
So it's going to match the R value difference straight forward if you try to call if one with X X is
of value.
So if one will match here, line it if one straight forward and if one is calling, if we do with E
is hella value.
So it's going to match F to straight forward.
Now the trick, if you try to call if one with ten ten is A, B, R value, B are value.
So if one will match yea if one with reference straight forward.
Now if two, if one is calling, if two which one would call.
If you say it will call F2 with reference then you didn't get the message that the value type isn't
equal.
The value category E is has a variable type of reference.
Right.
Value R value reference but it is L value if it all a here is going to call F to hear this one, the
normal one.
Why.
Because A is of any value and this is alarming.
If we have some good handwriting in the memory for F one here as an, as a, as a, as a way to avoid
copying.
But now calling if we do here is calling with the L value vision with the R value version.
Now we lost the advantage of the R value differences here.
So this is a big problem because if one can avoid extra copies, but if it will fail in extra copies,
that's why later we learn about the S to the move and perfect forwarding to solve this problem as an
extra.
I define the here and r r value reference of X twenty and I just got here.
F2 with X are in a very similar way, x R will call F2 because Exer is an L value.
It's a value category.
The last observation here that I would like you to keep in mind is as following, let's say that we
have defined these four values.
We have a variable global 20.
We have a function name to be our value, which is us return 10.
So it's actually a better value.
We have to function the returning reference.
So the Aurélie value functions.
The first one is returning the global variable.
So returning to a global variable is OK.
But the second one is returning is returning reference to a local variable.
This variable will be destroyed after the function Terminix.
So this is a very wrong style of coding.
The timber here will be destroyed.
There is another function named X evalu the function has a temporary variable to equal, then you cannot
return it by itself because this is now like integer reference reference are equal to this is binding
reference value to it will fit.
You cannot also in a similar way bind it ruthlessly.
The only thing that you can return here within this scope is to return or return from a competition
perspective.
This would work.
However, this also is as long as the value to function.
Why there are value differences are just the differences, like an L value.
If you try to return the reference of the index value ten here.
This guy is returning address of something that will be destroyed after the function return.
So this is very problematic.
So don't assume that given that the R value reference is pointing to the address of a memory function
here is going to keep it.
It doesn't have a control over that.
If we return it, this then will be destroyed in the memory.
So now the reference is pointing to something wrong and this will cause a runtime error.
So be very careful reference, a reference.
It can be destroyed.
You don't have a control over that.
There's one more interesting thing that I would like to say about Lione line 16.
Sorry for that, which is returning 10.
What is the value type of this returning statement?
It is of type integer reference reference.
So it is an R value difference.
But what is the value category of this line?
It is returning ten, which is a temporary value.
Now, this is interesting.
The value category here is our value, which is definitely has no name.
So now we have here and our value reference that is linked to an L value.
So the model of that is our value reference can be an early value and can be an R value.
I mean, the assigning here, looking to line twenty three.
This is an extra three.
Yeah.
Looking to line three here.
The this guy here has an M right.
So AC3 here is an M, so AC3 is an L value by itself.
But this guy here it has no name.
So it is an R evaluator.
So the model of that are value reference can be both L value and R value.
I mean as a as a type, I think I'm done with explaining for now with the value, our value.
We should move to explaining the semantics.
I went extra miles comparing to many others when it comes to explaining the value.
I hope I made it easy as much as I could.
I tried to be informal, but meanwhile maintaining correctness of the concepts as much as I could.
You are highly advised to do some readings.
This value category.
It is very nice.
I think the very that the first four links here are very helpful to give it.
They will involve some talk about what is X value, which is just corresponding to this function, but
you will not understand easily at the moment.
That's it.