In this video, you will see one of these very strong reasons and use it for the R value differences.
So far, we learned what is an L value, which is mainly something that has an identity, has a name,
for example, and we learned about the P r values, which are temporary, that will be destroyed soon
in the memory.
We knew that 11 year difference binds always to an L value, and our very reference binds always to
our value.
We learned that the Arborio difference avoid us unnecessary copies that might have it in the memory,
which might be very good.
We learned a very important to note that the variable time doesn't equal the value category.
We learned this golden rule.
Every variable name is elder value, regardless of its type.
And also we learned something interesting about overloading functions when there is an R value difference
and provided the R value reference when is provided is Matchett first if provided because it allows
more efficient processing.
Today we'll see one more strong usage for the R value difference.
Recall we talked before the Kobe constructor, something like complete, simply a reference because
there is an optional if a class has pointers.
We said before that the default copy constructor will just copy the pointers and this is a big problem
because it will create a lingering pointer point across.
The first destructor will destroy the data, but the second will try to destroy data that already destroyed.
And we said that the copy constructor is our way to provide a DB copy of the data.
But there is a notice here in in many in many codes.
The copy constructor is actually called a lot of times.
And there are two cases here.
You are either copying from an L.A. value.
Or either coming from and out of value, if you are coming from an early.
There is no way except just copying the data from it.
However, what if you are coming from another value?
We know that this our value data will be destroyed soon in the memory, any way that we can make use
of them to avoid unnecessary copying of data.
This is what more semantic will tell us about.
That's it for an administration.
I have here the middle class, but I switched it from two years to two printers.
Please take a minute to read the whole class here.
I'm showing here the copy constructor, a default constructor and also the set first function.
Notice it's a structure here, a check first for the pointer and we have instructor.
Let's now start to use this class.
I'm creating here a vector V and I started to push my beer line.
Fifty one.
I would like to stop the video for the minute and trace all the Allwood that would come from this single
step.
OK, this is a bit tricky, so would like to think about that.
It is what's going to happen, first of all.
Notice that my beer three and six is a right value.
It is tamburri.
It has no name when you try to create this constructor to integers or we are going to be created from
this set first and second in using the line you enter.
After that, you are calling the function to push back in the vector.
So the vector have to call the copy constructor to Cobbe.
You provided Meyerbeer.
To its internal element in the array.
So this is going to create other two copies in the deed.
Now we have two objects here.
We have the object that we best improve here and we have the object that was Cobbett to it inside the
vector itself in the destruction, we're going to destroy, destroy the first object and then we are
going to destroy their second object.
Overall, there were two copies and there were two deleting.
Now let's see how the semantic might help us to improve this problem.
That is what we call a move constructor.
The idea is very simple, we know that the constructor is something like my beer reference.
But remember, the constructor and the structure and the operators are just functions so we can overload
them.
So now let's provide another constructor.
But this time we'll use the R value reference and end here or reference reference as this is a function
overloading.
Now, if you best tamburri object and r value, the function with the R value reference will be Matchett
first.
So this is so far interesting.
We we call this a constructor.
We will know right now what we, what we call it a constructor.
I would if you would like to take a step and think about yourself, how can we make use of this constructor
to make it more efficient.
Go ahead.
But anyway, I'm going to say right now, we will see how can we avoid the extra creation and Cubby's
for the pointers and data using this our value reference constructor.
The idea is following.
Instead of cabbing the data from the BEA, we know that B will be destroyed soon in the memory.
So the idea is let's remove its appointers to my object and steal them and just not them.
So we are going to do what we are going to take the the pointers in this guy to us just could be the
pointer themselves, not copying the data and then set the pointer internal pointer of this object to
null.
Then what then.
This way.
I took a copy from the whole data but without really copying them it just the reference of them.
And when we said them to null then this guy in the destructor will do nothing.
So this way we skip the akabi and we skip that delete.
However, notice that it now the structure of my beer should be very careful.
You have to check first if something is not pointed or not.
Let's see some code for that.
This is the normal cubicle constructor, 915 in line to any we are providing the overloaded constructor
with the reference reference, which we call a move constructor.
We are going to make exactly two steps to implement the move constructor.
The first step will be the pointer addresses.
So I have a first pointer I'm going to take after the first pointer here and taking the other the second
pointer here.
I now steal the pointer of the other guy.
The second step, I am removing the data from the other guy.
Now, comparing this with the move constructor in the constructor, we actually create a new entity
for this guy and copy the data and create a new entity and could be the data.
But now we are just moving the pointer from here to here and removing the pointer from this guy looking
to the destructor.
The what happened in line 34 is we are checking first if this pointer exist or not.
If not exists, we are going to remove it.
This is now very important because we still the data of this guy.
We don't just want it to go and say, hey, delete first pointer, which, you know, is not worth checking.
First line thirty four.
That's why it is very important before deleting anything to double check if it doesn't exist or not,
I'm adding here an interesting check.
I'm saying if the first pointer is the null and the second pointer is not, please inform us that this
already has been freed somehow, which is typical here.
Let's try to see what's going to happen when we try to use this code like the first time we are basing
the our value here and our value will be created a constructor for it, which will create two integers.
But as now we are basing on our value, the move constructor would be called and there would be no creation
or cabbing for this guy.
So we just still it's a appointers for our Boynton's.
After that, the temperature data will go to be destroyed, but it will notice that it's appointer data
is already null at the point the Ergun and then the original V object here, the object inside the V
will be deleted.
If you noticed, we created only two integers and we removed only to integers.
There is no extra copy for the pointer here due to the date of the pointers and there is no delete for
them on the other side.
If you try to have a B one here and B two from the one, B one is an L value.
So this guy will call the copy constructor.
So this guy is temporary.
It will go the move constructor and this guy will call the copy constructor and this guy will steal
the data instead of doing an actual copy in a very similar way, we can provide the assignment operator
very similar logic.
The right hand side of an assignment operator can be something like B one equals B two, which is an
L value we have to copy anyway, or it can be a temporary value, like B an equal number of something.
So we overload the assignment operator, which will be have higher, higher priority in matching and
we steal the data for us, which is going in a way to be destroyed very soon.
So here is the old assignment operator side.
You check first if it is the same object or not.
If it isn't, you are going to if the other guy is a null, you are going to set first.
You are going to sit second.
Remember, sit first and second were written such that a check first.
If the first point that exists or not, if it doesn't exist, it creates it then copied it.
So this is a good thing for us.
Now the assignment operator here is going to do the following.
First of all, you need to free your own data, you need to free your own pointers because you are going
to take the other side if the other side is not.
You need to take it.
So anyway, we have to free our own data first.
The second we have to steal the appointers.
The third, we have to nullify the the pointers that we that we have.
Again, you notice there is a big difference between these two guys.
This guy here is going to do a lot of copies if the object is very heavy.
But this guy is just stealing the printers, which will be removed soon.
And then just to notify them here
in terms of cooling, let's say that we define here be one which will call the constructor, then we
say want equal Meyerbeer, this is an R value.
So the MBT one would be constructed, then the assignment or value would be called to steal the data
and the destructor would notice that the data is already moved and then another distractor.
So we don't make extra copies on the other side.
If you say something like B to equal we, this will call the assignment value case.
Let's try the blusterous operators for fun here.
Remember, the prefix operator is returning by reference so it doesn't really value the operator plus
plus here is returning by value.
So it is an R value the operator plus plus for the specifics.
Have to call the copy constructor in a way to make a copy for it.
This is an L value here.
Let's make a usage.
Now if we have B1 and B2, if we say B2 equal blu's must be one.
The plus plus B one is an value.
The return the is reference.
So it's going to call the assignment to DeLaval it if you call B1 plus plus the plus is returning this
by this is returning now by value which is assignment or value.
That's all I would like you to keep this in mind.
There are five things to consider when you create a class that has internally appointed three of them
are must you are a master to provide a copy constructor, assignment operator and instructor to handle
the data to avoid both memory leaks and dangling pointers for efficiency.
You are highly recommended to provide move constructor and move assignment operator.
This would be Matchett first for our values and will provide you a way to have a more efficient code.
Right now with the SDL is fully complete with mathematics.
So when you provide the assignment, the move semantic, you are making use of them to have a great
efficient good.
Here is one more covid.
If you try some of the code by yourself to play with the semantics, you would notice sometimes even
the copy constructor and the constructor has it because we say this before when we're studying the classes.
This is something called return value optimization.
The compiler do things behind the scene for the return values only, not for the function calls to return
the bodies, only to optimize things behind the scene.
The compiler is doing a lot behind the scenes that can be heard much faster.
So if you didn't see some of the output, then this is just because of the return value optimization.
That's it.