We will study the esteemable function, which is a very important function, and you will notice some
dependencies on next sections on it.
Recall we we we provided this could before and we tried to trace if one of 10 within is Ebby our value.
We notice normally that the barrier would be for another value difference.
So that then is matching if one of E and then we are trying to call off five to eight.
But remember that as we have a name here, then this is an L value.
So if it is going to match the effort with the L value difference.
But this isn't what we intended.
We wish, Dave, if we do a really cool the effort with another value different, I would like you to
try to guess a very simple solution actually that can work to this problem.
How can we force this function to call this function?
Give yourself like a minute thinking.
Here is a hint, if you couldn't do it by yourself, try to think about some casting that can end up
with this eight to be really calling this one.
As we know in C++, we can do a lot with the with with with many, several custom techniques, so we
simply can't ask a can cost to the value reference to our video reference.
If you tried to do something like static integer references, reference X. you actually got accustomed
variable to our value difference because eventually X and we are here like X here or be here are just
R R just L values.
So if you costing them they are, they had the address here.
They are addressed here.
We just to market them in the memory that these guys now are our value differences, which is an indicator
that you might be trying to move them or try to steal the resources or so we will know later about that.
So the the more of that here, because I think the variable is goes users to switch it from an L value
to our value difference.
But remember, this doesn't change anything in the memory.
For example, they would have the same address in the memory.
Nothing, nothing changes.
Remember crusting just here like it might affect the value, but otherwise we are still referring to
the same thing in the memory.
So going back to our code, if we did something like F2 of static, just integer reference a reference
to a then this guy is now casted again as an R value because that the customer return for us or value
difference.
So now the return here is an R value different.
So again, this is going to match if it do different.
Now it's your turn and Kersting here are from X and if one picks are, what is the code, which which
function would be called.
It would be if one if you remember X is a name and the name is the name of the value.
We know that this is counterintuitive, but keep that in mind.
Literally, our function, instead of just making it on the here, it's a bit ugly.
That's right.
Our our move function, which you take reference X custo and return for us reference, reference.
Notice that this function is returning a reference, but however, it is a reference to to a barometer.
So this is very easy because we said like when you when you are returning from a function, a reference
to a local variable, it would be a problem.
But this isn't a local bar.
This is actually the argument that we send.
So now here we are using the what are you doing here?
The same function that we are using the same logic.
But just we are calling the function now there there's an interesting thing here that will come back
later to discuss more about it this year.
So originally an L value.
When you cast it and you return reference reference, you are actually moving like marking it that it
can be moved internally.
You can still it's a memory, but it certainly has an identity, has an address.
This is what we call an X value.
And Xibalba is something that has an identity which here like we know the address of this eight, but
also no market in the memory was movable by this is that, of course.
So this is called the X value and would come back to that one again with.
Finally, instead of writing our own move, this is what is is the function listed function is a generic
implementation that internally doing a static costing from the eight to integrate reference reference
or from some object to object reference reference that set.