In case you wonder why to learn programming or why C++, I would like to share with you some of my thoughts.
First of all, learning programming sharpens your problem-solving skills.
This is a bit similar to mathematics.
When you practice math, your math
solving skills is growing up. In a similar way,
programming has some kind of connection, something that we call "the problem solving" or "computational
solving" skills.
And what is more sensible for you might be real-life applications, like, you have a lot of applications on
your mobile.
And you might think that I would like to build my small application or so.
When you learn programming, you have a much better chance in understanding the technologies that are
around you, and understanding some of the logic behind building them.
Generally speaking, in our career, we are one of the highest-paid guys.
So this might be also one good reason for you to learn programming.
And it is really fun, and many, many kids even enjoy it.
There is one of the interesting things in programming.
The programming competitions like ICPC for guys in university and IOI
for younger guys. It is really much fun, a lot of connections to build and travel.
You might also have a dream to work in big companies like Google and Facebook.
So, programming is your way to that.
About C++ itself. C++ is a really powerful programming language.
It has a lot of paradigms.
If I have to describe the language in a single word, I will say it's complex.
C++ language is really a huge programming language, and this is a great opportunity to learn a lot about
programming concepts.
Also, the language is scalable, fast, and portable.
It gives you a lot of control over hardware-level things which isn't available in other programming languages.
One of the most usage scenarios for C++ is when it comes to high performance, when you have to do a
lot of things very fast.
That is why C++ is in the industry and will remain there because there are some kind of applications
that C++ is the core player in them.
Fairly enough, C++ isn't the most important language among the programming languages,
it exists.
It's a fundamental part of the market, but it's still very critical  to learn. As an educational language,
C++ is one of the best programming languages to learn.
I'm still, like, 12 years so far and
I'm still telling my students this is the best language to start learning with.
An interesting thing about C++ is that when you learn it, and you come to move to other programming languages,
you will find it a very smooth process, but you will find the reverse isn't true. To some extent,
C++ is like a superset of C, it also has similarities with Java and C#. These are other programming languages.
To some extent, C++ is ranked somewhere between three to six, among many other indexing websites.
A little bit about the history of C++,
let's call what is before C++ 2011, the classical C++.
This represents the core syntax of C++. In C++11,
there was like a very big jump in additions and in syntax to C++, making the language really look
like a very modern programming language.
C++14 is more like refining to C++11. You can think of 14 like, this is where 11 should be,
but we need time to improve things.
C++17 and 20 and so on,
every one of them should be like one further enhancement to the language.
Since C++11, every three years we have, like, one round to change the language.
So three years, 14, three years, 17, three years, 20. We expect the next will be 23,
26 and so on.
OK, so one relevant concern here about programming, like, who could learn programming and how hard is that?
Programming,
it doesn't need math.
So if I don't know math or I'm not good at mathematics, I still can learn programming.
You notice now, kids everywhere are learning programming.
Here is what you need to know.
Learning programming is very, very close to learning a new, different human language that is a bit
very far from your language.
Like, for example, if you are coming from an Arabic or English background and trying to learn
Chinese. There is a gap in symbols and in the structure of the language.
It will take time.
So in the beginning, it's typically a bit weird.
But once you get it, get used to it, then everything is OK.
I would say everyone has to pass with these three stages.
You are very confused
in the beginning, you would like to, like, just burn your computer and then everything gets in the right
track.
So, take it easy.
Understand that the beginning is typically hard.
One of the unique things in this course is that a lot of my students highlighted that they
found that learning programming is a bit easier in my own style.
That is it.