There are three-audience for this course. The first type of guys who have no programming background
at all. There are no assumptions in this course at all.
I started from the very fundamentals and the very basics.
This course is going to save your time because the course has very short lectures.
I intend to make it very, very, very direct to the point. I avoid making the content very long and
repetitive, just to have like, "Oh, this course looks like a forty hours course".
It's just, to the point. I also focus on the skills.
So after you finish the course, you will not have to take another course to maybe enhance your information and your skills.
The other case, for the course is the following, it is very common for guys to have a programming course
if they enjoy it, but they discover after the course that they have weak skills.
This is very visible (when it comes to developing medium to large projects).
So, they discover that the overall-quizzes and overall-challenges were really very basic.
Also, sometimes even in different courses, the information sometimes is outdated or even missing important details.
So, sometimes you still have to take another course to enhance what is missing.
The third case, which is a bit tricky, if someone is already a good programmer, maybe have like ten
ten years of experience,
but he would like to do some refreshing on concepts, In this case-
maybe my course would be helpful.
For example, maybe some of the modern topics covered in the course, maybe an added value.
The best way is to just proceed with the content. Check it out and decide if this might be or is suitable for you
or not.
That is All. :)