The course has a bit specific teaching style, so I thought it worth sharing with you.
There are definitely a lot and a lot of complaints about other courses here or in universities.
So from my experience, I learned a lot about how to teach things.
The first thing is to know I usually differentiate between the major concepts and minor concepts.
Normally, courses are explained like unit by unit, explaining the complete concepts of a specific unit
with all of its details, which typically involve a lot of major and minor concepts.
And these minor concepts typically just cause a lot of puzzling for the students.
In my case, you would find me explaining some major concepts in a unit and delaying some of the concepts
to another round.
For example, you will notice that there is a unit named "More on Fundamentals".
It's like number twenty-four or so in the content.
So even in something like after twenty-four units, I'm going back to explain some
of the very basic and the very fundamentals of the course.
The reason behind that is they aren't mandatory at all.
You can skip them for a lot of time and focus on the major concepts.
So be careful from that. I delay concepts.
I intended to do that.
You also find me usually going directly to the point with practice.
So this is more of a bottom-up style.
Like, I go directly to the point that I would like to explain, typically highlighting some syntax and
then in between, highlighting the needed theory.
So it's more of very practical and this fits more with programming.
The other very critical point when it comes to showing the code, there are two styles.
The very common one is, live-coding style, where someone is starting to write the code line by line
in front of you.
This is very good from the engaging point of view,
but there are a few drawbacks.
For example, the content is usually longer than necessary.
Also, sometimes there are mistakes.
So, one has to make editings, which might be not suitable for everyone. On the other side,
The way that I go with it is ready-code snippets.
You would find me always pasting a picture here with the whole content directly, and I'm just explaining
it.
The advantage of that is really fast and the content is clear. The lecture
that is five minutes in code snippets might be like 12 in the live-coding style.
There is a single disadvantage with that.
To some extent, it might be less engaging than the other style.
You cannot gain the advantage of everything. You will not find
the lecture is short and still is live-coding style.
This is very rare and very hard to achieve.
So this is my way. This is how I see myself saving my time and other guys' time.
Also, most of the time I have this strategy like I explain something. I try to administrate
something through some easy to medium, sometimes hard to practice.
And this is typically followed by a homework.
So this should be like a common style during the whole content.
That is it. :)