I have a belief that this course is way beyond many other courses that exist here or even on other platforms.
And I would like to go a little more about that. So that, the overall picture is clear.
There are mainly four skills that I claim to be the goal of this course.
The first one is: (1-The Programming Skills Course).
And this means that you will be familiar with the (C++) syntax.
You can read it, you can write it,
and so on. Fairly, in any course, you will find this skill, like typically you see a lot of code during a big course.
So this is fair enough in every course.
The second skill here is: (2-Problem Solving Skill), and the problem-solving is more about computational
problems.
I know that this is vague at the moment, but when you start with exercising in the course, you will
understand more what is computational problems and why it is important.
The programming questions in the coming in the problem-solving part are mainly coming from my long experience
in competitive programming as a coach.
This skill I would say,
I'm not aware of any course here on the platform that is administrating it at all.
That skill is very important.
There are two courses that are named "The Data structures" and "Algorithms", and you will typically find
students when they are moving to these courses, especially "Algorithms",
they find a lot of difficulties in understanding and tackling the content.
And the reason behind that is they lack the problem solving or what we call "Algorithmic Solving Skills".
In this course,
I am trying to set up a good base for you to be qualified for the next courses.
Notice that, when we say mastering a skill, it might be a bit like maybe confusing or the
guys got it wrong.
There is no claim here that you are going to be a superhero,
OK. Let's be honest about that.
By that we mean you would be qualified due to the amount of problems that you saw to go to the next courses
and
like finding them very smooth courses for you. If you are aware of something like "codeforces" community,
you will find that codeforces division(2)-(A)-problems are smooth for you.
But this course doesn't teach you algorithms, but it teaches you some of the fundamentals of the thinking
in computational problems.
And this is mainly by focusing on very ad-hoc problems.
So this is mainly what we mean by problem solving skills here.
The third skill is: (3-Project building skill), and you will find in most of the courses,
the projects that are provided are very small and typically maybe one, sometimes two.
Sometimes there is a claim of many projects, but they are all very close, very small and so on.
So students complain that they cannot even tackle something like three-hundred lines of code. In this
course,
there are at least six projects (two small ones), (two medium ones), and (two large ones) so far
at this moment.
And when I say large one, I am referring to something like I wrote in like one thousand three hundred
lines of code.
You typically would write it at least double of that.
So I hope that by doing these projects and comparing your code with my code, then you are improving a lot
your skill.
So this skill is highly enhanced
in this course. while it is partially administrated by others. The fourth skill is: (4-The Object-Oriented design skill)
In most, if not all, of the object-oriented programming courses,
people focus a lot on the syntax of the (OOP) and how to apply it.
But however, the reality about projects is about the design skill.
So for me to try to make this course more about design not just about the programming syntax,
I created and invented a lot of homework that tries to help you to really deeply understand
the concepts and try to apply different design principles and patterns that are embedded in the homework
and in the projects.
This skill is also rarely administrated by others.
Let's all remember when I say that we are going to administrate this skill,
I am mainly referring to practice and homework because this is how we really build the skills. With a four
administrated
skills, we have like a promise that courses such as (Data structures, Algorithms, Software Engineering,
Design Patterns),
you will have a very smooth start in them because you build a very fair background and very fair
skills to proceed with them. That is all. :)