One of the key aspects of this course is the amount of practice and homework relative to others.
There is only one way to build the skills.
And as people say: "Practice just Makes Perfect". As a teacher,
this is actually a two-edged sword.
Some students might like the idea that they have a lot of homework and they have a lot of practice,
so they are enjoying and learning, however.
And I had like thousands of my students during my career, many other students might get frustrated
for failing to solve the homework or the practice.
And this kind of guys would typically leave like one out of five stars with some comment.
So, like,  it would be a risk for a teacher to provide more and more homework and have more frustrated
students.
However, as someone with a passion for teaching, I really think I should take the risk. In many
other courses,
this might be cheated with just easy challenges.
But for me, I think the right way is to challenge you.
There is also another classical mistake when courses are very smooth in their explanation and
their examples and the students suddenly find that the homework is really very hard.
So, you would always find most of my lectures have a fair amount of practice first, then amount of homework
to solve this problem.
Now, I hope you hear to understand that when you come to tackle something that's hard, there
will be a high failure rate,
and this is very natural.
And everyone that you see successful in his career has already tackled a lot of hard problems and has already
failed a lot.
So,
you will notice the following, with most of the topics there are practice and the practice will be ranging
from easy to hard.
And this is mainly you will find it very common in the fundamental part
and in the (OOP) part.  I advise you before I explain the solution to stop the video, challenge yourself and
then listen to my solution.
And remember, you will have hard problems. In a similar way when it comes to the homework, you will
find easy to hard homework with my solutions. When it comes to the projects, I'm trying to provide like
a wide, diverse range of projects for you.
But again, many students might find it very problematic to start the project.
Now, how to handle the difficulties of that? When it comes to the medium and the hard challenges,
you will typically fail.
This is intended. I heard that from hundreds of my students.
There are two types of failures.
One failure is to fail to solve the problem.
But however, when you try to understand my solution, you manage to understand it, it might be a bit difficult,
but it could happen.
There is a case that is harder for the students and causes more frustrations that when you try to solve,
you fail and you try to understand my solution,
you also fail.
So many, many students just run away at this stage or get very frustrated.
I would like you to know that in most of the cases, if you fail to solve the practice and homework,
even if you drop the practice and homework, you can proceed from lecture to another.
In other words, if you failed to understand or even didn't like to solve a practice or homework of a specific topic,
you can always move to the next topic.
I'm making sure of the dependencies, to minimize them as much as I could.
OK, so how now to handle this hard homework?  How to be good?
This approach is something I learned in my life.
It is for this course and you can utilize it in many other things.
Give, first of all, a serious trial to what you are trying to solve as a practice as a homework.
I suggest something on average to be ~30 minutes, maybe 45, maybe 60.
There are two types of students, some of them who get bored after like five minutes of thinking, this
is very wrong.
You have to push up your skills up to 30 minutes.
And some of them like to keep tackling a problem like hours and hours.
But this isn't very practical because there is a huge amount of content in the course of study. After you tackle
a problem for like 30 minutes,
check out my solution,
even if you solved the problem. You will find usually my code is smarter and shorter than yours.
One of the common mistakes is to skip my solution because you think "Oh! I anyway solved it .".
No. Wait, wait a second.
My solution is intended.
You have to read it.
You have to put an effort in understanding it.
And this is part of your educational experience.
My code is
typically smarter and shorter
and there is a lot to learn from it.
So, don't skip it.
Put effort in understanding my solution, this would be very valuable.
What if you even couldn't understand the solution, as simple as, you are going to put what you couldn't solve
in your to-do-list. Keep going in the course and come back later.
And here is a surprising part,
you will notice that for some of what you couldn't solve, you now manage to solve it, and some
of what was really hard,
you manage now to understand more about it.
The more you go in the course and you go back again, you will find yourself
managing to solve more and more of the hard difficulties.
Even it could happen that you move to next courses in your career and you come back later and you solve
more and more of them.
So consider them as open challenges that you have to keep coming back and trying them and so on.
Please, Don't run away from the course because you find it hard.
And please be fair when it comes to rating the course, don't just like give me like (one star) because
you failed to solve something.
This is intended and this is expected.
And I met many of my students who eventually managed to solve most of the content. That is it. :)