Let's provide an overview for the content of this very in-depth course, we can say it consists mainly
of four components.
The first one is, The Programming Fundamentals.
This is close to Programming(1) level course in your university, it's covering mainly the fundamentals
of programming languages.
I know that these keywords at the moment might be puzzling, but they are representing the fundamental
concepts of programming language and actually in any programming language you will have to find them.
The second set of topics are a bit advanced topics in the language and like (pointers , STL and the
exception handling the details of the competition process itself and how to use the debugger).
The third component of this course is the object oriented programming, a very fundamental paradigm
to use in Software Engineering development.
The paradigm consists of a specific like six fundamentals concepts, representing the (OOP). One of the
very unique things in this course is that I embedded in the homework, a lot of design principles and
patterns, so that later when you go and study a course of design principles and design patterns, you
will have a very strong intuition and intuitive usage.
Why we need such a design patterns and why designing them in this way.
The fourth and very unique component in this course is a wide coverage to (C++) 11, 14 and 17.
I'm covering a lot of the important and even less important details.
I would say the majority of the courses here is just focusing on (C++ 11) with a minor exception.
So this course has a very wide and very deep coverage.
Definitely, modern (C++) is extremely huge.
So I'm trying to focus here on the very fundamental and the very important ones and also the less important
topics if you have interest in very, very narrow, specific topics.
Please use the outline to verify what exists and what doesn't.
And finally, there is an extensive set of quizzes, practice and homework and projects in this course
to make you really strong.
One of the very common complaints in courses, they lack the practice and the quizzes that would make
you really skilled in (C++) programming and ready for the next courses like Software engineering, Data structures
and Algorithms.
In terms of books, also, I would like to highlight about that, I would say the content is very deep.
Most probably you don't have to read the book, but in case, if you would like, there are two suggestions.
The first one is: (A First Book C++).
This book is very well written.
It would be very smooth reading.
But there is one problem here.
It's focusing on the classical (C++).
Classical (C++) is before (C++ 11).
It's still a good book.
Still covering a lot.
Feel free to buy it. But if you would like a much more modern choice, then you can go with( C++ How to program)
which is covering up to (C++ 14).
And this means a lot.
This book is very well written.
The guy who wrote it is really aware of software engineering and aware of industry.
So the book has a lot beyond that.
If you are done with this book and would like really then to learn more about (C++ 17)
you can search for Internet.
There are books that are dedicated only to cover (C++ 17) extra topics.
That's it! :)
Let's provide an overview for the content of this very in-depth course. We can say it consists mainly
of four components.
The first one is "The Programming Fundamentals".
This is close to Programming(1) level course in your university, it is covering mainly the fundamentals
of programming languages.
I know that these keywords at the moment might be puzzling, but they are representing the fundamental
concepts of programming language and actually in any programming language you will have to find them.
The second set of topics are a bit advanced topics in the language and like (pointers , STL, the
exception handling, the details of the compilation process itself, and how to use a debugger).
The third component of this course is "The Object Oriented Programming". A very fundamental paradigm
to use in Software Engineering development.
The paradigm consists of a specific like six fundamental concepts, representing the (OOP). One of the
very unique things in this course is that I embedded in the homework, a lot of design principles and
patterns. So that later when you go and study a course of design principles and design patterns, you
will have a very strong intuition and intuitive usage
why we need such a design patterns and why designing them in this way.
The fourth and very unique component in this course is a wide coverage to (C++) 11, 14 and 17.
I'm covering a lot of the important and even less important details.
I would say the majority of the courses here are just focusing on (C++ 11) with a minor exception.
So this course has a very wide and very deep coverage.
Definitely, modern (C++) is extremely huge.
So I'm trying to focus here on the very fundamental and the very important ones and also the less important
topics. If you have an interest in very, very narrow specific topics,
please use the outline to verify what exists and what doesn't.
And finally, there is an extensive set of quizzes, practice, homework, and projects in this course
to make you really strong.
One of the very common complaints in courses, they lack the practice and the quizzes that would make
you really skilled in (C++) programming and ready for the next courses like Software engineering, Data structures
and Algorithms.
In terms of books, also, I would like to highlight about that. I would say the content is very deep.
Most probably, you don't have to read a book, but in case if you like, there are two suggestions.
The first one is: (A First Book C++).
This book is very well written.
It will be a very smooth reading.
But there is one problem here.
It is focusing on the classical (C++).
Classical (C++) is before (C++ 11).
It is still a good book.
Still covering a lot.
Feel free to buy it. But if you would like a much more modern choice, then you can go with( C++ How to program)
which is covering up to (C++ 14),
and this means a lot.
This book is very well written.
The guy who wrote it is really aware of software engineering and aware of the industry.
So the book has a lot beyond that.
If you are done with this book and would like really then to learn more about (C++ 17)
you can search on the internet.
There are books that are dedicated only to cover (C++ 17) extra topics.
That is it. :)