In this session, we will code our first program. Let's open a calculator. Enter: 3 + 5
to get 8. To program that, we need to state the exact set of instructions. The program needs to read number
one, read the operation, read number two.
Then we ask to get the result.
But how to tell the computer these instructions through a programming language? We use the programming
language to write a set of instructions to the computer.
Strictly, we follow something called "syntax rules".
Think of the "syntax rules" like grammar rules in English.
You don't just write anything to make a statement.
A compiler is a tool to validate following the syntax rules.
If you didn't respect the rules, the compiler generates compiler errors.
Otherwise, you get an executable to run your code.
Your coding cycle is typically three steps. Write
some code, compile it and run.
This is the "Hello World" program. Stop the video for a minute and read it slowly. Step by step, we should be
able to understand this whole program. Just for now, here, "My first Program.
Hello".
We know this is scary at the moment, but don't worry. If you try to combine and run the program,
we will get this screen, typically black.
It is called
"Console Screen",  just contains text. So a "Console Screen" is something that contains text. Nothing fancy
like web or mobile screens.
Notice here.
The printed statement by "My First Program, Hello".
So now let's go to the code. In line eight,
we see something called "cout", 'c' is for console,
'out' is for output.
This is a command to print.
Notice here the statement "My First Program.
Hellllllo."
Very important to notice here
the double quotes "  ".
There is a double quote here in the beginning and
double quote in the end.
Any statement needs, any string statement,
any message,
needs these two double quotes.
You can also find here a semicolon ';'.
The semicolon is just a signal to the end of an instruction.
You can find also, one here in line two and one here in another
line.
Anything else in the program for the moment, just write it as it is. I'm going to highlight some of
it just to make you more familiar with it.
But for now, what we care about is what will be between line 8 and 10 here
,this space. In line number one,
You see "iostream", (io) is an abbreviation for (Input and Output), and this is called like a
header stream.
Going deeper, the "#include" is something that contains things that are ready for us to use.
Let's say that you would like to compute √25, which is just 5.
Should you write a code by yourself to do that?
The answer is: No.
We, as language authors, we can provide you with a ready-to-use-code. Something like,
let's say: "Hey, here is a square root. Just use it to get 5. In something called "#include  cmath" ".
The "#include iostream" includes functionalities to read and write from the desk.
According to your operating system. There is something weird here called "using namespace std;".
This something that contains like all the things that you need inside (C++). You don't need to worry about it
at the moment.
There is something here
called "main". "main" is a function and if you notice it is lowercase.
When you try to run your program, the first thing that the operating system is going to call is
something called the "main".
You notice here also there are these two brackets"()". These are always attached with functions. Another interesting
and more important here, something called braces "{}", square braces, this brace and this brace.
We write the body of our code inside them.
That is it for today. :)