Welcome, everyone.
So in this section, we will understand what is exponentiation, how does exponentiation works
and why do we need exponentiation?
First of all, let us see what is the exponentiation.
Again, it's a very simple mathematical formula, and that is if I multiply a b times.
Then I write it as a to the power b.
This is normal exponentiation.
b is exponent of a and
This is basically the number of times is b right now b is 4.
If I say is 2 and b is 4, i don't think i need to explain this but still, 2 too the power 4 will give me 16
me.
16 .
So this is exponentiation, we all know this that if I want to multiply a term b times, we
get this.
So that's not what this lecture is about.
It is about how to find an optimal solution to finding and to finding the best complexity of exponentiation.
if I want to find out the best complexity of exponentiation that, OK, find me a to the power
b in very, very optimal time.
What are the best you can do?
The first approach is very simple that, OK, I can simply multiply a b times.
so whats a total complexity of this if I multiply a b times by using a for loop, it will be o of b
But that is not the complexity we want.
We want it to be better than o of b
So here what we'll do is we will take help of binary functions right and we will call it binary exponentiation
would.
This will be very, very handy, guys, believe me or not, in most of those of problems in which we
use mathematical expressions in which like, let's say, there's an recurrance relation is being
solved and that recurrance relation is being like, there's finally a formula that is coming up for a
particular n, let's say, n square minus two n plus one, or n to the power sum m minus something
plus something.
And it
So whenever there's a formula for generally, we have some exponent.
We have some of variables in there, we have some constraints and some exponent how to solve those
exponents in really very less time
So right now we are looking at binary exponentiation.
And after this, we'll be looking at a Modular exponentiation
cool, there will be require binary exponentiation, but still.
Now, let's move ahead with binary exponentiation
And let's take an example, so it's a very easy topic.
It's not a big deal and a very short code for this, so it won't take like more than two minutes.
But yeah, let's say I want to find out 2 to the power 10.
Cool, what we'll do is we'll take their exponent 10 and write it in a binary numbers them, as we know, exponent
is this 10.
If divided into binary, it is written as one zero one zero.
right, if this 10 is written as one zero  one zero, it means 8+2 , so what does 8+2 means
that yes, I do.
I divided this 10 into binary.
So.
So now let's see, how does binary exponentiation work right?
Right now what i'll say is
I'll take a I take B and I will take another dumb called resultant, so in resultant what I'll do is I'll
keep on multiplying a at some specific locations.
We'll just see this initially.
What happens is a is equal to two B is equals 10 and resultant is equal to one right because if I'm going
to multiply something to resultant, I want some answers.
So I should take one as a resultant value, not zero, because if I'm multiply anything with zero returns, me
zero zero is like a black gold right.
You do anything with it.
It will just absorb that thing and make it zero.
Yeah.
So in the first step, what we'll do is, OK, so right now i'll write b in binary form
over here.
So there are some steps that we need to follow, the first step is very simple.
That.
Check if b's last set bit
last Bit of B is set.
Right.
If the last and last set last bit of B set no it is not set, then what we'll do is we'll simply
say this will simply multiply.
Resultant into a, so I'm just not giving you an algorithm here, I'm just not giving you a dry run
enough to read about, and I also explain you like how did it come right before before moving on to
that, I just simply write 2 to the power 10 can be written as 2 to the power 8 into two to the power 2.
to right.
This is the whole funda guys is that we will simply divide 2 2 powers and multiply them right.
If I multiply 2 to the power to into 2 to the power 8, this will give me 2 to the power 8 plus 2 ie 10
2 to the power 10, this is a normal funda guys, the the main idea behind binary exponentiation
and how is that being done that I simply show you where they go.
Well, before moving on to the algorithm, let's take this quick example.
We have one zero one zero here.
what i'll do is
Zero, one, two and three, right?
If I take powers of two what i'll get is 2 to the power 0,  2 to the power 1, 2 to the power 2,
and 2 to the power 3,
I have 1 2 4 8
I just written to the two powers over here.
These are two powers.
And this is binary of ten.
And these are just indexes of my bits set bits
Now what I need to do is simple.
So here I'll get  2 to the power 1
One initially right now my a is 2 to the power 1, so this will be a.
Then 2 to the power 2,  2 to the power 4and  2 to the power 8 is the simple thing to notice
is that if I have one as a set bit, then I'll simply include these two values into my resultant and I
simply multiply these two values into my resultant so resultant into  2 to the power 8
2 to the power 4 is equal to resultant
And this will become.
To sorry 2 to the power 10,
clear guys.
Not a big deal.
So this is not 2
This is a.
That's what we are going to do, right, so for another example, let's say I want to find  2 to the power 14,
It is eight plus six successful.
6 is 4+2.
So this is 14 for this how?
How can I write  2 to the power 14 in binary form, it becomes simple to  2 to the power 8 2 to the power 4 and 2 to the power 2
So I formed these three terms how do I find these three terms very easy
I initially I have 2 guys
If I squared it, it becomes two squared.
If I square it, it becomes  2 to the power four.
If I squared it, it becomes 2 to the power 8,
If I squared it, it becomes a 2 to the power 16,  2 to the power 32  2 to the power 64, and so on.
so, whatever, a I'll have at that moment after one iteration what I will say is a equal to a.
That is a square.
Simple as that .
So that's what we are going to.
Do over here check last set bit if it is set or not
What does it mean if the last set bit is set and simply include, multiply.
A in two resultant, make sure simply multiply a into resultant not a big deal.
And if the bit is not set no problem, what is the second step?
No problem if it is not set simply right shift b, because I'm always taking the last set bit.
So if B is one zero one zero initially in the next iteration, B will be zero one zero one.
In the next iteration, B will be zero zero one zero next iteration, zero zero zero one in the next
iteration zero and right shifting B right.
What does right shift mean?
Just shift the bit right wards cool because I want to check all these.
Bit of B, right?
And while I am like shifting B so, right shift B.
And if I am right shifting b to.
What is the third step, both at the same time, I have to say.
a is equal to a square
I have to keep on multiplying a 2, right guys, so a will become  2 to the power 4 here,  2 to the power 8,
the power.
16.
It will become too square  2 to the power 4,  2 to the power 8, and  2 to the power 16
If the last set bit is set, then what I'll do is I'll simply multiply it into the resultant
what i'll multiply and multiply it into the resulting.
Whatever the resultant value I have, if I multiply a into the resultant,what I'll get is 2 square.
Then again, let's move to the third step.
This is the third step.
Here is the last bit of b set?.
No, if it is not set, do nothing right.
So resultant is still 2 square and then move to 2 a
2 to the power 8,
And what happens here is just check last set bit is set, yes it is set, then simply multiply a into resultant.
so  2 to the power 2,
into 2 to the power 8.
And then finally, what we have is b becomes zero.
If b becomes zero.
What does it mean?
And we don't have to carry on further calculations, because anything to the power zero is zero right,
so I don't have to calculate anything else.
So here I'll break what is the resultant that we got.
It is 2 to the power 10.
And so of course, you can apply for loop.
Check if the bit is set multiply it
If not, continue forward.
And I'll be using a while loop because the code becomes really easy to code.
right.
Let us quickly.
Do this, part after this, we'll move on to modular exponentiation guys, and that's also an interesting
part and very easy part.
Right, so.
Let's call this function power
So this returns me a to the power to b, what I have is I take resultant initially and resultant
should be one while b until b is greater than zero.
What I'll do is simple I'll check the last set bit, if b and  one, that means.
The last bit of b is set, so if you're not clear with all these big manipulation and and or and other things
things and simply watch out the number theory section
These are the basics.
right, what else is resultant into equals to a, i'll simply multiply a into resultant.
Otherwise, whether it b set or not.
I'll simply say a is equal to a square
That means multiplying a into a and b slash equals to 2 means I'm rightshifting b.
So you can do it.
This way also b rightshift two times or you can divide it by.
b rightshift one times, or you can divide b by two, it is.
rightshift b one times, if I do, if i multiply b by two, it becomes left shift b by 1
right.
So these are small, small tricks that you should know.
finally what i'll do is i'll return the result.
let's print this
But yeah, so let's take 2 and 10.
We got one thousand twenty four, right?
If you want to check, if you want to print out all these things, you can check that the directly cout
whatever stuff you want to and check, how is it working right if I do 2 to the power 20.
It's very simple.
I'll get a perfect answer because here we have used binary into work.
why we have used binary into work because
If I write, if I write B as in binary and let's say B approximately.
10 to the power 18.
Look, if I if I multiply it, if I find out this term.
Cool, let me.
If I say a into a to the Power B where b is approximately.
10 to the power 18 that I cannot find out this value.
It will be too huge.
for that i have modular exponentiation, do not worry about that
The second thing is that, OK, I do not have the machining capability of calculating this.
If b is 10 to the power 18, it will take a lot of time.
So in one second, for an like an average in one second, I can calculate 10 to the power seven steps
right.
So how many seconds will be required to calculate 10 to the power 18 iterations?
It will be 10 to the power 11 seconds.
I guess that is nearly equal to life of earth.
right.
It's too huge.
So.
So what we'll do is simply, we will simply convert this number into binary, so in binary, its length
will be at most 64 off length 10 to the power 18 and in only 64 operations, only 64 operations.
We will simply find out a the power B where B is very huge.
Always, you can check this out.
So this works in o of.
Log b.
right.
Why?
Because we are always dividing by two in every step, so there will be a time and b will be zero.
And how much time it will be zero when the last set, when the first set bit of B becomes the last bit of
B and it goes.
away in b
It so it's a very good complexity guys o of log b, so guys this power function.
It will be used in many problems and many statement, and it will also be used in many.
Mathematical sections right, it will also be used to calculate NCR.
It will be used to calculate inverse of a number using mod many things right after these guys will
discuss about a snippet and that snippet is, will be very useful to all, so we'll discuss it
and this is just a part of it.
Next section we'll discuss about modular exponentiation, not a five minutes, so we'll think
Thank you guys!