Cool guys so this was in the previous video we discussed about.
Binary Exponentiation normal
Now let's discuss about modular Exponentiation, so again it's the binary explanation only, but under mod
conditions
What is a mod guys?
What does mod means?
It's a reminder.
So if I say 10 mod 7, is 3
Generally, what happens is that.
The answers for some certain n for some certain problems are huge.
If those answers are very huge, then what does compiler do?
Of course, those huge answers cannot be calculated very easily because that will, of course, require
a lot of space and lot of time to be calculated, lots of cost operations.
Right
What is the problem?
So what does they do
They say, OK, give me the answer by taking modulo with some prime number why modulo's with prime
numbers because I leave it to you only find out why we use modulo's with prime numbers.
I go over to key cryptography section over the internet, just surf over it and check
Why do we always consider prime numbers?
Because there are lots of theorems which are only applicable to prime numbers right.
So.
Like, fermids little theorem and other stuff, cool
So what does he do is he says, OK, give me resultant mod prime by taking a prime generally guys
This primeis 10 to the power nine plus seven.
You might have seen it somewhere.
right other OK, he says.
Give me prime.
We all know about modular arithmetic operations.
how to perform addition, subtraction, multiplication and division using mod.
So that is already being discussed in the mathematics section.
So.
Here we will understand how to find out.
Binary.
How to do this  Binary Exponentiation and there modulus, and let's see if I want to find out 2 to
the power.
This is going to be huge lets say 2 to the power 100, so again, this this value is too huge, right?
Because 2 to the power.
64 is like around 10 to the power 18, which can be stored in C++ for long, long int.
But so this is around 10 to the power 19, right?
So.
But 2 to the power 100 will be a huge value, right?
We won't be able to store it, but still, if I want to calculate if I want to find out how it is, what
is 2 to the Power 100 and under some modulus statements, you gave me two of the power hundred,
with some modulus or less.
Let's take mod with some.
Let's call integer mod
So how will I do it?
Using binary exponentiation, very easy guys
So we all know that if I'm multiplying some a into b and I want to perform mod.
where a is less than modulus, and b is less than modulus.
Then this becomes a mod.
So this becomes a into B mod.
Right?
If I want to calculate this particular part, then it becomes like a mod into B mod mod right
and whole mod.
It's whenever i multiply to integers which are less than mod and I have to multiply and take mod, so I just
multiply them and take mod, right?
So similarly guys for addition also we do the same same stuff, right?
But that's not my point.
What I want to explain to you is that how is  binary, Exponentiation being done.
If I write, let's say I'm finding a into a into a.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine and 11, 11 times the how does  binary exponentiation  work
work, it will take this one a.
right, Then it will take this two a together and then it will take this.
a is together that is 2 to the power of 8, 2 to the power to 2 with the power one
will be equal to 2 to the power 11 right guys, so.
Let's get back to the code.
What happens here is I always multiply a into resultant and then I see is it goes to a is equals to a square.
What I want is I want all these values to be less than 10 to the power nine plus seven.
And I always want to give them less than 10 to the power 7
So how will I do that?
Very simple guys, because as you can see, there's only one multiplication operation happening here.
That means if lets say resultant is ten to the power 9
power nine both are nine lines, and if I multiply them, both of them will have 8 in length.
That particular length of 18 can be stored in long, long integer right.
Similarly, guys, this can also be stored in long, long integer.
They go after calculating both these values.
What I'll do is I simply take mod what I just reduce their values less than 10 to the power nine plus seven.
I just take a A mod
so firstly let me save this code
binary_exponentiation.cpp
And now it's the new code.
Yeah.
So here what we'll do is we'll simply do a modular exponentiation.right?
Let's take a constant int mod I'm why I'm taking a constant int mod because generally constraint
is not necessary.
I mean, this is not necessarily we can take int mod.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, I'm just taking it as a global variable right because in power function, it will be used by calculating
factorial might be it will be used right instead of passing it over here.
Just take it as a global variable because what happens is if in a particular code.
In a particular problem, if you want a result, mod some prime number, that prime number will not only
be used in this power function, but everywhere in the code, wherever you are doing, in addition
or subtraction or multiplication or division, it's better to take mod rather than to pass it individually
to all the methods.
Cool, so I've taken resultant to be equal to one.
I don't have to take a mod because it is already less than 10 to the power nine plus seven.
The problem here is that OK, if I multiply, resultant into a, both of them are of the range
10 to power nine.
So this will go in into the range of it 10 to the power 18
so integer won't be able to store that right for that I have already told you of workaround.
That is, let's define.
Int long, long Cool, now guys we have long, long integers over here, we don't have
to worry about the other stuff.
So after multiplying both of these values, what we'll do is we'll simply take mod
Let's take mod side by side resulting.
Mod and again, for a also let's do the same.
And so by doing this, because this ensures that a remains less than 10 to the power 9 plus 7
and resultant also remains less than 10 to the power 10 plus 7, so that whenever I do this multiplication and
I take the square off a, both of them go at max 10 to the power 18 because this are less than 10 to the power 9
and that 10 to the power 18 number, can be stored in long long integer
long integer, right?
So that's why guys they take 10 to the power nine plus seven.
right, because if I multiply them, they'd multiply two numbers of this particular value.
And they are they are they get stored in the long long integer
That's what we want.
And whenever I'm multiplying them and again, like.
On this one, I'm taking mod and I don't want the value to exceed this particular value right because they
are using calculations again, so 2 to the power 20 will be very easy, the same value, but let's
say 2 to the power 200.
This will give me mod with this particular value.
So this is not 2 to the power 20 and it is 2 to power 200 mod 10 to the power nine plus seven, if i take
remainders and why are we taking remainders, to make our values in limit that our language our compiler can hold
can hold, cool.
So this was it about modular exponentiation, not much changes required only.
We just took mod side by side we don't have to take mod by b right
Because we are dividing it, we're not multiplying or adding it by something it has to be in binary,
don't ever take mod into this.
Otherwise the value of B will change and then there will be some of the binary right.
Oh, thank you, guys.
Seeyou, in the next part.