Welcome back, guys.
So forever, very cool problem for you, and first of all, I want you to go through this.
And there are.
And types of people in the world, those who understand binary and those who don't.
So is this 10 or.
You can convert this to binary rate.
Well.
Now, let's move on to the.
Problem, so the problem is very nice, and it will give you a deeper dive into what is actually.
Binary explanation, it's a divide and conquer approach.
Right, but we are actually using manipulation to code.
Despite eight to.
The problem is very simple, you are going this in C++, I do not think of any other language because
it will become very easy, so.
What do you have is you have been given tremendous.
Eben, see, the fun fact is that all these three are less than equals referring to the power 15.
Eight.
And what do you want to do is you want to find out.
E into B.
My seat.
So you want to find out this interview, Marty, how do you do it?
So just imagine yourself sitting in an interview and solving this problem just because the video.
And try to do this, though, of course, guys, brute force won't work, so you can't just see out
into b more to see.
Vote by.
By brute force won't work.
Because.
Place, because is often the 15 inch wheels of train to the bar, 15 range.
If you multiply them even like even in like inside or if you're just multiplying them.
This this is actually exceeding my long, long into range.
Even Unsane long, long interchanges also being exceeded.
If you multiply these two values because the range of the new number will go around 10 to devour poverty
rate, which cannot be stored in any format, it can be stored in string eight.
But that will become again a heavier task recorded in it as strings.
And you have to do that pen and paper job again.
So I'm not asking for a string solution, but a good one.
So how do you do it, guys?
But this won't work.
We are very clear with this because this is going above the limit of my long longing and it will give
me a garbage value for garbage value.
Marty will be another garbage that you will.
So this is not working.
The second is some of you might be thinking the second approach and that is e might see.
Into we might see Nazi hate, so that's how we distribute my inside when we are trying to find is again,
there is the same reason.
So let's see.
Let's see.
That is equal to be is equal to 10 to 12 15 and see is equal to 10 to 12 15 minus one.
It is nine 14 times at eight.
Whatever.
So if you take a Motsi.
OK, so I think I have just reversed the situation.
So let's say, as he was too busy with strapped into the power.
15 minus one.
Right and seized and about 15, if you take MRC, then it will be only because C is greater than the
similarly guys B Morsi will be.
B only because it is greater than.
Because she's going to then be an Rachel, what does this problem statement conversion do, what does
it actually become?
Becomes a normal statement.
It is going to be Marty.
Well, NBA legend and inches awkward isn't going to work.
What I mean to say is this more is unnecessary in this case.
Again, more than we are offering 15 and above 15, all of them out of this range.
They can't, cannot be multiplied by brute force.
I just want you to.
If you're not like if you want.
And so this is normal unit that you are watching this video on the topic of binary multiplication,
so instead of exponential be a multiplication.
This is nothing different.
So.
It like it's a golf utility, but it's like relatable from this to this, you can easily relate.
It is in binary explanation what happens?
Let's read a binary multiplication.
Binary explanation, what does it do, is it calculate it to be and this will get great aim to be more
than will be taken later, do not worry about that March eight.
The counting is in by next one injection.
It is actually a multiplied buildings.
Your name's brought in by animal application, it is a plus a plus e plus a few times in both.
What we'll do is we'll simply divide.
Or break?
Being too binary.
Eight and.
The rest of the part will remain same late.
So here in like minded expert intuition, I was actually multiplying anyway, resulting in binding multiplication.
I will simply add it to the resulting theorem.
So you saying, is it going to be a square part in finding multiplication tables is equal to twenty
eight?
What does I mean that if I want to find out in two?
That is let's take an example to Windows 10.
So how can this better than this can in this window for?
But if doing to eight plus blustering to do.
And because they were divided and into Bindi's, not a big deal, guys divided the next term into binary.
And finally, do they do these multiplications and continuously take note eight who are very easy are
very easy to disguise.
So let's call it out.
I don't think much explanation is needed here.
A.
Oh, yeah.
If I want to yeah, this is let me say how I saved it.
Yeah, I've saved it.
So let's multiply.
My deep lie.
Let's multiply it into B.
With some with some sort of sea instead of this smart and.
At stake, this is retained as he goes to one guy, it's not a big deal.
So again, until I have B, then what I need to do is simple.
If.
I don't I don't know why today it is it.
If B and one, then resulting in close to deserted place.
Not my reply this time is it goes to India.
We.
Or instead, we can record everything is a political story, and we let you go through to a formalistic,
a very basic example is day to the Barberton, and let's say the mod is a very big integer one nine
platoon.
That's OK, it multiply.
OK.
But these children will not be one, it will be zero, because right now emerging things are multiplying
late initially to zero.
Yes, sir, I've got 20 and let's see about 20.
I know the march or not, because you're doing your 20s party again, branding you 20 will be 400.
I hope you understand this part.
Now let's do the modelling part again.
The same thing they're doing is to go through and place it whenever it exceeds my MA limit.
Let's dig more similarly, as you go straight into it air and whenever it suits me more limited, let's
take it.
Oh, let's dig marred by the.
Well, why am I doing this, why wounded exceed my long, long range?
Because very, very ultra long lines that I'm just adding it to resulting great so retreating is becoming
resulting, plus a look at both resultant and E alleged intent to devote 15.
Because I am continuously taking more.
If if you want to exceed their level 15, I'm going industry taking more rate.
If I add both of them, then what will be the range around 10 to the above 16?
In the worst case, if I had to integers of tangible 15 days in the worst case, they can go end the
worst 16.
But the standard 16 is easily storable in my data, in my long longing.
Easily storey buildings, because we are just adding two integers and again, part the second operation,
it's very easy.
We're not multiplying anything.
And so this is doing to.
Of course we're multiplying, but we can also write it as a plus equals to it.
And again, what I'm doing is I'm saying is going to be a blessing.
Again, I'm adding to Indonesia's of instead of.
So their total range will be less than 10 to the power 16.
And then when ultimately they will again become less than 10 to 15.
Why?
Because these less than 10 to the power 15 while taking more bases, they will again move back.
This is just to give you a brief idea about how does exponentially what is what is binary conversion
of a number?
How is this VI loop actually going?
So it's not about multiplication or only about exponents using this can be used in various places,
guys.
In the next topic, you will see what is metrics expert intuition in Dallas will be using the same thing.
I just wanted to give you a very.
Diverse obligation of binding and with it, so it's it isn't like binding members are a very big thing
and they're kind of if to the humanity, because everything that we see is working in binary, they
may been like under 200 years.
Everything works in condoms, which are not perfect binaries.
But yes, right now this is possible because of binary, right?
And yeah, so see in the next word, gays, thank you.