Always so welcome to the real four metrics explanation, the the explanation will come handy in various
dynamic programming problems and all those are all those problems in which you will be solving some
linear recurring solution.
Eight.
So for example, I'll give you the very basic example, and then we'll move on to various different
examples, of course.
So.
Right now, this small catfish here, and I'll help you prevent this cat face right away and will coordinate
things exponentially.
I will.
Not pass to the mattresses, but will work on during mattresses, in methods, in different methods.
Eight or windows are a nuisance.
They might be, but will avoid them.
They will avoid nuisance.
Now, let's understand how this matrix explanation work with an example.
So let's take an example first.
Let's say I want to find out.
And it's Fibonacci number.
And it's Fibonacci numbers, so it's a very famous series, guys, Fibonacci numbers cities because
it is being used in various places and there are some well-known facts about Fibonacci numbers, you
can easily search those facts.
So if I want to find out the end, it's Fibonacci numbers.
So let me write first few terms of this series.
It is one one.
The first time is one.
The second time is one.
Now, the third time is equal.
The third term follows this pattern that f and is equal to f off and minus one plus and minus two.
That means three will be equal to a fourth two three three minus one plus three minus two is f of one.
So the next term is equal to the sum of previous two terms.
Eight.
So it is two.
Two plus one is three five eight 13.
Twenty one.
Party have a missed No.
13 percent to end its 34 and then 34 in next year's.
Thirty four in twenty one is five and five, fifty five and so on.
So it's an infinite series.
It is never ending cities and after a certain time it goes like exponential rate.
You can easily see this particular cities.
So if I want to find out the end for when I can them, but and its end is less than equals to turn to
the power six, it becomes very easy for me.
I can directly use dynamic programming.
Dynamic programming.
Right, and a very simple cold case began easily undo this, not a big deal, if still you have a problem
using dynamic programming for finding just a Fibonacci number just to watch US action on dynamic programming.
And in the first example will be of it when I give numbers in one day.
DP eight Not a big deal.
So running programming is not a big deal for African economics, but easy stuff.
What happens in the name of Ghadami is that you take an area of land, think about six eight, and what
you do is you calculate that are done by using the first two dams and you calculate the Fortnum by using
their second and third dome in you.
That means you take an area and you simply fill the first two times that d b minus one and b b who is
also one.
And then they re you add a loop from three to in and say the DPA is equal to that.
Maybe a is equal to DP I minus one plus API minus two.
So.
This is a normal loop from.
You're doing great.
And after the loop ends, we have the end, no finish, so we have to be in after this end.
But guys, this is not the perfect solution that I want because it is for less than equal to 10 Dubai
with six and eight to four lots of my a of my friends got this problem is going to be a problem that
like a follow up problem they say now.
And this lesson in Gloucester turned the 18.
Now, how do you get to create this particular?
Even economically if and it's so huge, you cannot apply this law from three to 10 because again, we
cannot have attended the voting and it will take a huge time.
Eight.
How do you solve this, how do you figure this out?
What is the.
And also there is that number will be huge.
Of course, is this number will also be huge.
They're distributing queue of 10 to diversify.
It will also be huge.
Generally, whenever you face this problem, they will say that they might just like big what is actually
a comp. It's actually a drawback of languages of the computer system we have now.
It may be not up to 100 or 200 years right now.
This is a topic it's a bit more to.
They could it in in that limit.
You.
OK?
So how do you solve this problem in an instant, is it being so that's the main problem that we are
going to discuss in this election, right?
Here goes What I'll do is I'll take three.
Mattresses and just show you an example and everything will become all clear.
So let's take three mattresses.
The first mattress that I'm taking is a normal matrix, and let's call it.
Matrix F and kept live in this effort, Matrix is too gross value matrix, and in this I will be storing
Effen, which is the end for but and f of and minus one.
Well.
Now what happens is I have a Imitrex, let's call it biometrics, and I'll feel the value of it.
Oop, I want you to feel the values of the stigma have on you to find out the emergence of this dream
matrix, as if a multiplicity matrix to this effort matrix that is deep into effen this matrix give
me effen plus one.
It is this into this equals this f of endless fun to wherever, and I literally said, bend this one
and this one minus one is in.
What should be my be matrix of video games?
But easy that this f of endless one metrics is actually nothing but.
How is it ever and responded in it it is written as f and plus f minus one in the sum of previous two
terms in Fibonacci.
It is, and this is I if I dig two ones over here.
So this one multiplies with this happen and this one multiplies with this happen.
This rule multiplies with this column and gets me off of endless but eight.
Secondly, in the second, what we have to do is, guys, I won't happen to be here so I can take it
one zero.
If I multiply this rule with this column, it gives me a fine.
Well.
So Venezuela is not a big deal that if I multiplied the metrics with the F and it gives me, I think
this one eight now.
Now, let's see this if this if anything goes to evolve.
Rachel, let's get into it for you.
This will give me a of three similarly esteemed to of.
They will give me f off.
Similarly, they do it for food, will give me half of.
You and and so on.
It will go on forever.
So if I replace effort in this equation by the industry, then I can.
It is this way into being the F3.
Is Eagles do it four, five?
So let's say I'm just trying to find a fight.
So now let's replace FTD by using this equation here, where I get this thing to eat into e into a f
of a two is.
One more record is equal to three or four, five, eight.
So basically, guys, if I want to find out some f of RN and I know what it f of two, what do you have
to evolve to is nothing but of the F2 Dome and the F1 team, which is one one.
The base case is basically rate based cases.
So, yeah.
OK, so what happens is if I want to find out, be of end of this actually becomes the the power and
minus two yes or no.
Due to the power and minus two.
IndyRef2 is going to happen to win always, these all are mattresses which are being multiplied, multiply
follows that property, whatever it is associated or community in, which is to be in the sea, is equal
to A into B and C.
Hey, I'm just a blanket, probably over here, and simply I grouped all these, I'm just simply multiplying
all I'm just finding to the power in minus two.
What is do over here is the matrix.
One one one zero.
This is Matrix.
Hey, you know what?
What is the solution that I've come up to that if I want to find out if people, Nikki and I simply
have to find out the power in my next one multiplied by f of two that will give me effen, which is
even.
And if in minus one, and I'll just written the topmost value that will be called within the how do
I do this guy is how do I find due to the power and menace to?
Again, we can use binary exponentially here instead of multiplying to one by one here again directly.
Node by devouring minus two by using binary explanation because and minus two is an integer.
I can simply say by this time, empty of what what we'll do is we'll take a resultant.
Certain metrics that will be of one identity metric say other metrics will be 92 metrics and.
In each separate it needs to do is simple.
Just as binary exponentially, can we do that result in will be equal to resulting into if the last
British state and so on.
And so basically just consider it the city as another integer, right?
So we know as integers multiply, so so do matrix multiply.
As integers add up, so do mattresses add up.
Ed, I'm just.
Instead of doing a by explanation of unity, then I'm doing in binary exponential matters.
It is called matrix exponential.
It's instead of in multiplications.
And in these editions, we'll be having methods between multiply mattresses and advocacy.
So those methods will not take 2D error as a as an argument because I'll be telling you a best way to
code this out and you won't be like having this face.
Whatever this.
It is eight.
I hope you I hope you got this that.
Instead of in business, we'll just use mattresses, multiply them, add them whatever we do, and simply.
Use it right.
So I think that's it.
And so, first of all, I want you to call it odious and like nightmare third-rate functions, if you
ever understood this part, just.
Do they do it yourself first and then move on to the next for you, during which I'll call it out there
are there are various examples.
Let me give you another example.
This was a very easy to kill installation and let me give you a tougher one.
If anything was to happen.
These are records of relation.
Any recurrence, so instead of getting left, let's have smaller.
F off and.
Is he close to Earth at 15 minus one plus B of f off and minus two plus c f off and minus three?
How do you all this?
So always, whenever you face, whenever you will just face a reconciliation, a regardless of religion
and you going to use medical expert intuition, my first advice for you will be to.
Make this.
Vector, I make this vector that is Effen and this vector, which is even less when you take Effen Vector,
like what?
What thinks I have to make the nest next, what word things and then make the de vector accordingly?
If I multiply to do this, I'll get this eight or.
So let's solve this just positively, if you don't want to solve this puzzle, we don't think about
it and then, uh, you dive into this hit ABC are some constraints right that are being given to us?
So as I said, first of all.
We will have this f matrix and we will take.
Many we keep on changing world, we need eight.
So here we have endless fun metrics.
Let's have fun here.
F1 minus one here, F1 minus two here.
And, yeah, reality, I have a friend one.
Offend.
I finally an F and minus one because I'm replacing and when and endless fun.
And it's I have the year eight or.
Instead of let's take one.
Welcome, come to know, why am I doing this?
So, yeah.
Now, let's make this symmetric case to make a friend +1, what I want is I want one find one that is
funny to have, but in not one.
I bet.
Not one I have.
I won't be into heaven.
Be into.
F minus one, the endorphin minus two, 20.
Which is equal to evolve and listen.
Hey, not I want Evan in the second place.
So what is I in the second place?
It will be simple one zero zero zero.
It was Veneman replied the second row with this.
I will defend and it is zero one zero zero, then it is zero zero one zero eight.
So.
Yes, I did happen, I defend in my innocence, but here goes whatever it is, I don't want to be carried
forward.
I do not want a foreign minister to come at this location late, so the last straw needs to be changed.
What will I have in the classroom?
I want mind later it will be zero zero zero one.
So this is my teammate, this family played this dramatic stuff in Matrix 11 plus again and again and
multiplied by again again, f in my f in bliss two and then again and so on.
If I wanted to find out for friend is fine, go to the power end and simply multiplied by by if you
don't hate.
And you can easily solve this thing.
Well, guys, I hope you are able to.
Go back with this and in the next video, we will.
So this is another example of a bigger installation, you can have various examples.
Eight.
And now we will see an efficient way of cutting this in the next year.
Well, thank you, guys.