And everyone, welcome back to this Victoria Informatics six foot incision coding part in the last rural,
we went through matrixes Financiacion and now we want to code it out.
It's so basically we just have to.
The mean part of it is to have it devouring it and.
Yes.
So before that, let me tell you some good problems.
I think so it is CQ.
This is a problem called on board.
You can try this problem after this particular tutorial and there's another SBP.
You can also go to one spot to solve these two problems after this and get your hands on metrics exponentially.
Cool.
So firstly, yeah, so here we are.
Normal code, I've just taken it as wrong because we'll be using more again and again because guys,
very easy thing, you'll notice that if I want to find out Fibonacci number of that, bigger heights
of that, some effort about it rate, so its value will be huge.
I can't even imagine that huge.
What I'll do is I'll just take some more there.
Let's take a 07:29 pool and let's find out the Fibonacci numbers.
So.
Of art in the Indomie, let's say I have RN and let's call it in Italy, right?
It's I want to find out why.
What is the fifth Fibonacci number plate?
So I'll just be out and highlight a function or method which will give me the energy when I get eight
going, babe.
And and will come away and then through an economic hole.
So how do I quote this?
How do I make a matrix?
So as I said, guys, I'll be using a very special method, which is a structure in structures we don't
have to.
We won't be worried about passing on.
Different the eddies and other stuff you hate, what I do is.
A very simple.
Firstly, I just dig a matrix instead of all, let's take em and let's give it, let's give it a Constance's
rule.
So constant size is two initially incinerate because four, according this, but that is.
When I give our trade, we we need to cross remittances, and this is to cross-pollinate metrics.
Here you will realize one thing that we don't need even metrics.
We don't need f and plus one metrics.
We just need to use metrics and we'll find do the power and minus two.
And when I have to do the power and minus two after this, I just need to multiply that by one one.
What does this mean that if I take just first two terms and add them of thee, that will be equal to
if I multiplied the first two with one one and get F and some eight?
I'm not like going f in metrics and f and both metric because we don't need it.
We just want the metrics and it's about eight.
So here I just take a structure.
Metrics so lazy will easily see that.
Why is it being so useful to us by taking this?
That is being very useful to us right after this.
Alex Rider constructed metrics, and what it will do is it will just simply said this to zero.
It will set all the terms to zero.
Well, after this let's item method, which will return, which will convert the matrix to an identity
form, what is an identity matrix?
It is one one one under-diagnosed or let's write a function called identity.
We need this identity.
I've already explained this to you.
Why do we need identity?
Because instead of resultant resulting in multiplication was born in in addition to zero, it is an
identity element in metrics.
It should be noted in duty metrics.
So from I will go from zero to size and what I do it is I'm off base.
Race is equal to one.
I just in the diagonally, I will put all.
This is an identity matrix.
Eight.
And now let's go to the last word of this structure metrics and the most important part that is I want
to multiply two matrices.
Eight.
So how do I multiply two matrices if?
If you if not, if you have not heard about what are we going to do?
Operator overloading, just go and check it out.
It's a it's a very, very nice tone like out of OPA Overlord and operator eight I defining this that
if I use a multiplication anywhere, then this particular function will be called.
This is called an operator, overloading late.
I simply pass a matrix to it.
And what I do is I simply now nothing if I see Matrix.
OK, let me give you an example.
If I say metrics, are I just going to?
Metrics are and I see if is he to OD into, let's say, another matrix Q I didn't do Q.
That means all these metrics are this operator is defined.
There is a multiplication operator.
After this, this Q matrix will be parsed as an argument to the function of.
That means art method will be called where it will be, Bosasa metrics are different metrics as an argument.
Now what I need to do is I need to multiply.
These were these four mattresses.
That means it has been passed to the.
Argument to the method is an argument, and I have to just multiply them.
I don't have to do much part here now.
What I simply say, I just take a matrix.
Let's call it resilient.
So, guys, how do I multiply two mattresses into a third mattress?
If this is a matrix, a this is a matrix, be eager to see Matrix because both these metrics are off
to to who goes to do grows too will give me two grows to eight.
If I received the E!
F e.
What is this storm?
It is, he goes to the first row, multiplied by bicycle eight.
So matrix multiplication is actually and this will be actually size cube algorithm, right?
Because we'll be using triple for loops here by triple values, because you fill one location of this
matrix, you fill one location of this matrix.
I need to go for the rows and for all the columns of both The Matrix, it's into three eight.
So let's do this then.
So let's go from I0 to.
Size and then let's go from day zero to buddy.
So I'm not I'm just not doing anything here.
Not not a big deal.
No, I'm not doing a big deal of it at eight.
It's a very simple --, just multiplying two mattresses.
The first mattress is this that is my all metrics that this I've already been taking matrix of it and
passing to it as an argument.
And the third mattresses resulted in which I'm storing.
So this is a metric that I will return.
Before all these locations of IED, that means for all these resultant IED, what I need to do is I
need to simply.
Have one more variable called.
Right.
And what will Discovery will do in?
For 30 days, it will be blessed with two.
M.
I e that means chaos going on.
That means it's constant.
While the first matrix for this matrix are is constant and gays going one by one, I had for all the
columns and for the second matrix, what I do is simple it will be equal to a dot and that means is
matrix eight.
A., M. e.g..
Hey, on second Matrix column is constant and we are simply moving down the slope.
It's just a normal multiplication and addition.
And after this word, what we need to do is in this alternate using.
We'll just ignore it and do it by name just seven so that the value doesn't exceed that limit.
And finally, this certain metrics, which will be stored in a well.
This is a normal matrix multiplication gates, normal medical operations.
You can easily see it has become so easy right now if you would be writing different methods and providing
to the.
Arguments, Stuart, it in won't take those arguments because they cannot be passed.
So, Ernest, also a very easy matter.
Now you will easily see the similarity between the by an exponential and meticulous one ingestion rate.
Now you will see it.
So initially what I'll do is I'll just take the resultant.
Metrics and what should be resurgent metrics be, it should be.
Identity matrix case is written should be identity because I have to multiply the image to destroy it.
Now, guys, let's take the matrix goatee that we have defined over here.
Eight.
Where is Steve Maddox?
Yeah, I just have to in Italy, all all zeros or t dot m zero zero.
I have one e dot m at zero.
One.
I have one and dot em one zero.
I have one aid to add these three locations, I have one in this matrix who can easily see, well,
I just feel that the Matrix and now what is the need?
The need is very simple and.
If I want to find an interview when I can and what I have to find nobody to the and minus to it, we
have already discussed this part by in minister is needed because I have to multiply it by two.
Let's find out due to the power and minus eight.
So it's a breakdown.
And.
So before these guys, let's make a case, if an is less than equal to do, then what we do is we'll
simply run one pool and the way will simply subtract then by two and do the normal exponential you hate
by violin, if anyone.
It means it's an odd number is written as equals two, resulting in two.
Eighty eight and easy goes to be in duty there just to square the normal thing that we did.
And instead, she goes, You to look, you can easily see it has become so easy.
If I use the normal operator overloading, if I define a structure matrix is indeed very easy, guys.
If you have coded this out, if you're trying to score Gordon, just this.
Compare your code with Michael Wright and you will realize the differences.
After performing this value, what I'll have is I'll have a property that that I want.
I'll get to do the power and minus two in resultant.
Where in this progress to rate?
So I just have to add the first two terms in them to what else in Britain, resulting dot m zero zero
plus is rendered m zero one.
And also I have ignored you guys.
Never forget mod.
Oh, yeah.
OK.
But you not I it will be, I know, chases.
Yeah, just just let me check for some.
It is not the rate is returning, but M, my bet is it is a structured and integrated.
They took no idea, so what is he when I give five, it is five as in the output sick.
Yeah, the fifth time is fine.
So let's check for the system.
We will discuss the complexity it great, Bentham.
One two three four five six seven eight nineteen fifty five.
It's working perfectly.
Hey, this is the normal explanation, but we have discussed.
This is a matrix.
Right.
And.
Yeah.
So now it's their time to discuss the complexities.
So what is the complexity of this law?
It is not often and this is.
Log off and of log often, and in this world is happening, data matrix multiplication functions being
called place.
What is the time that the Matrix is taking to be multiplied?
It is size into size into that.
Is there this ice cube or do you say there two nature?
It is basically Tokyo, which is eight in do log off and eight so.
Isn't it so?
Any rate so that it is regulated at a size cube into or off lock and.
Hey, if any relating to the poverty, Dean, it becomes 64 in two it.
It's not a complex, it nothing, not even in 3-D, it's.
It so, yeah, so it's not even in four digits, it's just less than a thousand.
So that's the beauty of expert gates.
Well.
They've given you various examples of excellent intuition and by any explanation how they can be done,
how they can be coded out.
So this is a complexity here.
We cannot ignore says, because for this example, Earth values for so it will be for cube into law
of an.
It was at this size cannot be ignored and of course, goes after it, I just want this Borduin to go
to these problems as USP.
And there's another problem said it's called SB two because SB records the sequence something.
And then there's another thing it is people some unspoilt.
Try that, too, if you wish to.
Well, I hope this school is very clear to you guys, and the complexity of it is also very clear to
you guys.
So that's it.
In the next part, thank you.