Hello, everyone.
Let's solve this problem.
You blossom from spot.
So it's very easy in the problem statement.
The Fibonacci sequence is defined by the following relation f zero 07 their values and finishes, f
and management both have in mind Do we all know this?
So your task is very simple given to non negative integers and in them you have to calculate the sum
f.n plus f and +1 belief.
And basically, you have to find out the sum of these series of Fibonacci animals from f.n to F.M. made.
And, of course, Marty, that we know about Madrid.
So this is the input Elaine's, and after all this, Elaine will have zero three, three five and all
these things.
So how do you approach this problem?
We've already seen how to find out from an economist using matrix experimentation.
Well, there are two approaches for this problem.
The first one actually, both use this dramatic explanation.
There are two different ways of using it.
The first one is to.
We got all Peregrine's solution laid off the summer as we saw.
We were making the Imitrex when it emerged we had many things.
Similarly, we can take some, like some of some isn't.
Let me name their term.
It's called Essen.
It's called Essen or Desisyon.
Essen is.
Some and entry, we're not going to be secluded zero, 0.7.
Let's f to l f and wait, and then some will be a similar thing in f m and if we subtract s m minus.
And.
Or instead, let's minus as a minus one, then we can simply get what we want, which is.
Some from Dylan, eight days, I hope we all know this because it's perfect, some trait of some some
foreign aid is although some minus the previous, some remove it and we'll get this.
I hope this is very clear.
But then how do of you know this and you can make it to America in which you can Edison and then see
how does that you can make an effort matrix in which you can Anderson.
Right?
We can have a third very well.
That is.
And finally, you going to have a.
Safety metrics accordingly.
That's one of the approval discussed there as well.
But before moving to that approach, I want to discuss a very nice approach.
It's based on the property of Women Act numbers and will derive that property rate.
So A.
We say that Effen is equal to.
If.
And minus one plus F. and minus two.
So let's see what f and minus two here is.
They'd have been minus two is equal to in.
Minus f in minus one.
I hope you agree on this point.
Right.
So, well, the what will we have in minus three here?
It will be nothing but f and minus one minus f minus.
Know, I hope we are on the same page over here.
And so until.
Let's zero what did have zero?
OK, let me read one more and then we'll do so until it's zero.
It is a in minus 40.
It goes to a friend minus.
I've been minus three, minus F and minus.
To date, and in many ways, I am assuming the most three and minus.
Two, am I doing something wrong here?
And I've been minus two is offend minors, I've been minus one.
OK, so f and ministries f in minus one minus f in minus two.
Eight, 11 minus four is equals to.
F in minus C.
Okay, so I think this two and three should be replaced.
And so until eight zero zero zero is nothing but a fourth.
Let's put zero in this, and let's put any goes to do here, right?
It will give me half of zero and this will be f of two minus f off one.
I hope this is right now is whatever ad the allergies and the additives it, let's add these values.
This values this is nothing but as zero plus f one plus so until f and minus two.
Eight a.m. What is on the allergies on the on the orange is the right hand side?
I can easily see that this cancels out this.
Similarly, this cancels out this late because minus plus minus plus they all really can sit on each
other.
And in the end, F2 will also get cancelled out because of some values over here.
I what we'll get will get is he goes to f in minus f one.
Right.
What what I can see here is that they're still in, but still and minus two aid because they're just
starting from zero and going till and minus two is equal to 11.
Minus one, everyone is one night when I can find.
So if I want, let's replace and ban and let's replace an endless loop or delegate Elliot Essen, is
it going to evolve?
And plus two minus one.
A very symbolic resolution.
So if I if I if I want to find out.
S m minus Essen, which is equal to thirty.
Yeah, I want to find out the some from I'm doing day to f am doing.
This is what S.M minus.
Let me not add the brackets minus as in minus one, which will be what is S.M according to this equation,
it is f off and plus two minus one minus what?
What will be S.N. minus one?
According to this relation, it will be f off and plus one minus Rite Aid because here I am and minus
one here I and burned minus one.
So this investor will become an plus one.
Well, let's break this, this cancels out this.
What I have got four plus two minus F and plus one.
Right, so this is the final answer, and we all know how to find out if we win a case and was right,
we can easily find out FMI plus two.
We can easily find out if and plus one will can subtract them and more ignored because that model of
Robert is important.
Don't forget them aid because in sports, the answer is required after taking not, subtract them,
add more and then take more.
I hope this is very fine aid so you can easily go to now because there's nothing left.
And we have already coded how to find out if we were taking no.
Well.
Well, thank you, everyone.
Let's see you in the next part in which we will be using Matic's explanation to figure out this.
Coalition will.