I will.
So let's see this second approach.
The other alternative approach of explanation only if you are not able to figure out the.
This one, which is also a nice approach, it's just based on the property of people when I give numbers,
but just let it not be when I get on with some of this reading, we want to find some.
So let's see an example of how to do it.
Firstly, I always do.
I always started by writing some aromatic notes Alexa didn't have read.
Metric, and this is let's say it has some some deal and a.m. it has a Fibonacci number and because
some talent will look away from an IQ brain and it will also require if you're going to crewneck in
numbers and minus eight now.
What is the next metric that we can have if I multiply it by a metric into this metric, I should get
an F. And plus one metric.
So this replacing and by and plus one or more, should I get a cent plus one plus one?
F.n minus.
Right, right.
So this was.
But yeah, this should be if.
And not defend my innocent.
I'm replacing and by and press one right now again, Israel really major Demetri, which is very easy.
No, because after use these three things to make sense one what it is in Brisbane and it is as an plus
and +1 something and +1 200, which is Santaland to +7 +1.
So how will this will be?
It is very easy in Brisbane as it goes through F and +7 minus one.
So basically the sum of all three, right and the next I.M.F. and +1 247 +1.
It is f.n plus and minus 1.8, which is nothing but some of both the lower terms and the last one is
Effen.
I want to just find out if and which is does this cross diagonal?
So this is the thematics that's prepared for me for this particular f matrix.
And this is F and +1 metric in case.
So.
Let me just quickly share an example that it will work.
So the metrics in one one one zero one one zero one zero eight.
Let's see.
This metric is the basic let's make a base case we have and minus one here, right?
Let's make the best guess.
Let's replace and buy one.
Well, so this becomes F1, which is still one quantum is one, because if is one and if and minus one
is zero.
Well, guess what will be the multiplication of these two mattresses sort of be one plus one two.
And the next will be one here only, and the last one will be zero.
I hope, OK, the lawsuit will not be zero, it will be this one into this one.
It will be one eight.
This is the.
And plus one, which is after metrics and this content is to come to terms of it being accurate, which
is free when I get zero blasphemy in a given blasphemy anarchy to which is the OnePlus One.
It is true.
I hope you got this.
And again, if you multiply the time matrix with F.
Let's see if I multiply to Matrix with F2 or delete Alhadeff.
Three.
You can try this.
Well, let's call it out quickly.
And yeah, so this is just some previous code.
And let me just remove this.
I wouldn't change anything over here in the matrix structure.
And I just, yeah.
So this is the function for some will pass into it, and it will give me the sum of some of the anthem.
Always.
So, yeah.
Let me.
Hmm.
Yeah.
So let's see out ribosome, and we want to find out some detail and dump minus ribosome tail and minus
one dumb eight.
So here we can see that an is and can also be zero.
That means and minus one can also be negative, which is minus one.
Took.
Let's write some basic ISS, which is very simple if N is minus 100 and zero.
Right.
If and in zero.
What is the sub Murphy when I get the results of zero and if any is.
One.
And let's return one.
Well, it's written these three values now we know that.
Is greater than equal to age, so here, let me try that end is greater than equal to eight.
Now we have a resultant metric that we used to have.
This is the time metric that I have to make.
So the two metrics is one one one in the first two.
But do you not?
Zero zero is equal to do, you thought zero one is it goes to Detroit.
Zero two is it goes to one.
So fill the first room with one.
And also you can see that the size is three now.
That means all the mattresses here will be off regrows.
Three eight.
I hope.
Don't get confused, Rachel.
You're going to increase or decrease the sizes you want to.
And second row is zeroes on the second part, so let me quickly remove this 30 01 and 02 is one.
And the third one, we have it in just the middle part.
Let me remove this and let me also remove.
Right.
So as you can see, we have this zero zero advise, everyone will be.
We have these ones and everything else will be zero.
Now this is obaseki's eight.
So in the best case, I can.
Yeah.
So any greater than he going to do now?
Basically, if I let's see if I pass and go straight to here, what will happen?
It won't go here all.
This will fuel knowledge and is he going to do so, this value will go to so will it, meaning it will
try to find quiet of it?
Basically, it will find b squared.
Into whatever devices I'm multiplying rates, the base case here is nothing but this, which is one
one zero, which is F1 eight.
So I'm trying to multiply when would be square, but that should not happen because he's going into
everyone will give me f 2D and will not give f too late.
So if I'm passing and as to here, let me subtract and buy one and minus equals to win it.
Why am I subtracting and revenue?
Because if an is being possessed, I just want to find out the rest of it and minus four and not be
destroyed.
The power in those areas to the power and minus one into the base case is giving F2 and not F1.
I hope you got this.
Well, this is we are just subtracting one, because because let me also quickly write this because
it's quite urban history.
But F3 the which will give some till date similarly to you.
F1 is f word, right?
Basically, if necessary, then we are getting forward on.
So but we want parents, Rachel, I'm just subtracting and buy one so that we can get the third answer.
I hope that's fine.
Now, after this, we have found out that there is.
This matrix is.
We have hired the Treasury Department and minus one.
And after I found out the details of the boat and minus one, what I can do is.
I just have to multiply the first rule with the first column of the year because I just want S&M right
here.
I just want be as intimate.
I just multiply, defy stroke with the with this column, which is one one zero.
But indirectly, what will happen?
This will get multiplied by this.
This will get multiplied by this rate, and this will get multiplied by this to basically f and minus
one is zero because of the base case.
OK, let me let me read to you.
Basically, this deal is to the Bible, something let's let me call it get into the base case.
What was the base case one one zero?
We know the first rule will get multiplied by the system, so let me write first rule SABC eight.
So it will be in the OnePlus being the one OnePlus seen to zero.
We are not considering see what we'll do is we'll say in India and has been doing it, which is nothing
but result in dam zero zero e and is rendered M01, which is B.
I'm not taking the 3rd value because if I take this R value, I say this let's say zero one two, I
have to multiply it by zero rate a base in the base case.
We we saw that it's zero the f in metric.
We will not multiply this.
And finally, we'll take Maude and Randy values.
I hope this works.
Let me bill this quickly.
OK, it's who.
Zero zero rate.
So let me quickly go over this again, I don't think so, there should be an error.
This is the diametric the Dimitrescu's zero one one zero one two and.
And one or Kilkeel, guess what?
This is the first rate in the first rate should be one one.
And in the second, Richard, be two one.
My word?
Right now, we are seeing good numbers.
My word, sorry, guys.
Because in the first story, it should be one day I just copy paste it.
It always happens with me whenever I copy paste things.
So here what we have, we have 14 and yeah, so it will still not work away because I'm subjecting rate,
let's say the numbers are huge.
If I subtract them, they will not give me the right number because of the model's properties and reduce.
I'll add more.
And then I'll again ignored.
And then this should give me the overdoses as these movies.
Also, it was giving me the right answer, but I just remember this is the smallest puppy.
Don't ever forget this if you subtract.
So there was a time when I was giving some long talent and it took me two days to realize this because
at the time I was going to do programming, no one was going to tell the eldest part to me.
And it took two days to figure out that it might just be smart.
It might not be if I want to do more.
It should be A-minus.
B-plus more than Hallmark eight.
So, yeah, and we can simply submit this report as well on this budget and.
To the.
Yeah, let me submit it also.
Also, I would strongly suggest that you all try it once before and then somebody will do.
Thank you, everyone.
In the next part.