In this project we will implement a library system.
The project would be a bit bigger comparing to the previous project. Any library, like
when you go to the library
you notice there are a lot of books,
There are some computers, there's a program where you can search for some books.
Probably the admin can see some maintained information about the books, like, for example, who borrowed
a specific book in the system.
We're going to create a very simple version of this classical system.
There is a mainly one user for the system.
It is just the admin,
There are no more users.
So we are building the system from the admin perspective.
And over all, the admin can add a book, maybe add a user or perform some relevant operation for the book
or for the user or for both of them together.
You don't need to provide any login/logout functionalities, just very simple console system.
When the system begins, there is a typically like a menu of a bunch of choices.
The user here, the admin selects the choice, applies the operation and then the menu is going to be
displayed
again. this is the menu of 10 choices.
Please read the choices and think for a minute what might be behind them.
Let's try to list the details of these operations.
The first book operation is just adding a book.
As you know, every system needs some data.
The core data here in the system is actually the books and the users.
The admin needs to be able to add the books and each book is as following:
there is some ID for the book,
there is some name and there is some quantity.
An example for that would be the ID is like 101 and the name, something like "CppHowToPorgram"
no spaces here and the quantity is 7.
So we have 7 books named CppHowToProgram.
I'm using no spaces here just to make things simpler.
The book ID is 101, in real projects
There is always some ID attached to an object that we have like here, the book, for example.
But to make it simpler, we are assuming that the user is going to provide the ID.
But in practice, you probably will generate the ID by yourself.
The second task is searching for a book.
Someone came to the admin and asked him, I would like to know if there is a book named "CppHow
ToProgram", for example, then he needs to search for that.
You might think, OK, let's write the whole book name and just search for it.
But there is a more efficient searching strategy, what we call a prefix,
The prefix is an indicator to the first letters of a word.
Specifically, let's say that we have these 4 books in the system "CppHowToProgram", "CppFor
Dummies", "CppForAdvancedLevels" and "CoreJava".
Then the query gives us "Cpp" only,
So "Cpp" are the first three letters of three books.
This book and this book and this book.
So this is a prefix query.
You give a small prefix which is just the initial letters and then he is finding every book
starting with "Cpp".
So if the query was "CppFo" then we have two books, starting with this prefix "CppForDummies", "Cpp
ForAdvancedLevels".
If the user entered "core", then "CoreJava" will be the book.
If we entered "Java", nothing will be printed.
Why?
Because we are searching for "Java" as a prefix, any word start with "Java"? No
"Java"
Here is a part of the word.
You might extend the program by yourself,
If you would like to search for the keyword exist anywhere in the name,
It's up to you.
But here we are only maintaining the prefix of the search query.
Another general operation might be that we would like to list all the books in the system.
if your system is listing the data, there is typically several columns in this data like here,
You can imagine the admin is seeing a column for the ID and another column for the name and
maybe third column for the quantities.
So typically, one interesting question is what kind of ordering or sorting for the data should be provided?
I'm here asking for 2 ordering also an order based on the IDs and order based on the names.
So let's say that we have the following books, 1111, "Math1", 5041, "ArabicLiterature",
one one blah, blah, blah.
"Math2", if you would like to list the three books in the system, but we want them sorted by name,
then "ArabicLiterature" should be the first letter A, then "Math1" and "Math2".
But if you would like them to be listed by ID, then it should be
This guy is the smallest ID, so it should be "Math2" first, then this guy should be listed "Math1" second,
And then this guy here is the third because it is the biggest ID.
And I remember we said that the IDs are integer,
So we are sorting here by integer.
So this is the listing.
And remember, always there are some criteria, which kind of column has a priority in ordering
the data.
There is also another functionality, and here it's more relevant about the users
also, we would like to list which users borrowed a specific book.
So given that we have several books, the admin want to know who borrowed something.
The input would be something like a book name, let's say "Math1" as an input and the output would be
the list of user names who borrowed a specific book.
Moving to the other side, the user operations, also the admin might want to add a new user to the library because
he would like to borrow some books from us, every book will have an integer ID and will have a name, feel free to add
more features here.
We are only requesting two features, the ability to borrow a book and to return a book, feel free to
go more.
You can think of a lot of extra features.
As you know, borrowing a book is a very repetitive scenario in libraries, so each book has a specific
number of copies, like remember the "CppHowToProgram",
There were 7 copies of the book. to be able to borrow a book,
The quantity recorded in the system must be greater than 0.
So if there is a request to borrow a book that has a zero quantity, you should give an error message
that there are no more copies in the system for that.
If a user managed to borrow a specific book, then the computer quantity, about this book should be decreased.
The scenario goes as following:
The admin enters two things the username and the book name.
And then if there is enough quantity of a book,
The system will do two things,
First is going to mark that the this user borrowed a specific copy and also decrease the available quantity
with 1, if there is no available copies,
If there are no available copies, the system notifies the admin about that.
Returning a book is just the reverse of the last operation, so you mark that this user returned a copy,
so he don't have the copy anymore,
And also, you are going to increment the current quantity.
If we have five copies at the moment, they will be six copies.
Yeah.
Generally speaking, your whole system should be integral.
This means that your data should be correct, like really go and remove the user information and so
on.
That's all.