In this video, I would like to show a simulation for the usage of the system.
The user is faced with 10 choices here and then a menu request from 1 to 10.
I started to get the choice of 1, 1 1, 1, 1.
I'm feeding information.
So with every 1, I'm adding a book,
The book has a name, has an ID, has a total quantity.
There are three inputs from the user.
So the user here entered the input ID: 100,  name: "Math4" and there is 3.
The one who is entering this data is the admin. So entered
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6 books.
And then we give a choice of 4, 4
Here is printing the whole library but by ID.
So now the whole library will be printed in this order and notice here it's by ID, name, then quantity.
But the IDs here are sorted in inputs and these are the current quantity and there is no borrowing
for this book at the moment.
I can also enter 5, to order them by name.
So now you see what is ordered
now here is name, "Math1"
"Math2", "Math3", "Math4", "Programming1", "Programming2".
Now we have a different ordering at the moment.
Proceeding more, I entered input 6, input 6 is for adding a user, to add a user, you need to add
a name for him and I new ID.
So again, we entered 1 user, 2, 3, 4. 4 names only.
Now we entered 7,
7 is user want to borrow a specific book.
So I would like to enter two things,
What is the user name and what is the book name?
It seems that Mostafa borrowed that one.
And "Math2", and "Math3". "Ali", "Math1" and "Math2". "Noha" "Math1" and "Math2". now enter again choice
number 4 to print the whole library.
You will start to notice that "Math2" is borrowed three times.
By whom?
If you try to investigate,
here is "Math2" by "Ali", here is "Math2" by "Noha", here is "Math2" by "Mostafa".
So yes, this book has been borrowed three times. from another data perspective you might print
the users,
So here we start to see the user
"Mostafa" has this ID and borrowed books 101, 102, 103.
So now you see here our information has been reflected in different other operations.
It seems that this user, "Ashraf", has has no borrowing so far.
If we enter the choice 2, we are going to search by a book prefix, so now we would like to find
all the books that start with two letters, "ma".
So we have "Math4", 2, 1, 3. Another search with the word "pro" , show "programming1", "programming2".
If I entered something like "machine" for machine learning books,
There are no books with such a prefix. Choice
number 3 is who borrowed a specific book.
We entered "math1" we want to know which users borrowed
this book, it is going to print that "Mostafa", "Ali", "Noha" borrowed this book. in a similar way,
Who borrowed "Math2"? "Mostafa", "Ali" and "Noha".
Who borrowed "machine"?
There are no books with this name,
This is an invalid name. 4, let's print now the system.
The system is, as we showed before, in this way.
Let's now print the users we already saw that. we would like now to test the feature number 8.
Feature number 8 is returning a book.
So we saying that "Mostafa" is returning "Math1".
And you see here that "Math1" is borrowed three times and "Mustafa" really borrowed "Math1" here,
102, after this operation,
if we tried to print again the library, we will notice that the  "Math1" quantity decreased
here, the borrowed one.
So you notice here 2, but you notice here 3.
So the book is returned.
If we printed, the users will notice that "Mostafa" doesn't have "Math1" anymore.
So you see how the system is integral over all, the data is correct.
That's all.