This video will learn how to think in the data, in the solution of the second project, the library
system. Starting with the big picture of the project, we have here a struct for maintaining the
book and another struct for the user, a third one for library system, which we ran from here like
we did before.
We'll start to browse the code here.
Remember, make your first function something that provide the user with all these choices.
So we have here the run function which keeps looping, taking a choice from the user.
We have a lot of choices.
So based on the choice we start to call the corresponding function for it.
Let's do some basic browsing for the book
user,  the book struct.
We have here a book ID book name and also we have the total quantity, which will be like a fixed number.
let's say 10, and the current borrowed one from zero up to 10 maximum.
And we have some functionality like let's read, return a book, checking if a book has a prefix
or not and so on.
So every time you need a specific functionality relevant to the book, you put it here.
There are a couple of functionalities here that will help us to sort books, maybe by name or by
ID.
For the user struct, we have user ID, user name, and also we have like a list of the books that the
user has borrowed.
And given that this is array, we need some variable to tell us the current length of this.
In a similar way, we can read it, we can borrow something, we can return something and we can
check if this book is borrowed or not.
The printing of that, will get into the details of that.
So let's go with the choices.
The first the choice here is add_book.
I have.
while loop.
And then with an add book choice, I just have an add_book function.
The add_book function is as follows.
I have in the library system,
I have an array of books and array of users.
So here in the add_book function it's going to like...,
Get an object from here and ask it to be read, which was just to go and read the elements of a book.
So this syntax, I hope it isn't weird.
You get the array element which is now an object, and then you .read it.
To read the object, you would like to ask for the ID, name, and quantity and that's all.
And initially, the total borrowed
it should be zero value.
So this is our first choice, the second the choice is search books by prefix.
Remember, we need to give a prefix and we need to find all of the books that has this prefix. To make
our life easier,
I developed the has_prefix function as a function inside the books.
So let's iterate over all our books. For every book, we check if it starts with this prefix or not,
if it starts with that, we just print it.
The function has_prefix is a simple function.
You have a prefix and you have a name.
If the name is less than the prefix, then definitely doesn't match.
Otherwise, we iterate till the length of the prefix.
If at any point of time there is no match, then it cannot be to fix for it.
If we are done with this loop, then definitely we matched the whole prefix.
Otherwise, this run should be activated.
So this is the has_prefix function.
And this is how the search book by prefix, in general, is working; just iterate match and that's all. I hope
you are getting more sense of how to, like, put functionalities together of something like I need
search by prefix , which is part of the menu, the search
needs to check by prefix, you might do a loop here to check by prefix.
But it's much better to move it to the book data structure or the book structure.
The third choice here, let's close this menu, the third choice here is borrowing a book.
So to do that, we first of all need the book name.
And then I have here developed a simple function that help me to find a book index by name.
I give it a name and it returns for me a book index. From a high level from
now, if the book index is negative one, then we didn't find such a book.
Otherwise, we have the book and we have an ID for it.
So we check how many books are like borrowed from that guy.
If the number is zero and this shouldn't happen, then sorry, if the number of zero is, then we cannot
borrow any books anymore at the moment.
If we are done with this check and with this check, then the remaining is just to mark this
book as is
borrowed book.
Yeah.
Yeah, this is a point we are going to iterate over all of our users to check if this person borrowed
the book or not.
So the purpose of the function, remember originally that we would like to know who borrowed the book
by name.
So we give it a name.
We'll get an index.
We validate it is valid.
We validate that there are actually copies.
And after that we can iterate here. We have two functions to check, the is_borrowed is an easy
function.
You iterate over inside the book, inside the user, you iterate over the ...,
OK, the user here, we already said that, the user here has a list of books already so we can iterate
over the books.
And if I'm matching any one of them, then I already borrowed this book.
Otherwise, we return false.
Let's suppose this guy's going back to the library system here.
So this is the check of the is_borrowed. The remaining check is the functionality and the function is finding a book index
by name.
So we give it a name, we iterate over all of the current books.
If the book name matches it, we return 'i'.
The purpose of returning the index is to use it to do more job by it.
If we couldn't find it, we just returned negative one as a signal that no book with such a name.
This shouldn't happen.
But in case, like if you are providing right name then it shouldn't happen.
The fourth function is printing & printing. This two functions as printing one by ID and one by name.
So we mainly need to know we are here inside the library.
We need mainly to make a sorting for all the current books, but we are going to provide this same function
here to sort by ID, the sort of a name is very, very similar structure.
So the moral of that is we have an array and we know that array plus a total current box is a current
length.
If we provided a comparative function, then we can sort all of the data and then the remaining is just
to print the data.
After that, we have a function to add the user, so let's see how to add him.
We have a list of users already, array of users.
You just add the user here and just then you start to read the user.
Very similar structure,like the add_book.
After that, we have a user that would like to borrow a book, so to do this functionality, we
have here a helper function that will read for us the user name and the book name so that we
can borrow them together.
So let's jump in this function first. This function has here a user name and book name, and I'm giving
him by default a maximum of three trials. Within every trial,
I ask him for a user name and book name and then remember the find user function.
This function takes a name, you can get the logic; it takes a name and return its index to array.
If there is no such user, we ask him to try again. In a similar way,
we give a function of book name to return a book index for us.
If no such a book, it
gives an error message.
If we reached these two cases, we return a true. Observe here,
the user ID and book ID are sent by reference.
So the bool is an indicator if we succeed or not.
And the two parameters here are by reference.
Let's get back to here once we returned from this function, we have a user ID and we have a book ID
All what we need to do is to try to borrow for this user, for this book
this user ID. If we couldn't, we tell him that there are no more users.
Otherwise, we go to the user himself and tell him, borrow the book. So going to the book,
it just takes the book  ID and started to put it inside the class itself.
Uh.
Going back to this menu, I think all of them are following the same similar logic. If it would
like to return a book, in a very similar way, you try first to read name and ID for you, then you ask the book
to return a copy and you ask the user to return a copy. For example, here, this guy took a book
and you would like to return a copy.
So we have now an internal list of books.
We are going to find this book.
But the problem now is we would like to remove an element from the middle of the array.
So there are many tricks for that.
But one way here is just to make a right shift, like shifting all of the data after the position to
the current position.
For example, if you have like, say, one, two, three, four, I would like to remove three.
So move the four to three.
This how you remove the array and minimize the length here.
If you couldn't remove it, then you give a message that we cannot like...,
this user never borrowed the book.
Probably, overall I expect you to be confused.
The reason behind that is the project might not be an easy one for you.
It depends. In terms of thinking, it takes time so that you you can develop a proper view.
One way to think about it, let's say you would like to build such a system, start to figure
out all the names that should be used as a class or as a struct.
Here we can figure out that we need a book.
We can figure out that we need the user.
We need some front end to keep presenting the choices. We need here
some while loops to have list of choices.
We need one function for every choice of these guys and then we need to start fill implementation.
So this is how you can access the big picture of the system. By thinking what are the main items,
let's start to do at like scratch from something like
basics for them. In the second step, start to implement every function and try in a very early
way to recognize the utilities that you might need.
For example, observe here this function read the user name and book name this a very generic function.
It just read for us this couple of items.
I think it is used twice in the code.
So this is a nice utility that we developed during the code. The more
you can divide your code, the easier task for you and also easy to debug and easy to find the books.
So this is the overall. Think about your choices, develop function for everyone, start to develop the
code of them. Again,
try to do this code by yourself and after that, try to understand, read very well, remove all of
the code, write it from scratch by yourself. That's all.