In this section, we will move to a very popular topic, the binary search topic, but let's first
refresh the linear search or the sequential search topic.
If I told you we have an array of sorted numbers, return the index of a given number. For example,
if you have all of these numbers and the target is 50, so you proceed in the list, till finding 50,
which is at index four. What about 70? Seventy doesn't exist.
So the index is -1.
This is an O(n) algorithm.
Linear search is very trivial to code.
However, it is very inefficient,
also. There is one thing here, the array is sorted. Remember this advice,
whenever you have a special property, you should use them right. When we discussed the count sort
and the range was from zero to 500.
This is a special property, make use of it.
Now the question is if the array is sorted.
Can we find a way to make our search way faster than that?
Let me give you a smart analogy.
Imagine that you have a programming course.
You went to the professor's office to get your marked assignments.
You have all of these huge pile of papers here.
The good thing is the assignments are ordered in alphabetical order.
So let's say your name is June.
And you don't know where is June in all of that, but you know that they are ordered.
So how do you efficiently search for your stuff?
Logically, you will not just go name by name, right?
So here is a very efficient way.
This should be not name by name.
One way is as following. First, divide these piles of papers to two almost equal parts, and then get
the paper in the middle.
Let's say the name of the paper was Fiona.
Now you know that June is after Fiona, and we know the names are ordered in an alphabetical way.
So this definitely means my name is definitely not in the first half.
Now I can go to the second pile, the second part here, and start to do the exact process again.
Divide them into two parts and check the middle one and so on.
You keep repeating the process, in every time, you get rid of half of the number of papers.
This is very similar logic.
If you have a very huge page like a book of 4000 pages, and you're searching for page number two thousand
nine hundred, you know that the book page numbers are ordered from small to large, and you will
definitely can start by going to the middle of the book.
Or maybe after the middle of the book.
If you discovered, for example, that you open page number
1800, you definitely know you don't care about the first half of the book, you care
about the second one, and so on.
So this is actually what it is called a
binary search. This process that smart people do is a binary search approach, and it depends
on the fact that the items are sorted.
So let's try
simulate that here.
We have an array of numbers.
We are sure the numbers are sorted.
I ask you to find the value 55.
We don't know
where is it. Now,
.
Let's divide the array to two halves.
Assume for a while that the left pointer is at zero here,
left index, and the right is at index
ten. Where is the middle?
The middle is (0+10)/2, which is five.
Now we go to the value of five, which is 41.
We search for 55.
This means that definitely the value, if exists, will be after index number five.
We can only do that because we know the values are sorted.
So now we can safely ignore the values from index zero to index five.
Now our start is at left here, index six, and our end at index ten.
Let's do the same process.
Get the middle, which is
(6+10)/2, which is index eight, the value in index eight is 72.
I am searching for 55.
Definitely,
55 is before 72.
So this means we can safely ignore the array from index eight to index ten, and just focus on the range
six to seven.
In a similar way,
divide and get the middle, (6+7)/2 is just still six.
And now we just found it, so we are lucky about that.
Let's change the request a little bit.
What if I was asking you to find 60? Now, 55 versus 60 is smaller, so we know we need to go to
the right part, which is just seven and seven, and so on.
I would like you to try to think about how can we implement this approach.
And there is here a problem, LeetCode 704.
You can try the code over it.
OK.
Test cases, the test cases are as following, similar to the sorting ideas, you need to try
different lengths.
It's very clear also that considering unique or duplicate values is important, maybe also you try some positive
and negative values in your array.
That's it. Thinking about the search query itself.
There is two scenarios.
The element exists or doesn't exist. Now,
One important position to check is the first position here, index zero.
Another position is the last one.
I call that boundary thinking, jump to the boundaries because they are important.
You can also check some of the arbitraries values, maybe something in the first half, something in
the second half, somewhere in the middle.
OK.
What about the element that doesn't exist? You need to check also, and you can see that maybe the element
doesn't exist because it's before the first element.
So test -10, for example, or after the last element, something like 100 or something in between,
like 15 and 75.
So this is the overall systematic way of thinking about
test cases.
Eventually, here is the code, I hope you try to implement it by yourself.
The process is very easy.
You have a vector of numbers and you have some value.
Your start is at zero, your end is at the last index.
And by the way, remember when you take .size(), cast it to integer before subtracting minus
one.
If this value is zero, it will be (0 - 1), and .size() in C++ returns unsigned variable.
So it will end up a very huge number.
It will like roll back in the integer representation, so be very careful.
That's why I usually cast the size to an integer. Otherwise,
Yeah, you have to be careful this way.
Now the loop is as following.
while ( start <= end ), as long as, we have a valid interval of at least a single element.
I'm computing the middle value, which is ( start + end ) / 2, this is the index.
Now there are three scenarios.
If the index in the middle equals the number, then we found it.
We are done.
If the current value is actually bigger than the middle, then we know we can definitely ignore the
first part of the vector, which means we can start from the (middle+1).
If the middle is actually beyond the value, it means we have to ignore the second
part.
So the end should be adjusted to -1.
Now, again, as you see, it's all about the middle.
We have now three variables, we have the start, and we have the middle, and we have the end.
If the middle is the right one, we return it.
Otherwise, the middle is wrong, but which part focuses it? Is it start to middle + 1  or,
Sorry, Is it start to (middle - 1) or (middle +1) to end?
This is what's happening here.
Like, for example, if you have the value 55, and comparing with 41, so 41 is less than 55.
Yes, we have to move to the second array part.
So our start is after the middle.
So start is middle +1.
So as you see, it's all about either changing the start or the middle.
The start is moving to the right side.
The middle is moving to the left side. If this loop ended up with start is greater than the end.
It means we never found the array.
So here is -1.
Please do two things.
First of all, take the array that I give, and the test cases that I give, trace all of them one
by one till you are 100 percent sure you understand what is happening here.
Put here print statement, like put a print statement,
What is the start?
What is the middle?
What is the end?
What is the value of the middle? Print it, so that you can be sure from the performance.
The last thing is, what is the time complexity of this code?
That's all for now.