Let's solve brain researcher homework, No.
Two.
In the first task here, we would like to compute the smallest given threshold, as you see, we started
to work on functions and now not just the normal array.
So the first step always will be one or two minutes to verify that your function is monotonic, increasing
or decreasing strictly or not, but it must be monotonic function.
So this is the first thing here.
What is the target of the problem?
The target of the problem is the dividers.
So the first idea that you should think about it?
Let's say we have divisor the.
Air Force is telling us if it is valid or not, but it's very based on what?
Based on the submission.
So we have our if one which make the submission mainly and we use this to check the possible function.
Now let's think about about this submission function here.
Assume you tried some divisor and made the sealing submission, and let's say we get four foot four
divisor, the submission is.
What is the result of this plus one?
Is it random or increasing or decreasing when you have a bigger?
Divisor, the submission must decrease.
So it's a two year must be smaller than or equal to IS two one.
OK, D-plus two, it must generate a smaller value then is it all?
Is there equal to it?
So this means we have a metric decrease in function.
Again, the logic is as follows.
What does this function?
Does this problem search for it, search for a device, then tell yourself, can we buy in the research
on the devices?
OK.
To do that, we need to verify.
We need to make submission.
And we need to check possible.
We need to know if the possible function is mutagenic or not.
The possible function depends on the submission function.
And with every increase in the days in the devices that the submission is decreasing.
This is montoyo function.
So now we've verified it in a couple of minutes.
So the idea?
Let's just buy the research on the on the results.
So here we go.
First of all, let's make our submission function, the submission function.
Take the NUM's and the divisor iterate on every number and it should do.
The division was saying you can do the sitting in when amazed, like in C++, you can compute the seal
of a over B and then add here a small epsilon for any errors and then cost to integer.
This is one way, but there is a smarter way to do the ceiling, which you keep everything in integers
as following you would like to divide it over B.
Let's let's give an example.
Let's say you would like to divide the 16 and let's say who would like to do that over overfull now
16 over four is four perfect.
16 17.
Overfull is for something, this should be five.
How to make this five as easy as possible.
There are also two ways.
One way is you do the integer division, so 17 over four is four.
And the chick with the modernists is 17.
Modulus four equals zero.
If yes, then incrementally models answer.
But this is also a nice idea.
Let's make it way smarter than that.
What happened if you added for the 17 four minus one?
The idea is this following was every four values from here, when we divide them by four, we get extra
one when you try 17 17 plus four is 21, minus one is.
Twenty over four is fight.
So the moral of that is we're minus one is just one less value than here.
So if the mother is from 17 has at least one extra value, it will push this one to be one.
I hope it's clear for you, though.
OK, what about 16, which is already perfect if you added four minus one?
And here's four 16 over food is already the model is zero and complete, so four minus one over four
is just zero.
So the model of that is if you don't get it just right more.
If you would like to complete the of and be in integer domain, you just say A-plus B minus one over
B.
This is a seed in the integral domain and it is a smart trick.
So keep in mind, let's go back to our problem.
If you are puzzled with this line of equation, as I told you several ways to the seed, so just don't
confuse yourself with that.
We iterate on the rate.
We do the division by the number, but we keep it in the seed and this is the sum function and this
function is maintaining decreasing.
So now we would like their smallest possible variable.
So let's say that we were, first of all, what is the range of the values that we can try?
The minimum is one, the first, the smallest device that is one.
What is the average device or the largest device, which is the largest value in the race, the maximum
in the array in C++?
We can give the maximum with this equation in an easy way, so extra element would return to that maximum
value in the given array.
But the array must have at least regulated single value.
So now this is the start and the end result is want and end is the maximum because it doesn't make sense
to compute answers.
The voters want the maximum because the writing about all the maximum will just convert all of it once
you need more to good at that.
So this is a first a question, and you should always ask yourself about that.
What is the state and in the values?
Usually it is just little thinking.
Now the second, the question is.
I would like to do the search, so this condition is normal.
This one is normal.
I would like to find the smallest divisor, so let's say this is very divisor, this is very divisor,
this is very divisor.
This is very divisor.
I will take the smallest one.
This could should be look like the first occurrence of an element.
We need the first one, the first valid one.
So we are going to mix the condition for the small with the condition less so.
This here is mixing for the smallest and that the equality together.
So we say here, if the submission is less than or equal the threshold, it is a valid submission.
Please save this divisor for us, but we are searching for a smaller divisor.
So let's move to the left part.
I hope the overall good is clear for you.