Let's move to the second problem.
Uh, the book, it's one.
OK, again, I would like you to be very systematic in buying the research because it will work well
in like 80 percent of the cases.
What is a goal of this problem finding a number of days?
So the first thing you tell yourself, can we buy in the session days?
OK, we need to verify it's Montana.
So the possible function we should be able to take, the possible function is based on some competition.
We need to verify the competitions are monotonic.
So here is the point.
Let's say we have there is the one day to day three the.
If let's say that five buckets are possible today.
Then tomorrow, we at least have five book, it's after tomorrow, maybe you have one more book it after
after tomorrow, we have one more book.
So the more they use, the more flowers are blooming and we have more, more book.
It's ready.
This is clearly a binary search function.
I want tonic function so we can buy another associate.
So now the question is, let's imagine the research that that there is the first.
The question is, and what is the smallest day and what is the largest day?
So the smallest day is typically one day.
The largest day is the maximum day in the blooms days.
And here is our variable that we will see if the answer, isn't it?
This is just some optimization if there is no way anyway to make the answer.
The good is, as usual, this is a quality.
We can build the method as usual.
And what do we need year?
We need the minimum days.
So if this one is okay, D2 is OK, this three is OK, the four is OK.
We need the smallest one of them, which is the one.
So again, we need the lake the first two appearance, but we need the smallest among all of them,
so we would like to merge the condition of their little zen.
With the equality, so here we have the result of equality.
So what I'm saying here, I'm calling the function, it's called possible.
I give it out of this bunch of information.
So the possible function here, bill here is the first one.
Now I'm mixing the merging, the possible with the the competition.
So this good will take the number of waiting days so far and will tell me how many buckets are ready
if at any point of time the total number of buckets are enough.
We are done and we returned it through.
Otherwise we return false.
So here we iterate on the bloom days.
If the Bloom Day is less than or equal to the waiting days, like, let's say, the flower need for
these to bloom and we wait seven days, then this is a flower with us.
I am having year a variable adjacent to flowers.
It keeps telling me how many additions the flower they have so far.
So let's say waiting days is seven.
The first the flower has blooming of two, then five, then three, then eight.
So I am iterating.
Blooming day is OK.
Yes, count is one.
Blooming day is a case count to blooming day is a case count to three, but every day is okay.
No, it isn't okay.
So this is how I'm updating that dozens of laws now, Gridley, if at any point of time the current
adjustment, the flowers are enough for an extra bucket.
Then we have one more bucket from here and we remove its adjacent flower.
I believe this is a trivial function to write like its basic logic.
You have waiting days and you have things, then just iterate and get them together.
The sense of grouping the first elements is a very trivial, greedy idea.
Again, you do need to know what is good.
Great is just very logical.
As we mentioned before, this was.