Let's solve the third, the problem, the heaters, so in this problem would like to set up the heaters,
specifically the ridges of the heaters, so like we did so far.
What is the goal?
The good is the ridges, specifically the minimum ridges.
So the first thing you tell yourself is a radius itself, like it's a function is monotonic or not.
So let's think about it.
So let's assume that we're going to try this.
Let's say we try to Eq. one, and let's say it covered seven houses.
Now, when you try it, it is equal to.
What happens?
Is it predictable?
Yes, it must be at least given.
So maybe another seven registry, maybe 10 house now radius for maybe the 12 houses.
This is monotonic increasing function, so it seems that the more we increase the reduce.
The function that tells us how many houses are covered is also increasing.
So it does.
No one is done.
We are sure that this is a binary search about this piece.
Now let's proceed with that.
The first thing is deciding the minimum and the maximum of a certain end so we can have Regis equals
zero.
And the maximum is I use one item, one item, nine, which is 10, one nine zero.
Why this big number, the let good values are such a huge.
I went up 8:40, so I used the maximum value here.
Another way may be to just compute the maximum from these two arrays, but anyway, this is just one
way.
Why I'm showing it to you this way, especially for guys in competitive programming.
Sometimes you do need to care to think a lot about the end.
In a way it's going to be look value.
So just big enough value, small enough value are all what you need and the region as usually you do
them.
The minute we saw the first couple of examples of finding the minimum, so it would mix the condition
of less than an equal together.
Why?
Because we would like to find the fittest, reduce the smallest radius that is good enough.
So if, for example, R1 is good, R2 is good.
R3 is good.
We need this minimum one.
So whenever we have a solution, we keep pushing to the left side.
So so far, the recursion is very standard.
The only remaining thing is given a specific reduce.
We would like to know if this is enough or not.
So the possible function here is mixing the competition and the comparison in the same time now to make
that possible function efficient as possible.
I sorted here the the houses and the heaters.
So let me tell you the logic behind this function, which you should be able to develop by itself.
Let's see.
Let's say we have houses at the following location maybe one, maybe five, maybe 10, maybe 20.
And let's say we have heaters at the following location.
Maybe three, maybe, uh, maybe seven, maybe 30.
These are our heaters.
And now we have our let's say the R is to the radius is two.
So if we have three, they just do.
It means from three minus two.
Two or three blocks, two is our coverage window, so we do have this following, we trade on the heaters
one by one, we take the current heater and get the minus and B+.
So this is the lift, the coverage and the right coverage of the current heaters and then G is initialized
to iterate on their houses.
I keep iterating on the houses as long as the current house is, but is covered by the current heater.
Just move for the next one.
So let's say that it just is too.
So now we started with one here.
Three minus two is one.
Three plus two is five.
So is is one in the range of four and five years.
Move to the next.
The house is five within the one on five.
Yes, so move to the next house is then in the order and five no.
Now we move to the second heater here and computes its range, which would be seven minus two is five
seven plus two is seven plus two is nine, now is five.
And then within the current heater also.
No.
So we stop here now we move to the next heater and then get the minus two and +2, which would be twenty
eight and thirty two.
Now is a ten.
Is that is it then in the range and also not in the range?
So as you see, we end with this function that the G is still stuck at, then we couldn't cover it.
So we say, no, we couldn't.
Again, the model of this function is we iterate by the heater for every heater we get its range and
the cover as possible as we can from the houses.
And that's why we need even to sort of the houses and the heaters, both of them.
Because this ordering here, this logic here depends on the ordering, like it depends on that.
They are like maybe here two seven, uh, 12, maybe one, five, uh, 10.
So this is a this is a heater, does it cover?
Nor does it cover, nor does it cover?
No.
And so we can write this could to be more efficient, but still, in a way, it is possible.
What is the term complexity of this function?
It is just, oh, heater is a B+ house, is because this look at it on the heater and this little bit
of it on their house is this g is initialized only here, so it just cover only once.
So overall, this is in like and in the square or it's just queer, it is just that the house is built
as the heater size this functions here is in look.
In this way, Lou is look end times dysfunction.
So this again, overall, here is in again.
So the whole complexity of this function is in look at now we are done with the good and we are happy
and everything is good.
But I would like to tell you another angle for the reasons, and this is important.
So you see, now that even binary surgery can be handled from different angles, the previous angle
is based on the direct, systematic operation I did in the previous two problems.
You ask yourself, what is the good radius?
Let's obtain the assertion the radius.
Can we write an authentic function?
Yes.
Could it be that simple?
This one is based on observations.
So the idea is following Let's say this is some house here.
Which Heater will cover this house?
Logically, then it two heaters.
So if there are a lot of heaters here and a lot of heaters here, was this specific regions, at least
if any of this cover?
Also, there's too much to cover.
So the model of that every house is only covered by its senior staff, and it's the nearest right nearest
to lift a needed striped heater.
So the logic would be as following for every house.
Get its.
Duke loses to heaters and then let it be covered by the minimum one, like, let's say we have your
house in position 10, and we have a heater at position two and we have heater ed position 12.
So logically we can connect it to the to the smallest one.
So we need the heater a must of at least three to four this house.
So it is on every house, compute his minimum or his suitable heater.
Reduce and maximize among all of them.
Again, the idea coming from the observation that a house would be covered either by the left or the
right one, the nearest left or nearest right, which one is specifically the closest one.
So now we know that house one near the of, let's say, three houses to need a heater of links one house,
three mm of land, seven.
So the maximum among all of them is seven.
This is the answer, and this now takes us to a very different and easier implementation.
Now we only care about sorting the heaters only and for every house we can lower bound in the heaters
to find something that is, uh, we would like to find the nearest the heater for it.
There are two.
There are three cases here.
It is a house case number one.
We has a heater in the lift and heater in the right, so we need to take the minimum up.
Among them is number one.
We have a heater only before it, so just take it.
Case number two, we have heater only after it shows just take it.
So I'm handling here the two special cases and then that general case.
I hope you get the idea as you see one perspective in the normal brain research unit array.
Another perspective ended up with the generalized version of binary search and the key message here
don't lock yourself in a specific solution or even don't look yourself in the same implementation.
We can think of from different angles.
We can implement the the same approach in different ways, and I would like you to try to give this
a scale from the course.
That's all.