Let's see homework number three, which is a bit harder than the previous ones in the first task.
We would like to find the first, the missing and not the missing, not the first.
The Keith missing element in a binary search right now.
Let me first extend learned little more here.
We have an array for seven, nine, 10, starting from four.
What are the missing elements?
We have four, then five is missing, six is missing, we have seven, then eight is missing, we have
nine and we have 10.
So five is the first missing number six is the second.
Missing number eight is a third, the missing number considering only the beginning here.
Now the function will give you the array and give you equal one and ask you to find the fifth missing
element, which you hear is clearly number five.
OK, what about here?
Take one three.
The third the missing element is key equal eight here.
What about this one?
We have one.
Then we have two.
Three is missing.
Four we have four.
Five is missing, six is missing, seven is missing.
And so now it asks us for the third, the missing element, which is six here.
So this is mainly the problem.
This problem can be solved with the number two, by the way, is are sorted.
This problem can be solved with an end could in a normal way.
I would suggest for you to try to write it, but I would like you to develop an all look in brain research
approach for this problem.
The next the problem is following, and it's a very interesting problem.
This is a multiplication table, right?
Like let's you know, when the normal multiplication table is usually midterms and when we were kids.
So now this is a multiplication table for M equals three and inequality, which means you try you start
to say one times, one one times, two one times or three two times one two times to two times or three
three times one three times, two, three times or three.
This is a normal multiplication table of three times the three.
So the problem will give you two numbers M and N, which are there the dimension of the table.
It could be, for example, two and five.
So you say two times one, two times two, blah blah blah up to 2005 and so on.
Now, let's say, after we built this table, we put it in one diary and sorted all of them.
Now, the function would give you a key.
No, you're turning the key element in this one array.
So here is the problem again, the problem fixed itself like you will be given Mandan, which are a
bit big and key, which it would be in times in the range and you would like to find the key, the smallest
element in there, MS terms in the multiplication key, the smallest element in the multiplication.
In other words, if you flatten the array, the to the array and one the and all of them, we need the
key value from here.
Here is another example.
Um, we have two times the three metrics we wrote, the values we wrote them here.
We thought to them, we need number six.
So here is the sixth element in this list.
So as you see, the two problems are both the key element, but from two different perspectives.
These are merely the two problems for we have the challenges.