That's sort of the missing element in the array.
This problem is harder than what we used to.
Let's let's learn why.
So what is the classical way that we were solving problems so far?
The problem is asking for the kit.
No, let's obtain the research and the gift number.
Let's get the function of finding the gift number and let's have a weitzman tonic.
So we would like to find the gift number in the array.
OK, so maybe we say that maybe the storage equals zero, may be the end, may be equal, maybe any,
any big value, whatever.
And then the medal now represents our gift function.
Now we would like to develop a function, so if of if of the array and cake.
Well, what is that like it returning the current Typekit element?
This is our request.
It seems we cannot even develop a function.
OK.
It seems we cannot even develop a function based on that.
So at the moment, you should feel like this isn't going to be binary sociable and this is actually
the heart of the case.
The heart of the case and binary search when searching, when they're searching on the request is impossible.
So what should you do?
You should try to find.
You should try to find another relevant function that can help you in the request.
So let me give you an example of a wrong function.
So one might say, OK, I'm going to bind the research on values.
So maybe the smallest value is zero or the lowest, and the the largest value is maybe any anything
that's very big.
The end is something like 10 to the bone, right?
So now the this is a value.
OK, so now the middle.
Is a value.
These two things over two.
OK, so we need some if operate and meddle, the function may be returned for us if this is the kit
element or not.
So I'm giving it the ray and I'm giving it the suggested value and I'm telling it is a gift or not.
That's it.
The Boolean function.
Does this work when you think about it?
All of the entries will give you serious.
Mitt and Keith here.
And only one specific position would give one, which is the Keith.
And other thing is you assume somehow we can implement this one.
Again, this isn't a binary, searchable space.
It is the third the idea.
They did this following.
We will be doing the research on the arrays in this is itself so that small will be zero.
And the large will be, um, the length of the array minus one.
OK, what does that?
What is the idea here?
So the middle is now an index, the middle is some index.
OK, so some f based on the index and based on the array and maybe UK, what is a good?
Here is how we can develop a function, if that is useful, the function f will take the index and take
number and return how many numbers are missing until numbers of index.
How many numbers are missing?
And then numbers of ending.
OK, so let's say the array has a values like one, four, uh, nine and the ten.
So at one, how many missing elements are zero?
At four?
How many missing elements?
Two and three.
So there are two missing elements at nine.
How many missing elements so far to three and six seven eight.
So overall, five 11, six seven eight, let's say this is 12.
How many elements were we're missing?
10 and 11.
So the missing element now are seven.
As you see the good news about this function, it is an increasing function.
So the function which the how many missing elements, if the current index is the end of the array.
So we give it the index to return for five index the three, there are seven.
This is an increasing function.
Now the question is if we have this function.
Can you stop the vigil for a few minutes and think, how can you use it to guide the body in the research?
The idea now is very simple, by the way, if we found the first element where the number of missing
elements are greater than or equal K.
So let's go back to our case here, the one before, uh, nine and the 12, which was zero and two and
five and the seven.
Let's say I'm searching for their fifth.
Let's say I'm searching for their fifth fifth, missing the missing element.
OK, so I'm going to search for the first index where it's a SIM missing is greater than or five.
So this is the element, right?
These two are identical.
Five.
This is the first one.
So starting from nine, we can get the index to four, which is four, and count the key to find their
missing element, which would be, uh, four plus two, which is six here.
So again, we managed to find some relevant function that is binary, searchable.
And the idea was find the first index of that is greater than equal.
Keep the index before it directly can be used to solve the target problem.
OK, so how can we solve that?
Is missing function?
It's actually end up with a very simple equation here with the simple math you can find that is a let's
say we have an array that say, for example, three four five six 10, and let's say you are an index
here.
So now we know that from three to 10, there are eight values, but we are we are only were only at
index four here.
So what are these missing values?
They are simply missing.
So 10, which is the current the maximum value minus three, which is the original value as the current
index tell us how many missing elements in between.
So this function now can tell us how many missing elements.
Now we can develop the function in an easy way.
We are now binary searching on the right, and we are finding the first index that is greater than or
equal key.
So this time the condition for greater than an equal would be merged together.
Here we will keep binary searching.
This is an index.
We tell it, Hey, does this index has greater there or more than key?
It says no, it says this.
So we move to the right, but you have a chance in a bigger one.
Otherwise, we move to the left.
But I hope you good this problem.
You'll probably have to read that you review this several times.
There is also a techy editorial from the could read it.
The next problem depends a lot on the very similar idea, so please put an effort in before moving to
the next problem.
I understand that this is harder because now you can buy an assertion, the request as it is.