Let's solve the next problem, which again, about finding some key element in an array of the it.
There is a lot of similarity between the two ideas.
If I asked you to search for the key element, then f of Keith represent what?
Almost nothing.
This kind of equality is in a key.
It's very hard to build a binary, searchable function.
It the key from the previous function was and instead of thinking about equality converted to.
Inequality.
So inequalities, converters, a piece of.
There is once to a space of.
It this way in some some context, it can convert to the space to be binary searchable, so this intricate
is going to be done again.
So let me introduce for you the function that we can use.
We will let function count.
Less than equal here, the take the table and value to return for us.
How many numbers are less than the given value?
OK.
So, uh, we give it a table, let's uh, let's build a here, a small table for three times the three.
So one time is one one two three two four six three six nine.
So this table here, if I asked you how many values are less than three, this three and these two,
there are five values.
If I told you how many values are less than six?
There are here.
So aid values are laser sorry, less than six, sorry if I told you seven, how many values are less
than seven?
There are eight values less than seven.
So the function now, I hope, is clear.
The function is given meaning and value returned for us.
How many numbers are less than the value?
Please stop the vigil.
Take 10 minutes to think.
How can you make use of this function to build your brain research a solution?
The key here is this function is monotonic.
Why?
Because the value in the value is bigger.
The numbers that are covered are more and more in the previous table here.
One two three two four six three six nine.
If I asked you for how many values are less than 10, then that is bigger.
If I asked you for how many valid reason for then the values are smaller.
So as you see, this is a tiny, confusing function.
So for the money first, you are good.
Now the question now how can we utilize this function?
I am searching for the key element.
So if I give the function some value, OK, this time were into binary search when a value and the previous
one will be in the searching would index.
This one would be their search and the value, and it would work.
So I would begin their search with the value.
And tell it, hey, how many numbers are less than this value?
So let's say I give it value like seven, and I told it how many values are less than this value?
It will say one, two, three to four.
There are aid values less than seven.
There are aid values that are less than seven, so this means that the value seven is that they're made
for value.
Right.
If I say, hey, how many values are less than five?
It would be one to two to four.
There are five values, which is one two two three three four.
How many ones?
One two three four five six.
So this mean five is the seventh value.
You see the function now.
We can use this function to give give the function a value and the function return for us.
The actual index of it, you can think of this function as we give it.
Value it, give it us back an index of the of the of the of the of the of the value.
And this is a very common binary search track.
The index value track you binary search on the value.
The function give you an index.
We use this index to decide if this is good or not enough.
So, OK, so you know, the normal array you see, if I it give you 17, for example.
No, I say like, let's say let's call it inverse inverse of 17.
It's C I.
I can use this value to get my brain research.
So again, this binary search, when the value to give me back an index is a very common binary social
side, you can see this in many other problems.
Let me summarize that again, as this problem is heart.
We try to search on the kith value itself.
It didn't work.
Now, instead of searching for the cave, we searched for the value itself, so instead of telling the
function, Hey, fine for me is the seventh value.
We told it here.
What do you think about value?
152?
Say you know what?
This is the 13 elements in the array.
I told him, Hey, you know what?
I'm searching only for the 10th element.
What about hundred?
You tell me, you know what?
This is a seventh in that.
I told them, You know what?
What about 120?
You say, You know what?
This is the ninth in the right order.
What about one hundred twenty five?
He said.
You know what?
This is the tenth in the right.
So instead of giving an index, which is the case here to get a value, well, binary, search it on
the opposite of that buying decision on the value to get back and index.
I hope you got the the idea.
If we managed to implement to this function the binary assertion that was just following the smallest,
the value is one.
The largest to value is m times n OK.
Now we begin the research in a normal way can be the index and in no way.
And then we say how many elements are less than or equal this value, it will return infamy.
Its index.
I'm committing is with the target index and then I am doing my decisions here.
OK.
What about the the function?
How can we implement it?
I would be happy if you take 10 minutes to think, how can we implemented?
The function should be all I think of him.
Uh, yeah, oh, in all, no fruits.
So here is the idea.
The idea is very simple.
And this is one good thing to remember.
You don't have to make this function very efficient, just good enough for what you do.
It could be a brute force.
It could be improved brute force.
It could be.
Many things are possible.
So the key here is following, let's say.
We have five rules and seven columns, so this means we have values one, those two, five, two, five
and so on.
Yes, sir.
We have seven columns, and we are currently at number five.
So I rule number five one five two five three five four five and so on, up to seven five.
What does a value 30 means?
The value 30 means we are at the fifth position here, so 30 over five is just six, which means we
have six values one two three four five six.
What about three?
Thirty three over five is also six, six and some fraction, which means there are six values an equal,
so this should be, uh, 33 three.
What about 35, 35 over five is seven.
Seven values are less than, uh, in this room are less than three or five here.
What about?
This should be.
I did a lot of myself.
This should be 35.
It should be 40.
What about 40 40?
Over five is eight.
But wait a second.
The maximum number of rows here and zero, only seven so that we still have seven values.
I hope you got this, this this simple math.
So the moral of that is you will iterate on rule by law and in every rule will not just be there.
So we will not just iterate to get the numbers, we cannot accept an old one.
So if you are searching too for value here and you divide by Earth, it tells you how many numbers are
exactly less than or equal this value.
But you cannot exceed the number of columns, so we are minimizing with the number of columns.
I hope no, the function is clear for you.
I will fix it that the text here of this function.
So again, what made this problem hard?
We cannot directly search the request in the previous homework, like the homework that involved the
boutique, the threshold, the problem and all of that we would buy that assertion bloodedly the problem.
But in these two problems here and there are the challenges, we couldn't do that.
And the ATA now is how can we find a relevant function that can help us to find the answer, a function
that is monotonic and can help us here.
And this is definitely the heart of the board and it take a lot of time to develop this skill.
And I what I want you to remember from this one also is that index of value trek when a function when
the request is asking you to search for an index like the create value.
Think also about binary searching when the value and getting an index from it and using that to find
your target index.
That's all.