Another important generalization to know about it is that binary search can actually work on real values.
Let's start with a simple problem.
We have an issue of excessive which has this equation.
I would like to find the root for this equation.
This mean I would like to find an X where f of X is zero.
Now I'm telling you an information that X is guaranteed to be in the range two.
Three.
The answer to this function is going to be a real no.
Maybe something like 1.5 or so.
So now I would like to find X.
Can we begin research that to begin the research on it, first of all, you need to prove that F of
X is monotonic function.
And then you need to modify the binary search, good to start to work on real values.
I would like you to take the challenge and try to change the code by yourself to solve this problem.
OK.
Let's think about how to do it.
Practically speaking, there is no magic this thought and in the variables would be double.
We need a possible function to guide the search and we need to prove it is correct and one panic.
Uh, and that's it.
The only the only new concern is actually about how to stop the coup, which isn't that hard.
Let's start with the FAA function.
They function when you think about it, you have food to the power to the board.
Seven and X were given for us and the range zero to three.
So this term almost must be a positive value.
And this one is also another was the value.
And this is a negative value.
This means that this equation must be increasing.
Mathematically must be increasing.
If you are in doubt from that, you can simply write the function and just try a bunch of conservative
values.
So when you try to see here the Albert, you just notice it is an increasing output.
So now we are sure that this function is increasing, which means we can use it to guide our search,
for example it.
Yeah.
Yeah, anyway, let's let's keep going here.
It is the way their search function.
First of all, I have is thought, is you and equal?
Three, because the already told me the limit.
If the problem didn't tell you, you have to figure it out, you're starting it for a while.
Assume that it's just a zero.
So in the minus is third in the minus third greater than zero.
This is as simple as sending that ended the opposite side.
So to be is, is this then?
Uh, yeah.
As long as as long as start is this, then it is set, isn't it?
So this is exactly, um, the normal condition.
The middle is, as we used to do.
Now let's think about our guidance for the function.
We say if if of middle Lisbon zero.
So let's say we tried X, for example, by half, for example.
Now let's say that x of half give us something like f of x, give us something like minus 20.
Now this is more than zero, but we just need zero.
So it means we need to drop the first part of the search observer here.
We will not try to start equal mid +1 because we are working on real values.
So we'll just say start equal mode.
There is no plus one or minus one in more in 3D values and a very similar way.
Let's say the next time X was like 2.5.
If EXA-, for example, turned out to be 170, this is way beyond the zero that we need.
So this mean we need to drop the second part of the search so we right and equal zero.
As you see, this is how we use the function to guide the search.
But when it comes to assigning we just right start and end.
Now, let's go back to this condition, it's all about comparison of the double values.
We know that in this problem that start and end are at the zero and zero and an issue that is greater
than zero.
But Wood Lake wants to start and end are very, very close.
I cannot say, or I'll start, uh, just to just to greater than I could to just see that.
Because in real values, as you learned in the programming, the real values cannot be compared this
way.
So we need to compare this to an episode in which is a very small value.
This refers to the C++ course or Google that about how to convert double numbers.
So and this is just one way.
So the moral of that is, we say, as long as there is some error difference between them greater than
Epsilon, then that's we still keep going.
If once it become Lisbon Epsilon, but what does Epsilon Epsilon is a very, very, very small value.
So let's say the difference at some point becomes something like zero point zero zero to three, which
is a smaller than this value.
Now we know we can stop.
So this is a model of one domain estate.
So why?
Why it's minus nine?
Why not one e to minus 15?
What not?
Why items in a seven?
It's up to you.
And I would say some clarification about that right now.
Observer here there is no middle +1 middle minus one anymore.
Look, I would like to say some notes about competitive programming here.
First of all, sometimes you will find the problem, saying the answer should be within absolute error
of 10 to the bar minus nine.
What does this statement mean?
It meets if he were to take the flute absolute off your real answer?
And their answer?
I make sure it is equal to the bar minus light.
And here in the bonus research, you would like to put the smaller value so that you guarantee you are
very close to the answer.
If you use something like 10 to the minus minus five, for example, your error difference would be
greater than 10 to the minus nine.
I hope that this isn't hard for you to get.
I would like to tell you about some things that people do in competitions, and also it's good for others
to know about them.
First of all, many people than just a competitor start an industry that they use the flute obsidian
to avoid any kind of maybe possible overflows or infinite loops.
So they, because those are maybe like any anything, could have it in the double values they they use
the flute absolute to make sure that this one is always boasted value.
The second thing which is very important in programming competitions and many problems is still the
competition based on the absolute value is wrong.
So there is a trick here.
People replace the way loop of the absolute value by iterating maybe like 100 or 200 steps.
This guarantees that after 100 or 200 steps of dividing by two of the social space, that the error
difference between your answer and that answer is very small.
For example, your answer could be 1.5 five three one seven one eight two three, and their answer could
be 1.5 to three one seven one eight zero one.
So the only difference comes here in the last two digits, maybe.
So the model of that is instead of making it depending on the comparisons, which might be a bit tricky.
You depend on the iteration.
You'll find a lot of people just using the plus in the other two because the overflow problems are in
the big when it comes to the real values in most of the programming competitions.
But if something fancy that I almost never did did it before.
In some problems, if the left and right are greater than one, people use the square root of the multiplication
and they claim that this do for the conversions during my computer program create.
I never needed that, but in a way I just wanted you to know about it.
I'm showing you this good, but don't get it wrong.
I don't mean that this is good.
It's better.
Good.
I'm just showing you what I was just meaning I started this good year with Epsilon because I wanted
to multiply the start times and otherwise it would keep being zero answer.
And sometimes people return to their average of the start and end.
Not just the start, but but they never needed that.
Uh, and here is what I meant by the fruit absolute in the equation.
But if you are in programming competition, I suggest for you more to do it this way.
Iterate 100 iterations or 200 iterations and tell you reach the reason.
So if that is something you should borrow from this slide, it would be under this line.
17.
Because many problems would be wrong answers or maybe time limit exceed.
But this equation will just solve the problem for you.
That's it.