Uh, homework, no food, which many to this to their real values problems.
And the first to probably you will be given, uh, an integer X and you would like to compute their
square root value of it.
But you just return to their integer about four square of twenty years for something, you just return
it.
Therefore, we definitely can do that with the normal.
It's the library.
But here you have to use binary search to compute that.
And this is an easy problem.
The second problem isn't from, uh, Likud, I couldn't find good examples at Likud problems.
So this is mainly for from s'posed.
Um, well, lane judge.
Uh, I would add a video for these online jokes.
Um, this visual mean judges like Likud.
But this time you have to right the main function by yourself and you have to read from the council
and write to the council.
Um, anyway, let me explain for you, uh, this is a function that you can implement here.
The function will take a vector of double values which represent some bar.
You reduce it by here.
And also an integrated for the number of people the idea is following, each boy is a search console
and each boy has a different ages.
Remember we the the area of a circle is to buy our square, right?
This is the idea of a circle.
So everybody is a circle and we are given the radius of everybody.
We are a nobody and we have any people.
We would like to give them every one of them equally sized a piece from the body.
The beast doesn't have to follow any specific shape.
It could be for any shape, however, and even little pieces, whatever.
But it must come from a single body.
It must account from a single buy.
And there could be some leftovers from your pie.
So again, we have several bodies and we have some people in the body.
Everyone would like to think B will take a piece from one specific bite.
Maybe he will take this piece here, and maybe this person will take this little piece here and maybe
this little piece here.
And then what we hear here is the area of there received from a specific by the total area here for
this guy would be equally sized.
Now the question is what is the largest possible besides each person can take?
Let's see an example.
We have three boys at three.
This are the ridges and we have four persons here.
So here is how we can solve it here.
The answer is twenty five point something.
This is the largest area of an equally sized piece so that for the beast, no vote for the body.
No.
The first body was reduced for the idea of this piece is 50 something.
So we give this one to two persons, so every one of them take twenty five something here.
And then so then we cover two persons.
We take from this by 25 and from this by twenty five over all five people for four persons are covered
using twenty five here.
Another one, we have only a single bite of Regis five, and we have 25 person in the scene, so it
logically we will divide it equally between all of them.
So the that circle area of fridges for is this value divided by twenty five.
You get this value.
Another case here, if you have all of these resources and six people, so this is answers.
Now, as I mentioned, uh, a sport in the sport, you have to write me and you have to read from the
console and write to the console, you got it from fights.
Now if you try to read the description of his book itself, it will be lengthy.
But read it.
It will be a good idea.
I shortened it to be good for you.
There is also a trick in the text.
The trick is they say that the material should be added to the total case.
So in the text, they would mention 24 Burswood and you had lost one making here.
You would love easier and entering you this trick.
This tricks haven't a lot in competitive programming, and this is okay in computer programming context.
But as an algorithm, because I do not, I don't want to waste your time in such a minor concerns.
So, uh, uh, for for a sports, you have to write a mean and read and write.
And they also retest the cases like you did seven to eight cases.
And this is why it is the case.
Now I would like to make your life easier, so I did the following I'm providing you with this file.
It is, it says, something like Bush by I think it was 02, yes.
Now this file has the mean ready for you and has the function that I asked you to implement to year
ready for you to just try to do.
If you just took this file and filled only this specific function, it would be for more for you more
or less like it could you only and it could all the function.
So you take the template and fill only this function and submit it.
So this is just will be much shorter for you and could be based on the text from the website so that
it still could be herself.
One concern here we mentioned the minor search we can do.
Why look this way or better?
It it up to 100 iterations?
This one will fail with this problem responsibly and use this iteration this thing.
OK.
Another problem, sadly, from Bush, is as following, uh, I tried to simplify the text, it's a bit
challenging problem to understand.
We have a line.
And there are many people positioned somewhere in this line.
So the first thing that you think is victor oppositions for the people.
And you have a message of distance.
And our message is if someone here shouted a message, a person who is far like, let's say distance
of three is far three from you cannot listen to the distance.
So let's say this is better than here at six and this person is at three.
Mm.
Let's make it two and five.
So this person at to the distance of hearing is three, two and three five Callison, yes, if this
person is at 12 from five to 12 is seven greater than the distance, so he cannot hear, OK, here is
a it is what's going to happen.
The first person will hear the message and we would like to deliver this message to the last person.
So this people in the business as a team will start to arrange it with their positions such that in
the minimum time we can deliver this message, every person run at a speed of one unit, their second,
which you mean just like one unit in a way like the time is like the distance here.
And he either move to the left or moved to the right.
And from that, he will hear the message and shoot it to the next person.
And we would like the team to committee to collaborate together so that he can deliver the message as
fast as possible.
You would like to find that a minimum time for such a delivery.
The position array is sorted, right?
Let's give an example so that this very generic statements are more clear.
We have two persons only at positions zero.
And musician, six.
The message distance is three.
So if the first person who showed the message, then the only one at position three can hear it.
This people can arrange themselves in only 1.5 second to deliver the message as fast as possible.
Here is what will happen after rainbow in five seconds.
The first person will move to a location, one being fired in burial.
Two that the last person will move back to 4.5.
Now, the minimum distance is three, if this person is 30 to should this message a that is his three
steps before will be able to hear the message.
So now in all 1.5, I move here.
You move here.
I should the message.
You hear it?
Let's see.
Another example.
We have someone at position zero.
Another opposition foot and another one, a position four and someone a position eight.
And the distance for a hearing is only to the optimal for this one would be only one second of time.
Here's what would happen first, the opposition's zero will move to position one.
So he take one one unit of time.
Everyone in this one unit of time will decide his location.
So this one might be and also one unit of time go back to position of three.
And this one will go to the right to position five.
And this it will go back here to position seven.
Now for a one to three is just two from three to five is just through from five to seven.
Is just two.
So this person should the message to this one, will hear it.
Then this one should it immediately.
This one here it that this one should the message immediately.
This one here it.
Another a few other examples there, the message distance now is 70.
So the first person just should read it right now.
This person is very close.
You will listen to.
So we do not care about the immediate ones.
Another example.
We have a person at zero and a person at nine and Blitzen at it.
So the answer is for this person will go here for you.
It's sorry, will move back.
We'll move forward.
The four year position for this one would remain as a year.
This one would move back here at 14 in four seconds.
So you know, the distance here is five and the distance here is five in just five steps.
Everyone is now connected so we can shoot and propagate directly to the person.
Things can be more like a fraction here if you couldn't get what I am saying.
That's the trick.
It is very annoying problem.
Please go to the website itself.
Read it.
Understand the problem by yourself.
Again, I'm doing you a favor here.
You can use this template.
It is ready for you to use to build your own.
Could just the function and read them in.
Feel free to write them by yourself, or at least review my text to learn about it.
Let's hope.