Let's solve the homework, the first one is asking for the square root function.
This one is a straightforward.
We will start to use normal brain research.
So remember, what is the target?
The target is to find the square root.
So the first question is, can we bring the research to that lake, right, if of a square root?
So the point is, if we have a square root, let's say two, then the square value is like four.
If you have a score of three, then this is nine.
If you have the value four, then 16.
So this is an increasing function.
So it seems that clearly we can begin research on the square root itself.
So he would have the start from the zero and the maximum value.
We can just put a very big, upper bound like the value itself.
Now the normal way loop, the normal method.
Now we have the square root value here.
The subject is good value.
Now, if we're square with the value itself, let's say you are searching for the square root of 10.
But now the method is three.
So the first thing is three times three is nine.
So the the current the square, the square root is nine.
The target is 10, as we are less than that.
It means that we should move to a bigger one.
That's why we say if middle times the middle minus the value is less than zero, then we need to go
slower.
Another way to write it is just middle times.
The middle is less than the value itself, which means actually we need a bigger middle to do it.
After that, we come back here and if it happens, say, say, we have now the Middle East four.
So now four times the four would be greater than the target, which is 10.
So we need to shrink the values.
Now, once you are done with it, the thought would be our target value.
It is good here to add something like one item in a slate to handle any potential positions like maybe
you give me the input of four.
So the binary search, you will find two, but they actually will find one nine nine nine nine nine
nine.
When we add an epsilon, then we are helping that to be converted to some nine.
Then, as the function is here, we are returning an integer, so it will be casted in a way.
So this only would be the return value.