Let's solve the next problem about the boy.
So the first thing is what is the target or what the target?
Oh, what is the area of the slice that everyone would take?
Let's say that the current area is tiny and it covered the 30 person.
OK.
Now, if you decided to grow up and use a bigger area, 35, for example, as a as as this area, this
means less people can take now.
There is a chance, right?
So maybe still 30, maybe 25 now.
Let's say you decided to use a Bay Area of seven only.
Maybe you can now cover maybe 45 person.
So the moral of that is when you grow up in my area size, the people are decreasing.
This is a monotonic, decreasing function.
No, this is the easiest part.
Now this means that we can simply bind the research on the boy.
So is I started here with the following I started with creating a vector of double.
I named the Etherium and I will trade with the resources for every resource.
I would create the current idea among all of the current areas.
I'm going to compute the maximum that we have now.
The start of the area to begin their search is zero, but the maximum is the max area that we have.
Now this Dubai in the research, as usual, can be the middle.
Now let's write a function that say, take the current area and tell us the total number of people that
can eat from this area.
If this to the number of people who can read are greater than or equal the people, then this is a good
one.
But let's search for a larger piece.
Otherwise, this isn't enough.
We need to try a smaller piece.
Now the remaining thing is, how can we write the the total number of people who can read for it from
a specific way?
This is easy.
We have here the victor of areas and we have a base.
So for every four, everybody would divide it by the number, by the area.
This will tell us that the total number of visas, for example, let's say the by area is eight.
Let's say Britain is eight and you would like to divide it two pieces of land to.
So this means eight over two, we can divide it to four pieces.
He.
One bees to distribute support.
So if we divided about Area eight over two two pieces of land to Area two, then we have people of Forde
who get eat from this one.
So we trade one by one by one, get the total number of people who would eat from this boy.
Now add that to eat.
I hope the function is easy for you.
The overall logic of this function is trivial.
There is nothing magic in this problem.