Let's continue the binary search topic. In the last time, we learned about the process of the binary
search.
We start from zero here.
We start with the end of the array.
So this is our range.
Every time we go to the middle, we either discard the right or discard the left.
So here, for example, we discard the left.
Now this is the new array.
We get the new middle, we either discard the left or discard the right, let's say we discard this one.
Now we have this one here. Again get the middle, either the left or the right,
let's discard the right. Now, this one
here, we go to the middle, either the left or right, let's discard the right, and so on.
So the array, in every step, is losing half of its size.
For example, if the array is 256, then in the next step, it's going to be around 128,
then around 64, and so on.
There is a question here, what is the time complexity of that?
And please be very active during the course, when I ask you a question,
don't wait for me to answer it.
I'm trying to make the course like a very high level of engagement because algorithms is already a hard
topic.
So help yourself.
What's the time complexity of that? Within what we saw so far,
You probably didn't know, but you still can figure it out or at least do some progress.
So what is the answer of that?
In the previous code, as I said, we shrink to half in every step.
So this is mainly what's happening here.
We either shrink to the right part, or we shrink to the left part.
And as you see, 256 will keep reducing to over twos.
Does this remember you of something? Like one, two, four, eight, sixteen,
these multiplications.
This is 2^x, right?
The opposite of the division is the log.
There is a very strong relationship between 2^x or 2^n and log(n).
So the time complexity of that is what we call log(n).
And there is something very interesting about the log, you know, the number like 2^32.
This is a very huge number, right? Like in billions.
The log of such a very huge number in base two is just 32 steps, only 32 steps.
So as you see, the log(n) is really a very small factor.
Now here is the rule that I would like you to keep in mind.
If you have some number like n or a range, and you are reducing it in every step by half, then this is log(n)
to the base two. If you are reducing something with, let's say, a third, then this is log(n) to the base three.
Practically speaking, they are very small numbers anyway.
And this takes us to something like we so far learned about O(1), about O(n), about O(n^2).
Where is the log(n) and where is nlog(n) in this? So the log(n) is here between O(1) and O(n). The blog(n)
is here between O(n) and log(n^2), and so on. The order that we call it nlog(n)
has a name, people call it like this is a log-linear time complexity.
OK, so here is the graph that just shows what I was saying, the n^3, as you see, when
n is large,
then n^3 is bigger than n^2, n^2 is bigger than n, and here somewhere in the middle
there is nlog(n), before the n, there is log(n), there is O(1) here.
We can divide the log(n) to log(n) base two, log(n) base three.
But anyway, we don't care.
Also, most of the time when we write the log, we just write log(n) and we don't care a lot about the
base because anyway, the number is
reduced very fast.
Like even log(n) to the base two will make it a very, very small number.
Um, yeah.
Yeah, what else here?
Yeah, nothing.
You probably can notice here in the early, and this something has relevance in the time complexity.
So you see here in the early stages, uh, the n^3, for example, could be smaller than n maybe or
other stuff.
This is a real curve like a 0.23 blah, blah, blah.
So at some point when n is large, remember what we said in the time complexity, that some n0,
one of them is going to be always bigger than the second one.
So for O(n) and O(n^2), at this point, n^2 will always be bigger. For the n^3
and log(n), at this point, n^3 is always bigger, and so on.
Uh, yeah, this is mainly what does it mean to be log(n) complexity.
Donald Knuth is a very popular computer scientist, Donald has a very nice statement.
He says that binary search looks like very straightforward.
But it is very tricky to implement.
And in this lecture, I will show you one reason for that. There is something wrong with the middle equation
here.
Can you figure it out?
This mistake has been in the "Programming Pearls" book for twenty years, and the Java programming language
has a mistake for nine years.
Can you imagine? What is wrong with this statement?
It's very trivial, very easy to spot.
The problem is in the overflow. Can you figure it out why? Can you develop a fix to
this equation?
Now here is the point.
You would like to add (left+right)/2, let's say that left is an integer and right is an integer,
then definitely the middle of them is between them.
So it's also an integer.
Where is the problem?
If you have a vector and it has a very huge vector size, something close to the limit of the int.
Now, at some point, the left and right will be very close to the limit of the integer.
The problem is, if you added (left+right) at this moment, it will be beyond the integer limits.
So we will have an overflow.
So
always the plus and
the multiplication should remember you with potential overflows, always you should remember that.
So the problem is, as I said again, if you are in the very end close to the limit of the integer, adding
the (left +right) will overflow and the algorithm will never terminate.
So there is a question here.
Why did these people spend all of these years without figuring the mistake?
Because in most of the applications, we don't have an array that has the limit of integer.
This is extremely huge number.
That's why most of the people will not suffer from this issue until someone hit the problem
in the library.
Now, how to fix that? In a very easy way.
This is another way to write the middle equation, you write left + (right-left)/2.
So the idea is, here is the right, here is the left.
When you subtract them, you get the range here.
So let's say that left is 10 and right is 20.
So 20 - 10 is just, let's use something else, maybe 10 and 40.
So (40 - 10) is just 30.
This is the range.
Half of it is just 15.
Somewhere here in the middle, ten plus fifteen is twenty-five.
So this is the middle between them.
This is the middle between them.
So in this way, we avoided the division.
Now, this way we solve the problem.
Now here is the tip.
There is more than an algorithm in the algorithms that involves computing the middle.
So the same note applies for all of them, like the merge, sort, and all of the divide and conquer algorithms,
You should always remember that addition can make a problem for you and always use this replacement.
Now here is the fix in the code, you just use this new equation, that's it.
Let me take you with a similar problem, we have an array, sorted, unique values.
We have a lot of queries, for each query, you will either return the index or -1,
if doesn't exist.
How can you solve this problem?
Can you spot two different ways?
In the first approach, we can use the binary research, for every query, you just binary research the
array.
So it takes like log(n), and we have Q queries, each query is taking log(n), so overall O(qlogn) time.
Now the point here is we can definitely make something better than that. In the data structure course,
you learned about the hash table, and the hash table can tell us in only O(1) if the element exists or
not.
So this means we can answer every query in only one step, so we end up with O(q) queries.
So here we didn't make use of anything of the sorted property.
This is very important.
Sometimes people are trapped in the ideas that they know.
Like I know binary search as a tool.
I just use it.
Think bigger.
Maybe there are other ways.
Remember, the same problem can be seen from many angles.
And one of the best and most important skills that you should try to develop during the course is
having these multiple angles.
There are many problems out there, and they can be tackled in different ways.
Tomorrow, when you go to the industry, and you are like, let's say you are in Facebook,
and you have a feature, and this feature will be used by millions of users.
This is something that is very sensitive and we would like to develop this feature.
This feature can be developed in different ways and every way will have its own trade-offs. So try to
develop that, this is one critical advantage from studying algorithms.
Before ending that, I would like to tell you that binary search is definitely implemented in the STL.
It's implemented in three functions, at least, the lower_bound function, the upper_bound
function, and the equal_range function.
So the lower_bound function finds the first element greater than or equal to the given element.
For example, this is here the array, I ask you to find the first element lower_bound 17, lower_bound 17
means
find the first element f that is greater than or equal 17.
So seventeen already exists in the array.
So we just find it.
That's it.
Let's use another example.
What if I told you to find five?
What is the first element greater than or equal
five?
It is seventeen, and so on.
Uh, this array is buggy.
I didn't notice that, sorry for that.
This array should be sorted.
I'm very sorry for that.
So it should be like two, two, you must have the vector sorted before using it because the
binary search condition.
This should be 2, 2, 3, 4, 9.
OK.
So be careful from that.
I'm very sorry, probably as the values are bigger than the middle, the algorithm anyway worked
well.
So anyway, um, yeah, assume for a while it's sorted.
If I asked you to find the upper_bound, now the upper bound means the first element f greater than seventeen
here.
What is the first element greater than 17? It is
twenty.
OK.
So this is what does it mean to be upper_bound. Now,
What if
there is nothing greater than or greater than equal to the element?
We just get back the end iterator.
So you can always compare here the vector with the end.
If they aren't equal, you found something.
Otherwise, it doesn't exist.
Finally, the equal_range just returns the lower bound and the upper bound, so the equal_range doesn't
have its own algorithm, it's actually calling the lower bound and the upper bound.
That's it.
It's also worth knowing something, that the STL has a set and has a map. Set and map are implemented using
what we call a binary search tree, specifically the balanced binary search tree like Red Black
Tree or AVL Tree.
It's a tree where the depth is just log(n), and it's like a binary,
every node has two children, and it always has a height of log(n). So the set and map also have lower
bound and upper bound functions.
They have the exact meaning as we just explain, they are log(n).
So this isn't a binary search code like we were doing, but it is a very close concept.
So always remember that.
Finally, let's go back to Donald statement, Donald mentions that there are many
mistakes that could happen in the binary search. Today,
we saw one of them. In the homework,
you will find a very important problem and a very important code that as following, you should
find the first position of an element in a sorted array and the last position of an element.
You will notice that writing the code to find the first or the last, specifically the last, is really
tricky.
So this is a big problem.
By the way, the equal range in STL function can help us to find the first and last element,
as we said. You can utilize it to find them.
That's all.