It's sort of the lobster problem about what getting the message.
Um, so again, let's think about the brain research about the here.
If I told you that using ten seconds, we managed to deliver the message, then definitely using ten
point five we can deliver.
It was ten pointed.
Like 12 seconds, we can deliver it.
If I told you that six seconds are enough to deliver it, five seconds are enough to deliver it for
two seconds aren't enough to deliver it.
So this is a one trick function here.
So the possible function is to function.
So this is the first step, which is a stronger signal that we can bind the research at the time.
So we will start here with binary searching on the time the function had the position and the message
distance.
We bring the researcher at the time the limits are based on the problem fixed.
We can build the middle and we have a possible function.
If it is possible with this middle time, we are happy.
But let's shift to two and equal metal to try to find the minimum time.
If the current time isn't enough or the current distance, time, year, equal distance, if the time
or the distance isn't enough, then we need to search for a bigger party.
The challenge in this problem is in writing the book about function itself.
So here is the logic, which involves some good amount of thinking.
Now, let's say we have D units of time, which mean we can move distance of D, so the function here
take positions, the message distance and how the selected time were the selected distance.
Now let's say it is the busier person, the first person, the first person has the most distance.
So logically, he will use all of them, so he will use this more distance.
So now he and b zero plus move distance.
Once he reached this position, he will show the message which can go up to messaging distance, so
the shouting will go to a new distance, which is b zero plus maximum distance of plus the message of
distance here.
So this is the last.
So this is my last opposition and this is the last position for the message to reach it.
OK, so this are our first two values.
So the B zero can move to here show two here.
This is what happened in the first tier.
It's time.
Now we are done with the first person.
Now, at times for the second debate, so it is bizarro.
It is a move busy to move.
It is the shooting.
So here is the message.
The message can be here.
The second person at B.1.
First of all, we would like to know if this person can ever listen to this message or not.
As simple as I can move back to them using them of distance, so I will start to like logically, will
move back if I found myself, we can move back at least before or equal to the last position for the
message, then I can hear it.
What if my best is just to go back here?
Then I cannot hear the message.
So no way.
So the first thing is we need to make sure I can hear the message.
To do that, we need to compare my this my position minus the distance compared to the last position
for the message.
If I am greater than it, then I cannot hear the message.
OK, let's say I can hear the message.
So here is to be zero and it is location.
And here is the message of distance at, let's say, messages this year.
And this is me.
Now we went logically this person to take the message and go as far as possible to the right.
So here is the point.
The person himself can go in the maximum keys to this direction with that move distance.
But let's say I'm here a position to a and the distance is five so I can go maximum at was five.
I can go seven here.
So this is my maximum to go to this site.
But wait, I am limited with where is this message?
Let's say that this message here is at six.
Then I, although I can go one unit farther than it, I have to stop here.
So I am trapped between my best is to be between the minimum of where the message ends and what is my
maximum limit.
So the logic is followed, which isn't easy and all involved with a good deal of thinking.
The logic is as follows We start with the first person and move the distance.
Let's call that my last opposition.
Now, for every person at last position, his message can be heard from last message of distance.
This is the last position with the message you can be heard.
For the current person, I this is for this person.
Well, the current the person I the kind of person would a chick if I return it minus distance, am
I after their loss?
The message opposition?
If yes, then the message end here, but I can go back only to here.
So there is a gap, then no way.
OK, let's assume you can listen to the message.
What would be your logically last position that you can do?
You'd like to go to the right as much as possible because you would like to deliver to the next person.
So there's two limitation.
I can go to the right up to this distance, but I'm also limited with this distance.
The minimum of them would represent my optimal position.
Uh, if we managed to do that, then we can do it.
So the cure of this problem is not in the binary search, but it is in the bush people function.
But um, this question is harder than the previous two.
It's OK that some questions would hurt.
It's totally completely OK.
Take it easy.
Visit back to do list and all of the tips that we provided before.