Before ending this section, I thought specifically for this section, there were a lot of thoughts
and they were summarizing I see a lot of courses describing brain research in a very naive way just
to the the normal case, but brain research is way bigger than that, as you see.
So here is what we learned.
We learned.
Like any other course, that there is this normal brain research scenario that ascending or descending
order, the assertiveness here is very important reason for the logic of their brain research.
Then we started to generalize that two functions specifically what we call monotonic function, these
functions that are increasing or increasing and fixated, or decreasing or decreasing this way.
We also realized that the groove of the intensity of a function is usually a one minute time.
It's usually either the Model X, the model of X, so this is increasing or the more X X this is decreasing.
If you verify that congratulation of X is binary searchable.
Right.
The standard.
The good and the right of X and drive the possible function from it.
We learned the domain can be integer and real.
There is no big difference between both of them.
It's just minor changes.
We learned about the overflow concert.
We learned how to find the first and the last occurrence of a of the first and last occurrence of the
target.
And we learned how to do that on arrays and on functions.
Overall, you should note that binary sisterhood is very systematic.
You just do this kind of steps and write the template of the code.
The function f itself, usually in many cases it could be a one, sometimes oh, in a few cases.
And look, and so don't stuck like you are trying to find an all one solution.
You start with the brute force version and improve according to that.
If the function F is o m, then your overall complexity is o m log some factor usually A. So this is
overall.
During solving, we were trying to gain like some kind of bitterness, and this is something that you
should know the people who are very strong in competitive programming during algorithmic solving in
general as they solved many, many problems, they try to figure out the better in solving and whenever
they meet a problem due to their league, the depth of the experience, they managed to match what they
learned with some of the batteries.
So would like to give you here some of the clear patterns that we see.
So one better, which is the easy case, sometimes easy or medium, which is merely by searching when
the array, which you mean the start is equal zero and the end is equal the lengths of the remaining
one annual binary search to over the indices.
Now, in the second case, and we made that allowed in the binary search over functions, we binary
search on the given request itself.
So I ask you for a request you directly buy in the research on the request.
We see that in many things, for example, I ask you to find their divisor that do blah blah blah.
We binary search it on the device or in the body function.
I asked you for the Bay Area.
We binary search you in the Bay Area in that.
What does that do?
So that the license problem we ask, could you for the minimum time we binary?
Sorry, we bind the research on the minimum time for the heaters.
I asked you for the radius of the function we buying that associate on the hit radius.
We asked you for the minimum number of days to build the buckets.
We buy an associate in the days you see what's happening.
The problem is asking for a request you binary search on the request.
Make sure that f is one tick.
That's it.
The whole trick is how to write the function, not the wine the associates of.
And the moral of all of this once is ability to guide the binary situation.
Now this is a medium case, the how did the case?
We met two problems before them.
And in the third case, I give you a target, but you cannot bonus circulate.
So in the case of missing a problem and in the case the smallest, the problem you cannot directly buy
in the research on the target.
You cannot do that.
So what we did is we try to find relevant and the close function so that we can find the answer from
them that this one is specifically we switched it from finding equality to finding inequality because
what happens is, was equality.
This issue is this is like false reports of also true false or also false.
Was inequality.
It is like, what's false?
Forceful, the truth or truth?
What's what's?
What's in there in that?
In this second problem, also, we learned about the value index to track.
The problem is asking you to find the index, you buy an assertion of value.
So why this is hard?
Because in many cases you read the problem.
You don't get the sense that this is a binary social problem.
You just try to think about different approach, but it is binary, searchable.
But you need to put some thinking effort, some creativity to find this relevant function that we will
can use it to guide the binary search itself.
I think this is a hard case, and there are a few problems who are on the heart of the case.
Most of the problems are actually here, but in a way it's good to know about the heart of the case,
too.
That's all.