Homework number one in the binary search.
So go back to Donald's statement about the number of tricks that we can see in the binary search implementations.
As I mentioned in the lecture, we would like to have a function that takes a vector and
a target.
Then it will return for us to indices, the first index for the element and the last index for
the element.
If it doesn't exist, it returns [-1, -1].
So this vector will always have just two values.
I would like you to once try to implement your own binary search code and in the second one,
try to use the STL equal_range function.
Let's see some samples in case
here. We have here the array which is sorted and the target = 8.
So we see here eight exists at the first position here, and last position here, these are [3, 4]
Target
six doesn't exist
here, target zero doesn't exist in an empty array.
And so on.
So, for example, let me give you a bigger example.
Let's say we have 2, 5, 7, 7, 7, 7, 10, and I ask you for seven.
So this is the first location for seven.
This is the last location for seven.
Next, a very similar problem, which is finding right interval.
We have an interval, every interval is like a start and end, like when you think about here, numbers
zero, one, two, three, four.
This could be an interval here.
This is another interval, and so on. We would like to find, for every interval, its right
one.
What is the definition of the right one?
It is an interval that is after you.
This means the following that the second interval starts after your end, starts after your
end.
Now, among all of the intervals that are your right intervals, we need the one that starts earlier.
I would like you to develop, again, your own binary search, then use the STL binary search.
Optionally, you can also use the map lower_bound.
Provide a solution for that.
Let me give you an example if you aren't aware with intervals.
So here in this interval, for example.
So let's say we have here a line,
this is index value 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, and so on.
So we have one interval at three and four, so we have one interval here.
And we have, let's call it (3, 4), and we have an interval at two and three.
So we have one interval here
(2, 3).
And we have an interval one, two, so we have an interval here, (1, 2).
Now, let's go and see. For interval three and four,
there is nothing
on its right.
So the answer here is -1 for it. For the interval two and three,
there is only one interval after it, which is three and four.
Three and four has index zero.
So we put zero here.
Finally, one and two.
So (1, 2) has two intervals after, the interval (2, 3) and the interval (3, 4).
We need the one that is the first one, the smallest start.
So this one starts at two and this one starts at four.
So you just use this one.
And so on. So here one and four.
.
There is no right interval for one and four.
There is no
an interval for one and four.
Why?
Because (1, 4) is taking the whole interval here.
So this is the (1, 4) interval.
There is nothing after it.
So this is what does it mean.
The valid triangle number, you will have an array of integers, and we would like to build triangles
from it.
The question is to return the number of triplets that satisfy a triangle. Remember from what we learned,
If you have three sides of a triangle, then the triangle is valid if and only if the sum of any two
sides are greater than the third side, which are these three conditions.
So here you have this input.
So if you took two and three and four, this is one triangle. The second two and three and
four, this is another triangle.
Two, three, and four, sorry, two, two, and three
also a valid triangle, but you cannot take two and two and four.
This is invalid triangle.
And so on.
One more time, develop your own binary search, then develop based on STL.
Now, once you're done with these two, I would like to develop a code that doesn't have even the binary
search.
So this now needs some more observations from you.
I hope you understand the problem.
I would like to tell you something here. So early in the explaining in the algorithms
what and why, we mentioned that there are many types of algorithms like a decision problem.
Like an optimization problem.
There is also what we call a counting problem and many other types.
Now I told you recently what is an optimization problem.
It's a problem that's seeking, for example, maximization or minimization.
A decision problem is a binary problem.
It says true or false.
If I give you an array and ask you to return true, if the number exists, false, if it doesn't
exist.
This is a decision.
So decision is problems with true or false outputs.
Now, counting problems are this problem that tries to count something.
And usually this involves a lot of computations.
So this is a counting problem.
We would like to count the number of triplets.
So why
usually, a number of something is an algorithmic problem? Because you have a lot of choices, and you would
like to count specific items within these choices.
So this is another type of algorithms.
So keep that in mind.
The final problem is as following, we have n coins, and we build a staircase with them.
This is what we mean by a staircase.
So a staircase is something that has one step here, two three, four, five, six in order.
Now you have coins and you fill in order.
So let's say you have eight coins, you start to put here
one element only, there is two here, so you put two, three here, we put a three.
So far, we spent six coins.
Now we have only eight, so the remaining is two.
Now the question is, as you see here, we couldn't complete this row.
So the first three rows are the only ones that we can fill with eight coins.
So here is the problem. You have
n coins, and you would like to build a staircase.
And as I said, we would like to find the total number of complete rows.
So once you cannot fill it anymore, we are done. We definitely can write a linear loop to do this
problem.
Now I would like to find the binary search algorithm for this problem.
Now there's a question here, where is the array? We used to search an array based on zero, end
and get the middle.
Where is the array?
This is the time to generalize the binary search we learned.
We will generalize the binary search we learned. In the next lecture,
I will explain how to generalize the binary search to work on functions.
By the way, the limit of this function is a very huge number.
I would like to give a trial.
You can still develop it by yourself but just give a trial.
And as I said, I will explain the solution of this problem in the lecture.
Yeah, that's all.