Let's solve the homework number one.
So in the first problem, we have an array of integers, and we would like to find the first occurrence of
the element,
and the last occurrence for it, index twice. If there are no such targets, we should return just
[-1, -1].
I hope that this assignment probably taught you how it could end up really hard to fix
it.
There are a bunch of different mistakes that could happen.
I'm going to show you one way to implement it.
It's a good way, but it's really, like, actually problematic.
Then I will show you another way that's more decent, and you should keep it as an implementation style.
So let's start with the find first.
The first_first function is returning
the first index of the element in the array.
.
So here is an array of elements, let's say
zero, one, two, three, four, five, and six.
Here are our elements, let's say [1, 3, 5, 7, 8, 9, 20], and now we would like to find, oh,
let's make it like a seven and seven.
We would like to find the first occurrence of seven, which is at position three.
Now, when you think about it, this is an array, and the array has a start and end.
The start is at zero.
The end is at (size -1).
There should be some condition here.
Let's leave it for now. The middle is as usual.
previously, we have three conditions.
We found the element.
It is less.
It is more.
But now,
we have here the case of if it's less than, then definitely we need to go to the right part of the
search space.
If it is greater than, we need to go to the left part.
This is also previous
code, and we will not change it.
Now the problem is if we found it.
So let's say at the moment the index of the middle was, for example, at five, let's pretend
that.
So we found it, but we don't know if this is the first seven or not.
So we would like to say, Hey, you know what,
I would like you to have this part as my search space. So I'm going to put the end equal to the middle,
the end equal to the middle.
But this will start to create different types of problems.
And to fix these problems, we will start with something like putting this only less than to be less than or
equal.
So this is the first change. After that, we need to do here some further conditions to verify it.
If the start ended up less than zero.
Then it actually doesn't exist.
If the start is after the array, it doesn't exist.
We also need to verify that the found index is actually the target index.
If so, then we found it, otherwise, minus one.
Let me repeat that again.
The whole trick of this implementation is when we find a position, we update our search to include this position.
So the middle will be part of the new search space.
This is mainly the find_first here implementation.
The last way is very similar.
However, finding the last index is more problematic, finding the last index is more problematic.
Let me show you why. So we are going to follow the same trick, which means this is the goal of this
way of implementation to use the middle.
So this is the same, again, we have here indices, and let's say somewhere we have seven, seven,
seven, and seven.
And let's say the middle is here at the moment.
And here is some start and some end. As usual,
the first two conditions will not change.
The start is middle means we found the seven, but we don't know if this is the last element or not.
So we create a new search window from this element to the current element.
OK, we know that this trick in the previous solution ended up that we needed only here less not less than
equal to let it works.
Otherwise, it might go infinity or so.
Now here is another nightmare from this solution.
Assume that the positions are consecutive values, let's say five and six.
So these are the indices now.
And let's here value seven and value seven.
So our start is at zero.
Our end is at one.
Sorry, our start is at five.
Our end is at six.
Now ignore this plus one for now. If we used the normal equation, we will have
(6-5) equals one, over two
is zero, plus start is same the start.
So the middle is the start.
The middle is the start.
Now we found it.
We found it here, right?
So the new search involves putting the start again equal to the middle.
And this means the new start is again equal to five, and the end is still six.
We are repeating the same start and end again.
This code will go infinity.
So what is the value of this plus one?
I am forcing it if just two consecutive elements to use the second one first.
So here is the point if we have (start + end - 1) here and we have five and six.
So (6 - 5) is one, plus one is two,
over two is one, plus five.
So it will be five plus one equals six.
Now the middle equals six.
So here the next it will be like start equals end equals six.
The moral of that.
First of all, we decided to go with start = middle, so that we include the target element.
But this ended up that we cannot have here equal.
And also we have to put conditions here.
The second problem, in finding the last occurrence, the equation will result in an infinite loop.
And to solve this problem, we added +1 here, so that we force consecutive indices to next
use the next one.
Otherwise, it will go to infinity if you are unlucky.
So as you see, this is now a very problematic way to solve the problem.
I'm going to show you a way easier implementation
than this style, which is very nice, has good thoughts behind it, but isn't really the best way to
implement it.
So here is the way that I would like you to use it, which will save your life, and very close to our
usual implementations.
The whole trick is very trivial.
The idea is as following.
We will have an extra variable, initially, for example, position = -1.
And this one,
we will keep assigning it the found solutions.
So now here we will back to go
use less than or equal as it is.
We will have a condition for less than, and we'll have a condition for greater than.
And we'll have a condition for the equal.
These two conditions are as usual.
Now, the condition of the equality is as following.
We will put the (end = mid - 1) as usual, but we will mark the position with the middle.
So let's use the grid here.
Let's say we have seven, seven, seven, seven, and let's say that the middle is here.
Once we found it, I will say, Hey, you know what,
we found it.
And then in the next time, I will use the (middle - 1) as usual. If it happened that this new
range found a better answer, it will update our position. If it couldn't,
we just have our previous value.
So the moral of that is, with this saving one,
we don't anymore need to write something like end = middle, which will fire back on us
in the recursion.
Now in exactly the same logic here in the second code, we have the less than as usual, we have the
greater
than as usual. For the equality, we'll say the position = middle, and then move to the right part.
As you see the good advantage of this code, it is almost very similar to what we write.
It involves here less than or equal.
It involves normal conditions.
It doesn't involve any post-processing.
Very straightforward.
No runtime loops.
No infinite loop.
Uh, no
all of these weird tricks.
No changes for...
I don't think that we need this change.
Sorry.
I don't think that this change,
we don't need it.
This plus one, I'm sure we don't need anymore.
I will update the code to remove it.
So this is the way that I would like you to use
this code.
OK, the final code that I would like to share with you is about the STL, which we can use
STL as I told you before, stl equal range already finds the first element and the last element.
So the solution is as following, you will call the equal_range, return two iterators.
The first iterator for the lower bound.
The second one for the upper bound.
If we couldn't find it anyway , then X here will be for the first element,
which is good.
But why is after it?
And we know,
let me give you example.
Let's say we have here 5, 6, 7, 7, 7, 10.
The lower bound is seven, which is good what we need.
The upper bound is ten.
We need one step before it.
So this is the minus one here.
So this is the STL style. That's all.