Let's solve problem number two, which is about finding the right interval.
I hope you notice that this problem is very similar to the problem that we were writing here.
It's all about also finding the first interval, no more magic in the problem than
that.
So we mainly know that the right interval,
its start must be after my end.
Its start must be after my end.
And within all of the intervals that are after me, I would like the one that starts
very earlier.
So thinking about that, I'm going to create here the starting of all of the current intervals,
the starting of all of the current intervals.
So I iterate on the intervals, and right here at the start, and also mark what is its index.
And remember the starts are unique.
So now we are going to sort them.
What do we have now?
We have all of the intervals sorted by the starting element.
Now, I would like to search as following.
I'm going to search for the first element that is greater than or equal to me.
I would like to find, given my end, given my end.
I would like to find the first interval greater than or equal to this value.
So this is now like a very normal search for us.
This code is very binary search.
So let's say the logic one more time.
Let's say we have one interval that is maybe (2, 7).
Another interval that is (5, 8), and then an interval that is (8, 10).
And another one that is (9, 12).
Now I will create an array of startings, which will involve the two and the five and the eight and the
nine.
Now let's take the two and seven one here.
I need the first interval that its starting element is greater than or equal to me.
That's why I want to search based on the start, mainly, I would like to use my end, which
is seven to search based on the start.
So that's why we created an array of startings and sorted it.
We must sort it, so that binary search is valid.
So now we take seven, and binary search here for the first value greater than or equal me, which
is eight.
So when we take this one, we know that this is the interval.
So we take here the index of it.
Then the second value represents the index itself.
So
we take it back from this index here. Now for the recursion
code.
This is very normal
code. Again, we have a normal binary search.
We are searching for the first occurrence, so we need the position trick here,
the extra variable, the equal is as it is, the middle as it is, the first condition
is less than, that's normal.
But now in our case, we don't find the first equal value.
We find the first greater than or equal value.
So this means the condition for the greater and the condition for the equal are now merged.
So one change here, in this code here, this step is now merging the greater than and merging
the equal.
Why? We are finding the first element greater than or equal to me.
So I hope the logic here is very clear.
We just wanted to find the first starting that is greater than or equal to me.
So I created an array of all of the possible startings, sorted
it, started to use it to search.
I use my end here to search this array. If it is valid,
we take the one which is the index of the interval.
So this is mainly about this problem.
Let's see what other implementations we have here. In the second implementation,
I'm going to use the internal lower bound search.
So the logic here is exactly the same.
The logic here is exactly the same.
I'm going to add the startings, sort them, and then I'm going to lower bound because lower bound is greater
than or equal.
So this is actually what I'm going to look for.
So I'm going to use it to find the exact position, and just use it here.
So the moral of that is instead of writing our own binary search, we just used the
available one.
Now.
.
Yeah, the last implementation I would like to show you that we can use actually the map of
C++ so that we can also find lower bound in log(n).
So the moral of that is instead of putting the values in a vector and sorting them, we can put them
in a map.
So the map is key
and value, but the map is ordering the keys already, so we just add them here, say
the key is a starting and the value is the index, and this is the answer vector as usual.
Then I will iterate.
I will have my ending lower bound on the map by it, it will return an iterator.
Then we use the second one, which is directly the value here, which represents this index.
So this is how we can use the map to solve this problem.
And overall, the code is more elegant because the map is the intuitive key and value, which is here.
We are mapping the starting for something to the value of it.
Remember, this code is possible because the starting points in the input are unique.
Otherwise, if I told map[2] = 7, then said map[2] = 5, then we are overwriting
our implementation.
So this code is valid and mainly built on the given input from the problem itself.
That's all.