In this problem, we would like to compute the number of triplets that are creating a valid triangle.
A valid triangle is a triangle that has a summation of any two sides greater than
the third side always.
And this is, as we said, a counting problem.
This is one type of the algorithms.
So going to the implementation here, if we thought, and this is, by the way, a very good strategy
that I would like you to keep in mind. When you have a problem, start by thinking about the brute
force solution.
There is a big chance, maybe 60 percent, in many problems the brute force solution can
be improved to a better solution.
And all cases thinking and starting from brute force will let your mind think about it. So never,
ever start a problem by thinking about the optimal solution.
Just go ahead with the brute force solution, which shouldn't be hard to implement.
Now, when you think about this problem, the brute force solution will be three nested loops,
loop one, loop two, and loop three. For trying three indices, i, j, and k.
And now you check if the triangle is valid or not.
If it's valid, just count++.
Now, this is O(n^3).
Uh, the hope now with binary search,
maybe we can improve this performance.
So first of all, like any binary search problem, you should start thinking about the sorting of
the values themselves.
So let's take a bunch of the values and start to sort them here, like the edges, two, five, seven, ten,
twenty, thirty, and so on.
Now we will brute force on two dimensions, and sometimes the optimal solutions involve
some kind of brute force and some kind of smart ideas.
So it isn't like a completely brute force solution and a completely smart solution.
Many solutions will involve brute force on something and continuing on something else.
So in this one, we will brute force on two of the variables.
So, for example, I will have here the i, and I will have here the j. Now,
starting from here, where is the k?
Let's say the k can be anything here.
So the brute force k will just try the seven, and ten, and twenty, and thirty.
But there is a question here, what creates a valid triangle?
The valid triangle must have values less than the two sides we have.
For example, if we have two and five, seven, we must find, let's pretend there is a
value six here.
Any valid value must be less than or equal
six, must be less than or equal the value
six.
So any value greater than six,
doesn't make sense for us.
So, now, the moral of that is if we have the first two values, and we summed them here together.
Then in the remaining of the array, find the first element greater than or equal to this value.
So I want to use a better array.
So let's say we have here, for example, value 10, and we have the value, for example,
15.
OK, so 10 and 15 is 25.
Any value less than 25 is a valid value. So let's pretend we have here 17.
We have 19.
We have 20.
We have 22.
We have 25.
We have 26.
We have 30, 31,
and so on.
Now here is the i,
and here is the j, i and j summation is twenty-five, then any value greater than or equal to 25 is invalid.
So let's find the lower bound in these values.
Remember, the lower bound is greater than or equal. Where is the lower bound? Here 25, then from 25
to 30,
this is invalid.
Where is the valid range? Only from here to here.
So we find the first index that is greater than or equal to you.
And then from j to this index here, the in-between range, are all valid triangles.
So one, two, three, and four
are valid triangles.
So we are adding here the four elements that represent the valid triangles.
Next step, j is moving here.
So now here is the i and j.
Ten and seventeen is twenty-seven.
Any value greater than or equal to twenty-seven is invalid, lower bound twenty-seven.
What is the answer?
Thirty.
So from after seventeen to twenty-six are valid triangles.
So the moral of that is we brute force it two of the dimensions, and we used a binary search to trail
us a range of valid values.
I hope the overall idea is clear now for you.
So the winners this year, as you see, is a very simple one.
We we need the following exchanges.
First of all, this one here does he want to buy the research on the whole array?
It would like to bring the researcher from a specific story.
So instead of usually having gives thought equals zero, we will bust the start of the race.
So here we bust key, which we started here I +1 to search for the target value.
Uh, so this is the first thing that we need to do here.
Umm hmm.
Yes, I have an impression that we should update did with something bigger than just care here.
But it will it anyway.
It's going to work because what anyway, finding the first element that's greater than or equal to?
But for more efficient, we can actually keep reducing.
The key was increasing here.
Uh, I would say maybe we can always bus here.
K was something like, uh, plus one.
Yes, probably we should always, but the simplest one here in a way, I verify that later this is a
normal binary search.
We just implemented it in the previous problem, which is finding the lower bound.
So the lower bound, as we mentioned before, is MIT is merging the condition for the greeter with the
merging with the condition of the equal.
And we would use the normal position track.
So this is the first solution.
And in the second solution, I'm asking you to use the lower bound function or they still.
So it is exactly the same logic.
Uh, and here we would like to use the internet a lower bound, then then law, don't take it to.
Was it written for the beginning and trigger would end.
So that here is the biggest hit.
Refer to the like victor.
Number of zero.
If we added B+ key like pointers, it would be shifting it to be key elements.
So again, this is exactly there the same logic.
Now, in the second, the question I'm asking you if we can get rid of even the binary search, more
and more so for the binary search helped us to find their interval like they're the end of the interval.
So we now will know from after to the interval is all what we need.
He would like to take it one more step, I would like only to use two loops to brute force with it and
in a smart way, get the same message as their binary search.
So it is a trick.
Let's again pretend we have 10, 15, then 17, 20, 22, 23, 23, 25, 30, 40, 50.
And let's say we have here an AI and we have Reggie.
Let's start the brute forcing.
We will start with key here.
And we will count this is now look like you see here we have two loops and it seems like we have the
third it, but I will show you why this is a smarter and actually it's one over here.
Uh, it started from 17 and finding all of that, all of their valid indices for key.
So 17 here will check is.
We have 10 and 15 is 17 valid point.
So as long as greeter that is valid, yes valid is valid.
Yes, valid.
Yes, it is valid.
No.
So now we stop the here and we added the count of all of these elements in between as we did before.
Now here is the optimization track.
Let's say we moved from I.
We move to hear.
15 and 17 is 27.
The point is, all of the values that are here are pretty good values.
So all what we need is we will just, you see this key.
We'll just keep updating.
The key will not reset it again.
We will not receive the key.
We'll just keep updating it to check is 25 is OK.
Was done in 17 years.
So this is our new location is 27 Aquino.
So this is not our location and from 20.
From 20 to 25 is our new valid Rich Letson will.
The next is 20, 10 and 20 is 30.
All of these valleys are buried already.
You started from here.
Let's pretend that this 35 35 and let's pretend this is 39.
What what?
What was the number?
Oh.
OK, here.
Let's pretend that this was a twenty six, twenty seven.
Twenty eight, thirty.
Now we are at Didn't 20, which is 30, anybody that lives of 30 is good value.
So we check from the lost the key 26 is okay.
Yes, 27 is okay.
Yes, 28 is a key, as 30 is a key.
No stop here.
So again, from 30, up to 22 is the new added value.
In summary, we brute force it two variables and we searched for the first element to greater than or
equal so that we consider the range before it.
But the more of it and is to keep counting all of that, which we already did it.
We already know if didn't, 17 is greater than 20.
Then if didn't, 17 is greater than 22 definitely did and 22 2010 and 20 is greater than 22 because
that is sorted.
So every every I and G and I and jobless one is greater than I, and G and I and G goes to is greater
than angel +1 because the values are sorted and we win this kind of optimizations.
Before you need to avoid the unnecessary operations, you need to avoid the doubling operations.
And I just see this need very decent analysis.
If this algorithm is hard for you at the moment, but is a skip it come back in the future and right
again, the system, by the way, the complexity.
So this is to insist that loops that are clearly in the square.
The moral of this why this could doesn't increase their complexity.
The key here will be increased and better to the G once.
So it's more like I and G G G and get an increase together.
So this loop doesn't have an effect on the performance.
There is a different way if you would like to write this good so that it actually looks like just two
nested loops.
You can you can find it here.
That's all.