In this video, you will learn how to generalize the body in the research.
So far, we will learned how to apply by the research on a certain array.
We learned three things to find the number in general or find the first index or find their lust index.
This is wrong.
The last index for it now, binary search can actually work on functions.
Specific categories can function with its code.
Monotonic functions will come back to this definition.
The binary search youcould will be still very systematic.
We use almost the same code from a problem to another.
But the key is to figure out how to do that.
Let's go back to the range of problem.
Usually, when we are trying to work on functions, we need to define a function and we need to define
a Boolean function based on it.
Sometimes they are just written as a one function.
Sometimes they are written as two separate functions.
So let me introduce a simple function for you here.
Counter is a function that are for rules and return the total number of coins that if we try to fill
the rows from one to end.
For example, if are equal three, then I would like to serve three rows, which needs one +2 +3 coins.
So this function should return at six.
So count of three is six.
As you see, this is a very trivial function, which is our actually our times of virtue.
That's it.
So this is the accounting function that I defined here.
No, the Boolean function, which is very important here.
The function visible of our in what are is the rules and in is the current.
The coins would return it true if and only if any coins are enough to cover.
There are rules, for example, here.
Yeah, but yeah, for simplicity, the function is just returning if greater than or equal to counteract.
So let's see here it is a table, but all by rule, we have the count of AH, which is just submission
from one, two or so.
For example, count to five is 15, which is one two three four five.
No, the visible function is digging and again, it cleans cover one rule.
Definitely, yes.
Can it go into cover two rows?
Definitely.
Yes, because we just need three.
Can eight coins to cover three rows?
Yes, because we just need six coins and we have eight.
Can it coins the cover tin?
Can it coins the cover for rows?
No, because then we need 10 coins, but we only have eight.
So that is missing here too.
So false.
Can five rules be covert, false?
There's a question for you here.
Do you expect an answer for any role greater than five?
The answer is false.
Starting from four, we cannot do it, and we definitely, if we cannot cover for rules, we definitely
cannot cover anything else, anything more than that.
This is something very important to keep in mind.
Now I would like you to look to the Boolean function.
The binary search, is it still working and actually win a race?
But now with the array is a virtual array the array is following.
The race has a bunch of truths.
It's a virtual array.
So let's let's make it here.
We have an array, a virtual array.
At index, one answer is to index it, to answer it's through index or straight through from index of
four.
The answer is false, false, false and so on.
So a bunch of truths.
There are many forces now when you think about it.
I actually knew need the lust or cadence of true in the array.
We need this one.
Now we can write a good for binary search using exactly the same logic on binary circular arrays.
But this time we would imagine the array.
OK, what are the values of the array?
The values of the three are Boolean values.
They are coming from the possible function, which we based here on the counting thing.
I would like you to try to code it in binary search.
Be careful when submitting on it.
Good because the limit is two to the bar 31 minus one, so it might overflow with you.
OK, let's see, liquid.
First of all, let's develop the possible function.
The Blues will function when tick and and tick the rules, it compute the total number of coins we need
for the rules, which is the rules times rules plus one over two, then the bullion is based on the
following is greater than or equal the total number of coins that we need or not.
If yes, then true or false observer heroes are long long because rules can be up to two to the hour
31 minus one, and we would like to multiply that in itself.
So this could overflow overflow in this plus overflow in the multiplication.
That's why I consider those here to belong.
Long notice.
Let's go back to the search itself.
We know the way in the research you need to start and end.
Once you are working on functions, you have to decide what is your start and what is your end?
We can see here clearly, maybe we cannot even cover a single rule, so we need from you.
What is the maximum rule that you can have virtually like?
We can use something like and this is a very high about, but then only we can use it.
Maybe you can develop something based on the squirrel in, but we don't care about that.
Or what we need to get is we have a good lower boat and a good boat.
Now we need, as I told you, we have a series of truths then series of forces, and they need to find
the last to get us through.
So this is like finding the last occurrence of her internal.
Here is the left and right like usually not change.
It is the middle like usual no change and are the elephant also conditions?
Now, if it is possible to cover?
Mid-Year representa that represented that arose if it is possible to cover mid rules using the current
in the Queen's, then mid isn't uncertain because we managed to cover that they made.
So answer here is a.
And we are seeking a bigger and bigger answer, so we move to the left side as we did before.
What if we cannot cover like, let's say, we tried, uh, possible function of eight and four rules?
We cannot do that.
So there is no answer so far, and we need tools to change our search to be searching only in the range
of zero and the three.
Please take time to read this.
Good to match it with finding the last the threw in an array is exactly the same logic.
Here are two examples to trace them.
For example, if I give you an equal nine.
Uh.
In equal, 29, sorry, in equal tonight.
So we start by zero and 29, the median is at 14.
The sum would be 100 and the five, as you see, we have only 100.
The submission here is very high and we have only 29 going.
So we have to shrink now.
Go to the middle, which is now 13, zero and 13, is generating for us to anyone.
We need 21 coins, but we have to win in nine coins.
So this means that we can at least recover six rules.
But let's see if we can do better, so we jump to the right interval from seven to 13.
Now the method is 10 10 rules need 55 coins.
We cannot do that.
So let's jump to the list to reduce from seven to nine.
The method is eight.
It rules need 36 of coins.
We cannot do that.
So let's reduce seven and seven is twenty eight coins, which is enough.
So this way we keep updating their answer here.
I hope the idea of this part is true, but now I would like to take you one more step further.
How can we prove that?
How can we recognize the general functions for brain research?