We need now to understand how to prove that a function can be used with a binary search.
Um, try to take five minutes for your time based on what we mentioned and try to think about it.
The moral of it is as following.
We need to be to make sure that the the the baboons, the function can guide the brain research.
Remember when we do a brain research on the array that is sorted, so the middle value in a comparison
with the target value can tell us should we go to the left or the right?
If you're like intuitive and in an informal sense, you can see that your function can correctly guide
you to move to the left or the right.
Then this is definitely can be used in a binary search.
Let's be more specific.
There are two cases, either the evaluation of the possible function is as following forgiving values
through true, true, true, true and starting from as false.
There is always false after it.
This is case number one.
The second case is we have faults of all sorts of also faults, and once we have true, we have always
true.
So this is the only two possible cases.
Specifically, these are our virtual array.
These are our virtual array and we are trying to use their answers to guide us.
For example, you might be here searching for their lost true.
So if you're a search here, come to a false value and we need the last true, then we definitely need
to decide.
OK, we jumped in the research to this true.
That's good, we have an answer, but we need the truth.
So we start to search in this array to find the lost, the true and so in a very similar way.
If the search is bunch of forces and then bunch of truths, there would never be another false are here
because, you know, as you see, it is an assorted array.
So when we have a true, true, true, true, then false, false, false, this is a decreasing array.
If we have false reports of also, then true, true, true, true.
This is an increasing array.
So as you see?
The social space is sorted, it is just this time zeros and ones in a set of values.
That's why it is a virtual array, not array.
You could be searching for whatever you need.
Maybe you need to search for the first.
True.
Maybe you need to search for the last efforts.
It's up to you.
It's in a way an array of just to value zeros and ones.
Again, go back to your general intuition.
Can we guide the search or not?
If yes, this is a binary search?
Now the interesting thing is you just need one or two minutes thinking to decide if this is true or
not.
Like, think about the indices we have function, if so, if of zero, if one, if we have to ask yourself
what is happening?
Is it always increasing?
And he is always decreasing, like if this is the case, then yes.
OK, let's up like that.
Let's go back to the orange squeeze.
I explain that already in there in that in the bush will function the first moment that you decide the
current coins cannot.
Cover the coins that we know way too to cover it anymore.
For example, if possible, function of eight coins and three rules is true now possible function of
eight coins and four rules is false.
Definitely possible of eight and five is false and possible of eight and six is false.
Boosters would if any number that is beyond the four is false.
So this is a serious piece of true, true, true.
Once we start with the fools, it's false vaults, false reports of all supports.
So this is how we know the social space can be used to guide their binary.
Not.
Now, going back to the word, the monotonic function, the monotonic function is a function that is
increasing, just increasing or decreasing.
Maybe just increasing, maybe strictly increasing, strictly decreasing.
But it is just one of these things.
So this function just keep increasing.
It is increasing.
So it's important actually increasing function or decreasing function.
This one decrease decrease decrease.
This one is increasing and decreasing.
So this isn't when putting this function here.
If it's like that, then like that this is actually a function of forces.
Then once it's somewhat untidy, if the function is like that, then like that.
So this is Monacan increasing, then decreasing.
So the good about the monotonic functions.
They are logically can guide the binary search now in brackets with the NIC to think actually that much,
you will see that in the homework, that things are and are much less formal than that.
A few examples here.
Assorted array of duplicate values, it actually a monotonic function, specifically that decreasing.
Their little that it could function that we developed is increasing monitoring function.
Uh, I mean, they're restricting.
OK, now there is a something that's very useful to remember.
Let's say you have an array of non-negative values.
Can you bring the research on that definitely didn't sorted now I committed this disarray.
What's happening there is monotonic, so.
The accumulated array is a internet function, you can their social media and some problems.
The key is to figure out that you are actually searching based on the accumulation of the rate, which
is I'm an attorney.
So this is something that to keep in mind in somebody, you need to merely develop this possible function.
This is your virtual array, and you should think if this is doable or not.
The miners record is usually two section one section that has their start and the end and the middle
and the call for the possible function.
This is classical and repeated.
The second book is developing the possible function, sometimes the possible function, or this is just
one function and sometimes the possible function is doing some counting or so.
The multiple functions sometimes is actually complex.
This is actually the code of the trick to figure out would that visible function?
To figure out what it is, it's correct and to know how to use it in the overall homework of this section.
We will learn about a lot about different cases for that possible function.
Now, as I said during this course, I would be explaining in a and informal way and I would be more
concrete than theoretical because it simply make the course, which is actually hard by itself and easier
learning experience.
I would like to show you, what does it mean to speak in a formal way?
So here is how can we explain the binary search in a formal way?
We can say the following Consider a predicate be defined on some order set as brain research is possible
if and only if and then I can use this statement or I can use this statement.
I would like you to take a minute and try to interpret what is the relationship between that and brain
research in an informal way.
So that is what what this statement is saying.
First of all, Bridget could be just a Boolean function that returns true or false.
That's it.
Now what does this one say?
Here it say for all X as it's here, by the way, is just your sister's space.
For example, in the range of creates a problem.
The social space that has this start and end is it's now built.
X implies if bill fixes through.
It implies that the boy is truthful all way greater than X, how to interpret that mathematically is
following it sees once you found a true.
Everyone after this exposition, which are position is also true, which can be said in a different
way.
If the fix is false, every number before it is false, as you see.
This could be a bit confusing unless you have a good mathematical background and can barely understand
that this equal to this in the courts.
I just told you you need a bunch of zeros followed by ones or a bunch of ones, followed by zeros.
This is an informal description for that.
If you would like to make it formal.
It would be good this way.
It is still good and useful to explain in a formal ways because it make the interpretation easier.
Specifically, it make it more controlled.
Well, when we write an informal description, there might be a lot of questions to clarify the informal
description.
But the mathematics is much more, uh, much more limited.
This simple, by the way, is just the donut symbol taken in C++.
It would be the not operator.
Now, as I see, it might be tough for the people based on your background if you like mathematics.
This is OK for you.
If you studied the discrete mathematics, you should be very familiar with the symbols.
At least I don't mean that all of the algorithms are written in this way.
They are written in different formal ways.
But this is what we mean by a formal description and informal description if you would like to expose
yourself to a lot of formal descriptions.
You could read from the introduction to algorithms book or the one that named as the salaries.
That's all.