Homework number two in brain research.
The first task is we have an array of integers and we also given an integer that represent the threshold.
If we have some integer value, we can divide the array by the value integer division where you are
sealing the values and some of the values in the.
The divisor that you used is valid if the submission is less than or equal to it.
Now what is the turkeys would like to find the smallest, the positive integer that is valid here.
By the way, whenever I skip the limits, I usually mean you shouldn't depend on them.
Like you might ask what is the maximum number of the items in the tray?
I just mean, just consider it as big as 1000000.
What is the threshold?
Just a big value.
You can almost double check the values in the liquid itself.
Let me here clarify on an example so that if things are not clear enough, here is the array.
We can divide this array on different values, whatever we need as an integer, but do like a sealing
division.
So integer division was saved if we tried to divide this array by one.
So whatever one is, one one to over one is two five or one is five nine and so on.
Some of the values seventeen is 17 literary classics.
No, so we cannot divide by one.
Let's try, for example, the visor like put one over four a zero something.
So we set it up to one two over four is zero something set it up to one five or four is one something.
So set it up to two nine over four is two something.
Set it up to three.
So all of the values seven is seven.
Laser equals six.
It's also an invalid device.
Now use five.
When you use five in division, you will have one one one two, which is two that adds five.
So have less than three six five is the smallest, the positive integer that do that.
So as you see the small value like one, give me like one value, give it a high value.
The next value is four is still high value.
Five is a bit less value, so you'll find the smallest integer that satisfy that threshold.
This is where the problem means.
Yeah, but there is more examples to make sure that you understand the problem.
The second problem is a problem for my garden.
We have, uh, we have different flowers, every flower has some bloom day.
So let's say we have here some flower number one.
Here is another flower.
You know, the flower, flower flower and so on.
Now.
After this given Bloom Day, the flower is ready to be used.
Before that, it isn't easy to use.
So we have any flowers and anyone has a day where we can use it now in the garden or the in the in the
shop.
We need to make Emma buckets.
And it must have gay flowers, but must be a decent one.
So, for example, let's say gay is free.
Then I need to reconsider the flowers.
Maybe this three, maybe this three, maybe this three, whatever.
If you take it once, you cannot take it anymore.
Now the problem is we need em buckets.
OK, we need them.
And the problem, they call this one, and they call this key.
We need them a box and we would like to see the minimum number of days notice that we are limited with
their flowers day here.
So let's see an example here.
Um, here in this example.
We have, uh, one two, three four five where fake flowers.
We would like to create three buckets.
Everyone has only a single flower.
So now let's simulate after day number one, this flower is ready.
After day number two, this flower is ready.
After day number three, this flower is ready from these four to nine.
Nothing is ready.
At day number 10, this one is ready and this one is ready.
Now we need it three buckets so we can only with three days, which is the minimum number of days to
have booked so that we can create.
Let's see another example.
We need to book it if one of them has three flowers, so the minimum number here is seven, so let's
wait seven days after seven days.
We have here four flowers ready for us and two flowers ready for us.
Now, why is this only give us one?
Give us one one bucket, we need more than that.
We need, we need to.
So we would have to wait today, No.
12 or so that this not now is ready to add a date well on day 12.
So now we take this three and maybe these three, two and so on.
So I hope you, I hope now you understand the simulation of the task itself.
In the third dusk, we have houses, we have the location of the houses and we have the location of
heaters, and we would like to, uh, cover all of the current houses with the current leaders.
But we need to set their rediscovery of every heater.
So see if there is a heater here and the it is one, then it can cover one one, have one element before
and one element after.
It would like to find the minimum radius so that interior use so that we would add to all of the heaters
such that all of the houses are covered.
Let me give an example.
We have here three heaters.
So here is the location at point number one.
One.
There is a house at two, there is another house at three.
There is a third house and there is one heater here already.
If I use the use of one, then I can cover one unit before and one unit after, which is now covering
all of the houses that you have.
So the minimum wages is what?
In the second, the problem is following, we have four house his house at one, at two, at three,
at four.
So here is the house is.
And we have two heaters, one heater at one and one heater at four.
Now we would like to cover all of the heaters if we use reduce often this heater will cover one here
and here, so this one nose cover and this heater will cover one here and here.
So this heater is covered, as is the case we have here two houses one at House one and one at House
five.
The heater here is at medal at two.
That was the radius of three I can cover three units before, so this one is covered and three units
after this one, no is covered.
So the minimum Regis is three and so on.
In case you don't understand exactly the questions we need, read the text very carefully with the examples.
As I said earlier, don't wait for me to explain for you what is a problem statement?
It's actually your role.
I just know some people have weak English skills.
The immediate the problem and don't get it.
So I'm trying to give more help.
But it is an important skill for you to be able to understand the problem requirements by yourself.