So far, we studied the 1d array in the inner case and the character array.
So today we see a generalization for it, which is multidimensional array, let's motivate it.
If I told you to write a program that reads the grades for students, we have 100 students and
we have 20 subjects.
So how can we code that? you are probably going to create 20  arrays for the grades, grad1[100],
grade2[100], grade20[100] and so on.
In this case, we did a grade per subject for 100 students.
But this is very impractical and also it doesn't scale
well, what if we have 1000?
what if we have one more subject?
Let's visualize the data.
So here are 7 students and 4 subjects.
This is called metrix or a table.
So we have here some students and we have here 4 subjects.
We can describe it as following,
We have here 7 rows, OK?
And we have 4 columns.
Remember, in array indexing, we were using zero based indexing; so the same.
Let's say that the rows are indexed from 0 to 6 and the columns are indexed from 0 to 3.
So for example, row 0 here represents Mostafa and the column 0 here represents Math.
If I told you what is the value of the table of row 6, column 2 ? then row 6 is here, column
2 is here.
Remember, we are in zero-indexing.
OK, so let's use this nice notation ([6][2]) so one bracket for 6 one bracket of 2, to represent
what we need exactly from this
nice table.
C++ saves our time and gives us this nice utility, the 2D table, something that can be number
of rows times number of columns.
Exactly same rules like 1D arrays,
But now it's more of 2D. How to create it, like following a double grade[7][4],
It means 7 rows and 4 columns, to access an array use grades[6][2].
That's it.
So here is a matrix that is 3x4.
These are three rows,
These are four columns.
If you want to access this index, then it is of value of [1][3].
If I would like to code this in C++, I can do it as following,
I can say: int val[3][4];,
then I am done with the array but it isn't initialized.
I can say =, open two braces and write zeros, then they are all zeros.
But if I want to initialize it, mainly like that one, then I can come here and open braces and write
the first row, comma braces, then write the second row, then braces and write the third row.
If you used the =, this is more of the C-style, if you removed it,
This is a new C++11 initialization list style. if I would like to access it,
Very similar to the normal array, val[1][3], please take your time to
familiarize yourself with this array structure. Let's proceed more.
You will notice that it's just as same as the 1D.
But we are extending to the to 2D case.
I'm here defining a double array of grades, seven rows and six columns, and I put here zero,
So all of it now initialized to 0. if I want to put the grades of Mostafa.
So Mostafa was at row 0, so notice here, grade[0], grade[0], grade[0], grade[0].
And then I started to access the subjects, grade[0][0] is 50
This is for math. grade[0][1], grade[0][2], grade[0][3], and so on.
For Asmaa, it's grades[1], grades[1], grades[1], and so on.
So this is how we can put the values. again,
Keep remembering that our indices are zero-based, not one-based.
OK, so let's print it, assume I already initialized all of it to zero and then some values, how to print it?
We typically need to print it by iterating over every row, and for every row iterate on every column.
So it goes as following, in a very standard way: for (int row = 0; row < 7;
This is iterating on every row and printing here I'm in row 0.
Then you are iterating internally, for column = 0, column < 4, ++column,
Then this array access.
You are going to see this structure over and over again.
Please familiarize yourself with it.
OK, let's read the very same concept, let's define an array here, we initialize it to zeros, then we
started to read it.
So we iterate on rows, then we iterate on columns, and then start to read the array. that's it. If you would
like to print it. that's it. as you see just normal extension from 1D to 2D array just by considering
a table style right now.
That's it for now.