Let's solve the second homework set. The first one is  about the prime numbers in a specific region, and
we'd like each query to be answered with only nested loops maximum per query.
So how can we handle that?
We're going to read the is..., we will create an array, but instead of an array of numbers, we are going
to read the number and judge directly
if it's a prime or not.
There is no need to keep computing every single query
who are the prime numbers. We can pre-process the input data directly.
So while we are reading that n & m  raws here, we will read the value and then we will decide if the
value is prime or not.
Once we are done with these two loops, every single value in this read n*m matrix is
either zero or one. The remaining
part for us now is with every query.
Just iterate on the target positions here and count all of the zeros and ones in this guys.
So all of those will come to the total number of primes here.
So the trick was to make sure that you are doing this pre-processing early.
Other than that, you just need to learn how to be careful with your start index
and your end index, that's all.
Nothing more than that.
In the second problem, we would like to compute the mountains if you are good so far with the directional
array.
This one should be fair at the moment.
We will define the directional array, but for the eight directions that we have and then we need to find all
the mountains.
So mainly we need to find all of my 8 neighbors for every position but the valid ones.
So we will iterate on every single value and then we will decide the boolean if all of them are good
or not, for every one of them would iterate on all of the 8 directions, compute the next row and
next column for my neighbor, make sure it is a valid one.
If this valid one is less than this guy, then we know that that mountain is false.
So the moral of that is iterate over every position, iterate on my 8 neighbors if they exist, make
sure you are inside the grid.
Make sure that you are higher than all of them.
That's all. So mainly the direction array trick that
I hope that you are good at it.
In the third problem, I would like to implement this active robot problem and may be it might be challenging
for you that you have to move all of that one.
But if you thought about using the %  it should be an easy one. Again, this active robot is moving
in a grid in four directions so this guy can move in the four directions.
Again, this should trigger the directional ray. To implement that,
We will start with defining our directional array.
I used the order of the input to follow the order of my directional array to make it easy.
And we start with being at position zero & zero. With every query, we take the direction, convert it to zero
based.
Now we know if I am at position r and I have to move to, say, right side, for example.
So the right is one in the row, so it means one.
But what if I have to move five steps?
It move, it means to multiply five times this one.
So by multiplying the number of steps in the direction, you are actually jumping too many
steps in this direction and so on.
Again, let's say that you are position zero zero and you would like to move down.
Down means the number of columns should be the number of...., if you like to
go down, then the column is as it is.
But the number of the current row is going to be incremented.
That's why here we have the one here for the down incremented. Again,
let's say we'd like to move five steps.
So five times one is five.
Then this is the next  where you move.
The cycle is very easy to handle.
Like let's say you are moving one million step, but if you just applied %n , it is going to
cycle.
So always remember that %n can help you to cycle.
Remember, always the clock after every 12 hours it is useless so %n can help you get rid of
cycles.
We know cycles in clock.
We can also see cycles when it comes to the metrics.
The last problem which might be a bit overwhelming for you, but it is very good
one to know how to generalize the flattening idea so that you can see the big pattern is as follows.
I hope you manage to do some of it.
Let's first of all, construct the conversion from the multi-dimensional to the one dimensional, because
it is the easy one.
Remember, in the 2D case, we mainly had something like that.
We were multiplying the current row with the total items per column,
and then we are adding the current column.
The logic of multiplying the current row with the total number of columns is we know if we are 2D
it means that there are two complete rows that are done and every raw has total number of columns
here.
Now if we would like to extend it to 3D,
Now, if we are at the d, r & c, if we are at d, it means there are two complete grid rows and
columns are done.
So to handle that we need also to multiply the d of the depth with a total grid.
I'm defining here Db and Rb.
So the Db is the total number of rows times columns and the Rb for the total number of columns.
So by this way it is very, very symmetric for you.
We are multiplying here, but one, we are multiplying by  the total number of columns, but here multiplying
by the total number of rows and columns.
So I hope now you can realize it with depth three;
it means there are three grids.
Each one is R times C are already done.
Once you are done with this equation, getting the opposite of it is a matter of math.
Let's say you have some index and you would like to extract that guy.
If you would divide it by Db, then we know all of that is less than Db.
So all of them would be out of the competition.
And if you take a %Db, we know that this part will be gone.
Now, for this part, it is exactly the very similar way to the 2D part. You divide here,
then you take a %. That's all.