In this program, we will.. In this homework will solve the Tic-Tac-Toe some people, consider it a project,
but this is again a simple assignment,
so don't like don't be cheated by that.
And it will be challenging for you because I would like you to develop it in a smart way.
We would like to develop a tic tac toe, but it will not be three times three,
it will be N times N, for simplicity here,
let's say N maximum is nine, but you can do it in any number,
you will are run a game of two users who will keep playing till one of them win or tie eventually, print
to the grid after each round.
We started with three, for example,
the user write one and one, so we put an X for him,
now it is o turn three and one we print for him here the O here, two and the two we print for him
the X at the two and two.
Now two and one
we print it here, we put it at two and one for the O, the user now entered two and two which is already
there.
So we say invalid
try again, five and five, again, invalid.
Three and three is good position and X just won the game.
You can write this code to be a very ugly one, writing a lot of for loops to verify the rows and verifying
the columns and defining the diagonals,
I would like you to try to use the direction array track to implement this code in a very nice and smart
way.
If you found this hard, maybe start with the ugly way,
just write a bunch of loops to verify all of the rows, all of the columns out of the diagonals for
the winning cases.
And after that, maybe try to make it better or check out my solution. That's all.