See how to solve the Tic-Tac-Toe problem compared to other courses and materials
there are two challenges here. From one side,
I don't want you just to make it three times a three.
And also I don't want you to, like, just go with the very ugly and a lot of coding to verify the rows,
columns and diagonals.
These two things might make it a bit challenging for you.
So anyway, let's see how to code it.
The general flow of the program is as following;
we have here a grid that is initially initialized to zeros.
Zero means there is nothing here.
One means "x" and two means "o" we start with reading the input from the user.
Let's skip this for now.
Initially, we have the turn was zero for 'x' and then it could be one for 'o'.
And let's go.
We start with number of steps.
Let's say that we have a grid of 'n' equal three.
If the user did nine steps, which are three times three, we are sure that the grid is completely
filled.
And this mean actually we are in a  tie step.
So this is my first condition here.
Keep going.
But if the total number of steps is n*n then the grid is done. And then I decide the symbol
of the turn, it could be like initially 'x' and if the turn is 1,  we can switch it to 'o'.
OK, there is a more elegant way to do it.
You can create a string with letter 'x' and 'o' and based on the turn, you just get it from the string.
But I thought to make it simpler here and then we start to ask the user to enter a row and column
the user is entering something in one base.
Always be careful, so convert first to zero based.
After that, we need to verify two things.
We need to verify if it is valid location or not, and we need to verify if the cell is empty or not.
To verify that the position isn't outside the grid, we need to make sure it is less than the row or
equal to the rule, less than the column or equal to the column.
Well, and finally, we check if the grid cell, not zero.
If it is zero, this is OK, otherwise, it's already reserved.
Observe that this if condition is very popular in industry.
This is a shortcut circuit evaluation; like this
grid access will never be evaluated if any of these guys are invalid, because if any of
these guys are invalid, this grid of r and c will access outside the array.
So you cannot put this if condition here in the beginning.
It has to be in the end after verifying all of these four guys.
So now we are done and we have a valid location.
We bought it here in the cell.
Remember that the grid has 0, 1 & 2 for the turn.
So I'm adding here plus one.
And here is just a printing for the grid.
So far, so good.
We would like now to verify the winning of the grid.
One very direct way it just to go with very dense code we need to verify the N rows, then verify the N
columns, then verify 2 diagonals.
So overall we have to 2 N plus 2 verification.
We can do that.
But this is very, very lengthy code.
Let's see how the dir. array can help us to make the code very elegant.
Observer the following: the behavior of all of this verification is the same, how? The all of them need
some starting point, for example, zero & zero and then all of them keep going in a specific direction,
either the row direction, the column direction, left diagonal direction, right diagonal  direction and all of them go N
steps.
And this should trigger for you the dir. array.
So the idea is as following, we will create a single array that mainly or a few arrays here that mainly
maintaining the information of the two N plus one verification.
Specifically, we need four values.
I need the starting point, which is r & c , and I need the direction for everyone.
Let's give an example, for example, from zero & zero, I need to verify its row.
So the direction is one and zero.
We keep going in the direction of the row till it ends.
And also we need to verify its column.
So we need to go zero one, which means don't increment to the rpw, but increment the column.
So we verify all the columns.
If you would like to verify the left diagonal, which is also starting from zero & zero,
we could move in from one & one, so it's (0,0) now (1,1), (2,2) and (3,3), and so on.
If you would like to verify the right diagonal, where is the starting point of the right diagonal?
It could be, for example, 0 and n-1, which is the first row and the last element  and what
is the moving pattern?
It should be
go one extra row, but go one less column and so on.
Based on that, we can maintain the n rows, n columns, 2 diagonals in just these 4 arrays.
The 4 arrays represent the four values that we need here, the r & c values and the 2 diagonal values.
Let's make it here more accurate.
Now, let's see how to build that.
If I would like to add the n rows verification that I would like, observe that all what you
need is that to try the starting point r and 0. So r and zero are the starting point for a row here
and the direction would be fixed to zero and one.
So for example, let's say n is three, then we will add zero and zero.
One and zero.
Two and zero.
Now, all of them will be moving with no increment for the row, but there is an increment
for the column, this is how we verify all the rows, all the row elements in a very symmetric way.
To add the n columns, you need to try 0 & c as a starting point with a moving direction one
and zero.
So we add here for n is three, 0&0, 0&1,  0&2  and from here we start to
move one and zero, which means move the column
but fix the row.  Don't don't change the row.
Finally, we need to add 2 diagonals: the left and right, the left one start at zero and
zero and is incremented with one & one, and the right diagonal is 0 and n -1 as we mentioned
here.
And the direction is one & -1.
This way we added 2N+2 verification for our grid.
If you check this value, it should be 2N+2 verification.
Now, we would like to apply them so we iterate over every verification of them.
We take the starting point r & c and we take the direction row and the direction column,
and then all what we need is to iterate for n steps to check if all of them are the current first
element.
So first is
the current element at the grid of r & c. OK, if the first equal equal zero, it means it's empty, so we
ignore it.
Otherwise, we can even make one more if condition here to verify that the winner is the turn.
But anyway, let's say the first here is 'x', we iterate on the current row or column or diagonal
depends on the check and make sure that all of them are the current winner.
If this is a case of the count equal n, which means that a complete row
or a complete column or a complete diagonal.
If this is the case, then we say that this is a specific winner and we return zero.
Otherwise, we switch to the turn from zero to one or one to zero and increment the steps.
That's all. I know
that might be a bit overwhelming for you, but use n equal three,  verify these guys and will verify
these guys.
And I hope overall it should be OK for you.
This is the tie test case you might write, that's all.