In the previous video, we studied mainly the 2D array, so let's proceed more.
This is how we read the array, as we did before.
But now I would like to show you what we call "column-row order accessing". when we access row by row,
then column by column,
This is a column-row accessing. but we can also access it column by column.
For example, you iterate on every column, then iterate on every row, then again use a notation of row and the
column.
This is now is accessing the array column by column.
OK.
Remember the grades, what was the column in the grades.
Yeah.
The column was for the subjects.
So it's like now you would like to see it from the angle of math subject.
So previously we wanted to know what are the grades of Mostafa, what are the grades of Asmaa.
So we were focusing on the row perspective. when you iterate by column, you are iterating from the column perspective.
So now say what are the grades of the math, what are the grades of science
and so on.
One interesting thing to know, is that when when we access array 2D, using row then column, we are
iterating on it directly in the memory.
But when you are accessing it column by column, we are making a lot of jumps in the memory, you should
know later the reason behind that.
So the column-row accessing is typically slower than the row-access.
And this is a very interesting thing about the memory, like although this is the same as a number of
operations of row-column order,
However, this is making a lot of jumps in the memory and in the cache.
So, it is a bit slower.
And this is interesting because it has something more about the hardware of your machine.
Let's compute the average grade per student,
OK. so we would like to know the average of Mostafa, the average of blah, blah, blah.
OK, this is very simple exercise. Here,
we read the numbers, and then if we would like to get the average, then we iterate row by row, then we will
have a (sum) variable to sum for all the grades of a specific student.
Then we sum it and divide it by 7.
This is how we get the average per row for a student.
You can also think in a similar way,
I would like to compute the average math grade, for example.
Then you have to switch the column with the row and sum and divide by 7.
OK,
Here is a very interesting thing, what we call flattening an array.
When we say a flattened array, it means we simply switch it from 2D to 1D.
How to do that? you simply accumulate them row by row.
So this is a 2D array, 8, 16, 9, 52,
It's here the first row,
Then you take the second row to be here,
the second row, you take the third row to put it here in the third row.
If you look at it this way, you notice, and this is by the way, how it is in the memory.
So this 2D array is actually always in the memory, 1D array.
So the 2D array, and 3D array, and 4D array are all in the memory 1D, ok. they are flattened,
and that's why the row accessing, is just accessing it one by one in the memory.
On the other side, the column accessing is making jumps.
Now there is a question that we will try to stress on later,
I would like you to flatten the array as following,
I'm writing for you here, a simple
code that iterate on a matrix that is 3x4, for every one of them,
I'm printing its index in the 1D array and it's position in the 2D array.
I would like you to find the formula that can do the following,
It can take a position i and j in a 2D array, and tell me what really would be the index of it in a 1D array.
And on the other side, it takes the index in 1D array and it tells you the index in the 2D
array, the position in 2D array.
So print this statement, try to find the relationship.
Another interesting thing, and it isn't about syntax, it's about useful utility.
Let's say you are here in position I and j, and then there are neighbors for you.
There are two scenarios usually, and it can be more. here,
The scenario number one, we have only four neighbors, 1, 2, 3, 4, or 1, 2, 3,
4.
It depends on the order.
So how many neighbors? 4.
In another case, you can have eight neighbors like 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7,
8.
OK, or 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8.
Regardless of the order, they are like 4 neighbors or 8 neighbors.
They can even be more.
But anyway, this is the most common one.
So one interesting question for you also to think about it,
If you have a position here for some i and j, can we in an elegant way, get the whole positions of these
8 steps?
How can we do that?
Think also about it.
Finally, we would like to move to a more generalization to the 2D array.
Can we do more?
Let's motivate that.
What if we have five years in the school, for each year
we have hundred students maximum and we have a 20 subjects.
How now can we represent that?
one may think again,
OK, let's make five arrays, one array for every year.
That's OK, but not convenient.
C++ give you the ability to create a 3D array.
a 3D array, is a 3D-dimensional, so it has 5, 100, and 20. So we can create it this way, you
can access the grade for like if you would like to access the 3rd year student number 71
9th subject, this will access to a 2, 70. and 8.
So this would give you the information of this student.
Can I do bigger?
Yeah, you can do more and more. but be careful,
The number of memory is growing up.
When you say 5, 100, 20, you are creating 5 * 100 * 200 numbers in
the memory,
This is a lot.
For example, one, two, three, four, five, six,
This is one million numbers in the memory.
So be very careful from the dimensionalities because it just grows up in memory very fast.
That's it.