This is a recently added video on the positions neighbours.
I already explained it during the section, but I thought maybe making it more clear here will make
things easier.
The word matrix or the word grid refers mainly to something that is of 2D structure, like same number
of rows and same number of columns.
And we will learn today about some neighbors trick that make coding very easier. To give you some context, in many
problems we might need to check our neighbors.
Let's say you are at this position here in the middle.
Then you might sometimes need to consider your 4 neighbors: up and right and down and left.
So these four positions.
Sometimes you need to consider more than that, as these 8
conditions, these eight neighbors and sometimes
16 and so on,
it depends.
And what might make the code very ugly is that you have to keep addressing all of them one by one.
But there is what we call "direction array", which make our life much easier when it comes to addressing
the neighbors.
I would like to think about the following, think in position
0 and 0, what is the relation between the four or the eight neighbors it has? and try to create 2 like 1D
arrays, in each one list the differences such that from any (i,j) we can get the neighbor
So if I'm zero and zero, how to get this neighbor or this neighbor or this neighbor, or this neighbor,
what kind of a change happening to the current row and the current column?
Try to think for five minutes.
Let's see the differences.
If you are in (r,c) here in the middle to go up, you need to be at (r-1 ,c), to go down
You need (r+1, c), if you would like to go to the diagonal
You should be (r+1, c+1)
So this means that if I am at (r, c) and would like to go to the down, it means that the number of rows
will be incremented with one
but the column doesn't change, in a similar way
if you would like to move to the left, it means you would like to
You would like to
What is a change of (r,c) to the left?
This is the left
It should be.. sorry
This should be (r, c-1)
sorry for the mistake
So down we definitely have (r+1,c)
I made a copy-paste mistake here :(
If you would like to move to the left, the row doesn't change, but the column is minimized with one.
We can have two arrays to encode for us this +1/-1/0 changes and we call that direction
array mainly in programming competitions.
So here is how to get the four neighbors you maintain
mainly what is the difference that you need to move to the down?
You need one change for the row, but not change for the column.
What about moving to the right?
We need no change for the row, but one change for the column. Moving up
you need to decrease the row, but leave the column.
What about the left?
You need to do not change the row, but minimize the left.
Let's say you are at position here in the middle at (4,7)
If you are treated at four the steps and take the current row and column
oh, this is another
bug, this should be j, if you are at (i, j) and started to add the current row and current
column, you will notice that you are getting the neighbors, for example, if you are here at r
and seven and would like to go up then up would be 4+1 is 5 and j plus zero which is
which will be seven.
It's wrong here because I acceded with wrong one I didn't verified.
So this way the four will be five, but the j would be seven, in a similar way let's say, we would like
to move to the left
the four will be added to zero.
It would be 4 the g would be added to -1.
It would be six, it would be four and six, and so on.
I would like you to give you a trial to think about the array when it comes to 8 elements, it's like now how
to get this 8 elements? design something that is di and dj to encode all of this row and column changes.
That's all.