Let's do practice1 on the multidimensional arrays, you are to read a matrix, so whenever I read a matrix,
you are reading the row and column and then you are reading the whole matrix and then find the position
of the maximum value in the array.
If there are several ones you are to find the last occurence, the last position where it exists.
So if this is the input, we have several 10s and this 10 is the max value and it is at position 2x2.
So I would like you first of all to always give a trail, good trail by yourself and then keep going.
Here we have created The matrix and then we are going to extend our effort to get the maximum in
1D array, and just where is the maximum in 2D array.
So iterate on every row, then iterate on every column and then let's maintain here two positions for where
is the maximum so far.
If the current array index is >= to the maximum, then we just save this
new position here
is it. this way we are done with where it is exactly the maximum.
So this will keep be updated with the new position and so on.
So notice here, the ">=" here
Is that the one that helped us to find the occurrence.
What if you would like to find the first occurrence, then you just make it ">", this way,
Once you found a greater than value, you only replace, so greater than equal made it the last occurrence.
OK, another practice we are to read a matrix, then we would to like print four different
values.
We would like to print the sum of the left diagonal.
This is named the left diagonal.
And this is named to the right diagonal.
So diagonal goes like you start from [0][0] and increment row and column with one increment, increment row and column
with one. The right diagonal,
you start form the first row last column and go one step this direction and one step this direction
you also would like to print the sum of the last row and the sum of the last column.
So these are the four values that we would like to print.
For example, here you notice that 8 + 15 + 2 is the 25 value and so
on.
So this is basic exercise to just learn iterating on the matrix.
OK, so let's read the array and let's start with the diagonal
part. if you would like to go with the diagonal part, start at zero and zero and let's say
left_diagonal will be the summation,
We keep going as long as i is < rows and j < columns, every time we  add the value
at the position i and j, and we have here ++ and ++, to jump to the next position.
This is a fair equation in terms of the ++, like nothing risky here because i exists once only
in the equation and j exists only once in the equation.
So this is how we started from 0 0, 1 1, 2 2, 3 3 and so on. To get the right
diagonal,
We also start at position row zero, but we start at the right column, the very end column, which
is as columns - 1, and then, the equation should move to the next row, which i++, but it
should decrease the column,
So --.
Now we would like to verify it, we would like the i to not exceed the rows and would like the j to stay
greater than or equal to the zero. To find the sum of the last row,
You just start with the last row equals zero and  j starts with zero.
I think ...
last row here is where we are accumulating the result, j = 0 is where we start and
we are fixing here rows - 1,
So this is actually our last row.
So we are fixing the row value and the j is just moving from zero to column - 1. in a very similar
way,
We would like to get to the last column then we are fixing the last column and starting with the row and
just incrementing it. so it's more or less iterating on the array itself.
OK, let's read a matrix and then we will read indices of two columns.
We would like to make a complete swapping for a matrix.
For example, here is our matrix and we would like to swap column 0
With the column number 4, so after the result, you see here, 52, 6, 10, they come in here in this way, ok.
again, more of iterating on a matrix, and just doing some swapping.
So to do that, we read the matrix,
Then we iterate on every row and then we start to swap the value in position, row, c1,
with the position of row and c2.
Once we are done, we can print the new swapped columns.
That's it for now.