Let's do more practice on the multidimensional arrays. The greedy robot,
we have a robot and this robot will be starting at position [0][0] in a matrix of NxM.
Tho whole values of the matrix will be distinct.
You are to do the following: the robot takes the value in the current cell and then starts to move
but to where? it can only move one step to either right, bottom or the diagonal.
OK, which one to select
among them, is going to select the one that has the maximum value.
And remember, they are distinct values, they are different values.
And then you are telling me the total values that the robot is going to collect.
OK, so for example, start at [0][0], then move maybe to the right, then bottom, then left and so
on.
OK,
try to give a coding for it.
It might be a short code, but give a trail.
Here we are reading the whole matrix and we starting at position
'i' with zero and j with zero and total sum with zero.
We will start while looping and as long as the current 'i' and the current 'j' are within the matrix we keep
going.
We start with sticking the current value in the sum.
So we add it to the sum.
Then we need to make a decision.
Are we going to move to the right or to the down or to the diagonal and we need the maximum
one of them noticed that it is necessary that you have a right where you have a down or you have a diagonal.
It might be that you in the end of the matrix somewhere.
So we need to verify if we can make the step or not.
So we first start with the right to have a valid right.
Then the current j + 1 should be still less than the column.
This means that you aren't at the last column.
So if we are at the last column, we can take the next value for us from this position and we can
consider it our, the first place to move.
So right now, we already took the next value.
We are taking it in a temporary value with a best_i and best_j.
in temporary value.
So for now I'm asking and saying if we are in the next value.
If we can move to the right, take the value and say that we took these 'i' and 'j', so far we didn't move,
we just trying to figure out.
Now, let's check out the down, can we move to the down?
This is what happened in line 26 if we can move to the down.
We have two cases.
Either we already have a next value from, has a next value from the last step or not.
So I'm asking, I'm telling if best_i == -1, it means that this condition isn't achieved.
So we just assign the current value.
So we say, OK, let's move to the down and just keep it. OK,
What if we already have some best_value?
Then we're comparing our next value with the down value.
If the next value is better, we just take it.
So here at this moment we are actually checking, actually checking three things.
Can we move or not?
If we can move, do we have a value or not?
If we don't have a value take it, if we have a value, compare and make sure we take it.
Finally, in a very similar logic, we would like to check the diagonal.
So first we need to make sure that 'i' + 1 and 'j' + 1 still in the grid.
If it is still in the grid, there are two cases, either of these two values we can take.
We already took something from them or not.
So if 'best_i' is minus one, we just take it.
Otherwise, we compare our value with this value.
What happens after this step is we know our next 'best_i' and our next best_j.
So we update our 'i' and update our 'j' with the next value to move to there.
Once we move to there, the robot is going to take these 'i' and 'j' values, please take 3x4
matrix and start to put some different values in it and start from 'i' and 'j' with zero and zero and start
to do tracing,
tracing for the matrix. In this one, we are going to make a shorter code, but it is a bit
more complex.
OK, so make sure you are comfortable with the previous one first.
This is kind of to some extent might be a bit harder for you.
There is something in programming.
We call it a direction array,
this isn't about syntax,
it is just semantic idea.
The idea is following: in the last
code we tried three positions,
we tried the left and we tried the bottom,
and we tried the diagonal.
OK, thinking about the shift that happened from 'i' and 'j', this actually we either added (1, 0) here
or (0, 1) to get that one or added (1, 1).
But the code was very, very complicated.
So what..., the idea of the direction array is as following, you are to come and build two simple arrays
like the 'di' and 'dj', and start to put these shiftings that happen here.
So (1, 0) corresponds here for the first shift, (0, 1) correspond to the second shift, and (1, 1)
to the third shift.
Once you did that, your code here don't need to, doesn't need to give attention to the idea of right
and left.
We already coded the right and left here in the direction.
Once we are here, we iterate on the three directions, get the new direction, which is 'i' +
'di' and 'j' +.'dj'
OK, so specifically let's say that 'i' and 'j' at (0, 0) and you are taking the direction of zero.
So we say 'i + di[0]' which is 1, and 'j + dj[0]', which is zero.
So the 'i + 1' and 'j + 0'.
Now we have the next position which is lef here, but we don't care.
And then we are saying if this is valid position or not, if it is valid we say: do we have a previous
good value or not? if we don't have just take this one, if we have to make sure it's good.
So it's the same logic actually that we did before.
But this time we get rid of the, a lot of if-conditions that we were putting and just maintaining it in
this nice direction array.
Direction array make the code much more elegant to iterate on the neighbors, flattening an array.
Remember we discussed before the flatting array.
We say that this array can be flat in this way.
And I asked you to figure out an equation to move from 2D position, to 1D position.
So here is the idea.
Let's say that you would like to know or like position (1, 2) in a 3x4 matrix.
Where is it converted?
The idea is that the equation is i * number of columns.
+ j. Take a moment to try to think about it.
Here is what happens, if you are in row one.
It means that there is a complete column that we are done with it, which has 'cols' as number of the
columns.
So we will multiply i * number of columns.
We actually take the whole columns that we have so far and then we.
Just add the current j, so if we are at (1, 2), we take the first row for values and add
the current two values.
Another example if you are here, then we know that we can multiply 2 * 4 to get these eight
values and then just add this current position to here, this how we can easily convert from 'i' and 'j'
to some position. The one that is more tricky is the reverse,
if you have 1D and you would like to convert it to a position i and j, OK, the way to do it is mainly that
the position i is going to be the index is divided by the column, and the index j mod column.
So division and mod with column get the answer, for example, if we are at an index of 6, 6
divided by 4 in integer division is 1, and 6 mod 4 is 2.
But the question? is why such a formula? let's remember the math.
We know that from this equation that the position index is actually 'i * columns + j' when you
start to divide by columns, here is what happen i *
columns divided by columns is just 'i', 'j' divided by columns.
We know that 'j' is less than columns.
So this is actually is going to be 0; so end up with 'i', on the other side if we take the modulus.
When you take the modulus on this equation, 'i' modulus columns is going to be 0, 'j'
'j' modulus column is going to be 'j', because again 'j' is less than columns.
This how we can get the i and j position.
That's it.