The first homework set for multidimensional arrays, in the first one would like to compare two rows you
will start to by reading N&M for number of rows  and columns, three and four, three rows, four
columns.
Then you will read the matrix of N times M values here, three rows, four columns.
Then you will read number Q three here for Q queries.
Each query is two integers like one-two, two-three, one-three, the first and second row indices
but 1-based.
So one and two is row number one,
two is row number two, two and three is row number one
row number three, one and three is rule number one,
row number three, they are one-based indices for the first and the second row you will print
Yes
If all of the values of the first row are less than the all of the values in the, less than the second
row in a corresponding way.
For example, here, the first row one and two,
so this rule and this rule. Is eight less than three?
No, then we don't need to compare anyone.
We are done, now
second row and third row is three less than fourteen? yes.
Fifteen less than twenty five? yes.
Twenty-seven, less than twenty-nine? Yes. six is less than ten? Yes.
So for all of the row values, we are less than the corresponding one,
so the answer is yes.
the last one is one and three,
so the first and third row, eight.
less than fourteen?
Yes. sixteen
less than twenty five?
Yes.
Nine less than twenty nine?
Twenty five
Less than ten?
No.
So the answer is no.
In the second the problem will read an integer N and then read square matrix of N times N so
three then read three times three values.
You will print two values, the sum of the other triangular matrix and the sum of the lower triangular
matrix.
The upper triangular matrix is defined at this summation.
it covers all the
diagonal and all of the values above the diagonal and the lower triangular covers the diagonal and
all of the values covering the diagonal.
This example doesn't match this example here.
So in our example here, if we'd like to find the upper one,
so we should sum eight and fifteen and twenty nine and nine and eight and 15 and
twenty nine and then sixteen and twenty seven and the nine will give us the upper one, for the lower
one,
it would be the eight and fifteen and twenty-one and twenty-nine and the thirteen and the twenty-five
and the fourteen,
this is the lower one value.
The printing is mainly printing the lower then the upper, the upper and lower.
In the third problem, you will read again, N Matrix times M and you will compute another
array that is a transpose of it,
so you read this matrix here and transpose it.
The transpose is a switch from a row to a column,
for example, observer one, two, three, five,
in the new matrix, it becomes one, two, three, five. Six, seven, eight, nine,
the second row is the second column, third row in the third column fourth row the forth column.
So if the input matrix is four times five, the output matrix should be five times four.
So read this matrix number one, create this matrix number two, or make use of some matrix and do the
transpose operation.
That's all.