Let's see how to solve the easy part of the homework for the first problem "Smaller row".
I think this is very straightforward.
You need to create an array.
I wasn't clear about the N & M here in the problem.
Let's say, like we are like less than one hundred.
We just need to create the array here and then just read it. You don't  need to initialize it here
immediately because you are going to read it directly.
You don't need to put your equal zero and then initialize all of it, which is going to take some time.
You just are going to read it right now.
And after that, for every query, we can just like computed by ourselves, for example, iterate on all
of the number of columns and then compare the target first row with the target second row at this column.
And check if anything is wrong or not, if all of them are smaller than we are perfect enough, print it, otherwise,
just "NO".
In the second problem, we would like to
read a Matrix and verify Square Matrix. Square means the number of rows like number
of columns and check only the lower and triangular part of the Matrix.
Again, the solution should be straightforward here.
We would like to read and compare.
Now, there is one trick here.
The trick is we don't actually need to read a matrix as a matrix and compute the values.
And this is something that you need to take into consideration.
Do I really need to save the data, then process it or I can process on the fly?
On the fly means while I am reading, I can get the answer. Observer here,
if I am reading, I can figure out exactly if I'm in the diagonal or I am in the left part or in the
lower part or upper part.
So to do that, we are going to iterate on the Matrix, have our upper and lower variables, and while
reading we are going to check.
If we are satisfying this condition, then we are at the lower, otherwise, we are at the upper.
We are using the equal here because the equal is helping us with the diagonal value itself.
So this is mainly a nice trick to memory.
And that's why we do need to determine the value.
But let's also make it clear for guys here.
In the third problem, we would like to make a very, very common problem in computer science, which is
Transpose. Transpose just means to flip the matrix like rotating it 90 degrees.
To do that, we again need to just prepare the first array and the second array,
and then read the first one,
and then in the second one, while you are reading you just all what you need is to assign the value
"i" & "j" to the values "j" & "i".
Do I need to really iterate again 2 loops instead of making this one?
No.
Can I make it without having to create a array 1 even?
Yes.
So you'll have here the "i" & "j" position, you can read it as a value and then directly in array2 of "j" & "i"
put the value. So, read "i" & "j" and go directly and put it in "j" & "i". This way while reading a raw,
we are putting it in a column in the same time without the need to create even this first array.
But anyway, for simplicity. That's all.