The second homework set, in problem number one, we will read a matrix N times M and Q for
Q queries.
Each query is four values two indices I and G zero-based and number of rows and number of columns.
These four values actually representing a sub-matrix with (i.j) are the top left of it and  then (r ,c) are the numbers of rows
and columns starting from this (i, g) for each query we would like to print how many prime numbers in the
requested grid or in the requested sub-matrix,
each query should be answered using only nested loops and maximum not more so don't make more than
two nested loops
per a query.
per a query. In the future, with some smart competition, you will learn how to do that even without
any nested loops in the queering part itself, in computer vision filed we call that image integral.
But this is just feature information for you.
Let's see an example, here
we read The Matrix three times four, three row, four columns,
then in the first query, we add starting position, row number one, column number zero,
so this is row number one, column number zero, and two-two matrix, which is now covering this matrix
three, two, seven, eight.
The number of primes here are three, which are the three and two and seven,
eight is a prime number in a very similar way,
zero one, two, three,
there are three primes, the two and the five and two, even the duplication are considered.
So this is mainly what you need to do, in every query
you should only make two nested loops maximum to answer the query.
If this is a hard constraint for you, skip it for now. In the second problem would like to find mountains
in a matrix.
You will read a Matrix and you print all the positions that are mountain.
A mountain is a position that its value is greater than the eight neighbor values.
Code that in a smart way as we learned, for example, here you will notice that position (zero, zero)
is eight, eight is greater than six and two and three, which are the three valid neighbors for it,
so this is a mountain, position (1,2),
position (1,2),
is nine,
Nine is greater than one and six and two and six and four.
in the third problem, you have an active robot, we have a grid of N times M, and there is
a robot starting at position (0, 0),
you will read K commands,
Every command has two values.
The first one is a direction from one to four corresponding to up, right, down, and left.
And then you read a number of steps, which would be the number of steps the robot will take in
this direction.
The steps can be huge.
If the robot hits the wall, it just circulate in the Matrix. for every
command print where is the robot now.
So it is the input, we have a matrix of three, four dimensions and we have four commands,
the first command is two and one,
two means move to the right,
You see here, one is up.
Two is right.
Three is down, four is left.
So two is is right.
One step.
Three.
Two means what
three is down  two steps and so on.
And this is a position that you are printing.
Let's say you did this to make it easier for you,
the robot has a grid of three times before we start at position (zero, zero)
the command is to move right one step,
so the robot take right one step, then the robot take a command to move that down two steps,
so the robot from here will move one step, two step,
now we are here.
The robot now have a command of moving left two steps,
so this is one step left,
but there is a wall here so we circle it back and go to the beginning of the room,
so we end up here, then move up three steps, one step up, second step up,
we hit the wall again,
so circlet back in the column and come back here to this one.
I hope the visualization now make it easier for you.
You are to print the position where the robot ends with every command. In this problem
we will expand the flattening 2D array to 3D array, because I would like you to learn how to
think in something like 3D array in flattening
if you have to, you will read three numbers for the depth rows and columns, the dimensions of 3D array.
then read one integer,
it will be one of two cases,
if the integer value is one, it means we will convert 3D to 1D,
If the value is two, it means you will convert 1D to 3D.
If the input was one, you would be provided with three integers, the depth and R&C to convert them to 1D
position.
If it was two, you will read one integer position, convert it to three D
position. To make it easy for you,
here are the three for loops, depth, rows and columns for a grid three times four times five and printing
for you the index and the corresponding depth and row and column.
And here are a bunch of testcases,
for example, three, four, five with a conversion from 3D to 1D, you take three
inputs, the output should be twenty if you took twenty, the output should be one (0, 0) and so on.
Think about how to generalize the 2D  flattening array. That's all.