In the in the end of the second part of the Obbie, I would like again to make some summaries with some
notes that would be helpful to see the big picture.
Remember, we want to start with what is overtime and highlighted.
There are different concepts for it.
This is the core of the course here in the will.
But there are also to design things relevant to that, the principles of ALBE and that design.
There were several principles and some patterns that were embedded in the homework already for you.
These are the main concepts that you are now very familiar with them.
They are the fundamental ones of them.
We studied them, all of them, the first to four in the past one and the second to the greater operating
in Battuta to.
So going forward, like thinking about the big picture here is what will be the object and the classes
and the blah blah blah.
You can think of its relationship with other things.
For example, designing strategies.
The objects and classes play a role in this, in the obstruction of things and the separation of things.
Thinking about inheritance and the polymorphism and the zone better's they would allow us to make good
generalisations for the software, like we see how the polymorphism in the image editor would help us
to be very generic, for example.
And so from the perspective of software engineering schools, also, we see, for example, how the
polymorphism is allowing to have an extensible sense and we see how the objects and classes would allow
us to do some reusability and overall flexibility.
So this is part of the big picture that involved the object oriented with the strategies and the software
engineering goals that we would like to achieve.
We would like to highlight more about the reusability we would think usability, the IT to reduce something
that already exists, to avoid duplicating effort of coding and testing and all of that.
C++ or OBE in general has to do usability battens, then inheritance better and the composition better.
So competition is like CA has an engine and has four wheels and it has a relationship.
But inheritance is more of something is and something like a manager is an employee.
Decomposition, as we said, is more of like it has an ownership and it is like very strong relationship.
But aggregation return is a bit weaker relationship.
We can think an example of that would be like university is composed of a department and department
composed of aggregated of professors.
If a university got closed, the department must be closed.
This an indicator of a strong relationship, but of the department would closed.
The professors would remain professors.
This is an indicator of the aggregation relationship and we discussed it being consistent when it comes
to the multiplicity of the classes moving to the inheritance.
We have met many, many common, many, many, many formats for it.
And we mentioned inheritance.
The cool thing is to two classes with a better class would definitely have something in common and every
one of them would have something unique.
We highlighted how the dayman, the classes that here might be very problematic because class the secrecy
from two directions.
That's it.