Let's continue the summary.
These are the ships of inheritance, but here we would like to to focus on the problems of the inheritance.
One in one of the assignments we highlighted that sometimes we design our our inheritance hierarchy
looks while everything looks so good in the future in the class like we have here, a few classes that
armaments, all of them give us a Malcolm X and gives a live birth.
And so everything is OK.
And in the future, someone needed to add a new type of mammas.
But surprisingly, this one doesn't have this function as an applicable for it.
So if we just try to extend it from this hierarchy, it is going to support a function that shouldn't
exist, which is problematic.
So we have to be careful and we have to think in future if our to class is really aberrant for every
potential subclass or not.
We also know that sometimes everything looks OK.
However, it is buggie in another, like the rectangle class and square class.
This class is going to tell itself like I am.
A rectangle with two sides are equal so I can initiate a rectangle with width on right with same value.
And then everything would definitely be perfect.
Yes.
Then someone is creating a function that rectangle pointer as an object and he manipulate the with an
internal as you wish we would have what we call with a square pointer class object and the square pointer
class would be changed internally to be within equal height.
Now we broke the integrity of our square class, which is making this as a rule, inheritance relationship.
We also from the robot dog problem, we saw how how sometimes we end up with classes that involve a
lot of features, a lot of variables, a lot of functionality that that that aren't relevant to the
class like here.
When we made the robot, the robot, the robot dog, for example, the dog wasn't actually so it doesn't
go to tail.
So this wasn't a realistic one.
When it happens that you are doing a lot of inheritance, a lot of multiple inheritance, you might
end up with functionalities that doesn't belong to you.
We also have the the dam, and the problem is very problematic in terms of implementation, in terms
of accessing variables that doesn't belong to us.
So variables that are visible from different locations, they are all creating problems.
And we also saw how the how the inheritance laws might explode over time.
You start with initial Sunbus class and you would like to keep extending them with different features.
But every extension is like duplicating all the work that we have.
So the classes eventually.
And also we see how the inheritance in general is inflexible.
Inheritance is a design time, a choice you are cutting against some specific class.
You know, it's a productive members, it's public interface.
So you are coupled with this class.
What if we need more dynamic behavior during the runtime?
This is where we have to run away from the general multiple inheritance idea to something more of composition
and dependence on interfaces with polymorphism to have less cabling and less carbon system inheritance.
In practice, there are typically three types of programmers this who hated so much, this who avoid
it as much as possible.
But they have if they are using it, they have strong justification for that.
And this will go to study the basics.
I mean, here that this who didn't give time to be very good in the basics like programming and object
oriented.
They are aware of the problems.
They just learn some stuff and would like to jump on learning, say, Android or OS or Web development
without really understanding a lot of code issues in the basics.
Here are some tips.
Berfield Composition over inheritance.
We will come back to this point later.
Be aware of inheritance problem that we just described today.
Remember, the Berretta class should be super class for all elements of class.
Try to think it over in the future.
Do not just do inheritance to reduce some available code.
Don't do that.
There have to be strong justification for using inheritance before extending a class.
Doublecheck is this class.
Looks like it was designed to be extensible.
It was designed to be inherited or not.
If not, do not go with that.
That said.