Let's continue the summary in C++.
There are different types of polymorphism, the compiler and the runtime polymorphism where we started
learning programming, we knew about the function of loading, which is a combined time polymorphism.
So remember the word polymorphism.
I mean, there are many forms.
If you are overloading 10 functions, then the functions, they add Hastin different forms.
So this is polymorphism.
What's cambio time?
Because everything is well known.
Later in the course we took two types of polymorphism, the operator overloading, which again another
combined time polymorphism.
But we also take the virtual function, which is allowing the runtime polymorphism where things are
more deterministic.
During the run, it would be the system itself.
We discussed that if you have a reference and pointer drives the object, there are two cases.
If there is a virtual function, then the code is going to be to the actual derived objects, what we
call dynamic binding, which means that the actual binding to this object would be determined in the
in the real time itself.
Like remember the process chip function, it's taking shape.
It's branding its area.
It has no idea what what is this shape?
If a function is declared, which one any any function of it overwriting it will be virtual, even if
you didn't put the key word virtual on the other side, if you boost your function as an inversion,
you wouldn't put the visual key where the call will have been based on that use the pointer type, which
is a combined fire and a static binding case.
And this is to be very careful from it in the pure visual function we are actually we have in complete
case so the class isn't completed.
There are some basic functions.
We cannot create object of this class and of any object that doesn't have a complete definition and
declaration for all of its use.
The function, you cannot base a parameter to a function of time object that has your visual function
unless it's a pointer.
So pointer is OK.
Reference is OK, pointer is OK references.
OK, I think reference is OK to but you cannot just object to have a class that is abstract.
You have to at least one plus very pure visual function.
Logically, you shouldn't call your visual function from it's a constructor because it isn't.
It isn't.
This is undefined.
The.
Go to the bottom of myself, remember, polymorphism goal is to allow genetic code, so this is actually
the core of it, like the ED case when it comes to the ships, for example, in the future, you can
add more objects and classes, more classes with with really minimal code changes.
So we're here to help us to build what we call loosely coupled systems with systems where we have much
less dependency between classes.
Sometimes we have to do the casting, but double check for us.
Did you have a good design?
Is it OK to have this if they are typically healthy?
So maybe you can do it in a better way.
If you are confident about their own casting, you can go that course, which is cost.
But if you aren't sure and this is a case typically, then you better go with the remix and double check
the returning pointer, is it?
No.
Try to work much more with interfaces.
This is a Carracher in the Java programming language and it is very healthy Majelis with abstract classes
and much, much less with the multiple inheritance.
Remember that inheritance by itself is very problematic.
The more you go toward interfaces and much of the strawberries you are going to face sometimes will
provide interface for others to use.
Think of some infrastructure component that we are giving some interface for others to use.
So there are hundreds of projects.
We are using our interface and you just decided to break it.
You are causing a severe issue to others.
Think all over backward compatibility.
You need your class or interface after updating.
Still allow the previous functionalities, try to provide the minimal public interface.
The less you provide, the better for the consumers.
Remember that this is more and do not provide some of your common functionality.
Your brain functions interface is all about the common things.
Avoid anything that is irrelevant or hard to get.
Make sure that the functions are very expressive.
So the behavior expected from a function is as expected.
If you have a function of its name, add it.
You can do some subtraction.
Try to think from the client perspective.
What does he really need?
We also discussed about interfaces as interfaces, as probabilities, like I can have interface that,
for example, is despicable and I mean by that you can see this to the disk and load it to the disk.
This provide us with very powerful view to create powerful interfaces and relationships.
Remember, if you if some cross is visible from a different direction, more than a direction, then
add the keyboard.
Vishwa that's it.