Let's continue this summary so visual functions cannot be global, cannot be static and a different
function.
Think about the logic behind that.
Remember, the visual tables are more or less just an extra pointer that is found in your base class,
inherited by others.
Then we have one table per class and the number of rows is in this table equal to the number of visual
functions that should be available to class.
And all of that is eventually computed in the individual time.
Remember, one week when we combine, we definitely know all the classes and the relationships.
So from one perspective, we might think it's about runtime then how in comparison time when all of
that.
Yes, because combinat eventually can can resolve which which visual function will be called based on
a specific object.
The inheritance hierarchy eventually is well known, but beyond that the, the function, the behavior
in runtime is going to be, it's going to be different
if we are conducting eyes like you are conducting save for money by means of contacting airlines eyes.
The eyes have their own structures.
Do not depend on them directly.
User interfaces and obstructer classes do maybe like, for example, Rahab these classes or design your
own classes to implement something that implemented them and so on.
So the point here do not depend on something external like that, otherwise would preclude a change.
You will take a lot of time to change in your.
Also, like many framework's you, the invasion of control, where your function or cross would be just
cold by itself in a very specific point of time.
So instead of you are calling a function like you do in the library, actually, if someone is trying
to call you and we show that this person can play a role in helping.
That was highlighted.
The difference between templates and bullimore fit in templates.
The behavior doesn't depend on like a stack of integer is acting like a stack of string is acting like
a stack of employees.
So the type doesn't play a role here.
We know that this is more of templates, but in polymorphism, the behavior of rectangle is different
than the behavior of sheep.
Coupling and cohesion, we mentioned the word decoupling allowed the word decoupling refers to the number
of connections that are between different classes.
Cohesion is something that refers to within a class.
So to a degree, there are relationship between.
And so the class itself, the more that the class has connections internally, then the more the more
integrity between the items in this class.
And other words, the items in this class are really relevant and depend on each other.
So what we are actually talking is we would like the cohesion to be very high, which means that the
class has really relevant items that have some relevant to be and would like the coupling between the
different classes or modules to be minimized, because these dependencies give us half the time when
it comes to changing the code.
Far from that, users must depend on its public needs.
The public interface, but a class shouldn't depend on its users.
So when you are when you are building some class, you don't you never try to implement it, such as
it knows who is calling it and how is calling it and all of that.
You are more independent than others.
Capability, data and behavior in one place.
The more you do that, the better cohesion that you will have.
And remember, every class should have it like a single responsibility should.
It should have a single reason to change.
So while we are trying to gather relevant things in one place, but don't don't end up with having a
lot of logic in one in one class, probably you need to separate them in different classes as much as
you could try to depend on interfaces, not on the classes itself.
This reduces allow the coupling.
You can make a lot of the changes in the future with less impact on this division.
This is as a diagram to to ensure the public and cohesion look to these two different goods.
So first of all, try to evaluate the the cohesion this class seems has very good internal connections,
dependencies.
These are like variables and functions.
One, two, three, four, five.
And this one has also and from the other time, it seems that there is some connection between this
and this item on this item.
There are a couple of connections here.
One connection here.
This looks like a local cabling system.
This is good.
But here, when you look to that system, you will notice here, for example, the one, two, three.
They have nothing in connection.
So why they are gathered in one class.
This is wrong.
And also, we you look to the cabling.
All of the classes have a lot of connections together.
So this is, again, probably drawing the relationship between your class diagram items would help you
to realize that this is bad and bad modularization for your system.
We also highlighted before the intention behind your messages, when you provide an inversion function,
you are telling others that you are going you please do not override this function, but if you make
it a virtual function, you are telling him we have some default implementation.
But you are you are expected to implement your wants and in polymorphism set up, it will be use if
it's a virtual function or giving a message that we have no idea how to implement this function.
Or maybe, OK, this is just an interface to just who are telling you what is our public functionalities.
Back to the conversation over inheritance, so we highlighted more than once in industry at the moment,
it's very common that if you can go with wood composition, then you go with it.
So to make the composition look be more effective.
We typically use it with interfaces so that it'd be more dynamic and it avoids us all of the trouble.
So from one direction, the composition would get us for the like the combination that have an inheritance
and the interfaces would help us in reducing the advantages.
Now it is an important thing.
You might find it hard to, in most of the cases when you try to switch inheritance to composition and
it is again designed better and could help us from this perspective.
When you when you studied more about design patterns, you will notice nice ways to to make some some
composition effort.
So this is a good idea.
But remember, the composition would require two types of extra code and extra good to do more delegation
of the functions and codes and also an extra code to create instances of your of your different interfaces.
Objects that it.