Let's continue this.
This one is focusing in on the brutal flooding, we can divide the operators to three categories.
This operators that can be overloaded either as members function or no person.
This they can only be overloaded as member functions only.
We experience that.
And some of it cannot be overloaded at all like this.
Once we do here thinking which one to use the member function or the number function.
At this moment, you should realize that the member functions need an object on the left to make a call
to the operator function.
So this is a general is very limited.
But when we came to the number that functions, we noticed that it allowed much more use cases and we
can make them function to make them like a bit faster.
There is also some point of view here that this is more of improving encapsulation.
This is an optional reading.
So which way to go?
There is nothing specific for some people.
They just do as much as possible non-member functions for others.
They define it like what can be defined as member function.
They define it as member function and what can be defined as being functionally defined as no functions.
I'm not sure of like what approach is really better than another.
I feel nothing specific in terms of will be.
You would notice that the operator overloading not only allowed our code to looks beautiful, but also
it allowed the sense of extensibility.
Remember, for example, that we managed to do this to see any statement for new objects we have like
the cluster vectors.
I can I can override it to allow for me, for example, the concatenation between two vectors.
So in terms of what will be, it allows extensibility.
Remember about the operator overloading that the originally the order of evaluation isn't specified.
For example, if we have here three function calls, if one, if two or three, four, why do you think
it is intuitive that if one will be called first, if we do first, if a three, a third and then they
will be added.
But this isn't true in C++.
They would be they would be evaluated in different orders.
We highlighted that before in the order of evaluation before.
So what's important here is that when even you overload your operators again, it's just the same rule.
You don't know which operator to be which brand will be evaluated first.
I also highlighted before that the sensitivity C++ 17, the extraction operator here, became Left-to-right.
So this is a good one.
You now know that if one would be called and if it wouldn't be for the 17th, it was like that addition.
It might be if it was first F one for a second, then they are printed indexable order.
Restrict yourself to two operators and in using them in a way that has similar meaning, like the original
operators, for example, if you are using operator like addition to some logic that is close to subtraction.
OK, so make it very intuitive for others.
Like if I'm seeing you are providing me with some operator that I know without checking the documentation,
how does it work?
And also try to make sure there is a sensor behind using operator overloading like thinking about the
blast strings for communication, the subscript and vectors like extend like an array.
So it makes sense.
This is a good scenario.
Be aware of the briskness rules.
We had that in one of the homework.
If you have one plus two to the word for in math, two to the four evaluated first, but an operator
overloading the plus has her order.
So one plus two is embedded at first.
Now the math here is wrong, so be careful from such an operator.
I would say these are bunch of the typical expected operators here.
Be very careful from such operators.
They are a bit risky and even many others.
So this ones are probably one of the best operators to remember.
So retrograding burden comes with you, with the like with GreenPower, but now you have great responsibility
to double check what you are doing.
Exactly with your operator's thinking about line of code like I times equal to sink for a minute.
What does this mean.
OK, it just looks like we have a variable multiplied by two and that's it in C++, things now get more
complicated.
It could be the fact is that two would be converted to an object.
And now the Times is operator overloading times two.
So why do you think for a while?
Oh, just like a simple multiplication.
No, it isn't.
It could be like this is converted to object.
This is a greater value.
This means when even you see such a very simple line with some operator, you have to investigate more
digital types.
The conversions and so on.
So it might be more good.
Tracing and debugging does not make like people like Father.
You might think Olesya, for example, been to the constructor then.
No one is now thinking that the data is going to be converted to something and so on.
There are some cases where the ability to make a lot of sense, especially the math classes, big integer
fraction complex, something like mathematics and vector and so on the rise of linear algebra, I use
a lot of the very troubleshooting.
As we said before, the operator overloading is just another compile time, but you can overload the
operator plus in several ways.
For example, to do something we can say operator overloading has really two two goals, extensibility,
as we saw.
And also it you're reading the code is much easier and easier classes, much easier if you have a bunch
of matrices and you said Matrix eight plus B plus three times the this is very simple line of code in
troubleshooting the is the associativity.
The Arrietty cannot be changed, the default ones are used.
Arrietty refers to the number of hours like some overruns are binary.
You cannot use them as generate.
Some overruns are just unary.
You can use them as binary.
And so relevant to that.
Remember, if you created a pointer provided structure copy constructor and operator assignment.
This is a reading gives you for one side note.
Some language doesn't provide even greater value like Java.
That's why we don't think operator overloading like at all be concept.
It's more of a feature that exists in some programming language.
That's it.