In this video, you will start to know about the binary and unary operators. We already saw the arithmetic
operators, like the ('+', '-', '*', '/' and '%').
Arithmetic refers to properties on numbers, like when I add it. The word operator is just a symbol,
So the symbols for the arithmetic are like the '+' and '-' and so on.
Thinking about this expression (x+2*y-1), we call it in C++ expression. An expression can be
even as simple as just as a number, the ('+', '*', '-') here are operators, (x, 2, y, 1) we call them
operands.
So an operator needs operands, the asterisk here has two operands, the (2 and y), the plus here has two operands, the
(x) and the result of (2*y). This is a normal flow.
when we think about the evaluation of this expression, in math,
normal math,
we know that the multiplication and division are applied first, so we multiply those two numbers first,
then we start from left to right.
Add (x) to the result of (2 * y), and then (2 - 1).
The parenthesis is an extra thing in programming to enforce order.
If you would like (x+y) to be added first, then we need to put two braces here.
Otherwise though, I (y) be dividing over 3 first.
There are two operands that are used here for this operator.
So the (x+y) need X and Y,
you need to two. the word binary always means
two.
So we call it also binary operator because it needs two operands.
Another interesting, the operators are the minus and the not. The minus
helps us to switch a number from positive to negative.
So (6) would be (-6), (-6) would be (6) here.
So if we have (x=6), we say (y = -x),
it switches the sign of the number.
The other one is the NOT operator '!'.
The NOT operator switches the true to false, and the false to true, the zero to one and one to zero.
So if we have here (male=true), (!male) will make it false.
If you have not zero (!0) it will be one and not one (!1) would be zero.
The NOT operator is part of something called logical operators.
We will know more about them later.
Officially you can say it's (logical not or negation operator), but we pronounce it just NOT X.
So one of them changes the sign and the other one changes of the Boolean status.
How many operands here?
Just one.
So we call it a unary operator.
Unary for one operand, binary for two operands.
Interestingly here, the minus operator,
we once used it with two operands, so it was binary operator and here was one operand only,
So it is a unary operator.
So it has two scenarios.
That's it! :)