Before discussing the logical operator in the next video, it might worth to discuss first something in computer
science named as Truth Table.
This is something that you typically learn first in something like a discrete course.
And it's very intuitive, the first thing is something called the And operator '^'.
OK, let's say that I am 30 years old and my salary is 7000 and my weight is 120
kg.
If I told you that is Mostafa greater than 25 and his salary is less than 8000, you say
this is true.
If I told you is his
Age is greater than 27 and salary greater than 9000, you know that this is false, because Mostafa's salary
is just 7000.
So this is false information, but about 35 years and salary is less than 8500.
This is, again, false because this information is wrong.
And what about if Mostafa is greater than 35 and salary is greater than 9000?
This is false because the two conditions are false.
So now here in the logic of the word "AND" that we even use in our daily usage, we know that it will
not be really true unless both of them are true.
OK, in discrete we write it this way.
So we are now discussing programming or discussing basic logic. in the case of using the word
'And', we need both conditions to be true.
What about the "OR" case?
If I say is Mostafa greater than 25 or salary less than 8000, this is true because the
two conditions are true. is Mostafa greater than 27 years or salary greater than 9000.
This is true because I satisfied this condition.
And same here, I will be true because I satisfy this condition.
What about is Mostafa greater than 35 or salary greater than 9000?
This is false, because the two conditions are false.
So this is, again, from our daily semantic.
So, when we use the word "or", we actually need at least one that is true.
In other words, the answer would be false if both of them would be false.
So this is how we differentiate between the "AND" and between the "OR". this table is what we call the logical table.
It's kind of a summary to what we were saying. in the "AND" case,
if this condition is true, like greater than 25 years old and this condition
is true, then overall is true. if there is one missing condition,
In the end it ends up with false.
The "OR" case's is different.
If anyone is true, then it can be true.
Otherwise, if both of them are false,
It can be false.
The reverse of true is false.
The not of false is true.
This is the the the not operator that we know.
So now this is the AND table and the OR table for the two cases that we were just learning in the previous
slides.
Please make sure that you understand very carefully that, and you know what I mainly saied.
there is one case here to be true only. there is one case here to be false only.
So make sure that you understand it.
Now, let's expand it for three variables, OK, in a very similar way.
In the AND case, there will be only one case
that's true, when all of them are true.
OK, one here for true.
Otherwise we have all of them false.
In the OR case, there is only one case that is zero or false when all of them are false, otherwise
all of them are true.
So this is clearly the difference between the AND and OR. so the AND and OR Truth Tables are corresponding
to our human logic when it comes also to the AND and the OR. if you are applying to the college and I'm
putting for you conditions about your family income, your current age, your current weight
or something like that. I'm putting some conditions for you and telling you, are
you satisfying all of them or are you satisfying one of them.
This is like our normal logic.
And here is some example about what we're saying, but more than three variables, so is Mustafa
greater than 25 and salary less than 8000 and weight is less than 150 kg.
To make it simpler for yourself, start with simplifying to true and false.
Is Mostafa greater than 25,
True.
And salary less than 8000, true.
And weight less than 150KG),                                                                                                                                                   true.
We have ANDs, we know in AND we need all of them to be true.
So all of them true ?
Yes, then true.
Now here's another condition we simplified it to
True, true, true.
then also true. in here we have a simplified to true, true, false.
This is going to be false because we need all of them to be true. here,
false or true or false.
This is now the OR we need one of them to be true,
to be true.
So this is true.
So the answer is true. false OR false OR
False,
All of them are false.
And in our case, then it would be false.
So what if we have a mix of AND and OR, how do we as humans do it?
But let's say I said Mostafa greater than 35 or salary greater than 6000 or weight is greater than...this the previous
case, false or true or false,
This is true.
But now what about that false AND true OR false?
We as humans mainly we try to group first the ANDs together.
So it ends up like you are thinking is Mostafa greater than 35 years and salary greater than 6000? or his
weight is greater than 200 kg.
We then think about this condition first.
So we take this false AND true, and solve it first.
False AND true is false.
OK, false AND true is false.
Now we remove false AND true, and replace it with false.
So false OR false is false.
Another case, let's say, for this expression, we simplified it to true AND true AND true
OR false.
Then we solve the ANDs group first.
So this is like a priority. true AND true AND true,
we solve it to true. true OR false,
we solve it to true.
So this is how we simplify a big expression.
So in summary, if all conditions are ANDed, then it would be true,
If all of them are true. if all conditions are ORed, it would be true if any one of them true; false
if all of them are false.
If you have a mix, of ORs and ANDs, find each subgroup of ANDs, evaluate it first, then do
the normal ORing for the remaining.
Please make sure that you are comfortable with today's session before the next lesson.
That's it.