The logical operators are all about the truth table, but just we put in C++, that's it.
So in C++, we use these two symbols "&&" for the AND and these two symbols "||" for the OR, call it like AND AND
OR OR, and as we know that the AND is before the OR so the precedence of && is before the ||.
So, same concepts,
but just now in C++, and remember that the parentheses help us to force some order.
So now here, in the same logic if age is 30 and salary is 7000 and then we say here result = (age
> 25)
&& (salary < 8000)
So this condition is evaluated first to true, this condition is evaluated to true, true && true
is just true. in a very similar way,
this is another condition, this is another condition, This  is another condition that just evaluated.
In the third evaluation we say (age > 35)
this is false,
(Salary < 8500)
This is true.
So false || true
is true.
In the same way, we can mix operators together, but now be careful from the parentheses and their order.
So here, for example, we have one big parentheses,
It doesn't affect us.
And then we have three separate expressions, start to evaluate them,
It would be like this one is true,
This one is true,
True,
&& true && true is just true. Here,
in this one, you can find that the (weight > 200) is false.
So it's like now say true, true, false.
True and true and false,
It would be false and so on.
We can just normally solve them like we did the last time.
as we said, the parentheses force order.
So here, we have this expression that gives something.
But in the second expression, we are giving more priority to
To which parts? I feel there is a missing..
Oh, no, nothing missing. Here,
we have one parentheses here and one parentheses here,
So, this sub-expression is going to be evaluated first, OK, before ANDing here.
But this one is going to evaluate
This one, this one and then this one.
So these two will be evaluated first,
Then we apply them with the OR.
But in our case here, these two will be evaluated first and then ANDed.
Why? because parentheses force more order.
So in the default the case AND is applied first.
But if there are parentheses, they force a specific order first.
This is one big expression,
We can simplify it as we did before,
Nothing fancy.
You start with the sum and group and start to resolve it.
For example, you take this, first, take a minute to try to solve it by yourself, you should
be able to do that. We first can take this (T && T), resolve it to T, so we remove it, now it's T.
We can now take this parenthesis (false || T), simplify it to true.
So it's now here.
Here true.
There are no more ANDs now.
So we are done with parentheses simplifications.
Now we just go in the normal case, take a group of ANDs so (T && T && T),
This is just T, so it ends up with T || T, which is just T.
There is one interesting concept in C++ called the "short-circuit" evaluation.
The short circuit evolution is all about stopping, evaluating an expression when you could.
This is for more efficiency.
For example, let's say we are simplifying this expression and we are saying true or bla bla bla bla
bla bla bla.
Let me tell you something,
Can you guess the answer here before computing this result?
The answer is definitely yes, it is going to be true.
Why?
Because if the first item is true or something, then even if all of that ended up with false, it is
true or false.
So it's going to be true.
Definitely true.
In C++, once it figured out that we know the answer, it's going to skip what it can skip.
here is another case,
Let's say that we have here true && true && false && something, now
thinking about that, if it's true and true and false, then this is now false, false && whatever
is going to be false.
So in C++, we will do short circuit and we will stop early.
So in complex expression, what happens is C++,
the compiler will discard as much as it could, okay? it might discard some part of an expression, but
still continue in the overall logic.
So the idea is discard what can be discarded.
Let's give some example for that. Here in C++,
Why short circuit could be tricky? because of the side effects
also. here is an example.
If you see this expression here, X < 100 but here X += 50.
As this expression has a side effect, we need to be very careful, in a short circuit evolution
This condition might not be applied and this would be the case here.
X is 10 and we say X < 100, OK, which is true or something, now it is true or something
C++ would stop.
So this expression will not be evaluated.
So the side effect would not happen. In the same way
Here, we say X == 20 && something, once C++ figured out that this is false &&
something it will not continue here, it will not do that. a third case here we say like X == 20
&&
OK, so now when you think about it, this is now is false.
let me think for a while.
Yeah, OK, here in this case, this is a tricky case, so be careful from that X == 20,
So this is false &&, so it's like true && something.
Now, C++ would discard this part, the ++(x) > 50, not 10 here.
OK, so now watch out.
C++ will go and evaluate this sub-expression.
So what C++ will discard only
Here is this sub-expression.
Why?
Because using logic we can simply discard this one.
So be careful,
It isn't like it stops at some point and doesn't evaluate anything else,
It simply discards what can be discarded.
So this part here can be discarded
First, ok. In all of these expressions, X is still 10.
This is the first expression, that starts to change 10.
Here we say x == 10.
This is true.
True
&& something, we should still keep going in evaluating.
So here it's say ++X > 50.
This is true, this is true.
No, this is a false expression.
OK, OR x > 0, because this is false
this is going to be evaluated.
And after this guy.
Yeah.
This will be false.
So this one will be evaluated.
But the point here that this ++X now affects the variable.
So the moral of that is this is discarded,
Variable isn't changed. discarded, variable isn't changed
This is discarded, but this still is evaluated and so on.
Some coding mistakes do not put space between less than and equal.
Some guys will might try just (&)
This is another operator "bitwise".
We'll discuss it later.
It should be &&.
It should be || not just |.
One of the more tricky ones is writing = not == in the relational operators.
So it should be ==. to not put space between the result and the result.
Also here like "cout<< X < 5", C++ will complain, please put parentheses to make it easier for it to
compile.
Also imbalanced expressions like here, you open the parentheses and another parentheses, you close this one,
but you forgot to close this one.
So the C++ compiler is complaining, um, the precedence,
It's a good moment to see the big picture one more time.
Remember, the precedence is about the order.
Associativity is about left to
right. we now
saw a lot of operators.
So good to see all of them together.
This is in order group by group for the priorities.
We already know about that at the moment.
For example, the assignment operator is the lowest in order.
The unary operators are the highest. associativity,
As you see, all of them are left-to-right in C++ except two groups here.
The assignment operator is right-to-left.
The prefix operator, OK, is also right-to-left
Yeah, that's it.