For the homework of the logical operators, the first step is to guess the output of all of this program.
and then run it and make a comparison, in the second step, you are to creating a line of code for all
of these cases.
Assume, go ahead and read 3 integers, one for the number of boys, number of girls and number of teachers
in some classroom.
Then for every one of them, I would like you to figure out how to write a code that expresses it.
So this is more about converting logic to code.
So you say, for example, number of boys greater than 25, do an statement for that.
So every statement read it and decide the statement for it here we say, for example, the difference between
number of boys, and number of girls is more than 10 or number of teachers is greater than 5 and so
on.
So read every line and create a line of code for it, the final thing is a simplification.
Take every line of these guys and simplify it by hand, step by step and tell if they are true
or false.
Then you optionally write a line of code to verify if your simplification is correct or not.
That's it.