Let's solve the second homework here about the logical, let's first start with the tracing one.
I committed the first few ones they are direct ones, just direct comparison of the same thing
of one item, but here things might get a bit more complicated.
Remember the and operator what we call the && or whatever you say it, has a higher
priority.
So here the expression is a greater than five and d is less than 30 or C minus b equal 10.
Now we need to verify, we need to finish the and
part first.
So is a greater than five.
Greater than five.
Yes.
And d less than 30.
d less than 30? 40 less than 30? False.
So the first part here is false.
And as this is OR expression, we have to keep going, C minus b equal, equal 10, 20 minus 10 is
ten.
Yes.
So the first expression will be true here.
The second one, is A less B and B less than or equal c and c less than or equal c? In python
this expression can be written in a nicer way, but it's anyway just a chain of comparison.
So 10 <= 20? Yes. 2o <= 30? Yes. 30 <= 40? Yes.
So this is true.
After that this expression, a > 5? True. d  d?
30 > 40? False, or d % 2 == 0? 40 % 2 == 0? True.
Finally found something that makes all of this expression true.
So we have three old terms.
The last one of them is true.
We will have true.
In the expression after it, we changed this OR to AND, and we know that this is false and this is false.
And now c > d is false.
And this is && so we don't need to continue here.
This expression also is false.
So we have false or false overall is false.
The last two expressions, we have a == 10, this is true or something, do we care?
We shouldn't care.
So the answer must be true anyway.
this is a shortcut or short-circuit evaluation.
Observer here, if we are going to continue that, this expression here have to be done first, like
the b != 20 and c != 30, it have to be done together. In the next one,
We have parentheses for this first two items together.
This now is going to give them priority.
We have to finish this expression first, then take it ANDed with this expression.
a == 10? this is true.
We don't need to evaluate this part now.
So this is all is true.
True and the C != 30, this is false.
So now this all expression is false.
We have to keep going.
d != 40, this is false too, so this whole expression have to be false.
In the second homework, we have to create some functions matching the requested logic, the importance
of this assignment is, in industry customer doesn't tell us codes, the customer give us
a statement.
You might hear something like we need the number of boys to verify more than 10 students
and so on.
Customers give us expressions like that.
They give us a problem statement, a requirement, so we should be able to transfer requirements
to a written document.
The first expressions are easy.
We need to verify the number of boys greater than twenty five.
So this is can be done here.
Number of girls is less than 30.
Number of girls is less than or equal 30.
We have here OR condition, number of boys greater than twenty and the total is
greater.
I forgot what is empty. number of teachers, number of teachers is greater than two.
So this is OK so far.
And we just translate it here, as you see, very direct, just the AND is AND and the OR is OR.
Now, either nb < 60 OR something, so either OR is  just an OR expression.
This one might be a little more tricky.
You would like to verify that this condition isn't satisfied and that this condition isn't satisfied.
So this is how we think about it.
We would like to get this expression and not satisfy it with not here and this one here.
We can write it in a different way.
Maybe someone would write it like this expression is the same as nb > 60.
And this expression is as same as ng < 70.
So, sometimes even we can write them as requested or even make
Some simplification. The number of boys is ten more students, than number of girls.
So we need to compare here with equal equal.
The difference between these two guys, so we need to translate it as the difference, it's 10 or just this guy
here.
And finally, either nb is ten more than ng, so again, similar concept, OR that we did before
here, number no girls is 15 more than that guy.
So I hope it wasn't hard exercise for you.
The last exercise is about the simplification exercise.
And again, it's one more practice to make sure that you understand the priorities, to understand the
order of simplifications.
Let's take a couple of examples from them.
Let's say we have this big example here.
We know that parentheses has higher priority.
So let's see, searching for something that is very deep and there are no parentheses inside it anymore.
We can find this one.
This sub-expression here.
True or false? it is true.
So we switch.
We replaced it with true.
Then the another deep expression is true and the true, which is true.
Now we are done with all parentheses.
The next is a expression that involves AND.
So we have here true and true.
Let's move it to true.
So we now at this expression.
The second expression is true && false && true, this one has to be false.
So we replace it with false.
Now, the third expedition is true && true && false, this again is reduced
to false, so we replaced it with false.
So we have here this expression, the final
I feel I duplicated this line maybe, anyway, if we replace this guy with false we will have
this false here.
Now, we are done with all of the AND simplifications.
We end up with a single true because we have true or something, probably as you observe, we can
stop all of that very early from here, true || something.
We know all of that, regardless of the result, is going to be true anyway.
And this is like a smart reduction.
You get all of it suddenly and this is what we are going to do here.
Like we will simplify this expression to true, then this expression to true then we will simplify this
expression here to true.
And we have other parentheses?
Yeah, we would simplify this guy here to true.
Now, true or whatever something is just true, this shortcut is very important.
It makes your life simpler and also it get you used to how the compiler is actually implementing things
behind the scene. That's all.