In this video we will dig more behind the division operator.
Let's first remember the multiples.
If I told you the multiples of 4, to be 4 * 1, 4 * 2, 4 * 3 and so on.
So the multiples would be like 4, 8, 12, 16, and so on, the same for 5, the multiples of 5 are
5, 10, 15, 20 and so on.
What is the biggest multiple of 5.
Less than 30.
25.
OK, so let's try to investigate some about the division, specifically the integer part and the
fraction part.
If you say 6/2, this is normally 3.
12/2.
We can divide that to 6 + 6 divided by 2, we can distribute it.
So it's now 3 + 3 with the 6, 20 divided by 2 is like 12 + 8, divided
by 2,
Distribute 6 + 4 = 10.
Now what about 21.
21 is like (20 + 1) / 2.
So it is like 20/2 with10,
1/2 which is half.
So 10.5.
10 is the integer part, 5 is the fractional part.
Let's investigate what happens here.
25/5 is just 5.
26/5 is like 25/5 plus 1/5.
So it's 5.2.
Here, 27, it will be 2/5 which is 0.4, 28 will be 3/5 which
is 0.6.
29 will be 4/5 which 0.8.
So notice here, 1/2, 2/5, 3/5, 4/5, 5/5, is going to give us 1,
extra 1 so 6.
OK, this is like nice observation to keep in mind.
Moving to C++, when we divide two numbers and both of them are integer, then all the fractional
parts would be ignored.
So here dividing from 25 to 29/5.
It just the answer would be just 5, 30/5 is 6.
31/5 is also 6.
So two integer numbers divided by
We ignore the fractional part. On the other side,
If we use the double format or any one of them is double just one of them, if anyone is double then
the result is double.
Now we start to see the fractional part coming with you step by step 'till you grow up to the 6 here.
So the moral of that is, are you dividing two integers or one of them is double ? this decides the
final answer.
One of the very interesting observation is dividing integers by tens.
Let's see this number 12345.
Dividing it by 10
Give us 1234.
Why?
Because 12345
Divided by 10 is like 1234.5.
And in integer division, the point five just would be dropped.
Interestingly here, the relationship between 12345 and 1234
is that the last digit is removed.
Dividing by hundred will give us 123, dividing by thousand will give us 12, dividing
by this number, and so on.
So clearly dividing by 10, 100, 1000 is just removing numbers.
So dividing by 1000 is just removing the last 3 digits.
Dividing by 10000 is removing the last 4 digits.
If we use doubles this doesn't help, but it just we know that this fractional part is going to be divided,
dividing by 100000 end up with zero point the whole number.
So an integer part of this guy is just removed and we just did this one.
So keep this very important observation in your mind.
Dividing by 10s is just removing the last digit, last 2 digits, last 3 digits and so on.
Even and odd, even number is something that is divisible by 2, like 2, 4, 6 and so on.
If we divided a number by 2 and it is even then, there is no fractional part here.
So for example, 8 divided by 2 is 4, no fractional part.
on the other side, the odd numbers are numbers, that isn't divisible by 2, like 1, 3,
5, and so on.
When you divide such a number by 2, it will always has a fractional part 0.5.
So for example, 3 divided by 2 is 1.5.
So the result of dividing these numbers over 2 is 1/2 = half, 3/2 = 1.5,  5/2
Is 2.5, and so on.
So this fractional part always exists.
So it's like number .5.
So dividing and even by 2, give us .0 dividing odd give us by .5.
It also worth highlighting about the conversions.
We can actually make conversions between numbers.
Let's say that we divided here 8/3.
which gives us this big number 2.6666666 for infinity.
If we printed it, just we get this number and here it is approximated in C++.
Now look to this syntax,
We say here "int result = (int)num", this is called casting.
We are converting a double number to an integer number.
When we cast it, we just lose the fractional part.
So the .666 is just going to be lost.
So the result here would be 2. as we said before, even characters are internally represented as integers.
So if you casted a character to an integer,
it is  going to give you an integer value, interestingly, if we casted the small 'a' to the small 'z', we
get range 97 to 122.
If we casted the capital 'A' to the capital 'Z', we will have from 65 to 90.
There are two interesting observations here,
The first is that the upper case letters are smaller in value than the lower case letters.
This why we said before in comparison, capital words come before small words.
And the other thing that there is a range of characters from 'a' to 'z' and from 'A' to 'Z' here.
That's it.