In this video we will discuss about the Modulus operator, let's motivate it, let's say that we are
using a 12-hour clock style, let's say we are at 9:00. now,
One question is, what is the hour after like another 12 hours from now ? it's 9:00, it is again going to be
9:00.
What about 4?
If it's 9 and after 4 hours, it is going to be 1:00.
So far, so good.
OK, what about if we are at 9 and we want to go 16 hours.
So 16 is just a 4 + 12.
So after 12 hours, it would be again 9 and then after 4 hours it's going to be 1:00.
So after 4 hours or after 16 hours, is the same as 1, after 17 hours, it's going to be 2:00.
OK, what about if we are at 9 hours and we would like to go after 29 hours.
So we know that 29 is like 5 + 2 * 12.
So after 24 hours we are still at 9.
And so what matters really is 5.
So 29 is eventually, what's really critical is 5, so 5 and 9 we end up at
2.
What about before
24 hours?
We are still at 9.
Before 25 hours? we are at 8.
The cool observation here is every multiple of 12 is useless either in after or before.
What really matters is the reminder.
What really matters is here,
what is less than
a multiple of 12.
So mathematically (a) modulus (n) written like "a%n" is finding the remainder after division.
So we know X divided by Y, now
X mod Y, let's say that we have (a) with 27, (n) with 12 then (r) for remineder is (a%n)
For example here 27/12,
We know that 27 is like 2 * 12
+ 3 divided by 12.
So here 2 is the maximum possible multiples of 12 here.
So 2*12/12 is just 2 and then 3 divided by 12 is 2.5.
We say that integer is the integer division part or the quotient and it is the maximum possible multiple,
We cannot put a third one. 0.25 is the fractional part of the division.
It's mainly coming before because of the 3 divided by 12.
So 3 is actually the remainder of the division.
It's coming from subtracting the 27 from the highest multiple here which is 24.
So 27 - 24 is just 3.
So when we write 27 mod 12 it is just the 3, the remainder of the division. this
mod must be this less than 12 it must be, otherwise it would be one extra integer division part here.
Let's go back to the division of 25/5.
Thinking about it, we have here 0/5, 1/5, 2/5, 3/5, 4/5, 0/5.
This part is what represents the Mod here.
OK, so 1/5 in the division is .2, in the modulus, it is 1, 3/5 in the division
would be 0.6, in the modulus it would be 3.
Again, this modulus has to be less then the 5.
OK, so mainly try to solve an equation in terms of the multiples of 5, the possible multiples of
5, maximum one, then the remaining either use it as a fractional part or as a division part.
Here is one more example.
Let's say that we would like to try 27 divided by 7.
So now the maximum multiple of 7 here is 3, (3*7 + 6) / 7,
So we have 3 + 6/7.
So this is the fractional part or the mod is just here the 6, coming from 27 - 21
21 for 3 * 7.
Now coming to the really very critical observation about the modulus and what really matters for you
when it comes to engineering.
The modulus 2  and modulus 10, have nice observations.
First of all, the modulus 2, when you take an even number modulus 2, it just gives you zero, and if
it is an odd number, it just gives you 1.
So using the mod 2 "%2", you can figure out if the given number is even or odd.
This is a nice observation.
The second observation is the mod 10 "%10", let's investigate mod 10 here.
For example, 100 % 10 is 0, 1001 % 10 is 1
1008 % 10
is 8.
What is happening here?
the mod 10
gives us the last digit.
Remember last time we said that dividing by 10 remove the last digit now mod 10 gets for us the
last digit.
Now what about mod 100 ?
Gives us the last two digits, last two digits mod 1000?
Then gives us the last three digits mod 10000?
So then gives us the last 4 digits.
So the division and the modulus are playing very, very nice part in integers.
The division is removing the last K digits and the modulus is getting for us
The last K digits, this way.
We can split an number to two different parts.
Yeah, that's it, so mod 2 can tell us if number is even or odd, mod 10 can give us the last digit, divided
by 10 can remove for us the last digit.
That's it.