Homework number one for the division and modulus part, in the first program, you will read five
numbers and print the following, their average, the sum of the first three numbers divided by the
sum of the last two numbers.
So here are the five numbers that we read as an input,
And then their average is 3, because 1, 2, 3 is 6, 10, 15, 15
Over five is three.
The sum of the first three numbers divided by the sum of last two numbers, that should be one, two,
three, which is six divided by nine.
And finally here in C the average of the first three numbers divided by the average of the last two
numbers.
So the average of the first three numbers are six over two, six over three, which is two.
And the average of the last two number, which is nine number two.
And that is the question here.
Is there any math relationship between B and C? in the second the program would like to print the
fractional part of two numbers when they are divided,
For example, if you divide two hundred and one over twenty-five, the answer is eight point zero four.
I would like you to try to print this zero point zero four.
This is a fractional part that we would like to print.
Our reminder, we know that N%M computes the remainder of the division, I would like you to
write a program that reads 2 positive integers and print their remainders, but you shouldn't use the
model operator, for example.
Twenty seven and the twelve with models
we know they are three.
I would like you to get the three without using the model operator itself.
So remember, what is a math equation that we need to get this three value
That's all.