Let's solve the first homework here, the first one is very straightforward, you should read the five
numbers requested from you and then the average is very easy, just sum all of them and divide by five.
observer here.
I use the double as my data type so that the average is working well.
This is the request a, the second request is a sum of the first three numbers divided by the sum of the second
two numbers, so far so good.
And finally, we would like also to get the first average over the second average.
So let's compute here.
First average over the second average.
that's all, if you thought about the relationship between B and C, you will observe that
C is 2/3 relationship like that.
This is mainly the relationship.
So if you try to divide them, you would observe that this  average would be cancelled with this,
this sum here would be cancelled with this sum and this sum would be cancelled with this sum so the
remain is just the three over two values, that's all.
In the second the program, the fractional part here, we would like to get the fractional part of a
number.
So the idea is let's first divide the two numbers together.
We got a result.
If we cast the result to integer, we got rid of the integer part.
For example, if we divided here and cast this to integer, we get the eight.
Now, if you subtracted all of this number from the eight, we will now get the fractional part here
From this subtraction. In the third program, we would like to get the remainder by ourselves, not by
the math.
The purpose of the assignment is to make sure that you understand and know the equation itself.
So let's put it here.
Let's try something like 13 over five.
If you did integer division for 13 / 5, you get two, which means
there are two complete cycles of five, which means two times five.
Ten is like the upper bound here.
Now, if you subtracted the 13 minus this 10, you get the result.
So this is how we can do it.
You do float division for N over M.
Now we extracted the two multiply
it with five.
Now you get the ten back, subtract thirteen minus ten, you get the three.
That's all, nothing more fancy than that.