Today we will discuss about the "prefix" and "postfix" operators, which is a ++ operator. there are two types
of this operator, the prefix one, which "pre" means before.
So it's like ++X, where X is a variable.
The postfix "post" means after.
It is X++ variable.
So let's differentiate between them.
Here is the ++A, for example case,
Let's say that A is 10.
If we say it B equals ++A, it means as following,
so A++ is like, that means a = a + 1.
But in this abbreviation what does it mean exactly?
++A, means increment A; so now A is going to be 11 in memory.
After that, the assignment step is going to happen normally.
So it's now B = 11.
So when we print both of them it would be A is 11 and B is 11.
So A++ is as same as "a = a + 1".
This is all what happened here and then the normal assignment operation happened.
So this is very normal.
Now, the second case where we have the A++ the postfix, this is a bit tricky. when
we say A++, this is what happened,
First, the compiler is going to assign B to A without affecting A, so A is now 10 and will still 10
then assign it to the left side.
It's going to be now
B with 10. after that it is going to increment A with 1.
So it would be 11. if we printed both of them,
It will be 11 and 10.
Now again, thinking about A and thinking about B, A in both cases become 11.
So A++ or ++Ù is as same as "a = a + 1".
But the difference here in what is being printed or assigned, here, in the ++A
case we actually increment A first then assign it.
But here we actually assign it first, then we increment it.
That's why B has the old value of A, so we can summarize the prefix increment as an incremental step,
then assign or print, but the postfix is assign then increment.
This is mainly the difference between both of them.
Let's see more here in printing.
If I say "a = 10", then "cout<<a++" is going to print A first,
So it's going to print 10, then increment A,
It will be 11.
Even if you put in parentheses here, it's going again to print 10.
OK, so this is in summary the difference between both of them.
The "++" increments first, but A++ here just does assigning first then increment.
Eventually, A will be incremented but it is all about the other side,
Will it get the old the value or the new value.
OK, now one might write a fancy code like the following "cout<< a++ + ++a".
This is undefined, and this is undesirable.
We will discuss later more
why is that.
Now let's do one more tracing and let's say that A is 5 and B is 10.
What is the output of A + 5 + B, this is clearly 20.
But what about this "++a + 5 + b++".
Think about it for a minute.
If you thought about it, this is going again to be 20, but the question is any extra increment in the A ?
any extra increment in the B? here, the "++a" is going to be incremented first.
So we are going to get one from here.
So actually, it would be 6 not 5. Here,
The B would be actually used
as it is first.
So it will be 10, and later to be incremented.
So this expression would end up with 21.
The value of A after it is 6 and the value of B after it is 11.
Now going to the "a++ + ++a" case.
We are going to know about that a bit later.
But what I want you to know here, if we are doing X + Y there is no guarantee if X will
be evaluated first or Y will be evaluated first.
So let's say that we are going to evaluate the left then the right.
So A++, let's say A is 10, A++, we are going to take the 10 for the plus and then A will
be 11.
So we take from here 10 now and here A is 11.
So we increment it so it now will be 12.
So the overall of the expression becomes 10 plus 12, which is 22.
Now let's say the reverse happened that this one was evaluated first.
So A is now 10.
If we incremented it, it will be 11.
Then we go here and use it.
So it will be also 11.
So end up to 22, the results seems the same.
But the point is, you don't know which one to evaluate it first and what degree
it will affect each other.
Some important tips, do not overuse this operator, it's important, it's almost in every code, but we don't
overuse it.
We don't use it in complicated expressions, because we don't know the order of evaluation.
The best examples for it,
It could be something like that,
You have a normal ++X, which means "x = x + 1", or you want to use the postfix
one, use it and you just take a copy out of it.
There is another case, the "--" operator.
This is called decrement, prefix decrement and postfix decrement.
Sorry, this is postfix decrement.
In this case, it just goes the other side, sorry these values aren't updated.
it should be like 10 and 10, and 10 and 9.
Yeah.
That's it.