Homework
number two in the modulus and division, the first one "is even" I would like you to read the number integer
here and find the three ways that can tell us if a number is even or not.
The first one using the %2 only,
This is very direct, the second using the division over two and the third using the moduls
10, feel free to write extra lines of code here.
But the purpose is using only division two, using only %10, we can figure out the answer.
So think about that.
The last 3 digits sum, you are to read an integer and print the sum
of its last three digits, for example, if there is 1,2,3,4 the last three digits are two,
three, four, which is nine here.
If you are reading something like 15, then it's like one five and like there are zeros here so one five
is just six.
And so on, and in this one, you will read an integer and print the 4th from the right side
For example, if we are reading numbers like this big number, count four from the end, one, two,
three, four.
So we print here four, one, two, zero four, one
here is the fourth
number five zero zero one five
here is the fifth number.
If the number doesn't exist, even like it's less than 4 digits, then you have to print a zero.
That's all.