Let's solve the second homework sets here, so the first problem is about checking if a number is even
or not in three ways.
Using number mod two is the standard way to know if a number is even or not.
By the way, using mod two and comparing with zero is better for both even
and odd, for example, if you'd like to check if a number is odd or not, then check number mod two not equals
zero.
Why?
Because if the number is negative in the even case, it would not matter, because in both cases it
would be zero.
But if the number is odd, three mod
two is one, minus three mod two is negative one.
So now it's going to be tricky and you have to be careful.
So the best thing is to compare against zero, equal equal for even and not equal for odd.
Now this is a standard one.
How can we use the division two and modulus 10 to make a check?
Remember that when we divide a number by two, there are one of two cases for the fractional
part it is either point zero for an even number or point five for the odd number.
So the idea here is to get the fractional part, similar to what we did before,
We can get the double number minus the integer vision to get the fractional part,it the fractional
part is zero.
Then this means this must be an even number.
The mod ten is different case and easier one, if you noticed when we take a number with mod ten
if it is even,
then the last digit has to be zero, two four, six or eight.
So we can double check against all of the choices.
If it's any of them, then this is an even number.
Definitely.
We go with this approach in industry.
But it is good to be aware of other approaches.
In the second problem, we would like to get the sum of the last three digits.
OK, so let's see.
The idea here is using the modulus ten and division by ten idea, if you divide the number by 10, 10,
10 or by 1000, you actually.
OK, I'm sorry, I switched.
This is the fourth one.
Let me get this one.
Sorry.
Can I switch it, sorry for that.
If you would like to get the last three digits then you can take modulus ten, you get the last digit
and then divide by ten, you remove it, modulus ten, get the last digit, division by ten you get it,  modulus ten
you divide by ten to get it.
So for example, if the number is five, eight, six, seven, two, if you did modulus ten, then you get
the five.
If you divided by ten, you remove the five.
Modulus ten, you get the seven division by ten, you remove the seven, modulus ten
you get the six, division by ten, you remove it.
This is how you can get that three digits sum.