The third homework set for the division and modulus, first one, and it is very similar to an old program
that we did, write a program that read an integer and the print either hundred, if the number
is even or seven if the number is odd.
So, for example, if I entered it, it would guarantee a 100 because it is even if the input is one
hundred thirty-three, the output will be seven because is odd, this is very similar to something we
did before.
The second one is about the years, assume a year is 12 a month and each month is just 30 days,
So the each year is just fixed it for three hundred and sixty days.
You will read an integer representing the total number of days of someone and you have to print
three values, the total years, the total month and the remaining days.
For example, if someone is 360 days, then this means a single year, one year, zero month, zero days.
30 days mean one month.
10 days only been just 10 days here
0 years,
Zero month.
If someone is 391 days, it means he is three hundred and sixty days for a year, 30 days for a
month, and then a single day and so on.
Please read the more examples if you are still confused about it.
That's all.