The third homework, we already did something very similar to that guy, we would like to find an equation
that helps us to cancel one part out of the two.
So I'm developing here something that say is_even and is_odd and multiplying by 100 and by seven and is_odd
is just one minus is_even.
So if is_even is one then odd is zero, is_even is zero, then is odd is one.
So now only one of these two parts would be activated, either that part or that part, and based on
that we will get back the answer. Again, in the future,
The code of that should be much more trivial than that.
In the second problem, we have to apply a lot of modulus and division to extract the the three components
that we asked for them.
So let's see how to do that in a short way.
I expect that you wrote several lines of code to do it, but here is one shorter way than what you did.
Observe
First, if you would like to get the exact number of years, all what you need is to divide by three
hundred and thirties.
For example, if you have something like three hundred ninety-one and you divided it by three hundred
and thirty here, you will get something like one point zero something.
So we know that there is at least one year here.
That's why the integer division is going to get for us the number of years. Now,
I would like to get the remaining after removing the number of years, I can do that by days modulus
60.
Now, this is the total number of days for the month and for the days, for example, here, if we have
three hundred ninety-one and we take it modulus three hundred and sixty, it would be 31.
This is the remaining of the total number of days and month.
Now, in a very similar logic, we can again divide by 30 to get the number of months, then mod 30 to extract
the number of exact days.
That's all.