In this video, we will know about the assignment operator.
We already saw the assignment operator a lot.
It is just this Equal "=".
When we say integer X = 2 * Y + 1, we say that we assign a value.
So Y is brought from the memory, 2 * Y + 1 is computed and the result is stored again in X.
we call X "left Hand-side" and we call this expression the "right-hand side".
It could be like just 12, 10+2,  a big expression and so on.
It is evaluated first, then assigned to the X.
When you look to the right hand side here, let's say that Y is is an integer.
So the overall result is just a number which is assignable to X.
What does it mean to be assignable here?
I mean by that, let's say the right side is just a string, your name for example, then
you cannot say integer X equals some string.
The compiler will complain.
And more interestingly, we can assign several variables in a single line like this way. we can say
X = 2 * Y, Y = 10 + 2, Z =  X + Y.
Then semicolon ";". This is very common and the comma here is a comma operator.
OK, here are two interesting things about the comma operator.
First, it is evaluated from Left-to-right.
So every comma expression, every expression before a comma is evaluated first in this order.
This is one interesting thing about it.
The second thing, the last expression find the last comma did the expression after it, the
result of this expression is returned.
So if I say, for example, "cout<<(10, x=1, y=3+1 x = ...)"
blah blah blah, comma 40.
The result of this expression is 40.
So two things here,
Left-to-right evaluation for every expression.
The last item is returned.
The comma "," operator is frequently used in this case, but the people less use it based on the evaluation
idea from the left to right, which might be helpful sometimes.
Another case is this kind of operators,  +=, -=, *=, /=.
We call it a compound assignment.
The compound assignment means, it combines two things.
It combines the assignment operator with some binary operator.
So let's say that we have a number and we say number + 1 "num = num + 1.
There is a shorter way to do that.
We can say "num += 1;".
This is exactly as same as "num = num + 1", "num *= 2" this is exactly as "num = num * 2"
and so on, "num -= 10" is "num = num - 10" and a "num /= 2" is "num = num / 2".
So this is a more of convenient use operator, it is just to make your life a bit easier.
For the big picture of operators,
At the moment we studied the unary operators, which just takes a single operand, and we studied the binary
one which takes 2 operands.
And also there is a ternary operator which takes three operants.
We will see it in the future,
It isn't frequently used. from another perspective,
We also saw the arithmetic operators, which are the math operations, and also today the assignment operator,
which are these guys. we saw the prefix and postfix operators or unary operators.
In the next times we will know more about the relational operators and logical operators. in the future
We will know about the bitwise operator, which is a bit advanced operator.
That's it.