Let's talk about Precedence, remember math rules, if I told you to solve 2 + 3
* 4 - 6 / 2, in math, we know that the division and multiplication are applied first.
So, for example, we take the 3 * 4 and evaluate them to 12.
Then we apply the division to 6.
Divided by 2 is 3.
When we have now 3 items, we take them left to right.
So 2 + 12 is 14.
Then - 3 is 11.
So this is how we do it.
If we have The parenthesis in math, we know that it gives more priority.
So we now, although it is the same expression,
We know that this sub-expression should be solved first; so 4 - 6 / 2.
Again, we do the division first, now 4 - 3 overall, this is 1.
Now, this whole expression is 1. 2 + 3 * 1,
It is 2 + 3.
It is 5.
So the math defines for us the order of operations.
So it tells us if there is a parentheses, it is applied first, if there are times and division, they are before plus
and minus, this is called precedence and we have the same in C++. but now in C++ we have a lot more
operators.
So which one is before what?
So here are some rules.
We took this unary operators.
The unary operators are applied first before anything, then the math operations, division and multiplication,
then the plus(addition) and minus(subtraction).
Eventually the assigning operations are done in the end.
So let's say that we have such an expression and how C++ is going to tackle it, thinking about who
are the highest here in the priority.
This guy ++ and this guy (--) are the highest then this guy is the second highest then these guys
are the next one.
Items inside the group are of equal priority, like they can be applied in any order.
So here we first apply for example, the ++X.
So this is the first term.
Then we apply the -- for the T this is the second term.
Then eventually we apply the Y over Z and then do the final math operation.
So, and the parentheses, as we said, it helps us to force order or resolve some ambiguity.
If you feel the expression may be tricky for someone you may put parantheses to clarify your goal.
So here we have 7 - 6 in this expression,
We do it first.
So we resolve it here and then we do the normal of the expression. again,
In this case here, we know that this expression should be done first. in the last time, the
++X was the first.
But now this expression should be at least evaluated first.
So we go and evaluate it first and then we notice the T-- here.
So it could be applied first.
Then we apply the whole expression, then ++X.
The now Y is divided by the result of this expression, then the overall and so on.
So very intuitive.
Nothing new.
In a math expression, if you have a lot of parentheses, how would you solve it. as simple
as you figure out one of the deepest parentheses and solve it first.
For example, we can solve with this expression first or we can solve this expression first and
so on.
So let me pick one here.
I here made some assumptions about the values. we started with
This X + Y, which is a very deep parentheses nothing more inside it.
So, let's replace it, X and Y, X is 6, Y is 7.
So we replace it with 13.
We can now take this expression, replace it with 26.
We can now take this expression, replace it with 27.
We can take now this expression, replace it again with 27.
Now let's figure out another parenthesis that has nothing inside it.
This is one good example, so we can replace it with 5.
but when definitely we come to apply  it, then the ++C was applied first.
So C was valued 3 we ++ it first.
it was replaced with four.
Now we can here take this expression to 20.
Then we did this expression and then it's now -17 / 5.
So as we see what we did was, we kept taking an expression after an expression after an expression and
we did it.
Now there is a question here.
Let's say that this one wasn't ++C.
it was ++B, what is wrong now?
The problem now here is that the expression has B and ++B and we don't know which one the compiler
is going to evaluate first.
So the compiler evaluates this one first,
It will use it as original value, then this one will be used next.
Probably this is what we meant.
But if the compiler still can go and come here evaluate this guy first, so if it evaluated this guy
first, it would be incremented here.
For example, let's say that B was 10, if it evaluated this guy first, ++B,
It would be now
11 and here it would be used as 11.
So used here 11, and the used here is 11. on the other side,
If it started with this one, B was 10, it will use it as 10.
Then ++ 10 it will be used as 11.
So in one case, it could be 10 and 11, and in another case it could be 11 and 11.
That's why something like the ++ operator is very risky to use it when there are more than a
copy of it in the same statement.
So be very careful with that.
Associativity, as we said, what if there are more than operator of the same priority, like
when we have an expression with + or -, associativity is about grouping, about how to group,
is it from left to right or right or left?
What does this mean? in math,
when we have something like 10 - 6 + 3, we actually start to solve it from left to
right.
So we first solve 10 - 6, and then this gives us four.
Then we add the 3, which is 7.
If we have a bigger expression like that, you take the first two terms with 1, then the first
two terms with 6, the first two terms with 2 and so on, right to left grouping here will give
us a wrong answer, which means starting from the right and start to go.
So we first take the 6 + 3.
To give us 9, then 10 - 9 was 1, which is wrong in a bigger statement, 2 plus 1
is evaluated first to 3. 3 - 3 to 0, 0 + 4 to 4, 5 - 4 to 1
6 + 1 with 7, eventually 0.
So the associativity is about grouping and it is from left to right or right to left.
Now we have a lot of operator(s), who should be grouped from left to right and who should be grouped from right
to left.
Most of the operators are typically grouped from left to right and there is a few are grouped from right to left.
So here these are some of them, like the assignment operators are grouped  from right to left.
Let's see an example for that, let's say that we have X was 10, Y was 20, and Z was 3.
I would like you to read this variable.
Remember that it has a lot of assignments.
Remember that assignment is right-to-left, take a moment and try to guess what is the answer.
Now, the first thing we do is asking about the priority, who are the highest in priority, the highest in
priority here is --Z, then in the next priority, +=, +=, *=
all of the same priority.
So we first solve the --Z, Z here is 3, so --Z
would be 2.
Now, in the next case, we have the += and the += and *= are
all in same priority.
So now
solving this right expression, 9 - 3 - 1, should be our first step.
OK, like we are going from right to left now.
OK, we're going from right to left.
So this is the highest,
The most right one.
So 9 - 3 - 1 is now 5.
So the expression now is like the following X += Y += Z *= 5.
Again, they are all of equal priority.
Who is the most right one?
It is
Z *= 5.
So now Z *= 5.
Z would be now 10.
So remove it from the expression.
Now the expression is X += Y += 10, again two operators of same priority.
Take the most right one Y += 10.
Y is 20 and when we add 10 for it it's now 30.
So, finally X += 30 is 40.
So overall X was 40, Y was 30 and Z was 10, please make sure that you can trace it as I did.
This is a bad coding style.
Don't do that in reality.
I'm just telling you, like how to do it.
There is one final thing that I would like to share with you something that is rarely explained and
is a bit tricky for even many programmers.
It's called the order of evaluation.
We already highlighted something about it.
Let's say that we have an expression like X + Y, and X is some expression, and Y is some expression.
Once this X is computed and Y is computed, they are now operant values.
We know that X is going to be added to Y.
But an interesting question here, which one is evaluated first?
Is it the X or Y?
Sadly, we don't know which one would be evaluated.
And this is what's called the order of evaluation.
Order of evolution is unspecified in C++ in general, unless a few cases.
So it could be evaluated X then Y or Y then X. we already highlighted before this kind of example,
if we have something like X + ++X, this is very tricky because let's say X is one.
If X is evaluated first, then it will be here 1 and here 2.
But if the other side, ++X happened(evalutaed) first, now X is 2 and here is 2 also.
So in one case, it is 1 and 2 and in another case it was 2 and 2.
We didn't know, this is called side effect.
What a side effect?
A change happens in a state like this variable has been changed due to this expression, due to this
operation.
If an expression has a potential side effect, which means something inside it is affecting values
like ++X, *=, and so on, then this could be risky.
Another expression here, the ++A here and A here, we don't know if this expression would be
resolved first or this expression.
Mathematically, we can even evaulate this or this or this and this and so on.
A bit relevant to that is an expression like the following: "cout << i << " " << i++;".
Thinking about this statement for a while.
You would say, OK, the compiler is going to print I then I++, if I is 10, it will be printed
10 and 10. Surprisingly,
No, this isn't the case.
You should differentiate between evaluation and printing.
It could happen as following,
First we need to evaluate them.
So this one might be evaluated first and this one may be evaluated second, or this one may be evaluated
first.
And then this guy evaluated second.
But they are going really differently to be printed this guy first, then this guy.
But there is a difference between the evaluation and the printing.
OK, 'till C++17 this was the case, starting from C++17,
they are going really to be like evaluate this guy and print it, then evaluate this guy and print it.
So this is going to be more like your own logic, like what you expect, really.
So, again, if you noticed this, I++ has a side effect, so you should be very careful about
that.
As an optional reading, you might Google something like "undefined", "unspecified" and "implementation
defined behavior" to know what is the difference between what is unspecified and what is undefined.
Let's put the three items together, just in case you got lost of the real differences between them.
Operator precedence
Is all about the order of operations.
So there is some ordering here.
OK.
Specifically, we know, like asterisk "*" is before plus "+". notice here,
Nothing here about the operands still.
It's now about the operations itself.
I'm telling you, if you see an asterisk operation, multiplication, do it first before the addition.
Associativity is about grouping operands of equal priority.
So now we are going to try this again kind of ordering, but just depends on which one to group together.
But before we group, we need to evaluate expressions.
And here come the order of evaluation, which in C++ can come in any order.
So if we have an expression A - B - C, let's say that A, B, C are some expressions.
We don't know which expression would be applied first.
We know later that minus would have say a specific order of operation and we know it will be grouped like
A - B and eventually with C, but which one will be evaluated first? we don't know.
There are 6 different ways to evaluate this term
OK. if there is something here that has a side effect like "++A", "A++", "A *=", blah,
blah, then this side effect might fire on you. In practice,
If we avoided these side effects, then we don't care about the evaluation.
That's it.