In this video, we will discuss the operators' homework, there will be several homeworks in this lecture.
to divide it,
The first one is a guessing program output.
So you proceed with the program step by step and act like a compiler.
Most of the tracing here is what we said,
Good
expressions like they either have no side effects, like the A B, nothing weird, or just one operator
that we are increasing.
So it is fair enough tracing without weird things.
The second program is another tracing that mainly tests your understanding to the comma operator
in a "cout" statement.
In the third program, you have again, good tracing here for the code, but there
are like two codes that I would like to test your understanding.
But in practice, like, we still avoid coding this way, although it's correct, but it needs more
understanding of what's happening.
But still don't go this way.
I'm just testing your understanding.
That's it.