Let's solve this problem, which is all about tracing mainly. for the first
problem here, we have mainly variables A and B, with two zeroes, and then we are printing
A++,  ++ after the A means that the A original value will be used
first then it will be incremented.
So A is zero.
So zero would be printed here and then B++ would be done after the 'cout'  statement.
So after here at nine eight, the value of A now is one.
Then we have ++A, ++A will increment A first before using it and A is one,
So now A is two, then we print it,
That's why we have two, we were one plus one two.
Now, A + 2 * B + 1, B is 1, 2 * 1 is 2 + 1 is 3 and
then 3 + A which is 2, is 5.
So now A is 5 and then B = ++A * 2, A is 5, ++A will increment it
first.
So A will be 6 and then 6 * 2 will be 12.
If we printed here A and B, we will notice then they are 6 and 12, for A and B. assigning B to A
then
Now the two values are 6 and 6.
A = new value for A, 12 +A / 3 will compute all of this expression, then assign it here
to the value of A, A is 6, 6 / 3 is  2, 2 / 2 is 1, and then 12 + 1
is a 13.
13 - 4 is 9
So printing here 9.
And observe here, in math this three lines must  be done together the A / by 3 by 2.
In math the division will have higher priority and also the multiplication would have the higher priority.
So in math you should do first this expression then this expression then you do all of it.
So anyway,
Now the B is 6 and A is 9.
Now we are assigning A again to B, which is 6.
So A is now 6
And here we say 12 + 6.
The parenthesis will give higher priority.
So it will be applied first, 12 + 6 is 8, sorry, 12 + 6 is 18.
/ 3 is 9 or 18
/ 3 is 6,  / 2 is 3
So this whole expression
Here is 3.
3 - 2 is 1
Then 1*2 is 2, printing here 2 again, in terms of priority, the parenthesis will have
higher priority.
So this is very deep
One will be done first, then the remaining of the division will be done here second,
Then we will subtract by 2.
Then finally we multiply by 2.
It's important to know how to trace things like that.
Let's move to the second homework again.
Another tracing.
This tracing is mainly the Fibonacci tracing, we already took such a program and we referred to Fibonacci before.
If the first term of Fibonacci is A, and the second term of Fibonacci is B, then C here is = A + b is just
assigning the term intermediate.
And the moral of this assignment is just to observe that we have to print to the last value here.
Remember that the comma operator is evaluated from left to right.
This one is evaluated
This one,
This one.
And so on till we are done with this guy and we print it.
So in the comma we print the last one.
The comma operator is one of the least used in industry in this type.
And it is good to know about it.
And the third homework, we have another tracing, so let's see here what we have, it's merely an exercise
over the compound assignments.
We start with A as 210
If we divide A by 2, then the 200 would be 100 the 10 would be 5.
So overall would be one 105
105 actually is the multiplication of three values, 3 and 5 and 7.
If you divide it by 3, you will get 35.
Then by 5 you get 7.
Then by 7 you get 1.
And all of these operations involve the "/=".
So A is updated with every step.
This is an independent expression.
Too we have here these parameters have priority would be applied first, these parameters have priority would be applied
first, these parameters would be applied first, 2 +3 is 5, 5 - (-3) is 8.
So we have actually 5 * 8, then divided by 5 and divided by 8 , so actually overall
is 1.
We start here with A = 10, then A++ + 10.
it starts by addition.
A is 10 and 10 is 20, and this (++) would be done later.
So this would have to print 20. and then
now A is 11 and here we have again A + 10,
So you can think like oh A is 11,
11 and 10 is 21. and this will be applied first, then we have 22, so we have here overall
22. and A is now 12. and then the same concept here as we incremented A twice
and decremented twice then we are sure that A is now just 10.
So A is 10 and B is 20.
Let's add them A + B, A is 10, B is 20 then 30. and the ++B is incremented first,
then the B will have to be 1 early, so the output would have to be 31.
And we are printing the A here, which is 11 from this expression.
And finally this ugly statement, ++A += 10.
I wrote it in this fancy way to confuse you. you are incrementing the A first and then you are adding
the value to it. in industry we shouldn't try to code in a way that confuse people.
This is fair enough,
People will perceive it.
Such an expression might be a bit longer for guys, so you might divide it to several variables.
This are OK, OK expressions because there is only a single variable is changed here.
However, for clarity, you might consider making this say ++A in a separate line first or taking
a copy from that one.
You do not code in this way, and you don't code in this way. over all
You have to think in industry about your colleagues who are reading
code. even you after like six months, you might come back to read the code.
the code has to be clear.
So make sure to write something that is really clear.
If you are writing a line of code that isn't clear enough, it's a good idea to come and write some
comment here for the guys to give them some help, that's all.