In this video, we will discuss the relational operators. Relational is all about comparisons.
I would like you to stop the video for a minute and then read all of these normal text expressions
and then think about their answers and then visualize with your eyes what is on the right side.
OK, so is 3 greater than 5? false, how to express that in math we say 3 greater than 5.
Is 3 < 5? true.
We present it with that, now when come to equal, is 3 = 5? in math we use a single equal
but this in C++ is the assignment operator.
So we use here an == to express an equality, is 3 greater than or equal ">=" 5
false, how to write it
we write greater than ">", equal "=" and so on, notice
there is no spaces here.
If we would like to represent to the..., this is another one for greater than equal ">=".
This is for equal
equal "==" which is true.
Is 3 == 3 true , this is for greater (than) ">"
This is for not equal "!=".
So in a similar way we can make the less than or equal  like "<=".
Now, moving to the C++, this is just how we do, it so we can say 3 > 5, 3 < 5, and 3 == 5
>=, >=, ==, >, !=, !=.
3 != 4, you notice we use here parentheses usually we use them to avoid compiler errors.
So this is what we mean by a relational operator.
Relational is about the relation between two things, it help us to compare.
And as we are comparing it ends up with Boolean, it ends up with true or false.
So just what we call in C++ a condition. in a similar way,
we can only just work on constants, we can work on variables so we can say X > Y and
we have 2 X and Y values that
for example, we read them or so. X == Y and so on.
In a similar way, we can put the result in some boolean because we know they are eventually end
up with a true or false.
So one can say "bool result = x > y", then we just print it and so on.
Also, it's boolean so we can put the not operator "!", not result "!result" or not
x < y, (x<y)
is evaluated first as a parenthesis, then the "!" is applied second and so on.
Please make sure that all of the outputs here make sense for you.
In a similar way, we can not  just compare numbers,
we can also compare strings.
So if I have a string ' name1 = "Ali" ', string ' name2 = ali mostafa'  , string ' name3 = "Ziad" ' , Ali, Ali and so on.
We can start to say name1 less than "" name2, and so on.
But the question now, how are they compared?
We assume two things,
First, that we have a dictionary that is sorted based on name.
So as we know in the dictionary, something like "car" would be, for example, before something like
"laptop", OK, because 'C' is coming before 'L' in laptop and so on.
The second thing is we assume, we said before that C++ is case sensitive, we assume the small letter 'a' and
the small letters in general, the uppercase letters comes before the small letters.
So the small letter "a" here.
So for example, here, let's say that we have a name1, "ali", and name5, "ALI".
If we say name1 "ali" == name5 "ALI" -capital-,  it would be false.
If we say name1 > name5, the answer would be true, why? because the small letter 'a'
is greater than the upercase letter 'A'.
OK, so this is mainly how to compare strings. finally,
And more tricky is a double comparison.
The double comparison is very tricky.
Double in C++ is represented in an approximate way.
If you would like to go in a bit advanced, there are couple of very interesting articles here.
Now, let's say that we have something like "a = 3.0" divided by 7.0 and another expression
b = 1 + 3.0 / 7.0 - 1
Mathematically, these two terms are very equal.
If we printed A and B, it would be this expression. if we here wrote A == B, surprisingly, sometimes
it would be zero
not one, this is very weird.
They look the same number.
They are the same math, but not necessarily equal because they are internally approximate numbers. in
a similar way,
Let's say you said "a = 5" and "b = 4.9999999999999999".
If you try to print them, they will be printed like 5 and 5 because C++ will approximate that
to 5.
And still, if you compare them, it might not be 1 because it's still internally, it might not be
represented as 5.
So the moral of that is we do not compare directly doubles specifically the ==, especially
the == operator, the "" are OK.
But the ==, =.
We don't compare them directly.
In the future we will learn how to do that.
You might think about, how in future this would work.
But for now, just be careful from comparing doubles directly.
That's it.