So far, we learned about the (if conditions) and looping which are, what we call the program flow, it helps us
to control the flow.
Today, we are going to one of the fundamental concepts in programming, which is called "Arrays".
Arrays could be something like 1D or 2D or 3D, the multidimensional case.
So today, our focus will be on the array. Let's motivate the use of arrays.
If I told you that, I would like to read 1000 integer numbers and print them it reversed.
For example, read 1000 integers and find pairs of numbers with some one, two, three, four, five.
We can definitely define 1000 variables, but this is going to be very crazy.
C++ and any programming language provide us with the array of array.
The Array has some size (bits of K).
For example, you define K variables in the memory consecutively.
So we have now 1000 variable in the memory.
They are typically all of the same type, at least here in C++.
And once we have the one array, we can just iterate on it and do all what we want.
Well, let's see an example of that.
Here is how we define an array.
Let's say we we are targeting an array of five numbers.
This is the syntax of it.
We say integer numbers and then you open brackets '[ ]' and you put some number here.
And these are basically some values like .
Now, what does this mean?
It means, Create five numbers in the memory for us.
Noted that, we cannot change this five later, it's just now 5 and so on.
Now, the purpose of this syntax is instead of I'm going to create five variables by myself, I have
created five variables in a single command.
So this is the main difference between defining a variable and defining an array.
The array helps us to define a lot of variables using a single command.
Now, the question is, if I have five variables, I can access them by myself, get the values of the
value from the memory.
So now what about an array?
It goes as following.
The first rule is if you would like to access a specific value variable out of them, you start to use
brackets '[ ]' again and give an index.
An index is something that is a number.
So let's say we have five numbers, then they are... Suppose from one to five. in C++ and in programming
we see something called, "Zero Indexing".
This means, that the first number would be in the memory in position [0] and the last number in the
position is [size-1].
For example, if you define the five variables, then the first variable in the memory would be of position [0]
and the last one number is position [4]. Thinking about your number zero,
Number two,
Number four, you will notice that we are dealing with it as if it is normal variable.
It's actually all what happened
we defined five variables consecutively in the memory.
We just now have more convenient way to access them so I can access and set a value.
We can multiply the value, we can increment the value, we can print the value,
That's it.
Please make sure that you are comfortable with defining and initializing an array.
Thinking about the memory, here is what goes in the array that we defined. Initially, I say create
three or five numbers and also initialize them to .
So this is what happens in the memory.
Five numbers are reserved for you,
they can be the index from zero to four.
Now, in line 11, we say (number[0] = 9), so it goes in the memory here and switches to 9.
In line 12, we multiply the second.
OK, when we say position [2], remember that this is the third number, so we are multiplying the
third number by three,
and we are incrementing the fifth number.
OK, so here, if you notice the third number is going to multiply by three,
So (7 * 3 = 21), and the fifth number is going to be incremented with one step.
It's very important to be comfortable with zero-based indexing.
So it's all the time to be from zero to four, not from one to five.
I would like from now on to
just to start to think of it as just a bunch of variables in memory for you.
Let's say that you would like, for example, to print the whole array content.
Then we know that using a single loop like (for loop) like that, you can just iterate on the array one by one.
one by one.
So here we say 'cout << numbers[i]', so it's going to print the one, two, three, four, five for you.
On the other side,
If you would like to iterate from the backward, we can definitely say start from [size-1], (i >= -1).
(i >= -1), (--i).
But just for for sake of math, I'm just showing you a different way here.
So I'm saying here, [size -i-1], which is a starting from (4, 3, 2 ,1, 0)
and tracing backward.
OK, let's do one simple application, let's say I would like to give you an array, I would like to
read it and then I would like to find the minimum out of what I'm going to read.
So here, I declared an array of five positions.
But notice here, I didn't initialize it with anything.
This isn't healthy,
But anyway, now I'm looping five times to read the five numbers.
Now the five numbers in the memory are read. We are going to iterate on the whole array and start to
get the minimum out of them.
I took the first number of the array as the minimum for now, and then it started form the next position of one
going to the maximum, which is 4.
OK, so remember, the 'i' is less than five, It's just going to 4.
And then I'm saying if minimum is greater than 'i', then this is minimum.
Take this number as the minimum for now and keep going.
So as you see, we are just dealing with the array as bunch of variables for us in memory,
we can read, we can write, we can process, It just makes our life easier.
So now we are defining five numbers.
We now can define one million number and just go ahead and read them.
You cannot define one million variable by yourself, but using a single command, you created a big
array in the memory.
Some comments about initialization,
If you want to define a single variable, you could say 'int val1 = 100', or ' int val2 '.
or ' int val2 '.
OK, so comparing this syntax, you see here the braces directly for 'val2', so someone might mix it
mix it with the brackets.
So these braces '' are for initialization, this one '[ ]' is for the definition.
We can use the equal and then put an array.
This is more of a C-style, but the C++ has more of the initialization style.
I'm getting used to this style, but in your programming style you better get used to that.
The final thing is what happens if I wrote this way?
If I defined an array without a number here,
But I give an initialization list.
It actually automatically will know that this is three.
But if you didn't put the numbers here, it will not be able to figure out the array size.
The array has to be reserved for once in the memory and it is fixed it size.
So now we know it's going to be hundred numbers in the memory.
Here we know, it's three numbers in the memory and so on.
In addition, we are focusing on integer variables, but you can also define an array of "doubles", array
of "characters", array of "strings" and so on.
So no limitation.
The last thing to mention is what we call the index of the boundary error.
Remember, the runtime error is a problem that happened during the running of the program.
So there are two common mistakes that people do.
The first is to access with a negative index.
The second is to access with an index beyond the limitation.
For example, if you have an integer array of hundred, then this hundred can access from zero to ninety-nine.
to ninety-nine.
A very common mistake is to access it with one hundred exactly, due to one indexing.
But this is wrong.
It should be only indexed from zero to ninety nine.
The second mistake is that you might access it with negative 10, which is a negative number.
This is again wrong.
That's why we call it "Index out of boundary".
Your boundary is from zero to ninety nine only, so no one is doubling check the boundaries for you.
You have to do it by yourself.
That's it! :)