In the third problem, we would like to find the frequency of the number with the most
frequency.
However, one challenge is, now numbers are negative values.
We know from the frequency array style, we can handle it for positive value, but how can we handle it with
negative value?
We use an idea common in computer science, like shifting values. Shifting values
means you add some values and shift all of them.
If you added value of like, say, five hundred over all of these values, they will be shifted
to be completely in positive range.
So we will make use of this trick.
Observe here,
I'm creating the maximum of the array to be two hundred and seventy, plus five hundred, plus one, because now this
expresses the total numbers that we can find in this big range.
And after that, we create a frequency matrix, all of it initializes to zeros, and we iterate over
the values. For every value, we add five hundred over it.
This shift will make sure that every input value is just from zero to this max minus one.
And now, we are incrementing the frequency, and now we can find the answer in the given array.
One problem now is the value which is max value in the array now is actually shifted value.
So we need to shift it back to the original value.
This is how we solve the problem using the shift trick in an easy way.
In the next problem, we would like to find the digit frequency of given numbers.
I hope the problem wasn't hard for you.
All what we need is to start to iterate on the given numbers, take a number by number, and start to
get the digit with mod ten, remove the digit.
And for every digit, we accumulate it here in the occurrence list. You should handle the X == 0
as a special case.
Once you are done with that, occurrence, which is an array of length ten, will have the frequency of all
of the given numbers.