In this version of the problem, now the list is unordered, so we lost the advantage of having it an
ordered list.
Now it seems like the idea of having two nested loops is very, very straightforward.
But still, we can avoid nested loops using the frequency trick, especially that all the values are
just trapped between zero and five hundred.
Let's see how to code that.
We are going to create an array, again with plus one, to make sure the array is correct, and after that,
we will iterate over the numbers, assert is just a function in cassert here that makes sure this is an
input
valid. I do that a lot in my code to make sure I'm not messing with my code, but in practice in
industrial code, you shouldn't have an assert code because if something is wrong, the whole application
will fail in C++. Anyway,
skip it.
Here
I'm marking if I have visited this value before or not.
If I didn't visit it before, then this is a unique number, we just print it.
Otherwise, we mark it here as a value that
we need to mark it visited.
So this way with the visited trick, which is similar to the frequency idea, we are done with
the problem that we're facing.
In the last problem, we would like to sort the numbers.
I know that this was probably a big challenge for you, how to sort numbers.
You don't have to go to very complicated algorithms like selection sort, and blah, blah, blah.
The hint was the array has a maximum value of five hundred.
How can we make use of this idea?
The idea is very simple.
Let's compute the frequency matrix of the given input.
Now, what is the frequency of one? One.
So let's print it here.
What is the frequency of two?
One, two, three, then print three twos.
What is the frequency of three? Three, print three threes.
What is the frequency of four?
Nothing, don't print it.
What is the frequency of five? Four, print four fives.
What is the frequency of seven? Two, print two sevens.
What is the frequency of six?
Nothing, don't print.  Frequency of eight, nine, ten, eleven, and so on.
So the idea is if we know that all of the numbers are from zero to five hundred only, why not to count
the frequency of every one of them, then iterate on all of the numbers from zero to five hundred, and
print the number if it has a frequency.
That's all. I know that this isn't an easy idea, so feel free to not solve it.
Here is the frequency array.
We iterate, and we keep accumulating here, and then we iterate on all of our range if the number appeared
before, let's say, five times,
so we print it five times, four times, we print it four times.
This is actually a very popular algorithm.
It's called Count Sort Algorithm, and it depends on the idea of counting the frequency of the number
and printing it.
And this is the most efficient algorithm for sorting numbers,
if they are of small values. If they are big values, in algorithms course, you should learn about
what we call quicksort and merge sort, and some inefficient solutions like insertion sort and selection
sort.
But it was good to know about that at this moment. That's all.