homework set number three, the first one is for a butler sequence named Recaman's sequence, the word
sequence is just a bunch of elements consecutive following some relationship,
if I told you we have a sequence, 10, 20, 30, 40, you can figure out that this is like the iTH number
multiplied by ten and so on.
So this is a full sequence here, zero one three six two seven, blah, blah, blah, very big sequence.
Now, let's focus on this small one here and let's focus on the value and the index zero-based.
So the last item here in the sequence is seven,
so this is last item value is seven and its index is number five,
now, to get the next item in this sequence, there are two rules for that.
The first one is to compute the expression, last value, which is seven here, - the index,
which is five here, -one.
Compute this condition and double check two
things
First, is this value is greater than zero?
The second, did it appear before or not?
If these two conditions are okay, you are going to use it.
So here in our case, the last value is seven - last index is five - one
this is one.
The question here is a greater than zero?
Yes.
It didn't appear before?
No, one appeared before.
If this is a case and this condition failed, you are going to use the next term as the following last
value plus last index plus 1, which is thirteen.
Now you put thirteen here as the next value, and again now thirteen is the last value,
Its index is number six,
Apply the formula, decide if it's negative or not.
Is it appeared before or not.
If it satisfied the two conditions, you put it otherwise, you use the plus version.
That's how you can do it.
You will read an integer, which will be zero-based index, but it will be from one to two hundred and
then print to the value of this index,
For example, if I give you the index of six, then the output should be thirteen.
If the index is nine, then the output should be twenty one.
Seventeen, it should be twenty five and so on.
Do not use nested loops. before introducing the next problem,
I would like to stress the sliding window idea with visualizations, the word sliding window refer
to a group of consecutive numbers and in computer science we have fixed sliding window and variables
sliding the window.
So let's focus on fixed sliding window.
As you see here, we have a window of eight numbers and we call a sliding because we slide it one
step.
So if we slided this one step, it would be again of fixed size,
so it would be again, eight numbers, but now starting from eight, from two to nine,
think for a minute, what is the most very apparent relationship between the first window and the
next window?
The very visible observation is that all of the number from two to eight will come in and we have a
first number removed and we have a new number added.
If we try to slide this one step more, it will be starting from three to ten.
This is what we call a sliding window, fixed-size sliding window.
Let's assume for a while that we have this list: one zero three minus four to minus six and nine,
and let's generate all the sliding windows, all the windows coming from sliding in a length of three,
so what are the first three numbers?
One zero three.
What are the second three numbers?
Zero three minus four after that, three minus four, two and so on.
Now, sometimes we would like to make operations that, for example, we would like to give the sum of
every window.
It would be here sum equal four, sum = minus one, one, minus eight five, the sum of the items in the
window.
Sometimes I would like to find the maximum among all of these windows and so on.
And as I said, observe that the relationship between any two consecutive window is made about the
first and the last one, the variable sliding window which is out of scope
now its size grows and shrinks based on some conditions.
OK, let's move to our problem.
You will read integers K and N and K will always be less than or equal N, and then you read N
integers, you have to find a sub-array, which is a window or a consecutive number of key elements that
has the maximum sum.
This is the input that we tried in the previous slide.
And we are generating here all the windows of length three,
this is the sum of all of them observed here.
That window of five starting a position four to the position,
six of sum five is the maximum among all of the windows.
Try to do it without nested loop, but start first with nested loop, then try to do it without nested
loops.
There are two ways.
One of them based on the observation that we mentioned here, and another way that is harder as a hint
think about accumulation if it helped, but anyway it's a harder way.
So give your best.
The third problem, we should count the increasing sum-arrays, specifically, you will read N integers and count how many
sub-arrays are increasing,
we already know from the previous assignments what is an increasing array,
now, we would like to count how many ones, so let's say, as an example, we have the input,
one, two, three, four.
Let's generate all the sub-windows that we have, which would be some windows of length one and two
and three and four.
For a length one we will have only,
here, one list, second list, fourth list
For all the windows of length two, we have one two, two three, three four, of length three we have
one, two, three, then two, three, four. of length four we have one, two, three, four as a number
one, two, three, four is sorted,
all of them will be valid sequences.
so we have ten different sub-areas that are already increasing.
So here are the inputs, four number of items, four items.
This case would be ten.
If the input is reversed, then this is just four because we cannot build any increasing sub-array.
You can think of these first two cases here giving what we call lower bound and upper bound, the lower bound
and the answer would be the length of the sequence,
the upper bound of the answer has some equation that can help you to develop an efficient solution
and is another.
input, forget about the idea of lower bound and upper bound,
I hope you understand now what is a problem.
Try to do it with three nested loops.
Think how can we do it with two nested loops and think how can we do it only with one loop.
By the way, when I mean something like two loops, I don't necessarily mean only two loops.
You can have two different two loops or three different loops, but they shouldn't be nested like I have
two loops doing something, then another two loops are doing something and so on.
So I'm referring to this flexibility because time-wise all of them are equal.
But if you have four nested loops, this is so different from two nested loops followed by two separate,
two separate nested loops, In the fourth problem, we'll slove a very common problem in computer science named
as Josef's
problem. For this problem, you'll read two integers N, which is like two hundred and K, which is a very
big number, but for now consider it as a small number
in the beginning.
This is a game and there's a game winning and failding here,
the idea goes as follows.
There is a group of N people in a circle.
Numbered one, two, three, four up to N,  and then someone out of this N  numbers is acting like
the master of the game.
The guy starts from person number one and starts counting at key times like person
number one, two, three, four.
Once he counted K, he killed this person or for now, let's say, removing his from the from the circle.
He keeps doing this process until there is only one person remaining.
This is the winner.
Let's see an example here.
We have four persons in a circle.
One, two, three, four.
And let's say the K is two.
So now the guy will count one, two, then remove this guy from the list, starting from the three counting
one, two.
We are here removing four from the list,
now, the one after it is on here counting one two.
Removing three from the list.
One is remaining.
One is the winner.
You should print the order of removing people from the circle,
We remove two first, four, three, then one.
Now, I would like you first to solve this problem.
when K is a small and after that thinking an efficient solution that can act with K that is very,
very big.
even bigger than that, I'm giving here you more examples and fixing seven as a number of people in the
circle and then giving you different counters, so that you can verify your solution.
In the fifth problem you are to read an integer array
all the values are either zero, or one, you should find the longest subarray such that it's
number of zeros equal to it's the number of ones,
so we need array as big as possible in terms of size, but zeros and ones are equal.
Here is is an example.
Seven for the input and this is the input, the longest array is six.
There are two examples here.
The first one is the starting from this one to this one here, which have three zeros and three
ones or the last six numbers also are a good solution. in this input.
Here we have nineteen zeros and ones and then this sub-array here of length 8 is the longest it has
one, two, three, four, four ones and four zeros.
Start with doing this problem with three loops, it will be easy  for you, then trying to think, can
you do it with two loops? even without any extra arrays?
And if you would like to go one extra mile, try to do it without any nested loops.
And an extra question, if you would like to try, there is what we call in computer science reduction, reduction
a problem to another means converting it to another format.
So you describe another problem, but they are actually the same.
So can you reduce this problem to another problem as following?
It should be the longest sub-array of zero sum, another very popular problem in computer science.
So can we convert this problem from number of zeros equal number of ones to this problem of longest
subarray of zero sum?
Think about it.
That's all.