Let's solve the third problem set, the first problem is about this sequence, observe here the max
value as an input for zero- based is two hundred.
So one thing that we need to consider while coding is that what using up to two hundred and one (201), because
the last value is 200.
So be careful about that.
To know if a value appeared or not, we need to mark that in an array. one puzzling question is what
might be the max value here?
Because the jumps jump a lot.
I use an experimental value like "N*10" .
And during developing the code and checking within the given limits and "N*10" was a valid one.
This isn't a mathematical way, but still like a good experimental one, given the the value range of
your target problem.
Far from that, I think the problem is straightforward you're going to initialize a sequence with
the first two values, like the sequence of zero is zero and occurrence of zero is one, which means
that we are marking this value here and then we keep iterating.
We compute the expression as we requested and then we verify the two things if it is less than
zero.
And also it didn't appear before, we just use it as a current value.
Otherwise, sorry, if it is this is zero or visited before then we move to the plus version of the
equation.
After that, we mark that this is the current value, and its index here is marked as visited before.
So again, marking values in an array or computing the frequency is coming back in more problems to
show how can we develop efficient solutions.
And the second problem we would like to do this sliding window problem here; which is a sliding window,
is something that's very common in industry.
I'm doing it right now with my work.
So something that you should know about. In the first,
the solution here, I'm trying to code it for every window.
So this is what we call brute force.
Remember, the word brute force means to try everything that there is no thinking of it.
You can code it in two different ways.
The way that I use is to consider the "i" here as iterating over every window.
And then the "j" is just counting to the "k" times.
And then from "i" and "i+j" for "j" from zero to "k" is the current array.
You can do it in with two loops, but in different times.
Observer here to avoid accessing the index outside the window, I'm writing "n-k+1"
"n-k+1"
So this is guaranteeing that we don't get outside the current window.
I would like to learn you a trick that will help you a lot when you are puzzled about should we add
plus one or not.
The trick is as following:  "n" is one-based value, "k" is one-based value when you subtract
one-based value from one-based value, the result is zero-based value. And we know that when
we write "i" less something, we need something that is one-based value.
So adding plus one here convert it from zero-based value to one-based value.
So all we think about is what you are adding or subtracting, if you are subtracting to a zero-based value,
the result is
zero-based value.
If you are subtracting 2 one-based values, the result is zero-based value.
If you are subtracting one-based value from zero-based value, then the result would be one-based value.
If you are subtracting zero-based value from one-based value, you are doing
something wrong because the result could be negative value.
So this is how I, generally speaking, handle the plus one or plus zero for the for the zero-based
or one-based.
The second trick is about verification, like is it really the correct one here?
One easy way to do that is to to think about the very, very, very minimal values.
So I would like to verify the correctness here, go to what we call the lower bound.
What is the lowest value for "k"? one.
Then one means that we are actually testing every value.
So we are now making it like a maximum sample array.
So "n-1+1"  is "n".
And so it's like iterating over every element in there.
Perfect? Yes.
Perfect.
Let's verify the internal one for "j" less than zero and "j" than "k" which is one.
So "j" will be zero. Array plus zero, which is some zero, which is just an array for "i".
Correct?
Correct.
So these are the two tricks that I would like you to keep in mind.
The subtraction: one-based&one-based, zero-based& zero-based, one & zero-based tricks to know that are you zero based or one
based; based on the need.
And the second is going to the lower bound to verify if are you doing it correctly or not. Inmany times
the guys would go with the actual example,
but the lower bounds are always the best way to make sure that you are correct.
So anyway, this is a brute force solution.
Now let's go one step higher to something that is more efficient because the bigger solution is
just two nested loops.
And the idea here depends on what we see in the slides of removing an element and entering an element
here in the visualization.
I told you the next window is removing the first element and entering the next element and so on.
So the idea is let's build the first window and after that, from every next step, we remove the
first one, add the next one.
So if one efficient code is just to follow this idea.
Sorry.
Here we start with, first of all, summing the first "k" values in the array, and after that starting
from "k" indicating where are we starting the current window sorry, where are we ending
the current window?
So "k" is now the next end.
And that's why here I didn't need to change "i < n" end because "k" is actually representing the end of
the window.
In every time we are going to update the sum is as following, removing the first element which will
now be "i-k", and adding the current element, which would be an array of "i". Observe here again, "i" is
zero!
I is like like.... we are now
puzzling is "i-k" , correct or not?
OK, let's, let's go with the lower bound idea.
What is the lower bound here?
Put in "k" with one.
OK so when you put "k" is one here, then "i" equal one.
The "i-k" would be one minus one which is zero.
So now we are actually accessing the first element in the array that we would like really
to remove it.
And here we are going to add it again.
If you'd like to go one step higher, let's say "k" equal 2 and then this one would be representing the
first two elements.
So "k" now
"k" now equal 2. Again, two minus two is zero.
Perfect?
Yes, perfect.
And now we are adding an array of two which is a next turn.
Yes.
Perfect.
And we are definitely less than the boundary.
So we are correct.
So here with the indices and the lower boundary check, we can make sure that yes.
These are valid ones.
I'm telling you these tricks because I know that probably you waste a lot of time getting run time errors and
going out of the array and all of that.
To mark the....,  observer here, the "min_index", we need to go one window of "i-(k-1)" to mark
the start of the current window again with some basic verification.
You can know that all this is really the correct starting one.
So use the lower bound idea to make sure that you are correct.
Observe here, "k" is one-based value.
When you remove "k-1", "k-1" is a zero-based value. When you subtract zero-based value
from zero-based value,
it is zero-based value.
That's why you are more sure that this is really an index.
The last approach, which is a bit harder for you to guess, is the accumulation array, an accumulation
is very common in computer science and the idea is as following, let's say the input is one,
five, seven, six, two, five.
I would like to show you something.
Let's say accumulate this array.
Let's accumulate this array
If we accumulated it, we will have here one. Accumulation means the submission from the first element
to the current element.
So what is the submission from one to five here?
The submission from one to five.
The first two elements, sorry would be six.
The submission of the first three elements would be thirteen.
The submission of the first four elements would be nineteen.
The submission of the first five elements would be twenty one, and then the submission of all of the
elements would be twenty six.
OK, so far so good.
But observe if we try to do this accumulation, regardless how we would make use of it, we are going
to waste like two nested loops also to build that here.
So what's the point.
Still nested loops! here is the trick in building the accumulation array in an efficient way. Observe
that this is six.
For example, you tried to compute and get the nineteen.
We computed the sum from one to four, all of the first four elements.
But the observation is if we added six to the accumulation of the previous step, we get that value.
If we added this value to the current two, we give this value for the current accommodation to the
current value.
We give this value.
It means all that you need is to add yourself over the accumulation of the previous elements.
And this is what's happening here.
I am accumulating the array by starting from...,  this one needs to be two hundred because I am building
this one using one-based.
So one way to make your life easier with accumulation is to make it one-based indexing, not zero-based.
That's why you have less than or equal in here.
So now we are reading the current value and I'm accumulating the current value plus the accumulation
of the last step.
This is what is building here.
So first add one, five plus one is six, then seven plus six is thirteen, six plus thirteen is
nineteen and so on.
So this is accumulation rate.
Now the question here is, what is the relationship between this accumulation and our problem?
Here is an observation.
What is twenty six?
Twenty six is a submission from the first element to the current element.
What is nineteen? nineteen is a submission from the first element to the current element.
So it seems like it getting us a window some, but it is actually a window starting from position zero.
What if I would like to get a window of something specific?
Let's say I would like only to give the window of six, two, and five which should be six and two is eight, and
plus five thirteen.
The idea is to subtract twenty six from one element before the start, which is thirteen.
If you subtract a twenty six from thirteen it would be thirteen.
Another example, let's say you would like to give the submission from seven to two, subtract twenty
one from six to get the answer, which is seven and six would be thirteen and two it would be fifteen,
which is really the subtraction of that.
So the moral of that is the advantage of accumulation array is
you can get in a single step the submission of any window by subtracting the big window from the small
window.
So that's why here we have this subtraction. By subtracting array of 'i"  minus array of "i-k",
got a window.
Some of "k" elements starting from "i" to "k" elements after it, including it.
I hope you got the idea.
I would like you to try to put some time to verify why when we would like to get, for example, this
window submission by subtracting this number minus this number would get for me the middle?
It's more about like....,  let's do it here for sake of completeness.
What is twenty one?
Twenty one is the sum of a one plus five plus seven plus six plus two.
And what is thirteen?
Thirteen is one plus.
One plus five plus seven, OK, that's why when you subtract the 21 from the 13, you're actually cancelling
these three values with these three values, and remain for you the six plus two.
That's why when you subtract this guy from this guy, you get the submission window of this one.
So the message is, I hope you didn't get lost. The message is
First one, you can build accumulation with a single loop by adding the current element to the previous
accumulation.
Message number two, that accumulation array directly can get you the submission of every window starting from
zero to the current index by just axing array of "i".
The third message is that the accumulation array can help you get a sub-window by subtracting the current
accumulation minus the target index, but minus extra one.
This is all the dual messages.
Now, going back to the code, we iterate over all of the array, mixing it up to "n" and every time
we get the window sum ending at the current position and after that we maximizing over all of them.
This solution isn't easy.
And also you do learn this solution in algorithms courses.
But I wanted to share it with you.
It's a bit hard, but if you try to like paper and pencil, you should master it more.
That's all.