Let's solve the count increasing sub-array problem, which might be a bit hard to get an efficient
solution, the first version is a brute-force solution, which is just try every possible array length
and that's all.
So we are going to try every possible length for the array and for every one of them.
We will start from zero and move to n - length + 1, we talked before about
the correctness of this expression and then for every one of them, we will iterate over the whole list starting
from one to the length as long as it is OK.
And then we would like to verify if every element is less than or equal to the next element.
And you have to be careful about the indexing
a little bit of the expression.
Yeah, and that's all, if the window is perfect, that's good, otherwise we make it false result
plus equal is OK, would either add one or false.
So this is over all three nested loops, try every length, start from every start, iterate over the
whole window, make sure it's correct otherwise ok, I hope it is easy and clear for you.
So now let's see how can we make this in an efficient way.
The observation is in the second and the third solutions,
There are a lot of duplications in terms of the computation that we are doing and if we started to observe
what are these duplication, then
we are going to save our time.
Now, the idea is as following, why keep starting from every possible start and keep going like let's
say the first four elements are increasing.
Why when you would like to start to test the next element,
You start from scratch again, like this solution keeps starting from every start for every end.
But if the first, thinking about array that's completely sorted, for example, and the first four numbers
now in length four are sorted, then they are also will be sorted
in length five
if the next element after the four elements is also sorted.
So the idea is to avoid all of these duplications. To make use of that,
The idea is as following.
We will start from every start and then from that start, as long as we can keep going, then keep
going and add one more element.
So, maybe an example would be better
idea.
Let's say that we have something like one, five, seven, eight and two
and three, we are starting at one here.
So, we are incrementing result++ first because we definitely have an array of length one.
So ++ here.
Now this for Loop will keep going as long as the sequence is increasing now.
Is five increasing?
Yes.
So now we are adding one more ++ because we have now one more sequence and then one five seven.
Yes, add one more sequence.
One five seven eight.
Yes.
Add one more sequence. one five seven eight two?
No, break it and go ahead and start from five again.
Now five is one sequence here.
Five seven is another sequence.
Five, seven, eight is another sequence, five seven eight two isn't and so on.
So the idea is, keep expanding the current window as long as you can.
And with every expansion we actually have one more result and so on.
I hope if you are doing that with me, although we make it now two nested loops only, you should
also figure out that we are actually having one more source of duplication, when we kept computing
from one to eight.
And we added four sequences because the length is four when we started at five, we again added five,
seven, eight, which we know from the previous result should be OK.
It is just from the suffix direction and now seven, eight also and eight
now, actually the observation is, do we need to start from five and seven and eight or just to jump
to the two?
The answer is to jump directly to the two, if one five seven eight is a valid increasing sequence,
every subsequence inside it is a valid subsequence.
Now, how many increasing subsequences do we have here?
It will be n*n+1/2 where n is the length here, which is four.
And this is the idea of the third solution, which is linear one and very efficient.
The idea is as long as the sequence is increasing, then yeah, the idea is if we have an increasing
sequence of length four, then all of the four times five over two subsequences inside it are actually
valid one.
So we can keep going, get the one increasing sub-sequence and add n*(n+1)/2
..
Or for simplicity, we can just keep adding the current length for us.
So, we keep reading here
as long as the sequence is increasing, we keep adding its length.
If it failed at any point, we mark its length with one and then the i is starting from the next, from
the next element.
So let's make an example.
Let's again say one five, seven, eight, nine, ten, and then two, three, four, five, for example.
Now one, add one.
We start here with this one, one five.
Yes.
Add two, because we have now a sequence of length two, one five seven, add three.
Because we now have three sequences, one five seven eight, add four because we now have four sequences
ending at eight, one five seven eight nine, add five because we have five sequences ending at nine.
They are the nine, 8 9, 7 8 9, 5 7 8 9, 1 5 7 8 9 and so
on.
When we reach to the two we find that this is violating.
So we start again from scratch with length equal one for the two and do the same, if you don't get the logic
why adding the length, you can just compute the length so far and multiply n*(n+1)/2
not n
Let's call it m, m+(m+1)/2, but I hope you can get it.
So, the moral of these three solutions, this is what we call observation skills, by observing
what is
happening by digging in the details, you can figure out more and more optimizations.