Let's see how to solve the last problem here, which is a bit easy for a three loops, medium for two
loops, but hard to do it with only a single loop.
So let's see how to code it. In the first version,
you would like to just go brute force, just try everything.
Let's just try every start.
And then from this start, we will try all of the possible ends for every start.
And we can iterate in between counting the number of zeros and ones.
If the number of zeros and ones are equal, then we got it.
We have a valid array.
Keep maximizing among all of them.
So far, so good.
But you probably observe that, there is a lot of duplications here in a very similar to what we did
before in one of the assignments.
So let's see what can we do here. In this one, we noticed that if we tried every start and every end,
what about keeping incrementing the array and expanding it; the expanding idea like keep expanding
and while expanding, maintain the number of zeros and ones. We don't need to keep every time from start
to end and keep iterating between all of them.
We have a start here.
We have an end that is expanding. With every expansion,
we update the zeroes and ones and then if they are equal, we got one more case now.
So far, so good.
The third case is a bit hard
one. I wrote a clarification example here to show you the idea of it.
Let's say that this is the input, I took it from the slides.
I would like to maintain four types of information.
Let's maintain the total number of zeros that we have so far.
For example, here so far, we have five zeros from here.
Here we have seven zero so far and so on in a similar way.
We maintain here
the number of ones so far.
For example, here we have four ones; two from here, three, four, and then maintain the zeros minus
the ones or the ones minus the zeroes.
So let's compute the total number of zeros minus total number of ones.
For example, at this position we have five zeros and 1 one only,  five minus one is four.
Here we have six zeroes.
We have two ones.
Six minus two is four.
The last item here is first time. I'm recording the first time such a difference appeared, for example,
this is the first time, the five difference appear, but they are three differences appeared before
here.
So we maintain it here.
I also added here a difference 0.
This is before the processing of the array, because before we start, we have a zero difference between
the zeros and ones.
So this is something like a precondition and also the first time to have such a condition.
It is very clear if let's say we are here and the difference between zeros and ones is zero.
It means actually all of that will be zeros.
Right.
Let's pretend that this is actually zero.
Sorry.
Yeah.
Let's pretend that the difference is zero.
It means actually a very direct way.
The total here number of zeros and ones is equal.
But what does it mean to have here five as a difference?
Let's forget about five.
What does it mean to have four here as a difference and four here as a difference?
This range. what does it mean to have the same difference
Several times? I would like you to stop the video for five minutes and think about it.
What does it mean to have here 4 and 4?
What does it mean to have here two and again, another two here and try from that to get an idea to
solve the problem?
We're almost done with it.
The idea is similar to what we did in the accumulation sum. If this position is 4, and this position
is 4,
it means that the number of items in between after this 4 and up to this 4 must be an equal number
of zeros and ones.
So we have here zero, zero, zero, one, two, three, four zeros and one, two, three, four ones.
It means if we subtracted this guy, it means that this window must have a total number of zeros equal
to the total number of ones.
OK, because this extra gap between number of zeros and ones can be discarded by subtracting that window
before it.
So remember the accumulation.
sum we used to have this window to get the window
we need to; we used to subtract all of that from that is exactly the same idea having here a two and
another two.
It means that this window corresponding to this range must have equal number of zeros and ones.
So we have here one, one, one, one.
We have four ones and we have four zeros.
This is the moral of the idea.
So to implement that, all what you need is to keep maintaining the total number of zeros and ones as you go,
specifically keep maintaining the difference between them.
And whenever you have a repeated difference, then this window must be total number of zeros equal
to the number of ones. As we would like to maximize,
we would like to know the first time a difference appear.
So for example, here is the first time 4 appears.
Now, the last 4 with the first 4 will help us to get the best window for this case.
Again, the first two is marked.
Now we are facing two.
We are facing two.
Then this window is again a bigger one.
If you understood the idea, try to stop the video and implement it by yourself.
If not, let's go into details.
As you notice, the difference here can be positive or negative.
Let's say the array length is one thousand.
I know on the slides, I mentioned this is less than 1000, but let's pretend that they are actually one thousand maximum.
Then in the worst case, we can have all of them as ones.
So the result can be 1000 or all of them can be zeroes.
So the result would be...,  the difference would be minus one thousand.
So overall we are ranging from one thousand...,
-1000 to
1000.
We have overall two thousand and one values.
We can use the shift idea to implement a difference array that maintains the differences for us.
So that's why I am having here I am maintaining big differences here, this big value just to maintain
that this never appeared before.
And then we read the array and we start reading and first marking the zero. I'm adding here +1000,
it would be like shifting the negative to be positive.
So we would like to mark zero first, as appeared before the start of the array, and then let's go
over the array. If the value zero,
we add one.
If the value is..., sorry. That the value is one, we add one. If the value is zero, we add negative one.
Now "added" represented the total number, the difference between ones and zeros here, ones and zeros,
zeros and ones, ones and zeros starting from the big int  array up to the index.
I again make a shift here.
Now there are two cases.
Either this difference never appeared before or appeared before.
If the difference appeared before, we just the mark it with the first
position that the "i" appeared in it.
Otherwise, we now know that we have one more location with the same difference.
So the "subarrayLength" that we would like should be from my current position to the first position that
appeared and then maximize over it.
That's all I hope you got it.
We are trying to maintain the difference between ones and zeros.
We are marking the first time the difference appeared.
We are maximizing on the array length that we have so far and that's it, the whole trick was this difference
between zeros and ones.
And to a large extent, it was like inspired by the motivation, by the accumulation idea.