That's a practice on arrays. The first problem is you are given N numbers and they are distinct,
distinct means, they are different numbers.
You are to find the maximum and the first maximum and the second maximum variable in the array.
For example, here, (10, 20,   3, 30, 7).
The two maximum values here are (30 and 20).
OK.
So the logic is that you can think if I remove 30, who is the next maximum, it's just 20. I would like you to
stop the video and think how to code it.
So here's one way to code it, the idea is as following, you find the first maximum value index,
then you mark it with a very small value, then you find again the first maximum value,
and this is now your second max.
So here is the code.
We read the N numbers that we have and we do a normal (for loop) to find the index
of the maximum value.
Now I'm taking the max value outside and I'm marking the array, this index with a very,
very small value.
Then I'm getting the same code again to find the next maximum value.
One disadvantage in this code, that we needed to loop here once and here once, so we twice loop.
The second is we need to mark this cell with a very, very negative value.
But we aren't sure like we need to find some variable that definitely doesn't exist in the array.
And if someone put here, minus two million, for example, is going to fail. Our work is around this second
problem is just to double check that we aren't using the same index one before.
That's it.
Let's make it in a different way.
In this case, I am trying to maintain the two values for (max1 and max2), for example, I initially
started the program with taking the first two values in the array.
According to which one, is the maximum one.
For example, I'm seeing here,
if number zero is greater than number of one, then we know that 'max1' is number zero and 'max2' is number one.
'max2' is number one.
Otherwise, we know that 'max1' is number one and 'max2' is number zero. At this stage, at line 17,
we know that 'max1' and 'max2' has the first two values in the array. We start from two and keep going in that array.
in that array.
And it goes as following.
If 'max1' is the same number of 'i', then we definitely need number of 'i' for us.
So first, 'max1' we move it to 'max2' and then we take in the 'max1' the 'numbers[i]'
the 'numbers[i]'
This way,
We updated ourself with taking the value of the new maximum that we have.
OK, what if 'max1' is greater than actual numbers of 'i', then we don't need it but could still better than
'max2'.
So we double check here if 'max2' is less than numbers of 'i' or not, if it's the case we take it.
Using this logic, we treat it only once on the array to keep the two max values.
Here is another program I would like to read N integers, which are again distinct, find the pair
of different indices numbers whose time is maximum.
So, for example, if you read five numbers this way, the two numbers, 50 and 15, their submission
is the maximum.
So you are finding pair of numbers whose sum is maximum, but they should be of two different indices.
Don't say 50 and 50.
This is the same number.
OK, here is one way to code it.
We are going to iterate on the loop twice because we need the pair of numbers.
So one loop is from 'i' to zero.
Another loop from 'j' to zero and so on.
And we have here two indices for the answer.
Initially, they are all -1.
So first, I'm saying if it's a negative one, then we never initialize them.
That index would be 'i' and index2 would be 'j'.
Otherwise we already have two indices.
So now I would like to compare, Is the current two 'i', 'j' numbers are better than my best two numbers
numbers so far or not?
So I'm saying if the number of index1 plus number of index2 are better than numbers of 'i' and 'j' or not,
if they should be replaced, then we say index1 is 'i' and index2 is 'j'.
So the moral of that is, try every bit of numbers and keep the two ones that have the maximum sum.
There is a bug in this code.
And also from an efficiency perspective, half of the operations are useless. I would like to figure out
what is the bug and also how to make it more efficient.
The first bug the that we have here, is that we started 'j' with zero, this actually means that there's
a chance that, for example, we take a position 'i' was zero and zero twice or 'j' was one
and one.
But the program asked us for different indices, so to set with different indices, we needed
to make it a bit different, to make sure that 'i' not equal 'j'.
The second issue is, that we were actually trying, for example, let's say 'i' was (2), and 'j' was (4)
and after some time.
'i' was (4), and 'j' was (2).
We are actually doing every step twice.
OK, so one step that we could use to do that, is starting with 'j' starting from (i+1),
this actually solves the bug and also,
also it avoids us this duplicate of operation.
So far, so good.
But there's an interesting question here.
Can you do this problem with only a single loop?
Can we find pair of numbers with a single loop?
Think about it.
The answer is very intuitive and very simple, if you would like to find two numbers whose
sum is maximum, why don't you just find the maximum value and the second maximum value and that's it.
that's it.
So with a snigle loop, we actually can solve this problem.
That's it! :)