Let's do more practice on the 1D arrays. The first program is you would like to read N numbers
and then (you are going to read them definitely in an array) and you are to do a reverse in-place.
What does it mean "In-place"?
In place means that you don't take more memory.
That means that you don't, for example, create a second array to do the reverse.
I would like you to to try to think for a minute, how can we do that in an array without creating another
array to help with the reverse.
So the idea is, as simple as, we can start from the beginning and the end and look to the half of the array,
swab the first number with the last number, then swab the second number with the last second number
from here.
And so on, step by step till the middle, we can this way swab the whole array. Please iterate on this computation
and make sure that you understand the reverse through the swab idea.
In terms of code, we just read the array of, say, up to 200 numbers, then we walked to the middle
of the array and then for position 'i', will get the corresponding one for it, which is (n-i).
which is (n-i).
This is very important to be like very intuitive for you to compute the last number in this way
or be like symmetric number.
After that, you do normally swabbing like we did before in an assignment.
You just create a temporary variable.
Take a copy from here, assign it here
assign that back here.
After that you are done,
you just double think with yourself,
What happens if 'n' is even and if 'n' is odd and this computation.
Another exercise, we would like to read N numbers and find the most frequent number, the most frequent number is
is the number that was like used the most, ok! Each integer in this 200 numbers will be between
zero and one hundred and fifty.
So we have two hundred numbers and the value of each number is maximum,
one hundred and fifty.
As an example, this is an array of one, two, three, four, five, six, seven.
So given seven numbers and then seven numbers, you find that, for example, that the (1) was
repeated three times.
This is the largest frequency, then (2) is repeated once and (5) is repeated twice.
So the answer here is,  ... one, One was repeated three times.
OK, an easy way to do that is, as simple as, you just iterate on the array and then in another nested array,
you use it to compute how many times this value was used.
For example, you take the value 'a[i]' and check how many numbers 'a[i]', then take 'a[1]',
how many numbers of 'a[1]', and so on.
So we need a second loop that iterates on the array again and then double check how many ones were created.
So repeating now, will have how many times?
number[i] exist.
After that, we are going to update our max-repeated value with the maximum value.
So the 'max_value' and 'max_repeat' are just coming from the max frequent value,
then we say 'max_value' repeated 'max_repeat' times. Checking line 18,
I said 'repeat += numbers[i] == numbers[j]', in practice, I would like you to put parentheses.
Meanwhile, this is still a valid expression because the '==' has higher priorities and the '+='.
'+='.
So this expression is evaluated first, then the repeat is added here.
Either this would be true or false.
If true, it adds one.
If false, it adds zero.
OK, and so on. And here in line twenty,
we say if 'max_repeat == -1', it means that we didn't find any...
We didn't start yet.
Once we started we double check the 'max_repeat' is less than the current repeat or not. This code needed 2 nested loops.
2 nested loops.
If you have an array of (1000000 numbers), this code will do (10^12) operation!
It would be extremely slow.
So one question here.
Can you do it using a single looping only, think seriously about it, as a hint for you think in using another array.
array.
Here is a trick.
There is something that we call frequency array.
It is as simple as we compute the frequency in this array.
How to do that?
Define a new array, name it frequency.
We know that the numbers range from (zero to 150).
So 150 is our maximum number.
So we need [150+1] in the frequency array.
When we do these braces,
it means that we are sitting all of it to zero, all of it to zero.
Now we iterate on the input, read it and say here 'frequency[numbers[i]]++'.
What does this do?
Let's say that we reached number ten.
So we say frequency of [10++] now frequency of ten, is one.
Let's say that we read again ten, then frequency of [10++] now of ten is two and so on.
on.
So this frequency array now, will have the frequency of every number appeared in the input.
But now you just iterate and get the maximum of this array as we did before.
This way, we we broke a program of two nested loops to two separate loops.
This one just like almost one million operation or so!
That's it! :)