Homework set number one. In the first problem would like to check if an array is an increasing or not,
you will read an integer N  followed by reading N integers like here, reading four then four numbers,
five then five numbers.
We label an array as an increasing if every element is greater than or equal to the previous element.
For example, consider here one, two, two five.
The two is greater than one.
Two is greater than or equal two, five is greater than equal two.
So this is yes.
This is an increasing array.
On the other side, zero is less than one five.
So this zero is less than one.
So this breaks it, here -10 and ten,
Ten is greater than or equal -10
so yes, overall.
So check for every element of it's greater than or equal to the previous element.
And the second problem will read an integer, you will read an array and then we will have to do the following.
We should find the minimum number and then find the maximum integer, replace each minimum with a maximum.
For example, here is an array of seven numbers and then the minimum is one, and the maximum
is ten.
we would make a swap
the minimum would be maximum, so the one would be ten and the maximum values would be the minimum values.
in the third problem, we would be given an array of up to 1000 values, less than 1000 values and
the values, all of them are between zero and 500.
So every element in the array would be between zero and 500.
The N numbers are ordered from small to large.
So they are one, two, two, five, six, as you see they are sorted numbers.
We would like to find only the unique list of them.
For example, one is repeated twice,
we need only one of them,
The two we need one of them, the five one six twice when only one of them and so on.
So these are the unique list.
In other words, we are getting rid of the duplicate numbers.
We need to preserve the order, which would be the case here.
preserving the given order means, seven here is given before nine
then you should have a seven before nine, given that the list is ordered.
this doesn't make a lot of sense here, but if the list is unordered, as we will see in another assignment,
then it would make sense for you.
So for now, you can focus on making them unique numbers.
So observe they are ordered here.
This also will be sorted.
I would like you to consider the following constraints, first
don't use nested loops.
Second, you either use only one single array or even do it without using arrays at all.
So feel free to go as hard as you can.
In this constraints.
In the fourth number, we would like to check if something, if an array given, would be palindrome or not, a string
or an array is palindrome if we can read it from the backward seem as forward.
For example, here, the array,
one, two, three, two, one
this is palindrome because regardless if you read it form forward or backward
it's same and so on.
So you will read an array and judge it with
yes, if it's palindrome with.
no it isn't palindrome array.
in the fifth problem, you would like to read an array of N numbers, find the smallest possible result
of the following expression: A[i] + A[j] + j -1, try when you sketch the solution to
this problem, to think about kind of evidence or proof or like a good intuition why your approach should
be correct.
I found some guys doing some solutions that they lack the ability to justify the correctness of their
proposed solution.
That's all.