Let's see how to solve the problems, the first one is about the increasing array, this one should be
straightforward.
We will read the array content here and then we would like just to check if every element is, like, if any
element is less than the previous element, then we know that it isn't increasing anymore.
We started with an increasing equal one, like, a boolean.
True.
And then we keep iterating to check if any of these items would be violating that.
Once we find that one item is less than the previous one, we know it isn't increasing anymore and we
break the loop and after that we just do printing.
In the second problem, we would like to replace the MinMax.
So this is mainly find the min, find the max and do the replacements. To do that,
We see here, we are going to read all of the array.
We are going to read the array.
And while reading, we will maintain two things, we will maintain the minimum value, and we would like
to maintain the maximum value.
Whenever you are trying to do a min and max, minimization or maximization, you need to be careful about
your initial value.
So here it say that assume that the minimum value is zero and the maximum is two thousand.
For that purpose, we can initialize the maximum with minus one, which is less than the possible minimum value
or any value
less than zero would be OK. On the other side, we can initialize the minimum with any value greater than
two thousand.
If there are no given limits, C++ provide other limits, like, you can use the minimum possible
value in C++ and maximum possible value in C++ for that case.
But the moral of that be very careful about your initial values for variables.
For that, we keep minimizing over the minimum during reading.
We keep maximizing over the variables while reading.
And after that, we just need to make the swap operation or replacement operation.
So if the current value is equal to the minimum, we will change it to the maximum.
If it's equal to the maximum, we change it to the minimum.
And that's all.
Observe here, this code will not print a space after the last number, using this if condition,
It will not print the space after the last number.
In the third homework, we would like to find the unique numbers among a list, but this list is an
orderd
list.
When you are attacking a problem in this course or in software engineering,
There are what we call constraints, constraints or given extra information help us typically to find
the better solutions.
So when you think about this problem, given that they are sorted numbers or ordered numbers,
This is, like, a useful information for you.
You should think of how can I make a solution based on that?
The idea is very simple.
Let's say we would like to find unique numbers and we would like to make use of the fact that they are
sorted numbers.
We can keep going on the numbers and observe here,
This is one, if this one is the same as the previous one, then definitely it is repeated.
So we need to cancel it.
If two is not equal to the one, then it means it is the first one of its type.
So we print this two. When we go to this two, we find it equal to the previous, we ignore it and
this one is equal to the previous.
We ignore it.
This one is different than the previous.
So it is the first of its kind.
This is only valid because the array is already sorted.
So here to solve this problem, we just need to keep going during the array and just make sure that if
the item doesn't equal the previous item all what we need is to print it, otherwise, we just ignore it.
This is mainly making use of the fact that the array is sorted.