This is another solution to the previous problem that is exactly the same logic, but it's just making
one more advantage here, you know, that the array is sorted so we can keep only the last value on the
current value to make a judgment if we need to print or not.
So instead of saving the values and then iterating to check if the value is equal to the previous one,
all what we need is just to the previous one.
For that purpose, we don't need even to create an array.
So this array here, as you see, is now useless.
No need for such an array as an input here.
Let's move.
The next problem is palindrome problem.
The palindrome is a very common problem in computer science.
To think about the palindrome problem, all what you need is to compare
If its reading from left to right is as same as right to left.
But there is an observation here.
Do we need to make a complete iteration from left to right?
The answer is no.
It is enough to walk only to half the array, so only half of the content and make sure that the first
half is the same as the second half.
This is all what we actually need to make sure that the array is palindrome.
If it happened at any moment that they aren't equal, then we just say no.
Otherwise, we say yes.
So this is all what you need to check if a number is a palindrome or not.
The last one is the smallest pair problem.
This is just a direct brute force approach, in which the word the brute force is coming from algorithms
field and it means we are trying everything.
So instead of trying to be smart about the solution, we can just make nested of loops here, one for
loop on the i, one for over the j.
But be careful, start from i + 1, you don't need here to duplicate the operation, like, you need
to try every i and every j, right?
Makes sense.
This is a very important optimization.
Make sure that you understand it. In every step,
We try to take the tmp, the value that was requested from us and keep minimizing among all of them.
Now observe that one of the guys try to do the following.
He tried to find the first minimum and the second minimum and then compute the equation and
that's it.
But if you tried the following test case, you will notice that his idea failed the first and second
minimum are the first and last element.
But these two elements, for example, are a much better solutions.
The motivation behind his solution the he was trying to make it without nested loops.
But be careful when you propose a solution.
Try to consider like some evidence
Why?
Why do you think it is the correct one?
That's all.