Homework number two and the first problem will read an integer N for a set of numbers, but it would
be at least greater than or equal three and you will read this N number.
So you would like to find the smallest three integers among all of them.
For example, here we have an array of five numbers that the smallest numbers are one, three
and four.
And I'm printing them here from small to large, seven, nine minus two.
Also, I'm printing them there from small to large base.
Consider the following.
You shouldn't change the array content.
You shouldn't iterate on the array more than once, these are my constraints.
If they are hard for you, ignore them.
In this problem.
You will read an array of length N and but all of the values would be between zero and five hundred.
We would like to search this array for some numbers as queries.
So first we will read the number, the Integer Q which represented the number of queries and for every
query you will read an integer and find the last occurrence in the array of Q, if it doesn't exist
print minus one.
For example, here we read an array of length five which are these five numbers.
We have three queries, seven, nine, and two, for the query seven
you notice that the seven existed twice in position two and in position four the last occurrence should be four
for the query nine nine, doesn't exist, so we bring two minus one. for the query one
it just exists in the first position
so we return the position one.
Sorry, sorry, the query is two, which is position one, not one, so I get confused, try to start
the problem by doing it with two nested loops, to do with nested loops,
but after that, I try to do it without any loops.
in the third homework, you should read, an array of up to 200 integers, find the value that repeated
the most number of times, consider the following,
the value in the given array would be from minus 500, up to two seven hundred, a two hundred and seventy.
So, for example, this is seven numbers and these are the numbers and observe here that minus one is
repeated three times.
So this is expected out from you: minus one repeated three times, something like that.
or just minus one, no no, minus one repeated three times.
Don't use nested loops.
in this one, you will read number N and for every digit for all the...
Read an integer N for all digits from zero to nine we want to know how many times appeared
Yeah.
OK, sorry, here we have, we are reading here two numbers,  72 and 307 for all of the numbers
here,
consider all of their digits from zero to nine.
We would like to get the frequency of the digits from zero to nine.
For example, observe that digit seven, for example, digits seven appeared here once and here another
time.
So we write here, seven two, observe the digit three, for example, digits three appeared
only once here, the digit zero appeared only once here.
Digit six never appeared.
So for all of these given numbers, count the frequency of their digits and then print for me the frequency
for the digits from zero to nine.
And here in this one, we will find the unique numbers of a list,
but this time the list is unordered.
Consider the following,
the N can be up to nine hundred.
But what is more important?
The values from zero to five hundred now print the unique list of numbers.
But preserve serve is a given order,
the order preserves the given order would make more sense hear,
the output for this input is one five two seven three, the one for once time, five appeared twice so It printed here one
only, two once, five repeated seven, yes put it here.
But ignore this seven, three put it here.
So as you see, we ignored every duplicate of the number by preserving the order,
we noticed that five hear appeared before two,
so in the output five appeared before two.
So this is what we name the given order, this is preserving the order.
So we have some times sorting the values from small to large, sometimes by preserving the given order.
Do not use, again, the nested loops. Sorting the numbers,
you would like to sort a given input of numbers.
However, the very important constraint here is that the value of all of the given numbers are from
zero to 500.
Give your best to give your efficient algorithm, please.
don't Google how to sort numbers, sorting is a very fundamental problem in computer science.
If you googled, you'll find a lot,
and most of them I don't need it.
You can solve this problem without googling,  just think about it.
The hint that I would like you to make use of,  is that the max value in the array is just five hundred.
So how can we make use of that?
That's all.