Let's see the second set of the problems, we would like to find the minimum of three values, this problem
might be coded in many different ways.
So don't feel bad if your solution is different than mine.
So here is one way to do it.
The idea is as following. In the first three numbers that we read, I'm reading here, and the first three
values,
We are just putting it in a very small array of length three, which is equal to the minimum three values
that we would like to do.
And then if we have more elements than three elements, I do a very basic trick.
I iterate on the whole array of three elements to find the maximum one among them.
And then if the current value is less than this maximum one among the current three values,
I just replace it. In this way
In every single iteration, I keep the main array updated with the minimum value among all of the current
elements.
So overall, this is an efficient solution because G is just a small one.
In practice, if we have to find like much more bigger than three, then we should find better solutions
using STD as we'll learn later.
So this is mainly the idea here.
Keep iterating the first three values put them here, otherwise, get the maximum and replace them with it. After that,
I would like to order the three values so that we print them in a sorted way.
To do that, I'm just having here some logic also to just order them, and we already ordered
the three values before, if you remember.
So this is just one also logic to just sort them from small to large.
And after that, I'm just printing the array as it is.
Again, if you're having the ordering in the way that we did before or any different way, that's
OK.
And the second problem, we would like to search for a number and one of the given information that
we should utilize is a zero up to 500.
Definitely this problem is very easy with nested loops.
It looks like you don't need to do a lot of magic.
But the point is how to get rid of the nested loops.
to do that, we need to make use of the frequency array style.
So let's see.
Here is the direct way, You read the array, with every query you iterate on the array from the end to
find the target number and stop, we iterate from the end because we have here a request to find the last
occurrence, and that's all.
So this is nested loops. to get rid of the nested loops.
We will do a simple trick.
We will create an array of length 500 plus one.
So this is our frequency array or marking array call it whatever we are using plus one here, because the
values itself are from zero to five hundred and this means we need 501 numbers.
So always be very careful when you are accessing an array with a value, and then we initialize all of
this array with minus ones.
There are easier way to initialize than this way.
But anyway, for now we can just iterate and initialize minus one. the meaning of
minus one here that it doesn't exist.
OK, so that's why you have minus one here after that, when we read the array.
We keep getting the value as an index and mark it with "I", for example, let's say in the
first position we read value two hundred.
Then we go to array of 200 and mark zero here.
After that we get the value 70.
So we go to array of 70 and assign one.
After that we got 200 again, we'll go to array of 200 and now set the value of 2 observe that 200
appeared twice.
But as we are updating the answer, this means the array will always have the last occurrence
value here.
And then after that we just answering the query with a single loop.
As you see, we have a single loop here, and a single loop here, and a single loop here, so we're perfect.
So we have three single loops.
This is very, very efficient compared with having nested loops. ...I don't want
to dig in the details now, but in algorithms you learn about the complexity.
And when you have a single loop like that that's actually doing kind of any steps, we call it like
linear order.
So this is fine as long as you have multiple single loops.
This is OK also if you have multiple nested loops, but independent ones, they are also of the same
number of overall total number of steps in the solution.
Anyway, let's skip that for now.
Let's stop here.