In this video, you will learn about one of the rappers in C++ is named Optioning the word Rapper Mean,
it's something inside it.
We learned about this Keywood in the object oriented programming.
So sometimes we would like to express that something doesn't exist.
Typically in programming, we try to do that in some workarounds.
For example, let's say we are dividing two numbers and B, we all know that we cannot divide by zero.
So if you are writing a function that has just a double header, you would like to check if, if, if,
if B is in zero, but whether are you going to return here, it would not work with you like you would
like to, to communicate to the caller that there is something wrong.
One way is just to throw an exception here.
But this isn't the best thing to do.
Maybe we can just make it simpler.
We would like to express that we are going to proceed this query.
So another way is just, OK, let's define a pool with beer and double and then if it either return
true, if we can do it otherwise return false.
So look to the function here.
We are done with it, but the function is ugly.
We have to define it in this bad way.
In general, in general, since you might have two best arguments that you would like to communicate
with the caller that this argument doesn't exist or return or something and would like to say it doesn't
exist, we can send a pointer and give it the full value of pointer.
Then this guy check and there is agreement that if a best for you not pointer, it doesn't exist or
if a best for minus one it doesn't exist or return it to you minus one, it doesn't exist.
Such agreements that we do between ourself as programmers and write some documentation about it.
But all of that is very bad ways.
C++ 17 introduced the word optional.
An optional variable is variable that simply may exist, and this is a great thing.
It might be yes or not.
So it is how you how you define it.
You say optional and give it a parameter integer x one of five.
This means we have already a variable X one that has a value five sets it.
Or you can even do optional extra to five.
This is going to reduce the parameter type of file automatically to just interfere with another other.
You can call the function, make optional and give it five and it's going to return to the variable
for you.
So these are three ways here to define it.
Now, what if you would like to say there is no value at the moment, you can define optional and give
it the value of it similar to the pointer.
It's not opt or you can even just write it MBT here.
So now we see how can we define it or as exists or it doesn't exist.
Now if I have a variable x how to know if the value exists.
There are several ways.
One of them is just to use a function that has value, which is going to check if there is value or
what if it has a value.
You can write those value to to explain why this is one way.
Another way is to use as three x three as is the dereference operator is going also to bring to the
value.
So do you know if there is a value Younus has value to use it.
You use that value or use it as another way to know if it has a value or not is to use the just not
for not X before is going to call an overloaded operator that just convert the variable to true or false
if it exists or not.
So it's just more, more nicer way to bring to the value exists.
Now what what if you try to use X5, which is empty directly without checking if it has a value or not?
If you try to call the value directly, it's going to throw a bad option and access exception if you
try to use it with a strike.
This is undefined behavior.
So your program may be crash.
Maybe not.
Now, there is one one one nicer way in an IPPEI for what you can call the value or the value or will
do as following, if there is a value, it will return it.
If there is no value, it will take this parameter, this argument, as a default value.
So here this this one will already display minus one.
Finally, if you would like to reset the variable, like you would like to remove its content, you
can call the value function that reset, or you can just like a lot and you can put another value in
a very normal way.
So overall, we have different ways to express if something exists or not.
We have different ways to express it with the variable exist.
Check if it exists or not.
And we have different ways to get the value itself and we have exceptions or undefined behavior if we
wrongly use the variable.
So the moral of that select word choice to define select what a choice to check, select one choice
to get the variable, but be careful from wrongly using it.
Now let's rewrite the divide function to make use of the optional.
We're going to define a function by two, which is optional, double now as a parameter.
When you see that, it means this function may or may not return a variable.
So I'm hearing saying this B is in zero.
This should be zero zero point.
It just to be zero.
If being equal zero, then we are normally returning eval, otherwise we are returning empty.
So either we are optional level, equal value or optional double equal empty.
This how we define it.
Now we are calling the function if there is a return we just displayed here er in our case six or zero,
there would be no value.
So we are displaying it.
Let's see one more example, this function in the box and it takes a character pointer or a Conestoga
pointer and return for us into.
The point is the function would take some string or some character pointer.
And if it can be converted to integer, we will get an integer.
But if it cannot be converted to an integer, we are going to return to nothing.
This is our logic.
So this is a function in the string header file named Estás.
I take a character pointer and they take a string and convert it back to an integer.
Remember when when we learned the basic arguments I used the function it I from the cedar, please don't
use it.
Use a string.
This is much better for you now.
This function will throw an exception if it couldn't convert a string to an integer.
So we're going to make use of it also.
So if we can convert a return to the if we can convert the return to the value, if it happened that
we have an exception, maybe you can look something and then you just return it.
So one application for that is investing the arguments you hear expecta.
The program has two numbers.
So you are passing the first one and passing the second one and saying if we manage to pass the two
values, then just bring together some.
That's it for now, but he's practicing before the next lesson.