When you study algorithms, you will hear the word in place, which means you are doing something in
a memory efficient way.
The optional and the other rivers provide some implicit functionalities.
Let's see the reasoning behind that.
It is a class for an employee that provides a copy constructor and a constructor.
And here we have a normal MBT option.
That's OK.
And we have the direct initialization for an employee for the option.
It looks perfect.
You are just doing their initialization.
But sadly, due to the way that Oakshott is implemented, this would involve unnecessary kobie browsing
the output here.
From this example, you would notice that there is an extra copy that would be destroyed.
So these are necessary, Kobie, and this is unexpected.
Also, note that you have to duplicate the word Embley here and here.
Also here you have a vector of integrated obbligato, the vector of integral.
The employees functionality come to help us to solve these two problems.
So you provided the word in place and then you just did the arguments looking to the output that doesn't
exist, looking to the output.
It should be Embley and destroying the employee only.
So the employees would help you to directly really construct the employee object in a similar way.
This is a victory of integrity.
You don't have to repeat the entire world.
You just passed the arguments here, looking to the parameters we have here, like a template, arguments
receiving a bunch of parameters and forwarding them to the constructor here.
However, there is actually one important scenario where the object actually cannot be Kobe isn't copyable
and is immovable.
In this case, the normal directress solution will not work.
So the way to go here is just to go with the place.
So this is a mandatory amendatory case for the emblazed choice usage.
Another replacement for the EMBLAZED, if you would like to suggest to you the make optional, make
optional is like make any make unique, make shared all of that.
They all share the same implementation estate and same idea, and they use that recapitulation.
So they return it from here would be directly constructed here.
So no extra Koby's also would be used from here.
Finally, if you would like to replace an object like let's say you have an employee and would like
to replace the content with another way so that employees function can be used to directly construct
a new object inside an object and in a similar way, if you have a picture of it together, we can embellish
to replace internally and in place again, take a look and take a very template and pass it to the target
object.
Overall, if you would like to have a memory efficient usage use in place or make optional or emplace
for your needs.
That's it.