Another interesting reverend, C++, 17, is a very introvert, let's introduce the case, let's say
I defined I make beer of Mustafa Antin and defining year string event.
This is normally that we have two variables here, two data types.
We have the type of type integer and another type of diversity.
We have two of them.
You can make table with two and three of them and so on.
There's a question here.
What if you would like only one of them to be available at some point?
What if you have a function that can return a double or return an integer or alternatively or even returning
nothing.
But but but the function isn't going to return.
All of them just have different different cases.
Now, this is weird.
Now we have different data types and we we just need one of them only.
So one way for us as a engineers, as a workaround is just to try to maybe have like a function that
returns a table or pair of your things.
And then some flags are to say if it exists or not.
Again, this is a waste of time.
The C++ 17 provide us with what we call Verin actually C plus C++ before that has something that's good
union and it was used but was unsafe one.
So then you C++ 17 is what we call a variant.
So it is how we define a variant.
You say variant of a string integer var unless initialized with then this means that var can hold either
string or an integer and at this time of completion it has a value of 10.
So it's an integer.
So now this isn't like a beer.
You don't have both of them.
They will be, you will have only one of them.
Now let's forget the value of the bar.
You can do that in two ways.
You can do it by index or by the time.
So what is the index of that guy?
It is here in position one.
So you can say get one of our look to the syntax to get one over.
Another way is by the time we say get integer over and normally if you are, you are going to make an
integer, an integer.
Does it make sense because only one of them here is available.
So this is how you get it.
Another interesting function is an index function, which tells you which index is active at the moment.
So for the string, it will be zero for the integral to be one.
Now, what's going to happen if you try to wrongly get the variable, you will get a new exception named
the bad variant Texas.
So if you try to say get string over, but only integer is available now.
So this will give you exception if you get zero of also another exception, because zero isn't active
one.
There are two conversion errors if you try to use a data type that doesn't exist right now, the compiler
will notice that if you try to use an index that doesn't exist, the compiler will notice that this
is because this is standard.
And all of that is is spelled in the comparison type.
Another interesting function, you can use a pointer, you call the get a function with data type,
and you are going to guess it refers to the variable and it's going to return a pointer for you if the
variable exists.
It would be to have a value if this variable doesn't exist, like you're using the wrong data type is
going to give you another pointer.
So now you can also use the get to like use it in a different way so you can return the value in different
ways to assign it.
You can just go and assign it with a variable.
So this is creating temporary variable.
And just using it another way is you can use it by reference here for more efficient like say get into,
over, get into it is returning by Bio-Reference.
You can assign it a different variable, a different value, and the index would be changing.
So now the VA has a new value here in terms of constructor and structure.
When you assign a new value than the old one, if has a structure, it would be destroyed probably first.
Now let's see an application for that.
If you remember the roots of the quadratic equation, A squared plus B, C equals zero.
This function in math has three different solution.
One solution that has no roots.
Another solution that has one rule.
Another solution that has two roots.
If you do remember this math tutorial we just using as an example.
So now the model of that is this equation has three different statuses.
Nothing, one, return to return.
So as you see here, we have three different cases and only one of them will be available at a time.
So if we would like to represent that guy, we just can use double.
Who would like to represent this guy?
Who can represent a pair of double double.
What about the case?
We have something in the variable that's good.
Monistat So what's more, state molested me.
Just MBT alternative.
Let's say we have here a class embley.
And I would like to say it may exist or not.
You can say a variant of Monastir trembly and by now directly we can use the optional here as a better
way.
But the model of Monistat, it can be used with variant to provide you with an embittered alternative.
And there is an advice here I would advise you to always put it in the beginning.
Why?
Because the variant always by default initialized the first member.
So if you say the variant of Embley is going to initialize the variant to the barrier to Embley, but
looking to this guy, it doesn't have a default constructor, this line will convert.
So the advantage of model state, when you put it first, the word would be initialized to MBT.
And then if Embley doesn't have a default constructor, everything would be OK.
Now, let's go back to our function.
I need a variant.
The take three things Monistat state, a double, a double, and let's use the using from C++ and just
give it a name here.
So my function is going to return to this variant.
And now we have three cases who are doing some math that we don't care about it here.
In this case, we can return it to Bill.
So we are going to return to the beer.
In this case, we can return a single number.
So we are returning a single number otherwise empty.
So you see now how our function is returning three different things and the caller can start to use
it.
For example, calling the computer.
It's a function of three values which would be solved to two items and then we are going to print it.
Now let's see the print function.
Now, the problem is we don't know which one is is the return side so we can use that index function.
If the index is zero, then it is a real case.
If the index is one, it is a one rule case.
If the index is two is a too good case.
Now, this is an ugly the the new standard or the standard.
The best practice is pushing to do something good is to visit the division visit is following what we
call a vista design better.
You should study that in the design.
Better for now.
I would like you to define some struct and override and over overwrite three different overload, three
different function corroborators, one for every argument.
So here I'm defining it.
One for the single parameter, one for the double for the beer, around for the honesty, and then do
whatever you would like.
No here one would like to print you create you call.
The function is to visit and you give it the visitor that you would like to give here and you would
like to give the result.
So the model of that is behind the scene.
This also will be happened.
And just calling your function so for you, instead of you doing the FSA by yourself, someone else
will do it for you.
You just provide the different functions here.
What I would like to do some function that maybe something, something or so do another vista.
So for every operation defying your own Vestor before Bidis, yeah, you can also provide along the
way, the way like let's say here, let's say I have a variant of integer, double and string.
OK, let's make our code more generic so I can define the final number that is taking auto with reference
reference.
This is a very.
It was a reference for forwarding and just printing it.
Now I can say visit of the visitor Anvar.
So the moral of that is you didn't have to write a case for integer and another case for double and
after the case for string.
So you can make it more than the problem is what if I have really different types were such a generic
good cannot work.
It really can get very complicated to do again in a way or another.
Some offenses or very generic.
Good.
But for now I would like to keep it simple for that.
The endless function similar to the optional, the simplest can help you to make your code more efficient.
Let's say you have a variant of integral double and you initialize it with ten point five.
By the way, this is OK.
Now, what if you have your variant of integrating offloads and you give it ten point five?
The problem is ten point five can be converted to fluid or an integer.
We have three different types in this line.
This will combine error.
Actually, you cannot do that in this way to solve that.
One way is to use the endless function so you can say here you best the emplace index of zero to mean
that this guy will be converted to into you.
Or you can best in this type of integer to sit here.
So, yeah, let's let's try another thing here.
Let's let's define a vector of integer and string as variant so you can see here the in place of index
to zero and give it the list of arguments now that one advantage for the employees, it's very memory
efficient.
So this guy would be constructed directly in the vector of integer.
So this is more efficient, more, more, more efficient.
This initialized less would be best to the vector of it.
You.
If you define here, Victor, of integration double and and you give it value zero, this is OK.
Definitely this is going to be going to a of of intriguer here.
But what if you just defined the look and you give it zero to zero can be converted to any one of them
according to the standard disjointed compiler?
I don't know why it doesn't compile.
It combines with me maybe some some differences in implementation in a way.
Again, if you hear just the custody too long, then it's going to just work.
And normally the moral of that is the English can help you with the index or type to solve the conversion
error here.
And also it is more of being more efficient, the choice here.