You'll find many programmers saying that variant is a replacement for the old union thing and C++.
That's OK, but there's actually a more stronger use case for the variant as a replacement to visual
functions.
Let's give some details about that.
How could you define a very a picture of different data types like.
I would like to create a vector of maybe an integer and double a string.
How would you define something like that?
This isn't straightforward.
Maybe I would like to find something some this class and I would do some different drive the classes
and with some polymorphism.
This looks a lot for a primitive data types right now.
Here is how it is variant.
How can solve this problem in a very simple way.
You define your own variant of the different types and then you define some vestor over this variant
and start to make a vector of this over time here.
Now you can embellish back from the vector one to bring to help you not see it.
This is very powerful.
Now you have a vector of three different types and you can iterate and just each one of them.
So you see how in a very simple way, the very give you this compile time, different choices, but
otherwise you will have to depend here on the different runtime choices.
Let's make this just more generic for the sake of learning how to do more treatment, more generic treatments.
First of all, here I defined the brain twister.
Yeah, this is same logic,
lets here create a variant to contain it.
It is going to create like a vector of variance, providing here some template over a variant.
So here I have a variant of string and integer.
I'm creating a variant of like a subclass over this variant.
So it's going to be here and I'm defining my function.
That's named the visit.
You give me Vester, which I defined here, and use it to visit the operator.
So I treated over every object to call Deville's function and providing here to function, push back
an endless back.
So the push back is just pushing back in the vector and then BLIS back is taking the very arguments
and just passively to the endless back function.
Remember that this back is taking the the very dark tablets.
What else are here?
So, yeah, I'm here defining a vector of this type and then I'm directly in back of it in respect of
it and calling its visit function and basing for it Alamdar for my my vestor.
I'm just trying to make the code more generic.
Nothing about the variant itself.
So instead of here, one one I'm creating here over Vector for example, you would like maybe to create
something else.
Yeah, but definitely the eventually vector just just making you could more generic solve for the confusion.
Let's take one more example where we are seeing, obviously where the runtime replacement could happen.
Let's say you have a glass piece and another glass looks right from it and they have function that could
bring to name.
Now you can create a pointer over the bicyclers that equals one of your drive, the closest as in the
virtual function, and you just call the printer and function.
Now you notice here, this is all runtime behavior and this is virtual things.
Now let's see how the variant would help us.
We are going to make a very simple class base that is in virtual and we are making extra drive that
doesn't extend from it.
And then you have this variant of these two classes here and then you have say some some, some, some,
some function that just your visitor is just calling the function, the print and then you are just
visiting.
That's it.
This is good.
By the way, DOCTYPE you see here, the Alworth we care is that this object have the function print,
we don't care about its subject time itself.
So the moral of this video, as you see, we can get rid of the polymorphism if it isn't necessary and
just go with basic option with the variance over all of the variance is a replacement to what was called
the union, which I didn't explain in this course you the need and also as it is a replacement for the
body Murphysboro time in terms of the memory, like let's say you have a variant of four different data
types.
We know that only one of them exists.
So behind the scene, the largest member of them in memory size will be the actual size of the offering,
something that you didn't care about it.
There are some disadvantages for variant.
One of them is you have to know the different types in the competition time and the timing, which may
be sometimes like you need to be careful, like you are just expecting something to have a function.
That's one of the annoying things, is you typically when it comes to printing, it's annoying.
And was, for example, was Vestor.
You have to make a visitor for every different functionality and sometimes it's very complicated when
they are different data types.
It's really not that easy.
In the future you might go and read this link.