The third interesting river in the Sebesta 17 is that any river the Indian River can is to any data
type and you can use it in the own time and it change the data types normally, but definitely at a
specific point it has just one data type.
The more of it is the flexibility.
You can change it to whatever data that you would like.
So we hope we can say here any in the header file, any and we say any nothing.
This we have nothing or maybe all to nothing with any pretenses.
There's also the finding.
It wasn't easy.
Another way is say any twelve point five.
So now this has an integer or now equal string to change it to string or equal 16.
You can make a copy, observe any here is in a template.
You don't see any of integrity.
Just any.
That's it.
The type of any would be reduced from the value that you are going to assign if you would like to get
the value using the function any cost and give it the specific use the parameter to cast it for you.
But if you try to cast it to the wrong time, you will get an exception of bad and you can also use
the any cost with reference here to get back a pointer.
If it exists, it will be pointing to it.
If it doesn't, it would be better.
You can also make use of that and also the any custom with reference here is going to be like a like
retaining reference.
So you can you get a site, you can use the reset function to to adjust the cancer value inside it.
And it has value will tell you if there is a value inside it or not behind the scene that can do a lot
of memory allocations for your objects, that's going to destroy the previous object when you're using
it in practice.
There are no use cases for any, so we typically don't need it.
And you are actually advised to avoid it unless there is a reason for it.
So in practice, you will not use it.
Let's just try to use it with the objects, let's say we have an MBA class here and then we can use
the function, make any, for example, to create for us an object.
We best the arguments here and make any is an efficient function.
And if you would like to reassign, you can also use the endless function, which is also memory efficient
function to construct an object here.
And you can also use the in-place function, which is going to be much more memory efficient to to to
put the variable here.
So it is in place of one thing to observe.
Here is the any work only with objects that must be capable of copyable and movable.
So you see here the if you try to uncommented this to raise this good will not work.
The object must be be copyable and movable.
OK, thinking here about the content here about this guy, I created an employee so I could construct
a code for it and then I tried to replace it.
So it was destroyed first and so on.
So behind the scenes there's a broader memory structure for you.
There are no problems with that.
Let's see one more application for it.
I'm going to create a map, the take a string and maybe two any.
So now this is very interesting.
The the the key here is a string.
So you can say map of integer and you give it value, creating a map of a string and you can give it
string.
Be careful here if it's a map string.
Hello, this is the pointer.
So don't be seated by the float then 1.0 sorry 1.0 is 1.0 is above to float this.
This is is it.
The word here is wrong in a way less iterate over the map and we can use the beer here, get the second
value or you can even use the structure of the binding.
But the more of that is I would like now to bring to the value.
But what is a type of the value?
I don't know.
Like it's very dynamic.
Right.
So one way is to use the type ID or overeaten.
The type ID can can help us to compare the data type of different objects.
So for example, I'm saying the any is providing a function of the type, which are the type of idea
of the function.
So I'm saying if this type is the type of the integer then custo into you, if the time is type of a
string, then cast a string.
If it's type of double, then to double this one should be double and this will should be double.
So the moral of that is we manage here to see how this good can help us to be pointing to any generic
thing.
That's it.