Let's make some comparison between the three three rappers that we learned.
As you know, the institutional Ismailiya, when you have something may exist or may not, but the verdict
is when you have several data types, but only one of them is available at any time, anything on any
trial for that can hold anything of them.
But you are advised to use it.
Unless there is, there is no way to avoid it.
From the memory perspective, both variant and optional don't require any extra, no allocations.
Behind the scene, remember, for variant, the memories the legends member, but for any there is extra
memory allocations that happen from time to time.
If the data types are very primitives, then this will not allocate memory types.
But for larger objects, this will typically allocate memory types for you.
So you have to be careful with any as it is like it can consume your memory if it has been to use it
a lot with different objects.
From miniaturisation, prospective by default, variant is initialized with the first time.
And remember, we talk about the model state and it can help us to avoid initializing the first variable
optional on the other side is usually initialized to an empty optional.
Remember that both variant and optional can work with objects, even if it doesn't have the Kobe and
new functionalities, however, is the DNA cannot the object must be copyable and must be movable.
In terms of the FBI, let's say you're dealing with an FBI when you see guys are using, say, for example,
variant, they are giving you a signal that this FBI allow to return to different options.
But what of the FBI that you are using?
Is returning any this is now very risky.
You will probably have to have to go and read the code or the documentation by yourself to know what
are these guys exactly returning so any can be a bit scary in the eyes.
And you have to think and have to read the commission to make sure that you understand what these guys
are going to do
before.
And C++ any is a replacement for what we call avoid point or explain that in the modern pointer topics.
But you do need to learn it.
And also, as I said, the variant is like a replacement to The Onion, which you do need to replace
it.
The point behind this model is more flexibility, simpler good and several choices in implementation.
That's it.