In this section, we will move to another type of traversal algorithms, which is the breadth first
search similar to the dips, a first search, the first search is at reversing algorithm.
It works for directed graphs, for undirected graphs.
But let's remember the defense was exploring the nodes as deep as possible, and that's why we got a
depth of research.
This news here doesn't represent the nodes.
It represents the exploration order.
If we are starting at this node, which may be in fact, the number 17 or whatever, we keep going deeper
and deeper.
So this is where the algorithm keep going.
It say, Hey, do you have children?
Yes, two.
Oh, recursive two.
Do you have a child?
Yes.
Three Because they're three.
Do you have a child?
Yes, requested and so on.
Who in four say, I don't have any children that recursion go back to three, which jump into the next
chart, which you then go back and so on.
So this is the order of the defense, the defense keep going as deep as possible and then return, then
go deeper.
Return.
Go deeper.
Gordemer return.
We are done.
This is a depth first search and we solve it a lot.
I expect that you understand very clearly what I'm saying here.
Now, what about the B s the B?
If this is a breath, the first search algorithm?
Remember, we explained the difference between the two words.
So b a face explodes at the graph level by level.
Specifically, we discover the nodes in the following order.
So we are here.
What is the next level two and the three weeks of these two first?
Then what is the next level four, five and six weeks ago this first, then seven eight nine 10.
So this one next and then this one next.
So the defense, the B a first go level by level.
So now we have two approaches that are inspired from how we as human think.
Remember when to give you the top story?
Like, we have topic like mathematics, we have topic like maybe biology, maybe we have physics.
And then there are hundred books a year.
Hundred books are here, 200 books are here.
In the depths of her research, she will take the mass to finish it first, then take biology topic
first and finish it first.
Then the physics, go back and finish it first.
In the first state, you will finish one book for math, then one book for biology, then one book from
physics, then another book from math, another book from biology and another book from physics.
And so.
I hope the life phenomena and the corresponding one in the algorithms are clear for you, so it is clearly
the difference between them.
This one is a DFS and this one is a farce that the depth of research explored deep well why the physics
of lower level by bite of it.
Remember, this nodes doesn't represent the node values that they represent the exploration order.
OK, so this is mainly what is the first doing.
So what is the level of a node like when they say you were level by level?
We can clearly see here because I structured, I drew the graph to look like a level by living graph.
In practice, maybe node number one would be here, rule number two here, rule number three here,
node number six here.
When you draw the graph this way, it doesn't see where are the levels now?
I drew the graph to look like the levels from the perspective of node number one.
So the level here represented the shortest to Abarth.
So we know really what is a Beth, which represents like when I say, one two five 10.
This is above the shortest represent about ability in the graph itself.
So there are usually two facts for the shortest the values sometimes which is here.
It represented the total number of edges.
For example, when you think about node number nine, there is only one Beth actually from one to nine,
which is one two five nine.
We needed three edges.
We see the shortest.
The Beth from one to nine is three in a similar way.
The church, the best from one to seven, is one two three again, three edges.
So this is the definition of the shortest path, and later we would learn about the orchestra.
In the second part of this course, we will learn about the other definitions of the shortest Sabbath.
So.
So now I hope the the word level and the word the shortest Beth are clear for you.
It represents the number of edges from a starting node to an ending or from a source to a destination.
This is what are the levels.
So let's see some visualization on a general graph now.
No, I don't get I don't drew the graph to.
Looks like a good for you.
So here is a graph.
Let's say you would like to start and do it first from node number two.
So here is no, no, no, no to.
Now, Newt number two level is just zero.
The distance from zero to two is just you.
Which nodes do you think are at level number one, which means that the shortest bus is just one inch?
Can you spot them?
These nodes are node number one and seven and the food and the five specifically, they are the neighbors,
the food number two.
So they are good neighbors who neighbors represent nodes at level number one.
OK.
So as you see the this, the best now is just one step.
What about what about the rules that live in No.
Two, can you spot them?
There was no number two is three and six and zero.
So when you look to two, it takes two to two to three.
It takes two ages to reach six.
It takes two edges to reach zero.
Observe the following, uh, like, for example, nude number six, we can reach it using here one bathroom
from two to four to five to six.
This takes three steps, but we cannot stretch from two to five to six.
And remember, we seek the shortest to bath.
So the answer is about the one that is closer to me.
So the the closest way is this way.
Now your turn?
What about their level three?
Clearly, River three comes from node number seven here, which is as you.
Let's take another example.
This is thought to be a first from the number seven now, which, you know, at level one, just the
number zero, which, you know, at level two, just no food.
Which, you know, at level three.
Just include two and seven and five.
I would like you to observe the relationship between the news that we visited so far and the news that
are new for us, for example, who target news, no food.
You will not see this.
This is harvested bullet.
This is the unvisited booked.
So now some of the unvisited board will join our our our, our joint, our vested group.
So you see here Newt, number five Ken and number six from here and also can add new number three from
here.
Number two can add Newt number one here.
So we see that in.
Uh, let me go one step.
Uh.
Uh, one, two, three four.
I should add three, was you with us here?
So three should be added in this in this graph, OK?
There are no nodes at level five.
OK.
Three is already part of level four.
OK, I think one more example, yeah, here.
So let's see here one more.
I'm just trying to make you familiar with the idea of the of the Liberals now he had no one.
Where are the nudes at level number one?
Clearly, the neighbors, which are three and five and six, now live in number two.
So you see now nude number seven will join through number six.
Nude number two can join through number five.
So we see now they are added now at level number three.
Nude number four can come either from here or from here.
I hope you spot the relationship, not number zero two, the nude number seven.
I hope you get the idea of the levels in the next session.
We will show how to do that in a very systematic way.