Let's see their implementation here, first of all, we have uh, we have, uh, uh, the condition
here that I was referring to it, I'm early verifying if the if the current index already has zero or
not, if it has zero, we are done this something important here.
As you see in the while loop, I don't to verify the element that I get from the Q.
I only verify what I put in the Q.
OK, so the Goodyear goes as normal we have in nodes, so we have a vector of Boolean Q bush.
The Q, this is as we do this as what we used to do in the operation goods.
We usually have a lot of operations, so be careful to not duplicate the code.
So I am implementing here a process function that dig the Q, the visited array, the array and and
the current index.
And then I tell him to check index the blustery and index minus array.
The first thing is if indexing is in zero or it is actually a vista index, and then we turn a false.
If we find that the index is true, the index values zero, we return it through.
Otherwise we mark twisted bush in the Q.
A return for to be false mean we still keep going in the processing.
If any of these two calls return it true, it means we found the answer.
So we returned it to here.
If the Q finished the processing without anything that provide an answer, then we return false here.
I hope overall the the idea in this problem is clear.
Now let's see the second.
The problem, which is very similar to this problem here.
So this is again, another operation.
B is the problem and in this problem.
We would like to convert the number to another number.
But this time we have an array that we are going to use.
So here is the implementation, which is exactly very similar.
We have a starting number, so we put it in the queue market has visited.
We iterate.
Now where are their substrates?
We get them from the array.
So I iterate on the array and then try to move to this node plus and this mode minus and this node operator.
If any one of them is done, then we return riverboats one otherwise level minus one.
The process function is as simple as it to check if we are at the goal, we return it all.
If the number in this range.
And it is invested, then we added otherwise we ignored it.
And this is very important condition for correctness and also for the memory.
So as you see, the implementation is done now, then put into question how many states are here, given
that the function limit us to 1000 values.
This means you only maximum has in states and is just 1000.
So this is all what you this is all what you need for the memory.
What about the time complexity?
We have more nodes, but in in so total we have nodes.
And for every new world, we iterate on the wood array here.
So this is in the times, so total aim and implementation.
This is merely this problem.
As you see, the two of them is exactly very similar, including style.
So in the third, the problem, the one about the, uh, the one about the look.
So let's see here, is it different or not?
In fact, this is a very similar problem.
It's all about the it's it's all about that, the looking.
So again, you have a string as a starting point and you change it to an endpoint.
That's all.
So what we need is just iterate and do the bunch of things.
Now, a few things here.
First of all, um, we need to use set because to mark that, the strings, are they used or not?
Um, the verification.
Remember, I told you if you have to verify the initial state, but is verify them.
OK, what about the number of states?
We only have a string of four letters.
Every letter has four values.
This means we have 10 to the power for states only, which is very straightforward.
And in every step, we generate the children in all these steps.
OK, now, uh, this means that the total time complexity is the total number of states and the number
of children, but not which is the Times 10 to the poverty.
This constant in a way.
Uh, in C++, we can generate one child in all one, but in other languages, this isn't the case.
OK, let's see the implementation.
First of all, I have this to start, which is for two years.
We have that unordered, the set, which is a stable of nudes.
I'm initially using it with the ends.
Why that it ends look like just you can think of them like your vested notes that you shouldn't touch.
So some people will make two different sets to check if it is in the dead ends or the chicken.
The vested, why not just put them all of them individually at once?
Then we are done with that.
Now that you, uh, of this thing, because the truth now is a string, the nude is a string.
No, you need to make these two special cases early.
You need to check if if the visited, if the starting is already in the vested, the means that zero
zero zero is even locked.
The second case is if the start equal the goal.
So it means also you are ready, Richard.
Most of the problems of with this kind of tricks, I expect you to get maybe one or two wrong answers.
This is more or less like competitive programming, like will we try to trick people about that?
I honestly got a good answer for this submission here, missing that the starter could be in the ends
anyway, not our business.
Now let's keep going.
Uh, we again, Bush, the new market, visited ETRADE, get a child, they removed the child.
Now we need to generate the children.
We have four letters.
For example, maybe the current state is three one zero two, then for every one of them, we will try
to get it one step before or it is one step after.
Get it, one step before or one step after.
Right.
So this means the four four steps we actually have eight children, not just for sorry.
We have eight different children.
So four.
And everyone is trying to uh, some people are implementing that in a very lengthy way.
It is the right way.
I have next and previous functions in the next function will take a character to character.
So I said next of two, it would be three previous or have two.
It will be one next of nine would be zero.
Previews of zero would be nine.
These two utilities would be very helpful during coding.
So I thought, let's say we have three two zero seven in the first character.
I would say, what is the next character here?
So let's say three is going to be four.
So now the new string is four to zero seven and then I'm a checking.
In the in the in the CBS2 set, when you insert the element, it returned a beer where the second is
true, it's insisted already false if it's already existing.
So now when I say the second, it mean it's actually the first time to edit.
So I'm saying if it's if it's new state, but is -- here now.
After that, we would like to take three and reduce it, which is as simple as thinking four and reduce
it twice.
So previous of previous A4 is two to zero 07.
So here that's why I'm doing previous previous year if current equate equals target here or here.
Then we found it just to return.
Otherwise, we it here.
Now remember to undo that.
If you didn't make the undo, you would have to take a copy of the next string, which is, oh, a deliberate
step.
So when you, I'm keeping the next string as it is.
That's sort of the current district as it so that I don't have to copy the memory here, which is just
having a memory.
I hope you got the overall idea, the good, the little bit longer.
But the idea is exactly the same.
You have a string.
There are eight different operations that we can do to get eight different strings.
This this is A..
These are the nodes who are doing the conversion and that and that's it.