Phonebook number three.
Um, in this type of homework, we move to another kind of experiences that I would like you to gain
with the business.
So here is the problem we have.
We have a grid like that and we would like the following.
So we have here, we have three valleys in this grid.
We have minus one for an obstacle.
We have a gate, which is zero and we has a very huge value.
Specifically, this big value to fill an empty room and we would like to from from every meeting room
to know where is the nearest the gate for it or if it's impossible to reach a gate, we just should
fill it with the infinity.
So we take this to this structure and fill it with their.
Either the distance or that this infinity value, so here is the here is the gate and there are there
are mainly in this one.
There are two two rooms here, two gates hitters get what?
And he does get the gate two and for every MBT.
So we would like to record their distance to the shortest gate.
For example, I can go from here in three steps to here or one two three four two here.
So this is the shortest one for me.
For this one, I can go one two three four.
So four steps of four here or one two three four five six seven seven steps for you.
So the smallest is four.
So you return for every position, the distance to the nearest the gate.
Um, now here are more examples, basic examples.
Um, I would like you to try to process that in an efficient way.
You might be thinking in a very brute force way.
I would like you to do something that has a complex you of all rules.
Time columns.
So try to do something like that.
Let's move.
Um, we have here a matrix and there is a massive coalition, which is mainly can be represented by
the top above the top rule and the first to call them here.
I don't have the Atlantic Ocean, which is after the last, uh, column and after the last true now.
And here is the request.
Yeah, let me try to make sure that I didn't forget it.
It says that it's raining a lot.
And when there is a water, the water can flow to neighbors in the four possible direction that we used
to them, but it to flow from a cell to another.
It must be less than or equal to it in the current the height.
So this values here represent some heights.
And if there is water, come to this one here.
The water can float here and float the here.
Why?
Because they are less than or equal to it.
But for example, if the water at three, the three can float to one, but it cannot float to four,
it cannot float to five.
And this is very logical.
So imagine this everyone is like a height of this cell.
The water can float only to something that is equal value and less value.
Now what is the request?
The request is as follows.
You will return a list of the positions such that the water can flow from the position to both of the
oceans can flood to both of the oceans.
So let's see here if we are given this input here, this one now we can see that the value five can
float to the massive cushion and also can.
You can float to the Atlantic now for this one.
It also can float to the Atlantic.
And also it can float to the Pacific.
Now let's see what about the value at five?
The value at five here, it can flood to three, then one, so it can go and get flood to four and two
and go.
So as you see, so overall, you would like to return this positions that can flood to both of them.
So for a cell to float to the Atlantic, it has to reach either this one or this one here.
And for a cell to reach the massive ocean, it has to float here or here in the upper tier here.
So as you see the common between this problem and the previous problem, you have bunch of things like
it doesn't look like something want to go to something.
It seems like multiple of things would like to go to multiple things.
You know, we had another.
So how can we change our code to again be very efficient?
All those.
Times economies, for example, think about that.
And the third problem, it has some some mix between the idea of the previous two problems and also
something about the idea from the previous homework.
Uh, OK, so here is a problem.
The problem say a staggering number is an integer such that all its adjacent digits have an absolute
difference of exactly one.
So let's say we have three to one.
If you look to it.
This is the being number.
Why we have three and two and one between three and two is one between two and one is one.
The difference is exactly one four, two and one is in this tipping number because from 42, there are
two digits more examples.
If I say something like seven after seven, there can be only six or they can be only five because the
difference between them is two steps for the six.
After that can be five or four.
So the either will be seven, six, five or seven, six or four and so on.
The problem is asking for the following you will be given low and integer they are in the earlier in
the year.
Forget about this long ruling.
Here they are.
Integer law.
Integrate.
OK?
And you are to return list of numbers that has all of the stabbing numbers between the low and the high
and but is sorted them observe that the value is up to 10 to the bow nine.
So be careful from overflows.
So here is an example between zero and twenty one.
This is a list of the numbers between 10, 10 and 15.
That is only these two numbers who are stimming numbers.
That's all.