Let's solve the first problem about the walls and gates, and the really positive thing is we we have
several rooms and we have several gates and we know we can use one before us to find many things, but
we have many things to start from.
How can we still keep that as efficient as possible?
OK, so the first way to go is as simple as brute force by running the office from every room.
So far, so straightforward.
Now the question Can we do better than that?
Observed each room can be connected to one of the newest gates, but each gate can be used by many rooms.
If it's a virtual target.
So, no, this would be kind of reverse the thinking.
First of all, don't start from the room to find the single matching gate.
We will reverse it, that we will start from the gate and find the distance to every rule.
OK, so far, we didn't change the problem, we still have many things to start from them, so what
can we do?
We can introduce a new variant of the beef as it is called the multi source.
With this so far, we did what we call one two m bénéfice, which means you have one starting note and
you have multi.
This finishes because the first single before school will compute the BFS answer for the distance answer
for all of their neighbor nodes for all of the graph nodes.
So it's good one to em.
Now we would introduce what we call a multi source, where instead of just starting from one source,
we can start with many sources.
The idea is very simple.
The only change that you do in the code is if you have multiple starting nodes, you can add all of
them together in the queue initially.
So here is the idea.
And the news to the Q, so instead of singular starting point, you have multiple starting points.
OK, what's now happening in the Q when you think about it, this means Level zero has, for example,
five gates, level zero has five gates after level one each.
Get them.
I want all of the rooms that are one to stay far from them.
A level to each gate, actually like each new cell added to the queue.
Found the nearest room in two steps.
But remember and observe the following If one room is already visited from a single stab, it will be
already processed.
So we do need to process it.
And this is the advantage that we gained.
If you try to run beef's beer again by itself, you will have its kind of repeating the effort of others.
If you run all of them together, this means the gates the first, the gate that will reach a room will
block others from really consuming time to reach to this destination.
I hope the overall idea is clear for you, so the minute changes that we do in the multi-sports is as
following.
Initially, we start from one single note in the queue, which you keep finding notes.
Now we start from multiple different sources nodes, and this one in level one would add all of its
children here.
But let's say this one has also the same two children.
We add nothing.
Let's say that this one has one child, the from here and one child from here, we are nothing.
So this way they are collaborating together.
So the whole idea is they work together and once something is visited, no one else have to do anything
else.
OK.
I hope you.
It's more clear for you.
Like in the first, once you are done with level zero, level one has all of the knowledge at level
one.
So the whole idea here is living zero itself has multiple starting points.
And this is the take home lesson that I would like you to keep in mind if you have multiple starting
points or what you would like to do is to add them to the queue.
So this is only the way to change that you need to do to the queue, and that is one more change that
you need to be careful about it the size.
Remember, we used to initialize those to be equal one.
Now the size has to be equal.
What equals the total number of units that we started with them?