Let's see, how can we put him into that?
We start the year by MC and be a first of the rules to make the objects that we need in the query.
We this is a normal breakfast on a grid.
We will iterate on the metrics and any cell that has a value zero.
We know that this is a starting point.
So we use here kudos bush and market to market it as a visited and edit it as a starting point.
The second, the change, which is very important.
You should right size equal Q to size.
Maybe you can, even from that one, make it a habit like you always right size equal Q that size.
So if the Q has a single note, it's OK.
If the Q has more than not, it will be OK because if you forget this one, the good will not work.
But obviously everything else in this problem is exactly the general, uh, the general iteration on
the in the could not nothing, nothing more fancy here.
So the overall of this problem, we use the reverse the thinking.
So by reverse thinking, we we notice that the room need one gate.
But if we started from the gate, we got all of the rooms and all of the gates together can find together
the answer.
The second one is the multi source idea that we should hear.
Now, let's see the second, the problem, the second, the problem is about there, the Pacific Ocean
idea here.
So this is problem number two.
Now, this problem is going to be exactly very similar to the previous problem.
Actually, it has the same two components.
First of all.
From the cell perspective, it looks like more like one to one relationship.
Every cell is looking to one exit or a specific direction.
But if you thought it from the ocean perspective, the ocean would like to find here the ocean.
Like this one here, it would look to find all of the sensors that can reach you to me.
So if we revisit the problem, we think about the start from the ocean and the find all of the energy
that can reach to this ocean.
This would have it also splitting the problem to two problems.
We would like to split it.
One problem to find like from the best of caution, which are all of the nodes that can the rest of
ocean can reach it, Richard.
And also, we can do it from there other ocean perspective.
We find all of them is that it can reach it.
So the processing goes as following.
There are a lot of nodes here.
These are my starting points, I will use them.
And in a business, I find all of them is that I can reach in a very, very similar way.
These are all my starting points.
I will use them to find all of the notes that I can.
I can reach in this way.
If a note is reachable from massive and also reachable from Atlantic, that it must be part of the answer.
So again, this problem ended up like.
You thought, reversely, which is something very specific to the problem.
And more importantly, you have multiple starting points now one catch about the reversing ideas when
you reversed something which are the effect on the problem in the normal problem.
You are thinking that the sale will go to the neighbour because if I am five, it would be five or more
or less.
So it should be less than or equal me.
Now we are reversing.
So we would like the ocean to go to the hood so the ocean will go to the road if and only if the ocean
is greater than or equal to it.
So in the normal direction, less than or equal in their reverse direction, it would be greater than
or equal.
So just be careful about the flipping of the semantic.
Everything else is just a matter of cutting.
Let's see how to do that.
Two billion array Pacific and Atlantic with the grid the size, and then we would like to find the starting
cells.
So I'm iterating on the rule, getting the first through and through and getting the first two columns
and the last the column.
This now could.
It's my starting points.
I will do two separate business one offs on the Pacific Reachable and the best of starting here and
the second one on the Atlantic one.
Once we are done with this to be a first, I will read two iterations and there are three.
If the route is reachable from the massive and reachable from the Atlantic, then it's part of the answer.
For the BFC itself, it is very straightforward here, observe we add all of the cells to the graph.
So this is the first the change.
The second exchange change, this one should be queue that size.
So this way we are done with it.
Anything else is the same, but observers here.
The condition here must be ruled in a reverse way so that the this is this is more about the reversing
the idea, this two about the, uh, about the change itself in the.
In the multi source in the third, the problem.