Let's solve the third problem about this tipping number.
This problem involved with the two tracks that we learned so far.
It involved an operation based problem and it involves a multi source to track and keep in mind that
one type of hard the problems are these problems that are composed of such problems.
Once you manage solving these problems and learning about them and gets killed in them, you can now
approach hardhearted problems.
So let's see, what do we have here?
We have a positive number and we know we can generate maximum to new numbers from it.
So if I have three, three four and I would like to add one more digit, the next digit would be either
five or three because Ford has either five after it or three of it before it.
Now what about three zero?
You can only have three zero one.
What about three nine?
You can only have 398, so you can have maximum two new children.
The idea here we can use the first word be a force to generate all the numbers, then add only the numbers
in the range.
This task now involved with two things generate.
Select Saddam mixing both of them.
OK.
There are different problems I can tell you generate for me.
All of them are random strings and only add the Brent room within.
A specific range of this problem followed the same pattern you would like to generate out of such numbers
so we can use defense or be first to generate them.
Then we selected that target problem.
OK, so here's what we need to do.
You kind of start from the valleys one to nine, which is the minimum number of valleys that we can
have on all of them are are still being number four.
Then iteratively, one can add 10 and 11.
Two can add 21 and 20 through three for up to nine, then nine at night.
Keep doing that.
Now what is the next 10 will add for you?
One one one one eight one one one zero and one one two and so on.
Keep adding, keep adding.
Keep adding one observation here.
If you thought about the generation process, first of all, all of the numbers that would be generated
are unique.
The second all of the numbers are sorted.
Does this mean the number, the next number is usually bigger than the previous one, and it has different
benefits than anyone before.
So the condition that would make it unique and order exists.
So how can we stop once you find the number that is bigger than the higher limit you can install?
So again, the key idea here split the generation from this election, keep generating in order it will
generate unique values.
It will generate order the values once you have a value that is bigger than the current one.
Then we are done.
In terms of the graph, every number is a.
And there are two edges maximum here.
In the first, we'll start with multiple starting nodes, which are one two nine values.
You cannot add to the Q the value zero because zero when you add zero one zero two is just generating
the the zero one and two.
It could be like a like a more buggy, maybe.
So anyway, what they did is I handed the the zero as a special keys, so let's see here.
Um, first of all, I'm using long, long because the.
The limits are high, so to avoid any overflows.
This is my cue.
And first of all, I am checking if the value zero in their range in range is a function of the return.
True, if the value is in the range.
It is implementation.
It just literally true if the number between low and high.
Very simple function.
So I'm wondering here, zero special case, I'm adding multi source from all of these nine values and
also abandoning them in their queue.
Remember my advice in my quitting style?
You have to check your initial starting conditions as a special case, as a special treatment.
This is more efficient.
Now, in terms of the queue here, observe the huge size, this is important.
Now the office is not looking normally.
You get the number you above it, then you can record the next two numbers.
If I was no like two or three five, for example, no more 10 will get the five.
So now all what I need to do is.
I would like to generate the next number, so we have two, three five, the next number would be two
three five six or two three five four.
So I am multiplying this number within and either adding the digits with minus one or plus one.
Uh.
Now, the first one here cannot be applied if the digit is is zero.
This one cannot be applied if digit is nine.
So we have these two conditions to make sure that we don't go invalid if the Bruces function return
it a false at any at any time than we need, we know we can.
We can stop.
So now the process function is following.
The Brussels function say if the number is greater than how we can, we can stop because numbers are
unique and united in order.
The first one that is bigger than lie is definitely outside of the school.
Then we add that Q a number to the Q.
And if the number itself in the range, we can add it to the queue, we can add it to the answers.
Be careful.
Sometimes people might try to to try to generate only within the range.
So if he's generating only in the range, you cannot get the numbers before the range to generate.
That's why I'm saying split the focus on the generation and only when you have a number that is, uh,
is in the range, added Observe.
Why didn't we need, uh, a victory here?
Because numbers are unique, we would never need to visit the number that we visited before.
This is what it looks like a tree.
So like a one is giving eleven and giving ten and so on.
This is a tree.
There is definitely no cycles in this graph.
You can you don't need an invested array here.
That's.