Homework, no food.
And in this subset, we would like to address also a new, different type of graphs and before a problem,
so let's see the first one.
Hopefully the easiest among them as following, we have a directed graph.
Now, every edge has a color, either red or blue.
And there could be even salvages or or better it just here.
No, the point is the following we would like to move from nude to another.
However, the bath must be alternating.
The bath must be alternating.
The request is following.
You would like to return like a list or a vector of integers.
Such a that answer of exit, but isn't the shortest to Bess from node zero to Node X, such that the
edges must alternate in colors.
For example, let's see here.
This is a graph here.
It gives you a list of images and lists of blue edges.
The list of blue edges here is empty.
The red one or zero two were at one two in a directed graph.
Now here is the answer of a.
Answer of zero is the best from zero to zero.
This one would be always zero.
Answer often is the best from zero to one in alternating way, there is only one edge.
And this is a shortest to dancers one.
Answer from zero to two is minus one, why?
Because there is no birth of alternating energies we see here from zero to one in red.
We needed one to two, but but blue one, not red one.
But it doesn't exist.
So that's why you have mice that wouldn't swim here.
So it isn't about just finding the shortest bath.
The Bath must be alternating in colors.
Another problem here 01 is red, but two one is blue, so zero two zero would be zero zero to one one,
as we did before.
Zero two even doesn't exist.
Now, let's flip the problem.
What about 012?
But this way, this one exists, this one is minus one.
This one is minus one.
I hope the overall idea is clear.
Let's see more example zero, one and two from zero two zero zero from zero to one one in red from zero
to two two edges, but red and blue.
So it's an eternity.
It has to be like red, blue, red, blue, red, blue or blue or red, the blue red or blue red.
The final example here.
From zero two zero is zero.
From zero to one, there is one edge which is red good from zero to two.
There is.
One age that is also red, which is also good.
I hope the overall is clear.
It is shortest to both, but consider the coloring that we have.
Let's move something that's more generic.
There is what we call the water and drug problem, and this is a very popular problem and it has different
variants.
So here is a very, very good website.
So this is a jug of water and this is a jug of water that is a very popular problem that each one of
them has a capacity to say six liters of water, and this one is eight liters of water.
And you can do any of the following six operations, and you can do them as many as you want.
You have infinitely infinite number of water, by the way.
This is my description for the problem because the elite could judge a description is very bad.
You can do the following operation.
You can fill any of their jugs with water, so this one has a capacity of six and this one has come
too often.
I can fill this one up to six or I can fill this for up to 10.
And definitely can fill both of them.
The second operation you can imagine and one of them.
So this one has six liters of water.
Now I can empty all of it or can do that.
So as you see, you can empty both of them or can make all of them the full.
Now, the second third operation is this following.
It is a brutal operation.
Um, but let me give you an example.
Let's say that this is judge number one.
Let's see.
The capacity is six.
And let's say it has at the moment, four liters of water only.
And let's say that this is another jag of civil leaders, and at the moment it has five liters of food.
If you decided to fill from the first one to the second one, notice that the second one only needs
to your, it's safe.
We bought the from one to two.
We will take two units a year, so it will be felt to seven.
And this one would be reduced up to two units here.
So it would be only.
Two years here.
So the brutal operation is just following your boat from one to another.
Tell the the other judge is completely full or the first one is completely empty.
For example, if we assume that this one is true and this one here is just zero.
So what you can do is build that tool to the zero here, so this one would be two and this one would
be zero.
The operation is very loose contract to understand that from this perspective, now what is the request?
You will be given a target committee and you would like to play this operation as much as you can,
such as that at some point of time.
The water in the first one blows the water, and the second one equally equals the target capacity.
By the way, in some of other online judges, you would like one of them only to be equal to you.
But in this variant, and it could, you need the plus, OK?
So this is merely the request you keep believing and return it through if you can reach a stage where
that the sum of the two of them is exactly the tiger Kristie.
One of the problem here, the values are extremely huge.
So this is really there the problem?
So let me give you my examples of some examples.
The first one has one.
And the second one has to.
If you filled this one to one and this one to two, then the submission is three, which is the request.
If the first haston and the second has 20, then even when they are both failed, the submission is
just a throw when we need 100, so we no way to reach that.
OK.
If you would like to reach a three with three and five to six.
So here's what what we can do.
So let's say let's try to draw.
We have here.
Three units of water and we have here five units of water.
So here is this tips, first of all, I will start by filling the the first one, I will fill the second
one.
So the second one has five, so I will fill all of it.
So now we have five units here.
Then I will boot from two to one.
So now this one has five units Ubu two here.
So this one has three.
Also, it will be folded two three units and what remaining is just two then.
You, well, empathy, their second one, so we empty this one here.
Then brewed from one to two.
So take this three Yorkshire and Muslims thought now this one would be three.
Now, Phil, the first one, again it will be three.
Again, No three and three are six.
An important observation here.
The answer of three, five and six is true.
So the answer, also five and three, is also true.
OK, so this is mainly the problem as an extra thing.
If you would like to do that, you might even try to change your could to bring to the shortest operations
a sequence which is as simple as a bath that we printed before.
Look, one thing here that it could limits are very tight limit.
It's more or less like competitive programming.
It's like 90 percent your school goodwill Tilley mine were not really, but you will still almost most.
This problem has an all one solution.
It's wisdom, mathematics, and it's out of our scope completely.
Now, I don't want you to get in this puzzle of a lot of time.
Limit exceeds and waste a lot of your time in that.
So here is what I'm doing and providing you with my own training.
File my own book fight.
So it is an example of them.
But while it is stuck to the number of cases, then it lines each other and has no to cases.
So read and compare with your own one.
Maybe you can write some script to convert two files together.
So this is mainly what you can do for free to try to optimize your code to best the tiddly.
You have to avoid any slow competitors.
You have to make some optimizations so that it can best simply.
OK, so the next one, the sliding bottle.
Uh, a nice problem.
OK, it is what you have.
You will be given a two or three sliding buzzer like that, for example, then, but there is one two
three four and then zero and then five.
The request is we would like the grade to end up as following.
We would like the grade to be one, two, three, four, five and zero.
So this is the issue state and this is the final state.
Now what is operation?
You search for the zero and you can swab it with any one of their neighbors of the four neighbors of
it.
And would like to return, I think the shortest number of steps.
The lowest number of steps.
So this is so you would be given an initial goal.
And this is the target goal.
And you can swab with any of the adjacent to value the zero only and return the total number of steps
or minus one.
If no way to do that.
It is an example, please read it and try to see how can we move it?
The zero is here, so we can, for example, and the first one it will slide what, uh, four one two
five zero three.
This is the initial one.
It when it's light five years or bring five years or it is a zero, and then it will do what it will,
uh, zero one two.
So it slides zero above and Brentford here and so on.
Another example.
Then fix the problem.
Make sure to fully understand this problem, who is quoting so that you don't get puzzled about what
is what and read it after I explain it.
You have in the boxes.
Each books has the following information.
It has a status for its A.
So if the status is one, it means it is an up in the books.
If the zero is the close, the books, there are some candies that are inside the books.
Seven Candies, it candies.
There are some keys inside the books.
I can take these keys and open in another book, so with it that need this key.
And inside the books, there are more boxes.
OK, so be careful about that.
But there are almost one books inside e-books, so when you open a box?
You'll find that it might be open or closed.
You'll find some sweet candies inside it.
You'll find some keys inside it.
You'll find even some books inside it.
But but this box is my because that might be open to you, the know.
Now here is the point you would like to you.
Initially, you would be initially given.
You would be initially given some boxes that are you can start with them.
OK.
So you can take all of the candies.
And so this initial boxes consider them, they are opened in a way.
And now what you would like to do is you will keep taking Candice from the books and all of the keys
in the books and keep searching for other books.
Any books so that you can it, you open it, then take the candies inside it, then take the keys inside
it.
Open more books as long as your current keys allow you to open a new box up in the box.
Take the candies.
Get the keys of in boxes inside it.
Keep doing that until reaching the status where you cannot open any more boxes.
Now, return to the total number of candies that you can collect this way.
Overall, it could be confusing a problem.
I will.
I will leave it for you to try to simulate the examples and understand them.
Uh, yeah.
Also read this description in is it could be helpful for you while coding.
Uh, don't be scared.
Not that hard.
Just make sure you understand the details of the problem.
That's off.