Let's solve the homework of this problems.
So the first one about the shortest path in translating colors the red and blue.
Um, so let's see here.
This probably introduce us to a very important type of graphs.
So in a classical standard, the graph, you can have a graph of symbol nodes zero one, two three and
so on.
Now this is the graph that is something that I call history the graph in a stick graph.
We also have nodes and we also have edges.
But the node this time is a bit big.
It consists of many different things.
For example, what if you if you're not consist of a string and an integer like a string of three letters,
maybe, for example, Abbasid and a number from zero to nine, for example, here, maybe six, for
example, and that is somehow connection between the nodes.
So what is a state?
A state is bunch of elements.
The most classical state is a number from zero two to minus one, the largest.
It can have anything there.
The node may be representing a vector.
The node may be representing three strings.
The node may represent three strings and a single number.
The node may represent two numbers.
The node represents anything.
So, as did Graph is a case where the node consisting of many things together.
OK.
I hope you got this idea.
Now the key to this problem is to realize this problem isn't about a graph of any nodes.
They are actually like to any nodes or specifically.
It is a state graph where each node is an index from zero to the minus one and a Boolean variable zero
or one or higher red and blue.
If you realize this fact, you would be able to implement this problem in a very straightforward way.
So again, this is a steep graph where the node has to integer one integer representing an index of
from zero to minus one and another value representing is it red or blue?
A Boolean flag zero or one?
And that's why, given that the original graph has in the nodes, but like the connection from from
from another to another depends on the color we used to come to this node.
So this node isn't just now, but from zero to minus one.
It also has the color that has been used to reach this node.
So while we are building the graph, we're building it like I have here A. Let's say node number seven
and it has edge to node number five was color red.
If I.
Let's say also, I have another node like mine was color blue.
If I Richard Node seven was color, let's see red, then I cannot take this best.
I can only take this bus.
And once I take the nine, I Amaka that I Richard, nine, with blue.
So when you think of it, even in terms of Vista Array, the Vista case is again of two things a number
from zero to minus one and a status for Boolean value zero or one.
I hope you get the idea.
If you thought it this way, you now adjusted the whole standard to be a first to work on estates.
What we will do here in terms of coding will be standard and you can use it in all of the problems.
So the take home lesson is as following what is a solid graph, the second thing is just to generate
the graph and try to create like an explicit to any nodes the graph you get.
You might think of that, but don't do that.
So now let's see.
Let's see the implementation of this idea.
First of all, I created an image that this time consist of two and colors.
What is the note that we will go to it?
What is the color of this, not the color of the edge that has been used to distort?
And here in adding edge from from and to with color with just an edge from was there too and color,
there'd be a face to start as following.
First of all, the Line three is in terms of two.
And if I was to know that now you can just say I visited Node seven.
You must say, did you visit seven?
Was red or did you visit seven was blue?
It matters now when you think about that starting point.
What is the starting point here?
We have a starting node.
But wait, what is the color that you used to do the starting node?
We are now here, just starting, so we can think of this as a multi source.
We have two different cases.
We can start to the node with red or we kind of started.
The node was blue.
We have the freedom to do that and then also do their, uh, their initialization of that in theory.
So now we can say the answer to the start is zero.
We will keep answering was the best the value we reach.
Now let's go.
This is very normal as we iterate on every edge I have if.
The edgy color different to them might color a year will get the nod and get the color of there over
the nude if the color doesn't match the color.
And also, we didn't reach to their length not before, so it is invested before then we will watch
this new age.
We will mark its eleventh hour observed with the following.
The answer here is about the shortest way to reach wood.
So if we're Richard Node seven from red was value five first, then later.
If we try to reach the Note seven was color black, it must be five us, so we see here.
If the answer to the Note five is minus one, it means the first time to reach it.
Then just a sign this value, you will never reach it with something better than the current level.
I know that this could be a bit new for you might be chucking a little bit.
But what I would like you here to observe is we were generalizing the BFC could to act on a stick graph.
So you need visited array to represent that, um, the streets, you need to decide what are the possible
initiative states.
You need to iterate on the graph in a normal way, but is take time to review this vigil and to think
about it.
Think how can we generalize the graph form?
Just normal bunch of values that are connected together to as the graph?