Let's solve another problem where the idea of a state graph will come back again to the scene, when
you think about this problem.
You will notice that we have two jars like maybe one of them has capacity.
Six.
And another one has capacity.
Five.
When we do an operation, we get a New Jersey.
Maybe we get zero and five.
Maybe in another operation, we get like five and maybe zero, maybe another operation.
We get like a five and there maybe three.
And if you started to think in each two years together as a single note, then.
A state graph can be represented where we have a node that has no like, let's see here, five and zero,
that is going to five and three in a directed graph.
So once you think in this problem as a states, the state is to number the operation is converting a
state to another state, then you simply has a graph and the task is asking you if we can start from
a steady state like zero and zero and reach out to some state where there is a mission of the two values
equal it, for example.
Now this is a standard beliefs, but all what you need to do is to run it on their own the graph.
A few things to take into into consideration.
The first thing is most of the goods will fail in the face and that it could blind judge.
This is mainly due to like minor like tight, tight time limits.
I don't care about that.
I'm teaching you before.
So this is what matters here.
The second thing is there is own math for this problem, it's mainly based on Cobram and you said you're
going to check out this year notes if you would like, feel free to ignore it, it doesn't matter.
Uh, we can even do further improvements like this could.
I don't completely get it.
But anyway, uh, now we mentioned before that, um, the states and counting the states, uh, is important,
right?
I don't know how many number of states have this problem.
And as you see there, the states are very regular in representation.
Practically speaking, we can have up to 10 to about six times to a number of states.
Looks like huge numbers, right?
But practically speaking, it must be much less than that.
Also, the mass of the city and cobra homes might get involved in the problem to decide, uh, like
what are the really practical number of cities that could have been?
So generally speaking, completing the total number of states of this problem is completely out of our
scope.
Feel free to just ignore it.
All what we need is, uh, I'm assuring you that beavers can do it like it isn't like 10 to about 12
states this year.
Now let's see that.
See the implementation.
OK.
The first thing is, let's let's go here.
I'm handling two best cases.
If they're already the two covers, these are equal to the target were returning one.
If the two corpses are in a way less than the target, like, let's say, the cops, the five and seven,
the target is to we would never reach a twin anyway, so cancel it now.
After that, we can have a cue that you need the state state graph.
So what we have here, victor of India, maybe another one would create the structure and say Your legs
are one size, you are to size up to you.
I'm using some hatchet and I will discuss that right now and we have bullion found here now.
We have an initial state and we need to generate like we need to sit here.
So I'm writing here.
Process function.
You probably notice that when I have a lot of copy best I could I try to develop a function to do all
of this stuff.
OK.
It is the business.
As long as we couldn't find it, keep going.
Don't just explore the world graph.
And then we get from the graph, from the Q, the two numbers.
When you think about it, you have mainly six different cases as the problem is.
So I can, for example, MBT the first one, then it would be zero here for MBT, the second one.
It would be zero here or failed the first one.
It would be chemistry or field.
The second one, it would be chemistry to the third.
The case, which is a little bit maybe like a bit tricky, is the one about, uh, booting from one
to another.
You just have to be careful here.
Like, for example, if the if this one has these five units, this one has three units and this one
is empty, like the chemistry.
So when this one bush here, this one would remain three, but this one would be two.
So you need to know the minimums between the source and destination and the possible mass.
You can figure out what's happening here now.
The processing their processing is following the process function.
Take the current gen one and two and the target if it happened that Jaguar and to equal the target found,
is true and return.
I am trying to make an optimization like when you think about it, a state like five and seven is as
simple as seven and five.
And as you know, that are a huge number of states who would like to make things easy.
Optimizations are tricks are very common in competitive programming.
So I'm just saying, Hey, let's a standardized.
There is no need to mark a five and seven and seven and five.
Any of them is the same anyway.
This is kind of an initialization operation.
Now, the last thing is if the state is invested before we added to the queue, now let's think about
the visiting.
Now I would like to mark something as Vista, OK?
So there are a bunch of ways to do that.
The first one is I can use a hash set and order the set own bit of integrated integer or a hash set
or a vector of integer.
What is the problem here?
The problem is.
Bear or Victor are undefined for the hatch set for the northern set.
You have to define their hazard function herself.
I'll show you a code snippet for that.
But the good news here is this is a very nice trick.
Four bit of integers you can create the hash set for them.
In this way you create a map of integer and this integer is looking to end and order the set.
Now there is two good news about that.
The first the good news, it is more efficient because one of the values is the same and the keys here
are used, the ones so memory wise and in certain ways, it is a bit more efficient.
The second good news you didn't have to write your own like victor, a hatchet, for example.
So this is in a way, one nice way.
So the take home message here, if you would like to mark visited bit of numbers, you can always use
a map of an ordered set.
This is mainly there.
The key one here.
I think I wrote your song, could I will show you other two nice ways to do that.
The the second way here, which is a standard one, you create the hatchet, which is actually just
an ordered set or victor.
And then you have some hash function that take a vector and the complete hash function for it and just
return it.
I teach it that already, and we did a structure course.
There is one final ad hoc trek.
Also you can see in competitive programming, which is just following.
The idea is following.
Let's say that they remember Jack one and Jack too, is like one million to one million.
It's actually like a two year rewrite.
Like, you have a set of five and seven and so on, so you can simply convert any bit of number to a
single integer like.
If you are a huge jaguar in Jakarta and you know that that they mention here is up to a million, if
you multiply Jaguar and one million and Jakarta, you convert it to a single integer.
Now all what you need is an order to sit on a single number, but this time you are using longer look.
This is a very nice approach because if you have like, let's say, four variables I, G, K and L know
you cannot use MATLAB above unless it's very inconvenient way.
But you can convert aged care to a single integer.
So this is anyway good, but we don't go this way in the industry.
Be careful.
This is good for competitive programming, and in this theory, this lack clarity in industry.
You have to justify what you are doing here.
And we believe fair code that are very clear.
So anyway, these are the three different ways that you can use to, um, create a clearly this an order.
The set here was adjusted, by the way, give me time limit.
I forgot of this one.
Bastareaud give also me time limit.
Anyway, that I have time limit in this problem is very tight.