The sliding buzzer problem looks scary at the beginning, however, it isn't that bad.
So this is an operation is the problem.
But remember, in Operation Base the problem, you have some source like a string or victor or something
and you apply an operation and you get something else.
And we learned already when you see this kind of operation, this directly create that for you, like
a graph based, the problem.
So what you need here is actually you need to start from an initial state of the operation and get there.
That's it.
Uh, yeah, this is all what you need now.
Uh, the sit in, but can be represented as a victor.
But this would mean you have to create a like a hash, like a hash function to a victor.
But there's an easier way here.
What if you just represented the grid, as is just a string, not as a victor?
So in this way, you can keep using it.
Just sit on the on the string.
Now let's see some number of states.
We have six digits, right?
Zero one two three four five.
So in the worst case, we have factorial N. different states.
So the number of states here are actually very limited, which that the time complexity of this algorithm
is all in the factory.
We never see a similar order before.
So this is in the factorial because in the the time the memory complex, there is only factorial.
OK, let's see some coding things here.
Uh, the first thing is the numbers.
You can write an ugly code here, but if you would like to make things easy, remember that the dictionary
and the dictionary wiki were sitting with his word, right?
So if you have a string of six digits zero, one, two, three, four and five.
Now think of it here, back to the original grid.
You look to that, we have six indices.
Zero one, two three, four five, and for each index of them, you can know exactly where it's neighbors.
So the idea here, this is a victory of one two three four five six elements.
Every one of them is saying which what are the indices of my neighbors?
So the moral of that?
Remember that the election rhetoric, this is just one more like generalization freight.
Uh, so this will make our could very lovely and very nice.
We start the year by converting that import from Vector, a vector to just a single string.
This is a best case if the good is what we call the start to return.
Otherwise, we have normal set and we have the we wish elements in the vector.
The remaining of the good is very straightforward.
We get the root.
We babette's, OK, then search for the index in the current string.
Let's say the string is one two zero three four five.
So you get the index from here.
Now it's index number two.
You go to the direction of two.
It gives you the list of so let's say the list is of two is here zero one two one five.
So let's say that one and five are the neighbors.
Now you try to swear there the neighborhood, you got the new string.
Now check the good.
Is it okay or not?
If not, keep going.
Now you bush in the visited sets.
And the second, as we learned before, if it's true, then it is the new element.
Then you push it here and this is an important step undoing it.
Like I swabbed the two characters.
I swap them again to undo and get back my string.
If you didn't do that, you have.
At least two could be the original string in a new one, which is unnecessarily and waste of time.
As you see, the good overall is pretty simple, but still it.
The the main thing here you see the sted graph when strings.
Now I hope you learned to generalize things that are based on like sted graph.
You see, I know it can have a string, can have two strings, can have a victor, can have a bunch
of valleys and bunch of integers.
You just recognize it as a state.
That's it.