And that is the problem, this might be a bit puzzling for you, but one major source of puzzling is
actually not tracing and understanding the problem.
The second reason it doesn't look like darkly like a graph problem or a water like a b, a face a problem.
So the moral of this problem, this is what we call a simulation problem.
There is a process you simulated.
That's it.
So the problem is actually telling you, keep opening the boxes, keep taking elements from the boxes
up in the boxes to keys, open the boxes and so on as long as you can do nothing anymore.
So that's all in the in the in the problem.
So now when you think about it, if a box is inwards and the boxes inside and the boxes inside it building
the edges, then this is a graph.
So that's all.
Now when you think about it.
Well, what we need is to traverse this graph, but observe here the order doesn't matter.
This is one thing.
Also, it looks like the global status like the order doesn't matter, and the more you open things
as if the more keys you got.
So this is a very like and a standard here.
This is what makes the problem a bit hard.
So now you have a global status of what are the keys that they have, which are boxes are opened.
What are the number of candies collected so far?
This is like your global status.
And you keep updating it.
So, um, what we need is to just simulated, can we?
And given that this is a graph, remember this is a graph and the graph needs someone to simulate to
traverse it.
So one can think, OK, I'm going to use the first or b first to do that.
So B, if this was multi source, is going to be an excellent choice here.
The total number of states are just put in here.
OK, let's see the implementation.
So what do you have in the queue?
The queue has a queue of integers, queue of integers and we push in each itchycoo the box ID and we
have in the boxes at most.
We have here a vector of Boolean to say just visited or not.
So it's like, yeah, based mainly on the the size of the number of boxes I have here to helpful utilities.
The code is very ad hoc.
One of them that add the keys from the boxes and I want another one to open the boxes.
So I do that here for the initial boxes that they give it to me.
So I have initiated a status.
This will create the multi source that I have.
The remaining of the code is a straight forward.
You get the box, you Bobbit, then you add, you add the keys from it.
You open the more boxes that you can open it right now.
OK, at guys is just iterating on every box, getting the keys from this book's marking the key as one.
Remember, these are our global status.
OK, now the open boxes of the following We have a box and this box has.
And we have we have some, some new keys and all the keys, but the Vista array can tell us if this
is open or not.
So if any key is new for us now and never visited, we would push these books and market as listed and
take the Kennedys inside it.
This good would be okay, too good if the problem itself is in your mind.
If you don't have all of these elements together, you will get lost.
Um, I hope it isn't that hard to like to like to understand.