Let's continue our talk about the business in this time, we will learn how actually the business algorithm
works to get the news delivered by Liberty.
It's actually an easy idea.
So here is a graph I restructured and read through this graph to look like level relevant so that the
tracing is is an easy idea for you.
So as we see here with our eyes clearly there, that this is a first level here.
Level one, this is the will to live in 3D before.
So as you see, as I drew it to look like a structure, it it just looks like very nice here.
Now, the way it first goes as following, first of all, we need the cue data structure.
And then we will we need also something to mark what is vested so far like the difference.
And this is the first note, so we will add this note to the queue.
And also would mark this not as vested and the flu was as following as long as the cue has notes, we
get one of the nuts and get its enablers.
If the neighbor is invested so far, we market as vested and added to the end of the queue.
This is a procedure, so let's see it into action.
Here's a starting point we could hear the cue add one to the cue market as vested.
So here is the status of us.
The cue has one.
Vista is one.
As long as the queue is in, this isn't empty.
We will begin with which you note will come from the queue.
The front and one is just not number one.
What are the numbers of neighbors of note number one, three, five and six?
Now we will mark them as visited and add all of them to the queue.
So here is what would happen.
The queue now will have three, five and six, and the Vista nodes are one, three, five and six.
Give the next note from the queue, which is node number three.
Observed now.
We just started processing the first level.
What are the neighbors of November three?
We have no no.
One.
We have five.
We have food and we have seven.
But what is the following mood number one and number five are already market as listed in the queue.
So there is no meaning to consider them again.
So we only add a mark as wasted no deference given.
So here is the next view.
The queue has five, six, four, seven, and all of this news are wasted.
Do we have still more news yet?
Which one is the next nude nude number five?
So get it from the queue.
We are still in the processing of the first level.
Now.
You know, there is an observation here, also that the queue here has five and six and seven.
So it actually have have to move from level two and two loads of room level.
You would always observe that the queue has nodes in order, so the queue order would always be there
be a first order?
Now we get the frontal nude, which is five, get the neighbors of five one three four.
One is twisted.
These twisted four is twisted already.
OK, so we then add them here, so we do nothing.
So they just get five outside of the cube.
Next, we get them with number six.
Nude number six is the last nude here in live in number one.
Now it has only one neighbor, which is zero.
It is invested before and then market zero here.
At this moment, I would like to get to you to get the sense that we end it from one by visiting three,
five and six observe that the first delivery is done.
Why?
Because we added in the queue, the neighbors have.
So this was the queue.
We initially added one.
Then we removed a the one and added the neighbors, which are three, five and six, which means in
the next two, three times when we process the queue, we will get three, five and six, which are
and never number one.
Now, three added For us, uh, for us then would like four and seven.
And six added for us the number zero.
So when we are done with number five, number six, we will have the next nodes in the queue ready for
us and so on.
So let's continue.
Service number six will be removed from the queue and adding new number zero zero No.
Zero go to the queue and also go to devasted array.
The next node is Node No food node.
No food has neighbors of three, five and two, three and five are visited, but two is a new node.
We add and mark a node number two to the queue.
So let's see here now to get here and get here.
We add the next node, which is get the next node, which is seven seven, has number number three,
which is vested.
So we just do not think get the next.
The next node will be zero zero has one neighbor, which is two also visited.
So we just ignore it.
Give it the next node is node number two in the queue.
So that number two has one new neighbour, which is not number eight.
We added here and mark as listed.
So now we get the number two and we are the I hope you get the idea.
The tracing of this idea is as simple as I was doing.
You started from the node and its neighbors.
Now I would like to give you again one more.
I want more trial to get a sense.
Why really is this level by level processing?
We started by one in the queue and added its neighbours, which are three and five and six to one and
then one get outside of the queue and added three, five and six.
When we process the queue in the next time, the next two three steps will process three, five and
six.
So we are short now from two things we are sure that we process delivery number zero in order.
We are sure to process live number one in order.
So now when we when we process three and five and six, each one of them will add his new neighbors.
Now, neighbour number seven and four and zero will be the next.
The rules are to be added here in some order.
We don't care.
Two zero four seven four seven zero.
We just care.
They are the next level.
So when these three nodes are processed, seven, four and zero would be the next nodes in the queue.
When seven get Brussels, it do nothing for Brussels, it will get to zero, Brussels do nothing.
So when the four seven four zero are Brussels as the next level, their children?
Will be added here, the neighbors will be added here.
So that's why the DFS is actually going level by level this way, level whatever level level level limit
it gets to the rules level by level in this order.
I hope you get the sense why the first is actually resisting the elements in this audit.
Now remember, we infer to that the first is actually about the level of the road, which is the surface
to Beth.
So when we reach number two, is this really this to Beth or when you think about it?
Um, let me give you some some highlights for now.
When you think about it here, no no one will add the first level.
And level one, when we process it, it will add the second level and this one, when we added it,
will add the third level this way.
Number two must be the edge is far from the not number one.
What if not, no one has an edge early to number two, then actually in the first two step node number
two would be in the queue with three and five and six as just this dips of one level of one.
I hope the idea is clear for you.
In the next vid, you will learn how to, uh, how to implement it.
So the idea would be like hopefully more clear for you.
Now, one thing before finishing remember is dip in the first three.
The first is actually traversing the graph in in the same logic.
We never consider an edge that is ending at node that is listed before.
So the edges here, the bolded and black edges, this one should be this way.
The bolded and black edges are only the ones that are considered for them, but the three were not at
five because five was listed five or not at four because four was listed as zero at two because two
is listed.
So the actual edges would be this bolded edges.
And as each edge of of them is touching a new node, this means we never have a cycle and it means we
have a three, specifically a rooted tree.
Now starting from one.
So in a very similar way, like the defense, the defense is building this root tree.
If you look through to the graph, you will notice we have eight nodes.
Sorry, we have nine nodes and edges that we count them to make sure one two three four five six seven.
Uh, what do I missed?
I missed this edge here.
OK.
We have actually nine edges and we have nine nodes and we have eight inches.
So this is the graph that we have the first of three.
OK.
Um, try to implement this idea by yourself, defy an accused, started to add things and analyze and
do the time complexity for you, even if you don't completely get it.
You can still implement it.
That's all.