And there was a problem, a bit of challenging problems.
And the first one, the shots, the bridge problem as a swallowing.
You will have a matrix binary values which represent exactly two islands and the island is connected
in the four possible directions.
So when you have here a cell as usual, right down underfoot now, we would like to connect the two
grids together.
So you would like to take the minimum number of zeros, convert them to one so that they are connected.
So for example, here when you see the first one, if you converted this one to one, now the two grids
are connected here.
If you market this one as one and this one has one.
Now we are connected and this one, if you connected this one from here, it's now connected.
This is exactly the problem.
Now you can brute force this problem, but I would like you to challenge yourself and implement it in
all rules time columns.
The next the problem.
That extra problem is very popular computer science a problem, it's good, the three diameter.
The problem exists the only good, but it is premium discrete bulimia.
So if you don't have an account, you will not be able to obtain it.
I am going to use the virgin coming from sponge or mine judge.
So the problem is is following you will have unweighted, undirected, valid three.
You would like to return it the length of the longest to bath in the three, which is the length of
the longest between two nodes here.
Now in in in in graph theory, we called the longest to bath in a tree.
We call it the diameter.
So we call it the three day method.
So this is a description of liquid you will start to by reading one integer.
Each file is just consisting of a single graph.
You will read the number of nodes, which are three, then read the edges one two to three so that the
graph for you is like one to two to three, which is just to observe here the end.
But in the first bush is one be, so you have to convert that to zero based.
Am also providing you with a similar split symbol.
It would all you have to implement is just the three diameter function.
That's it.
Let's see some examples.
This examples from Whittaker's Likud website, which are just more examples for you here.
This is again two steps now in this one here.
If you look there, this here, here, here, here.
This is the longest Sabbath.
This is a three diameter.
Now it is a point.
We can implement this problem with two different solution, the first one is very, very popular on
the internet.
The second one is rarely mentioned and is mentioned more than a data structure, a context rather than
this problem context here.
Now, the first solution, which is very popular people do it, is using only to be a fiscals.
So you might think, how can you do it with two before schools?
Or you can think in a slow version, which can do multiple calls to find the answer?
The proof of this one is an easy one.
Now the interesting thing is, and this is what people most of the people do mention, we can't solve
this problem with only a single day for school, not just to give one one single.
I would like to give you a hint try to think in a rooted binary tree.
You remember the way military it has usually two children only.
So how can we compute the diameter of around crowded, routed by military?
Think of a symbol be a first, a simple defense that can do it?
Uh, don't waste too much time here thinking forever.
Maybe have an hour or so and then proceed.
Try this one too, and then see my solutions.
That's all.