It's solved the homework for this problem.
Um.
So the shot, the bridge.
Um, so let's let's imagine the following something that gives us an intuition.
Imagine we up here we are in a very big grid like that.
And there is some block here 10 times, 10 for the first degree and another.
Ten by ten.
Look here now when you think about it, we need to build this amount of cells to this, to this island
here intuitively.
You didn't need the shooters to pass off this note, for example, to any anything here.
You actually need to know what is the boundary of one island.
And the boundary of the second island.
Like, imagine there are any boundaries here and the boundaries here in the sense that it misses you
would like for every bit of boundaries to know what is the shortest birth.
For example, you take this boundary and try to see the shortest best to all of this boundary and so
on.
So in many times, anyone you would like to know what is the shortest boundary between every cell here
and here?
Let me summarize that.
First of all, the first intuition that you should get is a bone-dry idea.
It is all about we have two separate islands and we have their boundaries.
Remember, we implemented something before they get the boundary off of an island.
So it's all about the boundary of the first island and the the boundary of the second island.
So as a very brute force where you can try for every boundary here and every boundary here just could
be the shortest to both and minimize among all of them.
This looks like slow.
We can actually optimize it a little bit.
Remember the source idea, you can set all of the nodes here.
As one in the queue and then try to find the shortest the best to a specific note, this is a multi
source to one.
You can even do the opposite.
You can take one boundary from here and do it first to get all of the toys here.
So so far, we said one to one relationship.
We say to start with Maltesers and find the set or start with the source and go to the multi destination.
OK, can we do something better?
We can't do what we call multi source multi destination business, and this is a new variant in this
business.
We start to the queue was all over the destination with all of the sources that we need.
And then there'd be a first while working.
Once it found the annual of the destinations, it stops.
Which is very trivial to change for what we do.
So let me let me say that again, we have bounded inwards from here, create them and then find them,
add them to the queue.
And we have boundary nodes from here.
Find them the first wide working on all of this multi sources.
Once if I went to any node from the boundary of this one, it is them.
I hope you over all got the idea, and it isn't that confusing for you.
The purpose of this problem is introducing the Multi Source Multi Distillation variant.
The good news is following we yeah, let me, first of all, tell you a very nice simplification.
The logic say that we need to get the boundaries.
Do we really need to put an effort to find the exact boundaries?
I would say no.
Let's say that you found the the first island and you just add all of it to the queue.
So you added this one, this one, this one, this one, this one, this one, this one, this one,
this OK.
And you also added this one in the middle, which is embroidery boundary, but observed that this one
anyway is going to is going to like, fail to move in a way because it will find that the neighbors
are all market so it doesn't go to anywhere.
So this is a simplification for the could just end all of the needs of the first, the island in the
group in the queue and just play in any set of the second line.
That's it.
So here is how we can implement that.
We will do this first to find island number one, and we will cover all of it with the value two and
then add all of the values in the queue.
Now the DFS has all of their starting nodes and the grid has either the value zero or the value to.
Sorry.
The very one is now, too, and we still have an old one so that the grid now has values too, which
is from island one and one, which was from Ireland to sort of, if this is confusing for you.
Now we will run a single be fast, but four this multi sources.
We will we can use the rhetorics update as a vis a vis the grid by itself.
So now the cells, as I said, either two, four, eight and one or one four island two.
What about the zero zero are the empty sensor that we would like to flip?
Every time you meet a new cell that is zero, we will flip it to value zero.
So now we have three values.
We have zero one two and three four values.
Zero is a cell that is a still not flipped.
Three is a cell that is flipped the value one four of the grid, the two from Island two and the value
two from Island one.
Now if while you are working and you found the zero, then this is already fled to.
So we don't do anything if we find the value to you also stop because you ignore it because in a way
it's just part of you.
If you fell into any of the ones, then you know that you found their target destination.
The first note that find a one represents the smallest number of steps that we need.
I hope you got the message.
The purpose of this problem is introducing the multi source multi destination.
And I would like to confirm that the time complexity for all of the three variants we learned is the
same all of them or even as we now.
Let's see the implementation of that in case you are confused.
This is a normal is Ireland.
This is perfectly normal.
This is a defense, very standard defense on a matrix.
It taken all the color, which is here by default one and new color, which is by default at all.
And just do the new coloring and iterating friends.
So nothing, nothing new here.
We start by searching the grid for an island that has a single one, so I iterate on the wood matrix
and find a single one.
Once I find it, I'm going to do first two from it and break of three.
There is an extra condition here also that say as long as the queue is empty.
What does this queue here observe?
The queue is sent to the queue is global here.
I bush any any note that I find in the queue, all of them.
Theoretically, we should bush only there boundaries, but it doesn't matter so we can push all of them
anyway.
So this is how we initialize the multi source queue.
After that, we do very normal business, this is very normal iterating with the neighbors as normal.
If you found that the sale has value three, it means it was zero and they flipped it to three.
So this is like a vista if the value is too.
This is coming from the first islands.
Also visited ignited.
The first one that find the equally cool one is we managed to make a bridge, so we return to their
level.
Otherwise we wish the neighbor and avoided the sale with the value.
Three.
I hope the problem wasn't that hard for you.