Let's solve the next problem, which is about the three diameter, the three diameter is a very well
known problem in graph theory, and everywhere you will find people describing this first solution.
I would like to tell you a little bit about it, but I will not give too much.
So the idea this following, we would like to find the tree diameter, which is the longest to bath
between two nodes.
Now it is better for you when you are stuck and thinking to start with brute force.
Just think, how can we do everything we can?
We have a tree.
Let's say the tree has five nodes.
OK, so what about just the brute forcing every bit of nodes?
This is just one way, right?
Like dig this node and this new Warsaw and so on.
This looks like very stupid.
We can we can trivially do something better than that.
Just try for every node and then do a bit of force to find the forest node from it.
Do a bit first to find the first one for me.
So we have nodes.
Then for each node, I'm going to run one business, though this takes over all of the times it v for
every node I will find the forest.
What?
What first one from it?
OK.
Clearly, if the first if the node that you have is one side of the diameter, then we definitely find
the other side of the.
But which one of this one must be really part of the damage that we do know?
Let me tell you one very interesting approach that is coming on the internet.
The idea is following if we run beliefs from any random note and in the forest and not from it, this
forest and wood must be bought off one of the diameters.
Let me say that again, big any random note from here, let's say we beg the distance, compute the
forest, the not from it using a single force, which should be either this note or this note, let's
say this note here.
Then there is a claim that this note must be part of the tree diameter.
OK, where does that either a tree diameter dig this very far and wood and defines the forest from it?
So what is the forest one?
This one could be the forest student here.
So this now news represented their tree diameter.
So the algorithm in these is following big in Inwood, let's say zero.
Find the forest.
Not for me.
Let's say let's call it V1.
Now, to be a first from V1, find the forest node from it.
Let's say v2, v1 v2 must be the tree diameter.
What did the time complexity of that is just implies we will run this twice.
Let me show you the good.
So here is here is the cut the tree diameter function was following this first function, I modified
the beer fest to return to things it return to there the forest route and return the delta to the forest.
OK, but by the way, this is a nice observation to note.
We know that the buffs keep exploring the woods one by one, right?
So let's get this current outside of the loop.
Once this loop end, then current must be the forest route that the beef is reached.
Again, let's say we did best from here.
We first give this thing level by level.
Would this be a first and the last thing would we get from the queue must be the first, then we can
find that in a different way.
We can just iterate on the 11th ray and get the largest value.
But by definition, once the beef is ended, the less the value we get from the queue.
Is the forest node in the queue.
So current here to in the forest, the wood and length represent it's it's live.
Now, the second thing here we do is follow, I do first be a first from zero eight return home for
me, the forest and wood and its distance.
We don't care about the distance.
We will do another face from this note.
So to return for me, a new beer.
Now the beer here, the present to the forest and would so be one.
The return value that's first represented the opposite value, the other value and the second represented
the length of this value.
Good wise, as you see, it's matter of getting the forest and making to be a fiscals.
Now what's really challenging this problem is this following.
The the algorithm looks like intuitive when you think about it, if you found the forest node from any
node, then you actually Richard that one of the very boundaries of the tree.
So intuitively, this node seems to be part of that of the diameter.
So if you did another bit further from it, you should find the other opposite or the other end of the
diameter.
But the challenge really is to make a solid and formal proof for it.
Uh, I'm putting here's some initial thoughts, but I personally never try to prove it like in a full
way.
Now I would like to show you an easier idea that is more efficient and is directly to be understood
and easily to be proved.
Converting to this very common approach on the internet.
So let's see here.
And I don't know why people do mention this approach off, like they focus a lot on the office idea.
The idea is is following.
We have a three.
We will rule this three from anywhere.
So let's say we have the directive to lead this way.
I learned this algorithm the first time in the in the binary trees, in the binary tree, the same problem
is asked to find the tree diameter, so I learned this solution.
Now the idea is as follows This is a general tree that could have, maybe, let's say, here three children
or four children.
We will rule.
We will root this tree to grow this tree just the first from anywhere and then only the edges that you
take out of the one that exists as a direction.
So for example, if I did the first two from zero, then this would be the direction.
This would be the action.
This would be the direction and so on.
Routing the tree is something that's very common.
I don't know if people Chad Brown will now set out the tree or route the tree.
No, I'm not a native speaker.
Um.
OK, so now what is the point?
We have a three, which is the three diameter let's the let's pretend for a while that this is just
the binary three, OK?
Now, imagine that you are at the root here, we will find the solution with a single device.
Let me show you first the very simple task we will you will need it, which is the three height of the
road.
The height is the longest, the best from the north to the cliff.
So for example, what is the height of this node?
Let's make another try here.
That's the height is one, two or three.
So the height of this node three, because it is the longest bus would meet the height of this node
is just two.
Let's say here, the height of this node is to the height of this node is one.
And so it.
Uh.
It seems I'm adding extra one.
OK.
So anyway, so this would be like a four and three and the two and the one here, so every leaf node
is like one by itself.
OK.
This is the height of the tree, I hope it is an easy idea you should study the height idea in the data
structure.
OK, now what is a solution?
We are doing a device here, which is a 3D printer.
There is only two cases for the three there.
There is only two cases for the reader.
The first, the case is the 3D printer will best buy my nude.
Will Best Buy may not the second case is that idea ever thought it would not Best Buy my note, if they're
if they're then that doesn't occur, doesn't it read does it best buy my note, then that occasion will
find it in a way in one of my children.
What is the answer?
If the diameter will bear in mind, would.
The answer simply is.
One B+.
Your height from the lift is three and height from the right.
So let's say the tree diameter is as follows this way.
So the height from the lift route will go this way.
The height from the right note would go this way.
And then you add yourself five, let me say that again in a binary tree where everyone just has two
children.
The tree diameter is you either best for me or not.
For me, if you're best for me, then my answer should be the longest.
From the left side and the longest from the right site and adding me to them.
Otherwise, we just find the answer in the children.
OK, what if we are more than just two children?
What if it's a general three?
Then you need to find the longest sides in the longest to heights in your children, the longest two
heights in your children.
So let's see here.
Imagine we have the route here.
We have one would here.
This is one Beth, and we have another one here and we have another one here.
And we have another one here.
Now I need the tree diameter, so I will take the two children with the longest the height, which is
this one here.
And this one here.
And then add myself for them.
So this is the longest diameter that best with the current two.
I hope you good the idea, the good is very straightforward.
You first start by writing the tree diameter code itself.
OK, so let's first write the tree diameter grid itself.
The tree diameter would be one blasted the maximum off all of my children.
I'm here trying to take the maximum.
I'm keeping the maximum of my best to children.
You iterate as this is three.
I don't want to use the vista, right?
Uh, so if you don't want to use a vista array, you just make sure you don't go back to your spirit.
We did that before you recurs on your children and your child here will return to that height of this
child.
Now I'm giving the two maximum children.
If the maximum height is this then etche, then we take it here and give the maximum height to hide
one and give myself for this side one.
If it's actually equal or less than me, we see if we can give it to the second day.
This is a straightforward to find the two maximum values here.
Now what is the height of the new tree?
It is just one below the maximum height in it.
OK, where is the tree diameter and globally initializing variable called maximum there so far, and
I'm updating it.
So the maximum diameter here is the maximum height for me, plus the maximum height for the child.
And as leaf node return one.
So in a way, as a wrote, I'm included here.
It's like a brother here.
I hope you get the idea.
This good is mainly the good for the tree diameter, and this line is updating the max.
This this good is for the tree height, and this is the extra single line of code to find their tree
there with that.
So this one is updating the maximum diameter.
It's simply saying for every node, what is the longest diameter in this node and maximize among all
of them.
So now the advantage we get sort of this good is, first of all, it is trivial to good because it just
depends on the tree height, which is easy to cut.
Second, it's just single, the first not to be a fiscals.
Third, the logic to prove it is very easy.
We were practically speaking, we tried to compute the diameter, if it will best by a node.
And also, it has this nice insight.
You are thinking about that.
There are middle values, the middle nodes, the B.
If a solution is thinking about the boundaries, you cannot find the boundary.
Then another be forced to find another boundary.
But this the first solution is thinking about the intermediate nodes.
It say this is a node.
What happens if the Democrats best from here or find the longest and find the longest?
This is my my sequence.
I think this is a nice and intelligent solution.
We can still building the diameter with the S is a straight forward building.
The diameter here is also, I think, doable.