So we learned a lot of tricks, and it might be A. If you try it by yourself to always summarize things
like when you learn a lot of tricks from different angles.
Don't just let them float in your mind.
Try to make somebody.
So let me give you one good summary for the things that we're learning so that you can review it from
time to time.
Now, first of all, graph traversal is all about you have any nodes in some graph and you would like
to visit.
So the word traversal is mainly about visiting.
We learned the two main algorithms that we can use, the four that the depth first search and the bridge.
First, we can see that there are a lot of applications for both of them, like reachability, finding
connected components, detecting bicycles by birthright test and a lot of things in real life scenarios.
You can see that in different ways, like web crawling, for example, you have a beach and you have
another beach and you have another beach, and you would like to move from a beach to another based
on the links.
This is simply traversing for the links in garbage collection and social network.
I have my profile and your profile, and we have a beach and we have a boost and we are navigating between
all of them.
So this algorithms can be translated to real life applications that are based on connections.
When we think about the defense and defense we can think of from the flu perspective dips, the first
surge is representing the phenomena of going deeper and deeper.
The numbers here doesn't represent the new numbers, they represent the acceleration order.
So this one will be explored the first than this one than this one than this one.
Then the decision go back than this one because you can go back than this one and so on May 1st.
On the other side, follow level by level.
So we finish here, then here, then here, then here, then here.
And so on.
So this actually do like real life phenomena as we give examples before.
When you think about the properties, you will notice the following like defense, BFC can be used in
all of the reversal things like connected component and all of that, but there is one great advantage
for this device in an efficient way can be used to find the shortest path is in unweighted graphs.
So we learned that given the first is finding the nodes level by level, it means we can find the shortest
Abarth.
Can DFS find the shortest Abarth?
Yes.
But you will have to wait till you navigate the wall graph, which is less efficient than the office.
Now, don't get me wrong.
Don't think that this is is way better now than the office.
This isn't the case.
In fact, people discovered many Buddha abilities for DFS that billy a key role in many algorithms.
Let me give you some names for that.
No, the time is Tan Ming edgy classification, the biological sword, strongly connected components,
articulation edges, articulation nodes, Euler tools, and many.
Many of the algorithms observed that I probably will not cover most of these algorithms.
I plan to cover topological suit mainly, uh, not not all of this stuff, at least not in virtual and
not in M.2.
I'm not sure if there will be, but the theory of this course or not.
Now, should you go ahead and cover these algorithms?
The answer is no.
Is it added value to learning these algorithms out of graph theory topics are really fun and really
are very educated.
Um, in terms of real life implications, the strongly connected components may be the one that you
can see much more in.
Real life, oil output is very limited in real life applications.
Articulation edges is very nice, but there's also limitation.
So if you have to learn something among all of this maybe strongly connected component B be the one
to learn.
I'm saying that so that if you are following up on algorithm scores and you see this topic so you don't
get choked, this are the topics that I intentionally dropped, at least from part one.
But to.
And you can find a lot of details about that in the sellers book book.
Let's move.
So we learned that the office actually is way stronger than before.
The office is a few magical, recursive lines of goods.
We learned that we must use Vista Array.
The only exception is if you are using trees, observe that for dogs, you need visited arrays in a
tree in a graph like one, two, three and then one.
Or.
Three, you see, three is the vista twice if there is a huge tree here and you do not have visited
Ray, two would explore all of that.
Then Ford will explore all of that.
Well, it was visited the DAG.
You will not go here.
OK, so the only time and the only case where you do not need visited Ray is only the tree data structure.
By avoiding going back to your parent, remember that the defense is using a built in stack.
But remember, the built in the stack is usually small, so you have to be careful with their face when
it comes to denser graphs in it that you are in competitive programming and it seems that you have runtime
error.
Probably the device went to very deep.
The good news we still can write an iterative version of that defense.
Using our internet is that the code will not be intuitive enough, but in a way it's will be a face.
On the other side is a bit longer code that is iterative and using our belt.
To the structure.
We can use length to rate on a just say if it is visited or not, we can even use it to know the shortest
the birth of A..
We learned that both of the algorithms are using all those v for in the time and all the in the memory.
So I guess you are pretty good.
No implementation details.
Some thoughts on the nature of the algorithm.
The the device can be on a weighted or unweighted graph, but the context will decide what can we do
exactly?
The most popular usages would be reachability connected components.
Finding a in some cases now notes the following device is one to end the relationship you will see.
This 1mm notation, in course, is like a database course.
One time means one to mean the relationship.
So here in this context, we mean we have one node as a source, but we have multi destination nodes.
As you know, if I would like to add this to four reachability, I can run the FSA from one and then
explore all of the nodes.
So we say the difference is one in the relationship.
Now, what if I would like to know if all of the nodes in the graph can go to one or not, which is
always it now?
No, the problem is the office is one two m, not m one.
However, as we learned in one of the problems by just the reverse thinking, we can do the opposite.
So now if you try to reverse every edge in the graph, like, let's say here, I would like to know
if every node can go to zero or not.
So this is a graph.
I have to run the first from every node now, right?
So now the observation is, if you reverted this graph, so it's now zero, one, two and three reverse
at the edges and with only a single differs from zero, you got their nodes and you got the question.
So with a reversal track, we can also handle the multi source single distillation problem.
So insanity defense is one two m and to emit metal one, which is logically mean also to want one.
But it isn't M2M, which means you can start to use Multi Source two to target multi distribution.
Uh.
Looks like a big clean.
We me remember.
Uh, uh.
OK, let me tell you a trick.
How to make the first multi source multi destination.
Um, let's say you have.
Two three nodes here and two roads are here.
OK.
You would like to know.
Zero one two three four.
You would start from not zero, one and two and you would like to get you would like to get all of the
nodes that are reachable by zero, one and two.
So you can run the first two from zero to market three and then from one, it doesn't go anywhere new
to mark four.
So in this way, we are treated on every node to run the FSA from it and the array.
Would we be efficient?
This is if we algorithm there is a nice track.
If you would like to run only a single device, create a new node extra node.
Let's call it node number five connected with the nodes that you would like to start to form them like
zero, one and two.
Now run the office only from five five will get all of these nodes and out of this nodes.
I hope you good the trick.
If you learned the maximum flow topic, you will, you will see this trick a lot in a way, in a formal
way.
We can say that mainly the difference is one to m and limit to one a relationship.
Um, reverse.
The thinking in general is very useful technique, although it doesn't appear that much.
Another case remember in the Atlantic Water War problem, we did the first from the bone that is like
in the problem.
It asked us if the nodes can reach the boundary or not.
Then we changed the problem and said, Does the boundaries, Richard, are nodes or not?
So this kind of changes sometimes make the problem much easier.
But there is a common mistake here.
You should observe if reversing the problem definition should have an effect on the problem, text or
not, like maybe it is, and b now is greater than B.
So be careful about that.
This variable isn't the problem.
Now moving to the beef, the beef, this is mainly for unweighted graph, but it can also work on weighted
graphs such that it is going to send to value like, let's say all of the graph has value seven.
So practically speaking, it doesn't matter the value.
Doesn't change anything, so it's either unwanted graph, which is the formal definition or weighted
with the coolest tend to value.
We learned how to code smartly the level by level, and this is a smart contract that you should always
remember.
And also, I told you that there are two ways to implement their beliefs.
Some people verify early the starting Newt and some people doesn't in our could you have to verify early
if you have any condition on the starting Newt?
You have to verify it first as we learn it in the problems.
One of the key application for the first really is the shortest the birth you will actually notice Bible
use, say, in competitive programming.
They use the first most of the time, but when it comes to shortest to bath and unwitting graphs, they
use the office and we met a very nice application for that.
The three diameter application we learned there are three variants in, there are.
Actually, for very sorry for variance for BFC, we can do the one to one.
We can do the one too many, which is natural and classical.
We learned that to do the emitter one, we would all of the image in the queue and run it.
And we learned also that we can even make M2M by creating all of this node in the queue and all of this
nodes in the queue.
Like, let's say, here.
Let's say that this are your initial ones.
This are your final ones.
You can watch all of this for news in the queue.
Then this one in level one, this one would be covered at level two.
This one would be covered.
So in two double steps, we reach it from here to here.
So this is merely the variance that we studied, observed that there is a variant that scored zero one
before this.
The zero won't be a first means that a graph has values which are either zero or one.
But this be this variant can be easily understood when you study that extra algorithm.
Before that, it's very hard.
You would you would be bothered with the correctness proof of it.
So this many are the different things about their beliefs.
The graph it's important to remember something about revisiting the news, I would like to make it more
explicit here if you are in undirected graphs, then you can revisit the nodes.
But there are actually two cases here.
The first the case, if you are at, say, zero one two three four.
No, this is a cycle.
So we are wasting back our initial load.
The second case, which I call a fixed cycle when you go from zero to one and try to use the same edge
to go to one to zero, this is a fake.
The second case in the erected graphs and directly graphs that there are no fixed hikers, if you missed
if you missed the note, then you have it.
If zero one have two edges in a way, then it's any way given.
So this is fake.
And in that as a given example, you can revisit the nude.
So although in there there are no cycles, but you still can revisit the nude.
So you must use a listed array for that.
The only case where you don't need their vested rape is their trees, but be careful them from their
fixed cycle.
We look at the graph can be in any domain like maybe a problem based on Emily's management would enter.
The graph can be owner to degrade within a different ways to get the neighbors.
You should be good in that most of the time we can see that graph values are mainly on edges, but also
we met cases where the nodes themselves have also values.
Now, the reductions we met several problems, remember you were lucky because you see a problem.
That doesn't seem a grave problem.
But I put it in grave problems.
So you have 50 percent the hint that this problem would be mad to a graph.
In reality, you will not even know that you will read a problem about race and think it's a race.
And there is nothing that say this is a graph problem.
So this would be really tricky for you.
So, but anyway, we are an educational quiz fees.
So the key to figure that this is a graph is to interpret what are the nodes and then what are the ages?
The good news.
Most of the time we can see many problems are based on numbers, and you can see that a number or an
index is actually the node we learned in the lecture.
The case in the fractions we learned about the consecutive sequences in the practice and so on.
We also learned about the strings.
We can see that a string can be A..
And we learned about this operation thing.
When you have an operation that you apply on a string and get you a new string, then it just string
is a node and the operation create an edge for us.
And now let's generalize that whenever you have a state could be a number a string, five strings,
a vector object and an operation that convert it to another thing like from a stranger to another string.
Then this is another, and this is an so we call this as a state.
So this is this is how you generalize your ideas when you see this kind of relationships, a mapping
from social destination.
And this is what I call a state graph.
The key the key is that graph here is like a state diagram in software engineering.
It's the graph where it's, you know, it is a state, a state can be anything.
Maybe the state is like seasoned food is a bulb ID.
And on and off for this, it may be the state is a three strings, an integer like a b, c, d, d,
x y and 17.
This is you to state, and there is another state that has x x x y y y a b and twin in one or two other
than one.
These another state.
There might be edges between them.
I'm trying to to push you to think in a state in a very generic way.
The vector of the values might be a state.
So now what you really have to be careful about it is your vista set will depend on the total number
of different states.
So the first thing when you decide to approach it as a state is the problem is to think about the total
number of states.
Imagine, for example, each state is a string consisting of exactly five letters lowercase letters.
Now, every every lowercase letter is 26 choices.
So we have 26 I 26 the blah blah blah.
Five times this is twenty six times about two the power five, which which is 11 million states.
The good news is we didn't.
We don't usually traverse all of them.
We usually traverse a small subset of them.
And this is take us to a new tab here.
Avoid converting a solid graph to an explicit graph.
Maybe you let religion that it state by state and give them number zero one two blah blah blah.
Up to 11 million.
You can do that in theory, but this is very bad.
This is very time consuming in general.
What you need is to figure out where are the nodes and how to generate the edges.
This is probably would be the case, and we learned about the an example of that like the shortest path,
problem and other a few ones.
Later, when we study the backtracking, a topic, you will notice that backtracking is all about statecraft.
The office or office?
Let's finish here.
This is sometimes is an area of debate.
You usually need to get some words about the graph, and in many cases you do know.
But in a way, the graph size, the density, all of that gives you signals about the graph size and
what can you do and what you cannot.
If you have a graph that is the really large, dense one boasts probably the DFS and DFS will have big
computational problems and b, if it's if the target is at a reasonable depth like you are here.
And you know that anyway, the the answer is within four steps only.
Then this is pretty good.
But if that if the dips isn't known, for example, or very far and the graph is we're white by wire,
they mean every note has too many choices.
This means that you will have too many nodes and you are actually exhausting.
The whole graph or a large subset of it probably will face some memory concerns.
Also, be careful the defense can exhaust your built in a stack.
I also give you some insights about the iterative defense, where you only use some depth to say defense
up to level five defense up to level nine, they face up to 15, and you try in a gradual way to see
if you found the answer or not.
You can think of it very similar to that to the first in a level by level of state defense might be
more suitable for a general graph search, but again, be careful.
Defense is more friendly to use in a distributed environment because if you have different machines
and you have a very large graph, you can tell this machine to start from not.
This machine to try starting from June 27.
But anyway, still not that easy to implement.
You shouldn't memorize that and trying to give you insights about the trade offs as a good software
engineer and far from algorithms you should learn to.
Have trade offs, and as you see, there is nothing that is a full winner in everything.
It doesn't go this way.
You will be back the engineer, and you have choice for this technology or this technology or this technology.
Should they use this database, a style like the rational relational databases or I should use no sequel.
Everything has pros and cons.
That's all.
I hope you enjoyed it.