Let's continue and see how can we implement the idea of the breadth versus.
We will implement two versions in the first version, which is a very standard one.
The function is as follows it takes an adjacent Celeste and inserting a note, so be a face.
Always need a starting point and a victor would be returned.
This victory represents the shortest line of I.
Which you will return is the number of ideas from the start to die.
In other words, it is the shortest to from the starting point.
To this point, I said I didn't serve.
The start must be with zero.
Now, initially, we'll initialize all of this array was a big, a big value, for example, one million
or so, it depends.
So this then can be now indicator for the twisted itself, like if the value is, oh, we know that
this node is invested so far, if it has a value, then it is already sold with that value, the processing
of BFS goes as following.
Whenever we have a new node, we market as vested in the referee by putting its current length.
And we add to information to the queue.
We add the current node and it's the level.
The level of A. is one of the Birand level.
So let's see the implementation here.
We started by creating the lens array of nodes and all value that you will have two values on item.
Initially, we say we started from the start with level zero and we mark here that the length of the
thought is zero.
Now, the queue will keep working as long as we have more and more nodes in the first system.
We get the next note from the queue and we remove it.
We added only a single element here, so we get the single element here.
So let's say the starter was just one.
So we market that length of one is zero.
Now from the View here, it seems that one will have three neighbors three, five and six.
So the current node would be three delivered would be zero.
We start iterating by over the neighbors, so neighbors here would be the three and five and six.
And each time will check if it is visited before or not.
So if the rest of the neighborhood equal, it means we never visited it.
Otherwise, if it's visited already, we just ignore it because we already found the churches to both
what it would do.
You visited it.
If it is a first time to visit the node, first of all, we push it to the queue, so the queue in the
next time will have three value three.
And the level will be level plus one, which is here zero.
So it's one.
So now after this is Deb, the queue now has three and one, and the next iteration it would be five.
It will add five on one, then add six and one.
Now.
This, too, is done, and we go back here is that you and Betty know that you now have three values.
It has that next to three values that are exactly one step far from me.
So one is removed.
But it added for us three and five and six so that you will keep going and it will take the value three.
The value three is at level one.
Who are the neighbors of three, five, one and five and four and seven?
Observe that one has length of zero.
Five has length of one.
So these two will be ignored in this condition.
But the value four and very seven will not be ignored.
So when it comes to the value seven, for example, it would push seven and level two, which you mean
we took two steps to discover seven and add here levels of seven is two in a similar way.
It would add length, so food is two.
We already did this dressing before.
So now the Q has a value five and six and seven and four and so on.
I hope the the implementation just reflects what we already explained.
Before you keep going in the queue, become a big government, get its value to level, then iterate
on the numbers.
If we visited this neighborhood before then, we already know the shortest path for it.
Otherwise, we are done.
For example, five can be explored from one to five in a single step or from one to three to five in
two steps.
So five would be similar to early from one.
So we don't care about three five as a connection.
I hope the idea here is clear.
Now I would like to show you a smarter implementation that is also easy to get sense of correctness
of it.
Here is the idea.
Assuming general put on this graph, assume in general, the third level has five news.
The third delivered has five news alerts.
A pretended IQ has now exactly the five nodes.
What happens if we've processed the Q five times only?
Five times early, if we book the five notes only from the queue.
First of all, all of the nodes in level three will be gone from the queue.
Second, all of the nodes in the next level will be added.
So observed with the following.
Let me give you an example here the queue initially has value one.
If we process only one time after a single step, the one would be gone from the queue and that you
have three, five and six, which are their second delivery in the queue.
Now how many nodes in the queue?
Three nodes.
If you bruces the queue three times, then three go out of it and at seven and four five two eight six
eight zero.
After that, what?
What, what has been done?
Three, five and six, which are level one, are one, seven, four and zero are in the queue.
Let me say that in a different way.
If you bruces the queue such that in each single step, you process the size of the queue all of it
at once, you remove all of the current river node and add all of the nodes of the next level.
So what does this mean, we can determine the level from the processing order going back to the previous
version?
We needed to give it the level here as a tribute and edit here as the villainous one.
What I'm telling you is we can't actually know this information if we processed in a smarter way.
What is the advantage?
We have a bit similar code.
We don't need this integral from here.
So let's see the new implementation.
The new implementation goes as following.
It will keep going again as long as the queue isn't empty.
Now there is new to things here.
I initialize variable named the level, which is zero and there is a block here.
After the level, the level would be initialized to B+ Plus.
So the committee 2+ plus Sullivan will go here zero, one, two, three and four.
The second thing is the size, which is initialized with one is always replaced with the current queue
size.
So let's see what's happening here.
This internal body is the same.
We didn't change it.
The only thing is the cuno has only the node value, and we bush only then would value.
So here's what happened in the first step that you would have size of one.
Then this way you will only be processed one all the time.
So after one one year, one step, only the three, five and six would be added in the next step.
The size would be three.
So this way, look will be processed the three times which will process three and five and six, and
there are more nodes will be added in the queue.
But what matters is after three steps, the three, five and six would be booted out of the out of side
of the queue and the seven and four and zero will be added to the queue.
So the new size is again three.
Then we processed three times seven, four and zero will be processed and got out of the queue.
Only two will be added.
So in the next step, the queue would have only the next one next valley here, which is to as size
one and so on.
So the idea is it's following we can literally process that you literally level by level.
And this while loop here is what allowing us to do that.
So which version to you is most of the time when you need the actual level, then this is the way to
go because it is way easier than other ones like it doesn't need here a beer or fits.
And second, all of that you just maintain the level here.
Uh, if if you don't need the level, then you can just use this version, and even in this case, you
will not even also need this interior for the river.
You don't need the rivet also here, for example, in some Boolean function.
If we would like to know if this is reachable or not.
So this is mainly the change here.
The length also as an array, you keep using it if you need that and if you just need to know it's visited
or not, then you can just use a normal visit.
So it depends most of the time you will notice you are using this version.
Now, let me highlight some properties about the algorithm, and I hope that you got the tracing of
it.
Some people like to say that we have three status here white, gray and black, which are the colors
when you think about the graph.
We actually have three different statuses for the them.
The first is the status that the node is never visited.
The second status is the node is marketed here and visited, but not breakfast yet.
The third state, when we buy it here, the node is visited and processed, so we can say we actually
have three statuses for the for the nodes, implementation wise, as you see.
It doesn't matter.
We don't care more than it is visited or not, and that you will get the next one.
So we don't have to keep labeling it with the three different cases.
The second thing is clearly that you would always have to have have unique values.
Why?
Because we only push the value if it is never visited before.
So every note is only bush the one time.
The third thing, which is an interesting observation now when you think about Vision one here, the
Vision one.
Keeps adding and moving in a conservative way.
This means at any point of time that you will have.
Mix up to two levels, for example, that you could have at the moment.
Five six and the Valley seven six and Valley seven and seven four, maybe seven four zero and two,
maybe only seven and foot that you would always have either information from one level or two levels.
Does this matter?
No.
But again, it's just about ability here in this one.
The interesting thing is, by definition, after the processing of the wood level, we will have only
the nodes of the second level.
There is one one minor difference between the two things.
This one is a bit easier to think and prove compared to this one.
This one is a bit more complicated because the queue in every iteration has this mix of the two levels.
You are updating yourself all the time and you don't know exactly which one you belong to.
In this one, when you try to think about the correctness, it would be way easier because you just
are adding he had no delivered by it.
OK, so remember, this is what we could there be a first three, right?
So actually, the beef is three, which represent the only the only use.
The edges here represents actually the shortest the bath, where the shortest path here represents the
number of edges from the starting point to the target point.
So when you think about the search from one to five, it would be one two five four one two zero two
one six zero from three to zero eight.
It would be also three to eight here, three four, two eight and so on.
You don't even want the shortest.
The bus from three to eight must be also three four two eight.
But anyway, we don't care about that.
What we care, the major focus is the best from one to any one of them actually represent their ages
here.
Please feel free to check out the the formal proof in the sailors book.
But however, it's very easy to get an informal sense of it.
The complexity we only add in the queue, the unvisited nodes.
This means we will have only all nodes to be explored in the queue now forever renewed.
We iterate on all of its neighbors.
Thinking about it individually would be hard.
But when you think about it as a global view, aggregating that every node is treating its children.
So the overall we actually iterated on all of the edges.
So the addition of of the neighbors here.
From a global view, I just represented the this is exactly as we did before in the defense.
So the total complexity is, again, Ebola's V and that you will have maximum of any nodes or vineyards,
so we have all the memory complex.
This is exactly the same memory and time complexity of the device.
Now for the correctness, the sailors book is actually implementing Division One Division One Brew.
It is still intuitive, but not the direct uh.
It is very beneficial for you to try to read the proof.
But I would like you to like, give it the following in mind when you read format proofs expected to
iterate a lot and it isn't helpful to try to explain formal proofs in lectures with full details.
The best thing is if you would like go ahead and keep reading and reading it, read maybe five or six
times or more.
It depends on your mathematical background until you get it.
I would like to give you some keys because you might be new to the the silliest books I would like.
Just give you some symbols.
G represented a graph.
So G that V is like the graph of vertices.
Think here is an object and g that V is an attribute when we say g that v minus s this minus mean subtraction
mean.
Except so it means, like all of the vertices except to the searching vertex you is a vertex itself.
U the smolka ripper is Vertex.
You will not see it in the Sudoku, for example.
Use that colour.
Remember, we mentioned they have three colours.
You did colour you the D you did by the dot here like an object.
So this is obviously the colour, obviously the distance object, goodbye and so on.
So the first here is like a thread on every node that isn't the starting point and initialize it in
this way.
The boy here represented the parents there by a representative parent, for example, the parent of
four would be three.
The parent of six is one, the parent of zero six and in the homework we will see you would be asked
to bring to their dad to bring to the actual birth.
So you will need to add the parent the delta here.
This Delta symbol represented the shortest about.
So when we say this to is and we it mean the minimum number of ages from SC to V.
So using this symbol should be enough so that you get you don't get confused about the symbols.
Feel free to read it for the correctness.
Version two is probably way easier than proving the first the first version because the Q in every stage
has only the vertices of the current level.
So one would generate for us three five and six, three, five and six hundred seven four zero seven
four zero three two two would generate it, and it will go in exactly for live, as we did here.
So when you think about it informally, this one got the first level.
Definitely there is no shorter birth then.
One two step two three one two step two five one step to fix.
Now, in a very similar way, the three is adding the next one here.
When you drew the graph in a vertical way, this way you can see it.
Clearly, three is going to add its neighbors.
If the neighbor is visited already, then this mean we definitely know a shorter birth.
If if we never met it before, then it's definitely the shortest path for it because if it was found
in, it really was, it should be visited.
If it is in and we are iterating and processing in a level by level this way, then I must be the shortest
path here.
This is very informal definition.
If you don't get the intuition in a very strong way, believes feel free to, uh, to read the to read
the book and read a lot with the proof itself.
Feel free to do that.
Also, after solving the practice, I'm trying to make the course more practical.
But still theory is part of the mixture, but the practice will make things much more intuitive.