The first homework in the office, the first one, I would like you to modify the lecture to bring to
the best from the starting A. zero to every other note.
So here is an example.
This is this is a graph as we see we have five nodes, so this is the usual reading style.
You read number of cases, nodes, edges and so on.
So we have your very direct one zero one two three and then two to three and then four to three.
OK, so if we started from I think I was going here from zero, right, yes, from zero, if we started
from zero, you can see here I'm listing the best from zero to one zero two zero three zero four.
So zero one is just one zero two, just two zero three zero one two three zero four.
There is nothing here.
And here is the bigger graph.
So we have my notes, so you'll print from one to eight when every note you would bring to the bath.
So how can you get you get the bath you need?
You will need some beer and tray and you would need to fill it somehow, and you need to print it somehow.
So this is the first task and it's an easy task.
Don't get scared from it.
In the second, the problem, we will solve their Grass Valley tree problem firmly in this problem,
it says you will be given a tree.
OK, so you'll be given a graph and would like to validate if it is true or not.
So the labels would be from zero to one and you would be given it just as usual in Lakewood is just
two values represented.
There represent the ages and it is actually an undirected tree and and values zero based.
You are literally true only if this is a valid tree.
OK?
If there are no silver loops or remitted edges, and I would like you to use fence, we definitely can
implement that with the defense believes a stick to using us as much as you can during their the homework
of this section.
So here is a graph.
Clearly, this is a tree.
Remember the tree?
There is only single base between every two nodes in the tree.
There are no cycles.
OK, so for that, in the second example, here we have, as you see, this isn't a graph, isn't a
tree because we have a cycle here.
And the third problem we would like to do the following we have, uh, let's see an example here, whether
you have a to the matrix and in these two metrics, you have the person and you have food and would
like to know that how many steps it will take to reach it.
So let's see there again the definition of the problem.
So you would like to to find the shortest birth to any any food cell.
OK, so how is The Matrix represented?
You will have only one star which represent your current location.
The hash is the cell food.
You would like to find any one of these multiple ones.
The zero means that this is a free space so you can move inside this.
Is this an x represent an obstacle.
You can move in the four normal directions, and you would like to alternate the shortest path to any
of the food cell.
So the the closest one to you?
Otherwise, you return minus one.
So this is the first example.
It is the second one.
The person here, as is, he cannot go to this one.
And the third example, the person can go here and here, so this is the shortest one here, so there
are two food cells, but we only need the shortest one, so please, yeah.
Read the full example and verify it.
And here here are more examples, please read and verify.
Yeah, that's sort.