Let's solve the first homework, the first one about money printing, they're bringing their bath,
and this is actually a symbol of change here.
We started by creating an array that we will call their parents and we initialize it with minus one.
Now.
We expected the following, like, let's say we have a disconnected Gadhafi's following, for example.
And let's say zero one two, and we started from zero.
So expected that no one would have been in zero, not two would have burnt one.
This knew, and this would have been a minus one minus one because they are disconnected and no zero
would have minus one as this connected.
So what happened here is as normal.
We just add this here line here.
Load of could we see that the parent of the neighbor is currently the parent of the neighbor is current?
So we are told, for example, food we have here child five, a child, the sixth child seven.
And I am saying that you know what?
The parent of five is food and the parent of six is food, and the parent of seven is four.
So in this way, we are building a building their relationships, and there is an interesting thing
here to highlight.
I previously told you that in the rooted graph, one way to represent it is just a single area.
Remember that?
We mentioned before, if you have a tree like zero one here, two and maybe four.
I told you that in a routine directed graph like that, where every node has only one parent we can
represent, that was an array, right?
So I can say here that.
Zero one, two, three four.
I can see the berrent of zero is minus one parent of two is you parent of one?
Is you parent of four is two?
This is minus one here.
So this way we represented the complete three using an array, and this is very compact representation.
When you think about the parent relationship.
The parent relationship is actually where we are building that we are.
But I cannot say what is the child of zero using a single tree because it cannot work.
But if every node in I wrote it in a rooted tree has one parent, only we can use this representation.
So the built array here is actually a tree representation, and it's the best of format because all
what we need is just weird automobiles.
Now, let's see, how can that help us?
Let's say we would like to bring to the bath.
OK, so let's give it a very simple example.
Zero.
Go to one.
Go to two.
Go to three.
Go to four.
So we know that the parent of four three two one zero minus one, let's say I'm asking you to bring
two for me, the shortest the bath, the bath from zero to four.
We're going to start way forward here and say, what does your parent?
Three, OK?
Three What is your parent to do?
What is Berrent one one with?
Is your parent two zero zero?
What is your minus one already, Richard?
So we see the best is three two one zero.
But this is the reverse at Beth.
We actually need it to be zero one two three.
Why is it reverted?
Because we started from the four going back to the zero through the parents, so we need to revert to
that.
So you have two ways now, either you do that in any threat of way to get the rest and reverse reversal
or maybe an easier way to do that in the decision how we recurs.
We start here.
Why not force and then we we recurs on the parent to fool with Jeffrey after we are done from that,
we bring to their current mood.
Remember parenting their triangle in a forward way and in a backward way?
We did that in the recurring right.
So please, if you aren't confused about why is this recursion is bringing it in the right way?
Please go ahead and review the, uh, started sprinting in the recursion section.
By the way, if you got this line here before it would print to three two one zero.
If you bought it after it, it would bring it to zero one two three.
So this is mainly the first problem about the, uh, about the printing.
This is all what we did.
We started from this is thought we iterated on all of the values.
If variant of IE equal minus one, it means that we never found the path for it, so we ignored it.
Otherwise we bring into their target, Beth.