Let's solve the problem, number two, about about validating the tree itself.
Now this problem is very similar to something we did already when their defense.
Remember, we we already mentioned that, um.
The three and there are two -- and put it in a tree.
First of all, the tree must be must have exactly in the minus one edges.
The second thing is that we cannot have a cycle.
Also, the three must have one bath from any note to another.
Now, if you try to verify that the there is a bathroom any new to another.
This is this might be hard, but the good thing is verifying only these two condition is enough as a
three.
So if you verified that there are in the minus one edges, you verify that there are no cycles you provide.
They are all connected.
Then this is a three.
Now this is exactly when you think about it in the lake.
Give it undirected graph check if it has a cycle or not.
But instead of doing it with defense, as we did before, we just want to know it was before us.
So that's all about this problem.
It ends up like justifying the graph.
So first of all, we start here with with a simple check if the number is not equal minus one.
This cannot be a three.
So now the remaining number of idiots is exactly in the minus one, which you mean anyway will have
and will be clearly solution here.
The second thing is we check if we have cycle or not to do that.
We have here the length array and uh, we have here the Bear A. will see its usage.
So now I'm trying to handle this the separate connected components.
You can even uh.
Yeah.
Like practically speaking, we can we can write something better than that, like shorter.
But you know, it doesn't matter.
So in a way, I'm going to start from any uncultured and visited node and just do one b first.
Practically speaking, if I could one and we found that there another connected component, then actually
they are separated.
But anyway, uh, so it end up like we need to verify the B if it's like it from here.
So it's actually all about the assignment.
How can you verify the site code using BÉNÉFICE?
This is the real purpose of this homework.
So here is how it goes.
We know in an undirected graph.
Like that?
We have a cycle, right?
The second coming from going from zero back to zero.
Now the only problem is the fixed Typekit coming from it's like going zero one thing, going back one
zero again.
So we need to know our Birand so that we can and don't go at it.
We can.
We can detect that in the device we used to base recursively the parent ID so that we can know if we
best with it or not.
But it's not the case.
We get something from the Q and we don't know.
So to solve this idea, that's why we need to give the appearance.
So the idea is I would the parent here if at any point of time my neighbor is actually my B-roads,
then we know that this is a fake psychic.
Otherwise, we just go ahead.
If the edge never visited, we added in the normal way, otherwise we actually must have, we must have
a psychic.
So actually we ended up like zero one one try to go to zero, which is its appearance.
So we don't go one go to two two two three one three, try to go to zero, which is vested, which means
that that, uh, this is actually it's like if it's having that, say there is like a connected component
like that one.
And then also we have four and five here.
And, uh, let's uh, let's move this issue, for example, maybe and maybe add edgy this way or recycle
this way.
So in a way, if there are multiple components, we can even early, uh, discover them because all
of them must be reachable from then would zero.
So this is mainly, uh, the uh, the problem here about validating the three, which in the very beginning
of the cycle and want to see how to do that in BFS?