What are the problem number three?
It's actually a very straightforward application for the beef's, but this time on there, uh, well,
with the undergrad, that's it.
Nothing more than that.
So this is our normal array.
This is our validation function.
We can comparison of that in a single line of goods.
And here is our business.
So I started by the following a couple of iterations here that will tell me where is the starting point?
So we keep searching until we find the first to start.
Then we put the here you can try to brick and break because anyway, there's research here, then with
daily BFS to start from this starting point.
Once we are done with that, we start to do our asset.
So we have a victory, which is to the metrics as usual.
And I have a queue of sell to make it easy for myself.
I can make it kill, bear or so, but just it's more lovely this way here.
Uh, you start, you add the queue, start to the queue and then you market position was through our
very classical port here.
And then we get the four neighbors.
If it has a hash, then we return at level plus one, which is the shortest to bath at the moment.
So this is the first the hash we have.
Otherwise, we added again and just keep going.
So as you see, we don't have anything more than what we needed.
So that's all I want to say to you that maybe some people will just not use visited array and use the
matrix itself to market by setting an X in the matrix.
So you might, if you want, you can ignore or you can ignore, ignore having this one and just keep
changing.
The metrics itself was X, because in a way we don't we don't go to, I said with an X value.
This is good for competition.
This is good for fun.
But actually in industry, we didn't do that in interviews and do that.
Sometimes I actually tried to use their centre parameters.
But just remember, this is like maybe create a shorter code, faster code, but in industry wouldn't
do that.
And one reason for that is sometimes our function are paralyzed.
So there are more than a thread that is using this the same object, and no one is expecting you to
change the object that is given to you.
Anyway, that's all.