Homework number two.
And the first problem which is jumping, getting a game.
So we have an array of non negative integers and these are a specific starting index in this array.
And there are some values with values zero.
And I would like to jump from the index to that any index that has a value zero.
OK, so how can we jump?
We can move to if we are at Index I, we can move to Ibrox or if I or I too early, minus RFI RFI.
So from any position you can only go to I Blosser if I or I minus reapply it now.
You would like to know.
If.
This is both civil war, not can you end up at any of these indices or not?
So let's see an example here.
In the first example you say, the starting index is index number five.
So zero one two three four five.
We start to hear.
At this index.
Now.
We would like to see where are the values of values here?
We have only one values zero here, which is here.
I'm sorry.
This one should be.
Here is zero one two three four five.
This is the starting index, and this is the current.
This is a good index, so we search for the zeros.
Any of the zeros is a target for us.
So this is zero.
So the question is, can we start from five?
And in the three indices, the operation is to increment yourself with the value or subtract the value.
So we start at five.
The value of five is one.
So we either go five plus one or five minus one.
If we go to five minus one, which is at Index Food Index, what has a value three?
So you have two choices either you go.
Four minus three or four plus three for Flossie is out of the array for minus three is four, minus
three is just one.
Now we add in this one here at index one here, the index one has a value two, so it means we can either
go one plus two or one minus two.
Woman two is that out of that, a one plus two three, which is a go.
So as you see, we can go from index five to index of three with this sequence.
And here is another way.
So you are you will return it to if you can follow this operation, whatever how and find your destination
or what we need to do is to go from the starting index to the ending index.
So what is the graph?
This is a question that you have to answer.
More examples are here for you to think about them.
In the second, the problem, we will have a number, so we will have a sorry, we will have an array.
The array has distinct numbers and you have a starting values thought and you have an ending value goes.
And here is what you should do.
You would like to start from X and keep changing it with operations to end the op the good.
OK, what are this operation?
How can we change the number?
You cannot change it by the following.
First of all, for any X in this range.
You can try any index in the array and then you have three operation, either adding numbers of AI or
subtracting numbers of AI or soaring numbers of AI.
If you don't know what is X or like, what is X or B, just write it and think of it as a like plus
minus asterisk division or prediction.
Just an operation at the time, and it's Betway celebratory.
So let me explain the Tuskegee.
You have a starting number.
And you have an ending, no.
So here is a start.
And here is the goal, and we cannot change the start to another number.
Let's say the renames has five values.
Then you can change it to five different values.
And for everybody who can agree to change it to other five bags, but the only condition is the new
oxygenated must be between zero and 1000.
OK, so it is a case we have the starting six and would like to end at four.
The values are one or three.
So we either add one two six or subtracted or explore it.
So these are the three operation here.
Now, if we can go six seven four, using first exhorting was one, then second exploding with three.
Here is another case you start from.
Two would like to go to 12.
Now we can.
Add to the 212, this move us to 14, then we can subtract two from the 14 to this end up with, uh,
12.
Which is a good I hope you good idea.
So again, it looks like we have a bunch of numbers, have bunch of operations would like to model that
as a graph.
How can we do that?
More examples for you to trace.
And then the problem you have a string, the string represent a look, if you go to the gym, you probably
see, so she looks a lot.
Each look is like a fool for circular wheels, if you will.
From them is just digits from zero tonight.
And then it has a best one.
Maybe, for example, the best one is two one seven zero.
So this is the best one of your look.
If you roll the the values so that they are two one seven zero is going to open.
So the problem is as following we start from this drink zero zero zero zero and we would like to go
to this target maybe two one seven zero with the minimum number of steps.
So each step would involve just you can take a value and push it forward or backward.
So for example, if I have a zero zero zero zero and I would like two two one seven zero if I push this
zero two steps and this zero one a step and the seven seven steps, then we have in total 10 steps to
reach to this state.
But this is so straight forward it is the catch in this problem.
There are some dead ends.
Some states, maybe, for example, two one one zero, for example, it's a dead end.
If if it happened that you'd look at best with this number, it will get logged and you cannot open
it anymore.
So you have to avoid thing by any of these dead ends.
So the problem again, you start to from this four zeros, you would like to go to the target here such
that you don't best buy this dead ends and you have to do that with the minimum number of steps.
So here is the target zero two zero two and you cannot iterate on any of these values.
So one sequence would be take zero zero.
Change it at one here.
One step.
Another one here.
Another step.
Then this one here or the step.
Then this one here.
So another step and then removing this one from here in the system.
So as you see, we ended up with one very big choice.
But this sequence, for example, is invalid.
Why?
Because we iterated on the value zero one zero two in the middle and zero one zero two is here as it
did, and you cannot iterate over it.
So this is mainly what you need.
Uh, this is Mindy.
What you need to do?
Observe the following.
In the problem paid, it's say that you can move forward and backward as you want, you can move forward
and backward, as you, as you would like.
Say the truth here that the wheels can rotate freely and wrap around.
This means that nine can be go to zero and zero can go to nine.
OK, so here you see, the last example here is just is zero zero zero nine.
So if I have zero zero zero zero and then fled this one one step backward, it will be zero zero zero
nine in a single in a single step.
So this is mainly the problem.
More examples for you.
Please consider this examples because because this puts because it could has some of the special cases.
I don't want you to keep getting wrong answers.
So consider this once while cutting your approach that sort.