We once discussed the bus pay reference and in functions, we highlighted it, but it's time to maybe
to elaborate a little more about that.
So recall in the memory, when we define something like integer age fifty-five, what happens is there
is an entry in the memory, let's say, at location three to seven.
One-four is going to reserve it for age was very fifty-five and data type integer.
Typically when you see addresses you will see it in something we call hexadecimal representation.
So this is hexadecimal representation just think of it like just another number.
You can use this online calculator to convert normal numbers to hexadecimal numbers.
They are eventually the same thing, but different views.
Now, if we would like to get the address of the variable, we can use the reference.
let's say we define the variable integer age.
Fifty-five and then you can print age, which will get fifty-five from the memory.
But if you did reference age, this is the ampersand operator, then it's going to get the actual location
number, but just print it in the hexadecimal format.
So this is just to the location in the memory now.
So age is a value reference.
Age is the address of the value in the memory.
Now, this takes us to further utilization of the address of the operator as follows.
Let's define here age and then we say here integer reference, equal age.
This is just an alias of the variable.
What does this mean?
It means this isn't a new variable in the memory.
It's actually the same variable is just looking at it and giving it a new name.
So now when you put here in the declaration reference before a variable, they are looking to the same
position in the memory.
If you try to print to the value and the address of this variable is again going to show you fifty-five
and exactly the same address, you can again define a new variable, say the reference to looking to
age or looking to reference one when you try to print it again it will print the same value.
If you try to change the value of any of these three items, the value of all of them is changed.
why they are all now referring to the same position in the memory.
That's why we call them the alias.
they aren't new things they are actually defining just the address of the variable and they all are pointing
to the same thing.
Now, let's learn about some constraints.
When it comes to the references, the first constraint is you cannot assign them.
We define here ref.
to age, you can't come back and make ref equal another.
It doesn't go like that.
So it just wants to declare
exactly this way. it has to be a reference here.
It has to be another variable here.
You cannot make it look without initialization.
You cannot initialize it to a constant because this doesn't have a well defined
location in memory for us?
OK, one more constraint.
If you would like to take a reference, it must be the same as the time.
So you cannot refer to to the double from an integer.
And this is that has to be with consistency in the memory itself.
So these are some of the constraints.
So typically we have to define it in this exact way, otherwise, we typically get compilation.
Now let's apply more with the references.
The first thing about functions, let's say we have some function here that has variable X and returning
it to us when Y what observation here.
If we try to print to the address of X here and the address of Y here, we notice it is a different address.
So X here isn't the same Y here we are returning just a copy of it.
What happened after the user returns from this function.
X is a local variable, so X is going to be destroyed because the scope of the variable is going to
be done.
So once the scope of a variable is done?
It is gone from the memory.
So here X and Y are two different things.
So this is about the return by a value.
You have to be careful to return by a value. the pass by reference.
with the first time for us to know about the references.
So we have here a function that takes read. it takes a name then two references X and str.  name is passed here
By value, it means some could be in the memory having but X and str pass by references it means we are actually
pointing to the same thing in memory.
If you look at it you will notice exactly the same format as the by reference.
For example, here we are sending X and here is integer
reference X we are sending a message.
Here is string references str.
So this is like your writing is string references str equal message.
It is the same logic.
Exactly.
That's why this is str and this message is there is an alias for this message.
They look in the same location in the memory.
Now your name, all of the three variables are changed, but only the X and Str will be reflected here
with an update.
they will be changed.
But my name here is.
Mostafa, go to a name, change it to some dummy name when you return it back again.
Mostafa here will be just as it is, it will not be changing.
So just x the message would be updated, this is for pass by reference.
Now let's see the return by reference.
Let's say we have here a struct that have variable name.
It has a print function that can print the name and it has a get name function that isn't returned
just a string it return string reference.
So what is this return?
This is a returning for a reference for the name variable.
Now let's make use of it.
We have here defined my name.
We just ask for a print, which is Mustafa as the default value.
Now I say here this is following string reference str equal my_name.get_name.
The .get_name function is going here to return to the reference of the name variable.
So it's going here to put a reference point about as I started to change this str, it will change
the content of this struct.
So if I start to Zyad and it prints for it is going to print Zyad one more very similar syntax to
that.
But a bit weird for you if I say my name dot get name equal belal, if you print it would be belal notice.
This is a weird syntax.
You this is the first time for you to see a function on the left side that has a value.
You all the time see it on the right side, but now you are seeing it on the left side.
The question here is, is this address or not.
This is something related to something called the left value and the right value.
So here the dot get name.
What does it actually is going to get this reference to the name?
So think of it like remove this get name function.
We have here a reference to the name variable in the memory.
You are now changing it.
So this is a valid C++ syntax because although this is a function call is going to return by Reference
now going back to the return by value, and return by difference.
This is a normal function.
It's returning here, reference to hello.
But a few minutes ago we said that this temp variable is going to be destroyed.
So returning a reference here is completely wrong.
In Eclipse, you would see a compiler warn like a reference to local variable.
You are trying to return a local variable.
There's going to be destroyed very soon to be very careful.
When I return it here, the reference, was in a struct because the struct will be alive with us.
So be very careful about the difference between them.
Another concern is using the reference with the iterators, when you are iterating here over a vector
with reference Val, you are actually looking to the memory of it.
If you try to change the value content, they will be changed.
So if you try to print again is going to be printed, if you don't want to change it, you can put const
here.
So to be const and reference, now, this is good because the idea of the difference is it's looking
in the memory.
So there's no copy on the other side if you didn't.
if you didn't
put the reference is going to make a copy Step-By-Step for this vector.
So over all the changes here will not have effect.
But the worse is you are taking a lot of memory steps.
So be very careful.
What exactly do you want from that?
The last thing to share here is a common mistake we highlighted before in the stl.
Let's say we have a simple struct like an employee and we have a map from integer to employee.
I define no one object of type employee, but then I put it in the memory.
I can get it from the memory in two ways.
I can get it by reference.
So it's now e2 is looking to exactly the same pointer in the memory or I can get it by copy.
What's important here to know e1  e2, e3 have different three addresses in the memory.
So what happens is some mysterious during implementing the projects they define e1, they put it
in the map, they start to play with e1 expecting the map to be changed, but they are different
objects.
So you have to be very careful about that.
So if you have a reference for it, you can change it freely and it will change the map.
Otherwise, they are different objects will be very careful from that.
That's it.