So far, when we were discussing the pointers, we were just using pointers to refer to an existing memory,
but actually, the real power of pointers comes when you have to create dynamic memory by yourself.
Let's motivate that little more.
Remember the array's definition,
You define an array of constant integer size 100, then just an array of 100.
OK, here is a problem.
This is a fixed allocated memory.
If you have 100 employees and you have just 100 values, that is it.
But in reality, you might need more than a specific size.
OK, here's one way. Let's define an array of the maximum possible size,
but this is very impractical.
C++ allows us to create dynamic memory using the new operator and pointers.
So here is the logic.
Let's create a single element.
Here is a normal logic.
In the past, we define variable X, then p0 is looking to the reference of x.
This is referencing something that already exists.
p1 here referring to the null pointer.
So far so good.
Now the new syntax is integer asterisk p2 equals new
int then when we do this line of code here, we are defining a new variable in the memory and
then we put here the value of 20.
Let's see the diagram here.
When you define here, the new int, new is an operator to create a memory is going to create some place
in the memory that has some location.
So it's going to return to the address here.
New int is going to return 0x18c here.
So now pointer p2, which is another variable, is going to be a pointer that's pointing to the new
location.
So remember, this is very similar to when p0 looks at X. We have two boxes, we have an address of
X and we have an address of the pointer.
Now, the address of the pointer as it is,
but when we say new int, there is some temporary location in the memory with some specific address
is created and the pointer now looks at it. After this line of creation,
I can come here and say asterisk p2 equals 20.
So the pointer go here, here, here,
and put the value 20 here. We can initialize it in different ways.
Also I can say integer pointer p3 equals new
int, open the C++ brace initialization style,
I'm put 30
This one did the declaration and definition in a single line like creation and initialization
in a single line.
You can also use it in a similar way to the class and the struct style.
So instead of braces, you can put parameters.
So this is a standard way to create and initialize value in a single line of code.
Now, let's delete what we have created, which one we're going to create, which one we're going to
delete, two things only p2 and p3,
Why?
Ok, what is delete actually first? Delete is as you create something in the memory,
you are going to delete it.
OK, why don't remove p0 and p1? p0 is already a normal variable.
p1 is just a null pointer.
We don't remove them.
The compiler is going to handle the creation and removal of X as we used it through the whole course.
But if you redefine a memory by yourself, you have to remove them.
So the new is an operator that creates, delete is an operator that can delete in memory.
Let's create more than an element,
and this is what we motivated originally.
This is a normal array,
we defined it of 10 elements and fixed size.
Now when it comes to the pointer we do the following: Instead of just new int,
we open the brackets and put the variable N here, N here can be any integer,
It doesn't need to be const.
We can read it from the user and create array with it.
Once, we created the array, we can normally just use it as an array.
Let's delete it.
If you'd like to delete the array, you have to delete it with these two braces.
OK, so two brackets here.
So back to this one, if you are creating a single element, you just use the normal word delete.
If you are creating an array and this is a big source of mistakes, you delete it as an array.
If you just tried to say delete pArr, this is wrong, and it will compile sadly. That's why it is a very common mistake.
There's a question here, why do we have to delete?
I would like you to understand something about what is happening behind the scene.
When you use the operator new, there is some specific part of the ram that will be reserved
for you to use it. If you didn't delete it, the computer never gets a request to release this memory.
So, for example, if you asked for 100 mega for your array and you didn't delete it, the hundred
mega will be used and reserved from your machine even after your program closes,
and this is what we call a memory leak.
A memory leak means that there is some memory created by this program, but no one released it.
Only you have to restart the whole machine to solve this problem.
Here is one more interesting thing that happens a lot in practice.
If you have a function that reserves really huge array, but it is wrongly releasing it or forgot to
release it. With every call to the function that does this big array, much of your ram is going to be consumed,
let's say that with every single call, 300 mega are consumed from your ram.
The second call there is another 300, the third call there is another 300 and so on, then
your whole machine memory is going to be consumed. At this moment,
your whole machine is going to hang,
and this means that just your own memory got consumed. Side notes for guys who work on this kind of pointer
things. In practice, they have a lot of tools that can help them discover this one.
This is very advanced.
You don't have to go to learn that.
As a funny note, given what we just said, you can check your task manager.
If there is some process running and you look into it, let's say it's now five hundred mega
and with every few seconds is going to take more and more memory.
You can figure out from the task manager that this task, this process, this code actually
have some memory leak.
So this is a bit funny.
If you look at the task manager, you can figure out sometimes that your code has a memory leak, but this
isn't a standard way to do that.
Here are a few common mistakes that people do when using pointers.
The first thing is to use delete instead of delete array.
The second one is to use delete array instead of delete,
but the first one is much more common. A much worse problem if you tried to delete a pointer twice.
This happens a lot in industry.
It creates something, what you call dangling pointer.
The first one would be removed safely,
the second one would cause a crash in your system.
One of the common mistakes is to access a deleted memory.
You created something, you deleted, then you access it.
This program is going to crash. Or accessing an initialized variable.
No one knows what's going to happen.
A few tips.
Never leave a pointer
uninitialized, always put it to a null pointer.
If you delete the pointer, assign it to a null pointer. Before deleting a pointer,
think twice about these notes here.
That's it.