...So this is a struct of an employee class that has just a normal constructor, some function, and print
function.
Now, if you would like to define it in a very normal way like — you just say, employee e1 10, Mostafa.
you want to print, that's it.
So far, so good.
Recall, how do we create a single element with a pointer? We say integer, pointer,
X.
You can open the braces and then a new integer and then you can use these two parentheses and then 50.
Defining an object of type employee as pointer is exactly the same logic.
Instead of int, we have here employee. Instead of int here, we have an employee. Instead of 50 here, we have the
constructors of the struct and that's it.
So this way we declare a pointer of type employee.
Now here is a new thing.
If you would like to use an object this e2, you cannot just say e2 dot print. C++ uses this arrow style,
It is dash, greater than without spaces.
This arrow style is used with pointers corresponding to the dot style with the normal objects.
So this is one more thing.
It just for the sake of fun. Here,
If you remember, if you say asterisk e3, you are getting the actual object. As its actual object, you
can now use that.
So one way is just to put these two parentheses, then put the asterisk and just use it. Don't use that in practice,
It is useless.
We don't do it.
It just I'm telling you the that is available. In a very similar way,
we can have pointers who also looking at existing variables.
So I can say asterisk e4 equals e2 which is a pointer, or e5 reference e1 which is an object that
we need its reference,
and remember, this is more of a modern C++ style.
Now, here I am defining another variable e6, and I'm giving it asterisk e2.
This is also normal.
You can take the reference and e asterisk here is just getting the variable. Reference
needs an object here
but the pointer needs the address itself.
Now, you can start to use the variable as normal.
Notice here, if I started to change e2 to 111 and print e6, it is going to print the same
value of e2 because it's by reference. In a very similar way,
I can create a vector of employees like — here, I can push back e2 as an object of a pointer.
I can also push back a reference of e6 and just use it.
Going to delete objects, we have here e2 and e3, the only two created ones with pointers.
So these are the only two things that we remove,
and after you remove it, please use a null pointer to initialize them.
So yeah, that's it about the pointers to struct here
in this slide,
and remember always to remove the pointer that you created.
That's it.