In this lecture, we will learn about an interesting and critical topic to understand what is
happening behind the scene in the memory.
First of all, I would like you to recall what was the stack data structure.
Remember, if we have a bunch of books in this way, we put them in order and we wanted to take the
top book from the stack,
we only can take a book.
We can only take the top guy.
So if we push something, if we push a lot of things, I would like to pop something,
we can only accept the last thing that we put in the stack. It's kind of the stack is closed.
So you cannot reach this guy unless you took all of the items that are here.
Now, going to our topic, the memory of your computer is divided into a bunch of regions or segments,
and today we are going to know some about that.
One segment in your memory is for what we call the local variables, and another one has a free memory
style and then another section that involves the global variables or static variables and even your
programming instructions.
So the stack here is a special region where the temporary local variables of your function exist.
Remember, local variables always attached to like functions.
On the other side, the heap is for the memory that is free that you typically
create like using
(sorry, this should be new) using the new and the delete commands. The local variables
as you know, they are automatically managed for you.
You don't create the local variable.
When you say integer X, you don't create it in the memory, you do not delete it.
This is going to be handled by the computer itself,
but the heap is where you create and delete by yourself.
You notice that the local variables here have a local scope.
Remember, we always say that you shouldn't try to reference a variable outside of your function, but
you can create an integer pointer and return it for others to use it.
Let's go into details, the runtime stack, or what we call the call stack is a stack of function calls. We learned
to make a stack of integer, stack of strings.
This is a stack of function calls.
When a function is called, it enters the stack and once it's finished, it goes out of the stack. What
happens for every active function in your stack?
It will have the following details:
It will have information about the return value, the parameters, the return address and the
information of the local variables. As you see, all of the information that it needs.
So now here is an interesting question.
Why we cannot reference something as a local variable in our function and return it back to the caller?
because once you are returning from a function, all of these active variables are going to be deleted
from your stack.
So if you try to call a function here like function p1, p2, p3, A.B.C., you will notice in
the stack we are going to put all of this information here.
Once the function is done, all of that is going to be destroyed.
Let's see a simple example of that. We have here
three functions,
The main, the fun1 and fun2. Function main has variables X, Y, Z, and is calling function 2
which has local variable
i and receiving two parameters and returning an integer.
Here is what happens in the execution:
The first thing that happened is the CPU is going to run your program, which you start with the
main function here at line 17. Function 17 is calling function1.
Let's say it's in some address 0x2b.
It is still in fun1 that you should return your result to my address as 0x2b to continue
my instructions.
In the next step, the function fun1 is called. In the stack,
there will be different variables that will be added.
It will be the variable a, the variable x, the variable y, and the variable z.
Also in the stack, there will be a mark for what is the address of the function that we should return
to it after we finish,
and also it's going to return a value, int temp value, for the return result here.
The function fun1 is going to call fun 2 and is going to go here from the address 0xff. The function
fun2 is going to say I have m, n, and r, all of them are on my stack function's active
parameters and I'm going to return the result 0xff and then return the results, execute and return
them to 0xff.
Once we are done with that, the fun2 is going to be removed from the function calls stack,
all of its local variables will be destroyed. In a similar way to
the fun2, fun1 now is going to return the result here.
So also all of its parameters would be destroyed.
If you tried to reference some local variables inside the stack, it will be destroyed.
Finally, the main also is going to be destroyed,
and once we reached this state,
The whole program is going to be terminated.
Now, let's learn some of the issues that you cannot understand without understanding that note about
the stack. Take a minute to think about what might be the problem in this array.
It is unused definitely, but what else?
The problem here is as follows: this is what you call a stack overflow problem. When we create such
a very huge size, There is a problem.
The stack typically is small in size.
So such a very big array is bigger than the stack size,
and this would make a problem in your code.
Your program will terminate wrongly.
The stack size in windows is typically like 1 megabyte and in some Linux machines are like 8
megabytes.
This is a bit configurable, but also still has limitations.
So the problem here is you are going to consume all of the possible memory for your stack.
Now, one question is what I would like to redefine such big data?
This is what the rule of the heap would come to that. Here are another two examples of potential
problems. Take a minute and try to guess what's happening.
Why would that be a problem?
In the first case, function1-recursive, it's going to call itself infinity.
So this is definitely a problem that's going for infinity.
But another problem is the stack would be exhausted by this function.
Here is a more clear example.
Function2 is another recursive function.
It's a proper function.
Nothing wrong with it.
It takes a variable N and keep reducing it.
...
If I call the function recursive with 10, it would be called ten times,
but what if I call it with a variable like one million, there will be one million function entry in
the stack.
Every one of them has 100 integers from here
local variable and has the integer here and the returned integer from here.
This is a lot and more than the one mega limit of the stack.
So eventually this will give you another stack overflow problem.
That's why in practice we avoid recursion because it simply can fall in this stack overflow limitation.
Now, going back to how can we solve our problems if we would like really a very huge data.
This is where the new int and delete comes to the scene.
When you define a pointer 1 and pointer 2 in this way, the amount of data here like the N or 7
are going to be reserved on something else called the heap.
The heap is a free memory,
It is a very big one, up to the limit of your machine.
That's why there is no problem with using it.
More interestingly, who has created this data? You. You created it and you deleted it.
That's why
I can come here and say integer pointer, pointer 1, pointer  2, I can delete pointer 2, but I can
return pointer 1.
Now, this guy can use it and can delete it. Comparing to the local variables,
this guy will not be deleted by the end of the function.
It is going to be deleted by me whenever I decide that.
So in the stack case, the local variables are created by the CPU and destroyed by the CPU in a local fashion,
but when it comes to the heap and the new operator, they will be created on the heap, which is much
bigger in space and you have to decide to delete it.
What if I forgot to delete it?
This is going to be a memory
leak. A more interesting thing to notice is as follows: the variable ptr1 and ptr2
themselves are actually local variables,
they are on the stack,
this is very interesting, but the data itself here is created on the heap.
Remember, the pointer is just like a pointer to something.
So this is something is on the heap
but pointer one and pointer two themselves are only stack.
So when this function, the pointer 1 and pointer 2 themselves will be destroyed, but the active memory
will be still here.
Then you create another local variable p to return...
array from here.
So one more time going back to here, we said that the local variables exist on the stack.
These are all your variables in the function and the heap is huge, it is free memory.
You have control over it.
What about the global variables and static variables?
These are permanent storage.
Once they are declared, they are there forever.
So they have some of these similarities with the heap that they exist
till they be removed
but they are also similar to the local variable in that you are not the one who created them in the memory by yourself.
So that's why they have a separate handling for them here.
That's it about this kind of memory information.