What we learned so far in pointers is good, but however, in real projects, it can give you a lot
of troubles and I would like to highlight why.
Let's first highlight the first issue, which is the number of copies in memory.
If you have a class ( struct ) that referring to another struct, let's say that you have an employee and
departments and the department class want to say a vector of employee, departments.
The problem with this line as we know is to get the number of copies. If you have a department and you pushed
it in the vector, there are now two copies in the memory.
If you got it back from the vector without reference, there's a third copy now.
So this is a lot of copies and you will get a lot of bugs in the code with assume that the vector
now is updated, but it isn't updated because they are actually several copies in the ram.
So the way to go with that is the standard way is to refer to it using a pointer.
So you say vector of employee pointer, now you created it once and people just are pushing back the pointer
reference, which is just the address of the object.
There is a workaround to avoid that like — we did in one of the projects, we just use the object
once and other guys have an id about where is this object.
This way, I avoided making a lot of copies in ram.
I just have multiple ids like here multiple addresses, multiple ids.
Still, there are two troubles.
One of them is easily manageable and one of them is hell.
the easy one to be managed is who is going to create a pointer and who is going to delete it.
The deletion is important to avoid memory leaks.
The second one is a potential loss of pointers, which might end up with some dangling pointers
as we'll see. Later in object-oriented programming, we will learn how to reduce the pain from that,
and in modern C++, there is something called smart pointers that makes our life much much easier.
So let's tackle the first type of problems. We have here a struct employee, which has a pointer to an array,
we create here an array of five elements and initialize them with this list of numbers,
and here we are printing the value of what it (pointer) points, the address
of where it points and the address of the pointer itself.
Now, here there are two cases.
If I created a normal integer with new int, I deleted it.
Very good.
But here if I created an object e, which creates here an array, and then it goes out of the scope.
So it's now destroyed.
Who deleted that one?
No one deleted it.
This is a memory leak. Let's make a simple rule.
The one who creates a memory has to release it by himself.
So the employee class created it, the employee class has to remove it.
Here is a simple solution from C++ itself.
There's something called destructor,
remember, the constructor is something that creates the object, the destructor is something that
is going to be called automatically if the object is out of scope.
So what we do is as following:
We use this character here, and then the struct name, and we write the logic to delete whatever we want
to delete.
So here I'm deleting the array pointer to xPtr.
At this moment, I release the memory.
So now in the creation, this construct here is called and going out of scope, this destructor
is going to be called.
So now this one is releasing memory. When do you need to provide a destructor?
If you have a pointer that you used a new operator for it, pointer-new.
If you have these two cases jointly, then you need a destructor to avoid the
memory leak.
So far, so good.
Let's go to harder issue.
Let's define two objects,
e1 and e2, let's play with e1, the first element in the array
we get 20. Let's print
e1 and e2.
So the value of e1 here, first value is
20, here is 1.
So far so good.
This is the address of the memory that we created.
This is the address of the pointer itself.
This is the address of pointer so far.
Now, let's execute line 30. Line 30 is assigning e1 to e2.
This is going to take every element in e1 and put it in e2, which is here
the value where xPtr is pointing to the value of e2 is pointing.
Try to take a minute to think about what's going to happen in this program.
There is two severe issues here.
Take a minute and think about it.
If you try to print now the e2-print, you discover the following: the value of
my pointer is the value of the e1 pointer ( the value of the first element of the array ).
The address where this pointing to is the same of the address where this pointing to. My personal
address is different than this personal address.
So what happened?
Where is the critical part? the address where he is pointing to is now the same as my address where
I point to,
but this is a memory that I created and this is my memory that I created.
If e2 called his memory address, then we lost 0xaaa.
We lost it.
We don't have this pointer anymore.
So this is a memory leak.
We lost this pointer because I took the where is pointing to me.
So now this is a first memory leak.
The second and actually the worst is the following: e1 destructor is going to destroy
0x19c from the memory, and then this guy e2 in the destructor is going also to destroy the same memory.
So this memory is going to be released twice.
This is what we call dangling pointer.
This program is going to be crashed at that moment.
If you look at line 41, it also has this equal operation
so it's going also to do the same issue.
However, line 30 and line 41 are different.
Line 30 is a pure assignment.
There is no object creation here.
This exists and this one exists.
Line 40,
this one only exists but this one we are creating it.
So in the creation, the problem also can happen if we are using another object.
For now, I would like to teach you a temporary solution for this problem.
You are going to these two lines 20 and 21. Read them carefully.
These two lines as following: line number 20 is going to prevent line number 29
Line
number 20 is going to prevent line number 29 and the line number 21 is
going to prevent the line 28.
If you try to do these two lines now, the compiler will complain about them, which is good
So that you are warned that these two lines will create for you a big problem and your
program will crash if and only if you have an internal pointer.
You don't need to do these two lines if you don't have a pointer internally because if we don't have
a pointer internally, we aren't afraid neither from memory leaks nor dangling pointers.
Only if you have an internal pointer that you initialize with new, use
these two lines. Later in OOP, we will learn how to handle these problems in an easier way.
But for now, in your projects, I would like you to be warned by the compiler that three is something
that will create a big problem for you.
That's it.