One of the fundamental topics in C++ is the pointers topic, and this is one of the unique features in
C++ compared to many other programming languages that give you a very good space to play with the
memory and to understand a lot about the memory layout.
So it's actually a great advantage in the programming language.
So starting with that, remember, when we define a variable like 15 and we can also take a reference
for this value. If we try to play the value and its address in the memory, it will be the same
as the reference here and it's address in the memory.
So far, so good,
We learned that before.
Now, here is one more thing that we are going to introduce,
and for a large extent, it will share similarities with the reference that we already studied,
It is the pointers.
So here is how we define the pointer.
We define integer asterisk, we read it integer pointer.
So the asterisk before playing the role in multiplication (I can say 2 times 3) but now it's playing a unary
role as a pointer.
So we define it as integer pointer
ptr, we can have asterisk here,
No problem,
equal reference val.
Now, we saw before the reference here on the left side, when we are defining a variable and say this
is a reference variable and then we mean it will have the same address as its value.
Now, when we on the right side, we take a reference. Reference value here when we printed it,
It prints an address.
So this means the value of the pointer is an address.
This is very unique thing.
So here is what happens in the memory when we define the val and the reference. In the memory, in
the position
0x7f1, there was like a box for you with a variable named val  equals 15, it also has an alias name
reference.
So both a val and ref are playing in the same memory location.
Now, here we define the pointer and we put its value the address of ref, OK, what is the address of ref? It is
0x7f1.
So when we go to the variable pointer, its value would be an address.
This is a unique and fundamental difference. But wait a second, pointer itself is a variable,
so it also has an address.
Now, there are three fundamental things when to come to print the pointer. Here,
the middle one, if you try to print ptr, it will give you 0x7f1.  This is the value
with the pointer, which is another address that is pointing to.
The second thing is if we try to print the address of the pointer itself, which is the address of the
box here regardless of where is he is pointing which is 0x9f2. So far so good,
,very very logical.
We put in the box a pointer to another variable, and we have an address of us. Now, here an extra thing
in C++, when we say print asterisk pointer, this is
doing the following:
It says, hey pointer, you are looking to another variable, right?
Yes, go to this pointer and go to this address and get the value of it.
So it prints 15.
So, again, the value of a pointer is an address, but the pointer itself has its own address. When
we use asterisk pointer,
It means to go to where we are pointing at and print the value of it.
This is the fundamental thing that we are going to see all the time through the pointers
topic. Please, make sure you are very comfortable with these three items.
So a pointer is a variable that store the address of another variable.
So given that it is a variable, it has an address and it's pointing to another variable, so there
is another address.
So when we say pointer, there are two different addresses that we have: The address
it points toward it, which is the content of the pointer is the value of ptr itself. It is own address
can be, as usual, brought by the reference ptr. How to get the value where I am pointing out to?
using asterisk ptr.
So asterisk ptr is a unary operator, we call it a dereference operator and the role is indirect addressing.
By that we mean it is looking to the address in somewhere else.
So we read it as follows: when we say a pointer, we read it like you can read it as a value
pointed to by this pointer.
Let's yeah.
This is an example that we already saw.
So let's continue playing with the code.
If I started to say asterisk ptr equal 20.
Now remember asterisk ptr means to go to the pointer that
I am looking to it, get its value.
Now, I'm putting its value with 20.
If I try to print the value or the reference or asterisk ptr, all of them now will be 20, why? Because
the value of the pointer here is now a third reference to the same location.
So now the value, reference, and asterisk ptr are all playing with the
same thing.
Now let's define a new variable.
Let's say we call it another and it is value is 30.
If we try to print in the memory, we have another with value 30,
and we have this address for it. Now,
I'm going to change the value of the pointer to be the address of another variable.
So I'm saying here, pointer equals reference of another.
Now, if I tried to print pointer, it would be the value of it,
the value where it points is 30.
Its address is the same as another address, and its own address didn't change. So the ptr is a variable
by itself.
Its address in the memory is the same, but where it points to and the value of where it points,
is changing.
Now, if you tried to put the pointer value where it points to, sorry, is 50, you will notice the following:
The val, which is the old variable, didn't change from 20, but the value of another and
the value of pointer changed.
That's it.
OK, here is one more thing.
If you want a pointer that points to nothing, you can say pointer equals nullptr.
It means a null pointer.
The word
null,
We met it before when we learned the character array,
It has a null character. So the same thing, null means nothing.
So null pointer means I am pointing to nowhere.
You cannot do that in an explicit way to the reference, Ok!. The reference has to go into something.
OK. If you would like to check if a pointer is pointing to something or not, you can say something
like if not pointer, cout null.
So it's going to put a null.
Notice that if you tried to make an asterisk pointer or pointer that points to null, It is going to make
a runtime error because it points to nothing. When it says an asterisk pointer, it means to go where I
am looking and get the value, but I'm looking nowhere.
So this is wrong. In terms of pointer initialization,
here are a few tips.
When we here define a variable X, we can make a pointer looking direct to X.
This is good. If you would like the pointer to look to nothing, in c style, we say asterisk equals null with capital letters
and this is still OK.
But the more C++ and the one I prefer is to use the word nullptr. In C++, it also allows you to use the
value zero.
So the value zero is also means that it points to nothing.
But notice that this the only case.
You cannot, for example, put the value of one.
So this is a special handling for the zero as a null pointer.
OK, here is the worst thing ever that you can do.
You are defining a pointer and you are giving nothing here.
In this way, the pointer is going to be just garbage.
So be very careful about that.
That's it for today.
I would like you to be very familiar with what we said before moving to the next topic.