Let's continue playing with pointers. The only way by the way to be good in pointers is just to
keep playing with it.
In this example here we have two values, val1 with 5, val2 with 15.
So here we are printing the addresses of these two values,
then I started to define pointer number one, p1, to look at the address of val1, pointer p2
has no value here
but then I assigned the value here to point to the reference of val2.
Now, if I started to say asterisk p1 equals 10, asterisk p1 means the value pointed by p1 which
is val1 equals 10.
OK. So whenever you see asterisk p, start to think, oh, where I am pointing val1,
then val1 is 10.
On the other side here, I'm saying asterisk p2, which is val2 equals asterisk p1
...
which is val1 plus 6.
So val1 is 10 now plus 6 is 16.
So if you printed the two values of val1 and val2, 10 and 16.
So advice number one, every time you see asterisk p1, just think, oh,
what is the original value of val1 used here? val1 equals 10, val2 equals to val1 plus 6.
That's it. Keep going,
I'm saying here p1 equals p2.
This means that we are going to take the value inside p2 and put it inside the value of p1,
but what is in p2? it is a reference val2.
So now p1 is looking to the reference of val2.
If you tried to print to the address, It would be the address of val2. Now, asterisk p1 equals 20.
Wait a second.
What is asterisk p1?
It is val2. So putting val2 with 20 and printing the two values here, which is now focusing
on val2 not val1.
Here I am changing again p1 to look at val1. Printing the two values, it will be 10 and 20.
I can call the swap function of STL and swap both of them.
If I swapped both of them, I'm swapping the address of p1 with the address of p2.
So it's now asterisk p1 and asterisk p2, it will be 20
and 10. If I define double X equal 10 (I try to make the address p1 to be pointing to
the X ) is going to compile-error. It will tell you double-pointer conversion to an integer pointer.
It means you are trying to make a pointer of type integer to look at a value of type double.
Don't do that.
So you need some consistency here.
Similar to defining pointers with integers, we can define a pointer with double, I can define a string
and then refer to this string. I can have a vector and then pointer to this vector.
I can change the value of vector with another value of a new vector.
So here the value of the vector, initially of size 3. I changed the content of 10 numbers.
Now the size is 10.
We are going to play more later with vectors.
So the more of that, you can definitely use different pointer variables here.
There is a very fundamental information here to know.
The size in the memory of all of these pointers is the same.
The size doesn't change when you change the data type.
Remember, the pointer is just a variable that's looking to an address.
So it doesn't care if you are looking to a vector or looking to a very big array or looking to a single
number.
It's just need an address value.
So this is all what is a pointer is, so the size doesn't change.
OK. So far, there is a fundamental question.
Why do you need to introduce pointers?
It seems like just references like another address in memory.
OK, here is the fundamental reasons why we have pointers.
Pointers allow dynamic memory allocation.
What does this mean?
If you have an array of size 10, this is a fixed memory allocated array of a change 10.
You cannot rechange the array to be bigger, it just 10 nothing more.
Remember, something like the vector in STL. The vector is growing up,
what is happening behind the scene?
There is a pointer to an array, and we keep reallocating the array every time we need.
There would be...
a video session about dynamic memory allocation.
I just wanted you to know
why are we introducing pointers?
There will be several lectures that will be just exploring a lot about pointer syntax, which will have
a lot of correspondence with the references,
and after that, we will come back to the memory allocation issue.
That's it.