Let's see when pointers come with arrays.
There's a lot of nice things here.
Before going to the pointers, I would like to refresh with you how the array in memory existsed. If
you have an array of four numbers.
So, for example, if you say cout array of 2 equals 7, then it would be 7. In memory,
C++ has defined 4 integers consecutively in the memory. Consecutively.
They must be consecutive.
For example, it might define them with the following addresses.
If you go to the memory, you'll find the 5th, 6th, 7th, and 8th are consecutive and this is their
addresses. In 2D array,
It's a bit similar one.
Let's say that you have an array here of 3 times 4.
Remember, once you did the flattening of the array, if you have an array of 3 times 4, we can
flatten it to 12.
Now, what happens in memory actually is that we have these 12 numbers consecutively in the memory also.
In a row-major order style,
They are actually the first row,
then the second row,
the third row in the memory.
There is something that rarely used the column-major order, which is column number 1, column number 2,
column number 3. The same logic for 3D arrays.
So here is the 2D array.
We take the first four numbers, followed by the second four numbers, followed by the third four numbers,
all of them consecutive in the memory.
What if I have 3D array here?
Let's say that you are looping with i, j, and k from 0 to 1, 0 to 2, 0 to 3.
OK, the order of accessing the array of i, j, and k is the same order for all of these elements, which
will be 24 in the memory.
Now, let's go back to the pointers.
This is an array. Surprisingly, and we never did that before,
If you tried to cout the arr here, it is going to print an address.
This is a bit weird thing for you.
This is the address of the first element of the array.
Remember, all of them are consecutive.
Wait a second.
If you say this is the first element in the array, then the value here in Array 0 should have a reference
array of 0 to also be the same value,
and this is what you see here.
...The array of zero is just the first integer,
Right?
So if you said the reference of the first element in the array, it is going to print the first element of the
array, which is the same as here. In a similar way, we can have reference value to point to the
first element of the array
and again, the val would have the same reference as the
array.
Now, let's go to the pointers.
If you defined the pointer, you can put here directly arr. OK, why? because arr array here is an address,
actually an address
when we see from printing. that's why we can directly assign it.
So we see so far when we assign something to the pointer, it has to be addressed. Either array directly or
another pointer, or if it's a value, then you have take the reference.
So you eventually have to put an address of something.
Now, the address of the pointer is looking at the array.
Let's print our three common things.
Let's print asterisk-ptr and reference of ptr. Reference of ptr is my pointer
address.
We don't care about that.
The ptr itself, which is a value, is the same as the value of the array and the value of it is 3,
which is the first element in the array. Now, here is an interesting thing.
Once you assigned a pointer to an array, you can deal with the pointer exactly as you deal with the
array.
So for example, I can say pointer Zero equals 10, pointer 1 equals 20 and I can iterate on the
array and print it, then just print it as if it has changed already.
So this is an interesting thing about the pointer to array.
Please familiarize yourself with this line of code.
There is also a fancy thing that you might use from time to time, which we call the offset notation.
so here is an area and we define a pointer to it.
Now, if we try to print pointer plus zero, pointer plus one, pointer plus two, this is going to give you the
same address of the first element in the array, the address of the second element in the array, the
address the third element in the array.
So pointer plus index, which we call it the offset notation, is just moving cells in the memory, moving
cell by cell. In a similar way,
If I did here something like asterisk ptr plus zero, asterisk of ptr plus one, notice the parentheses here, asterisk ptr
plus two.
This is same as array of two here.
OK, in a similar way, surprisingly, you can even use the offset notation with the array itself.
If you say array plus two-asterisk, it is going to print the value of the array at position 2.
So here is the logic.
Array is eventually an address in the memory. Array
plus 2 means move two cells in the memory.
Asterisk means get me the value where this pointer is looking at, which is just the value of the array.
So array of index we call it subscript notation using the bracket style and asterisk of pointer plus 2
we call it the offset notation.
here is one of the common mistakes.
What is the difference between asterisk pointer plus 3 and asterisk, open parentheses and put pointer plus
3.
So here is the logic.
Once we used an asterisk, it means to get the value of this address.
So asterisk ptr is going to get for you the value 3, which is the first element of the array,
then when we have another 3, it would be 3 plus 3,
So overall 6.
Now, on the other side here, when we say pointer plus 3, it means to move through three cells in
the memory, which will be at 9.
If you are here one steps, two steps, three steps,
We are at now at 9, at the address of 9. Asterisk of
that is going to give you the value itself.
So be very careful.
Where are you applying your asterisk.
Is it directly on the pointer or is it on a shifted pointer.
Here's a shifted, here directly.
Pointers arithmetic, remember the i++, and ++i, you can do the same arithmetic
on the pointers, for example, if you have a pointer here( A few minutes ago,
we said that pointer plus one is moving one cell in the memory) plus-plus pointer is moving one step
in the memory so that we can print it.
So if you are here at 3, plus-plus pointer is moving one cell in the memory. We are here now printing it comes
5.
If you said asterisk-ptr plus-plus, this means to print the value where this pointer that is pointing,
then increment the pointer.
So asterisk-ptr here is now at 5,
we are going to print it,
then it moved to the next cell,
It would be at 7 then asterisk
ptr is printing 7 again. Now asterisk plus plus ptr,
this is going to Increment the pointer to the next cell first, then get the value of it.
So we are here at 7, move to 9 first, then print the value 9, print the value 9. Similar way,
we can use the minus minus to go steps back.
Also in a very similar way, you can say plus equals 2, minus equals 3.
You can move positions in the memory.
So if know we were here, if you moved two steps back, It is going
to be one step,
two steps is going to be back at 3.
OK, now if we get another minus-minus pointer, it's going to go one step before the first element
in the array.
Be very careful.
You are now out of the boundaries.
OK, back to pointers,
Let's say I said pointer equals array plus 3, given the pointer is an address and array is an address, if you
subtracted them from each other, the compiler will compute the number of shifted cells from here to
there.
So the pointer minus array is there are 3 cells pointers difference.
OK, let's do one more thing.
If I said here pointer is an array at the beginning, then I say plus-plus asterisk pointer.
Remember, we have here the syntax of asterisk plus-plus pointer.
Again, think of the pointer and do it step by step.
The first thing applied here is an asterisk, asterisk pointer is getting the value of the current
cell, which is the first element, which is 3.
So the value is now 3, now 3 plus-plus is 4.
Now here's an interesting thing.
If you tried to subtract, the pointer from the array, it would be zero.
The pointer didn't move.
So be very careful.
There is a difference between asterisk plus-plus pointer and plus-plus asterisk pointer, both of them are
prefix,
but which one is applied first?
Look to the pointer, here
the plus-plus first then you get the value. Here you get the value then you increment it.
OK, so this one is playing with the address in the memory.
It's moving it one cell forward.
This one didn't move the pointer at all.
As you see, it could be a bit puzzling and tricky.
I would like you to play a lot with this Syntex to make sure you are familiar when you apply minus
minus and plus-plus,
What really happens to the pointer?
A few interesting things,
We can iterate over an array using the pointer just for fun.
Let's say we defined here asterisk-pointer to be here.
We can now do the following: while pointer not equals array plus 4. What is pointer? it is an address.
What is the array? array is an address.
So as long as the pointer didn't reach the address of one element after the array,
then we are simply we can print the numbers.
So this way we are printing them.
If you tried to print five elements, It is going to give you definitely here a wrong garbage value so be careful.
So one lesson here,
you can use the pointer and you are now comparing addresses together, which is a very fun thing
In a similar way,
If you defined an array of characters and you defined an asterisk to point to it, you can also keep printing
it,
but in an easier way here, we know that this hello will have a  null character in its end.
So we can as long as the str not equals the back-slash zero, just go and print it and move to the next pointer.
Comparing pointers,
this is a bit very tricky and a common mistake.
Let's say you have str1 and str2, which both are
Mostafa. If you tried to say str1 equals-equals str2, it would definitely say true.
Now, let's say we defined 2 pointers, pointer p1 is looking to str1, pointer p2
is looking to str2. I'm here using the initializer list style, which is more preferred in C++ style.
Now if I tried to say p1 equal-equal p2, this would be false. Wait a second, p1 is an address, p2
is another address.
Are they equal addresses?
No.
OK, but we didn't target to compare addresses, we want to compare values.
So if I said asterisk p1 equal-equal asterisk p2, it would be true. So be very careful.
Do you really want to compare addresses or compare values?
You have to be careful to avoid mistakes.
That's it.