There are three cases when it comes to using constants with pointers.
The first case is when we define a pointer to constant. Let's first define two values here val1 and
val2, and they are just have values.
Now, if you defined const in val3 equal 40. What we know is that if you decided that val3 be
40, you cannot later change its value.
Remember what we said before when I defined integer val, I need an integer pointer to look at it. If I
defined double val, I need a double pointer to point out at it. If I defined const integer val, I need
a const integer pointer to look at it because I want to guarantee that the value will not be changed
even through a pointer.
So now let's define a const integer pointer ptr looking to val1, which is just an integer
value.
Here is the thing, you can do something and you cannot do another.
What you can do is changing the value of this pointer, changing the value of where it points to,
even if this val was a normal value.
So regardless of its value ( val1 or val3 which is an integer and const-int ), you cannot change
its value.
But you can change where the pointer itself is looking. So I can change from val1 to val2,
val2 to val3 as I would like.
But with every change..., I cannot change where the pointer
is looking at.
The second thing is interesting, you know, defining it as an integer pointer const. In the previous slide,
we define it as const integer pointer.
Now we are switching.
It is an integer pointer const. This is a constant pointer.
This means that once you are defining the pointer, you cannot change the pointer itself.
So I cannot come back here and say p2 equals reference val2.
I cannot change the pointer itself, but I can change its value.
So the pointer to constant, you change the pointer but cannot change the value where it points to. In const to
the pointer, you can change where it points to,
but you cannot change
the pointer address itself, the value of the pointer itself.
In a third case, you are defining it to be constant
pointer to constant.
So here you see a very weird syntax, const,
integer, pointer, const ptr equals some value.
Now you cannot do what you changed.
So we have three variants for that.
That's it.