Let's discuss the use of functions with pointers.
Let's refresh here a reference.
If you have a function do-math that has a reference X, X here must be a number no guarantee that it will
like be no null. By guarantee,
I mean you don't expect that the function would be called and really X is pointing to something
wrong in the memory. This would not happen.
Now, let's define some X1 equals 4 and call the function do-math with X1.
The function is adding plus 1, then multiplying by 2, then multiplying another 2.
So 4 plus 1 is 5, 10, 20.
That's it.
Now we overloading another function.
Overloading, sorry. We are overloading another function, integer-pointer-X.
So now we have one function that accepts the reference, another function that accepts the pointer.
The first thing when you have a function that takes a pointer is you have to make sure that this value
is a null pointer.
Otherwise, the program might crash.
So there is a check here, if this is a pointer or not.
After that, we are going to do the same logic. I'm first putting asterisk X plus 1.
So I'm incrementing it.
Then I'm saying asterisk X times 2, then I'm saying asterisk X times equal 2. Notice that the asterisk here
are a lot and they are confusing.
This asterisk is a pointer asterisk.
This asterisk is a pointer asterisk. This asterisk is a multiplication asterisk like 2 times 3.
OK, so don't get confused by asterisk X, and asterisk equals 2.
They are two different asterisks types.
Once you are done with that, you can also print them. In a similar way,
If I have a function that takes a vector pointer, and I am defining here a vector, I can just send
the reference of it. Here for X1,
I also use the reference of it. With the reference of it,
you can read it as follows: this integer-integer pointer X equals reference of X1.
This is how you can think of passing a parameter. Here
we say what? We say integer-reference-X equals x1. Here we say integer-reference asterisk X equals reference
X1.
Here we say vector of integer-pointer-ptr equals reference V.
So this is actually the normal assignment, it just now in terms of functions.
On the other side, we can also return a pointer. Let's say that we are defining a function that takes
two pointers that are pointing to integer values, and we are going to return one of them that is a
maximum value.
Again, you have to be very careful with parameters and make sure they null.
So I'm using here
a simple logic.
I'm saying if p1 is a null pointer, just return p2.
P2 could be a pointer, could be a null,
we don't care.
And if p2 is a null pointer, just return p1. Otherwise, compare the value with p1 is pointing
and the value with p2 is pointing and returns the maximum one.
Now, we are sending a parameter as a pointer and returning again one of them here
back from the function. We are defining here
X1 with 1 and Y with 5, and then we are calling maximum using reference and reference
to be able to call a function that is expecting a pointer.
Now there is a function here called integer-pointer some, and this function is ...
..., is creating a temporary variable, local variable, and returning its reference.
Never do that.
Remember, all of the local variables of a function or a scope will be destroyed after
the function.
So this function is trying to return the address of this temporary memory,
and when this return is returned to the caller, the temp will be destroyed.
So now we have a pointer pointing to something that doesn't exist.
So be very careful when you have a function that returns a pointer. Never return a pointer
looking at something that is local. Now,
thinking about this function here Max, Max is taking two pointers and returning one of them.
This is very safe.
But here you are returning reference to a local variable.
This will crash.
Be very careful.
Another case here,...
If we have a pointer and would like to pass it to a reference.
Now, here
this is a function that takes a reference X. If I have X, I can call it hello X.
This is normal.
If I have here Y2, which is just a reference, I can also pass it.
But what if I have pointer p equals reference X and I would like to pass it to reference X.
I cannot just say p, p is an address, and it is expecting a normal variable.
here is a very simple way, you get asterisk p, now
asterisk p is just like an X here.
So remove asterisk p and put X. Now, it's taking the reference of X. This like a two steps two to get back to
the address itself.
So this is how you pass a pointer to a reference X.
So now we learned how to pass
a pointer to a reference and also we learned the reverse.
Here is one more thing about the differences between references and pointers.
Let's define three functions, the first takes X reference, the second takes const-integer reference, and the third takes
integer pointer,
and let's define some X and pointer to it.
Fun1 can takes X definitely because it's a normal integer, so it's pass by reference, that's OK, but it
cannot take a pointer because the pointer is an address and this is expecting a variable.
What if I have a pointer that I would like to send it? Send it using an asterisk pointer. So I can say
asterisk pointer, which is the last step,  just would go to the value
then we take the reference of the value.
Can I send an integer?
No,
I'm expecting a reference in the memory,
but this is just an integer.
It doesn't have a memory.
OK, so it doesn't work. On the other side,
what if the function is const?
It is same logic, except one thing.
C++ allows you to send some constant value that doesn't have a clear address for us, it's a temporary variable
here to the function here in a normal way.
So for the fun2 of 10, ten here creates a temporary variable to be passed.
This can only work in two cases only. The first case if the function doesn't take any reference.
The second case if the function taking reference,
but it is const. There is something else now for the move semantic reference-reference,
but this is another concern for now.
So now here the only difference that is a bit more flexible. The third case, if the function
is taking pointer. I cannot send for it just X. X is a variable and it is expecting an address. I can send
for it directly the reference of X because the reference of X is an address.
I can send for it pointer because this is a pointer and
this is pointer.
I cannot send for it
just 10.
As you see, the most flexible one is const integer-reference X.
But remember, this implies that the X will not be changed.
Reference is to some extent safer than the pointer, but there is still no guarantee.
There is a very wrong statement coming between software engineers that references cannot have a null
value.
This is completely wrong.
We can do some workarounds to make reference points to a null value. You might try to think to get
it.
So all what we guarantee is as following: if we are here calling with X, there
is a very high chance that things are really safe.
But still troubles can simply happen
and we can find out where to assign a null value. A few tips: In practice
in many modern C++ software codes, pointers aren't frequent.
In general, we prefer references much more than pointers.
Remember, that STL inside it,
It has a dynamic memory allocation, as we will know later.
So STL is actually from the side,
It must use pointers to make things more dynamic. Avoid pointers as possible
and go ahead more with with reference.
If you are using pointers, you have to double-check the null pointer. later,
we will study OOP polymorphism where pointers are playing a great role in allowing us to build reusable
and generic code.
If you have a small data type like an integer, don't even try to put a reference to save memory.
It is a big deal.
Like if your function like hello integer X, you don't need to think, oh, let's make it const integer reference
X.
This is very small and it will have a very minor headache, but we don't need it.
You can start thinking about the references.
If you have something like say a vector of person struct.
Now this can be heavy in memory, you have to be careful.
Do you really want to copy it?
Or better to use a reference to save time
and memory.
That's it.