In this session, we will highlight the tools we use in compiling.
There are mainly three ways to do compilation. The first way is you write some code in your notepad file, you
write the commands to compile the file and that's it.
This is not easy in the beginning,
so we will discuss it a bit later.
The second way is using an online site that compiles for you. This is the easiest way, but not so convenient.
So one site we are going to talk about is "ideone". You create an account for yourself.
It is going to save your codes.
You can compile and run, you can edit
and so on. The last way is using "IDEs". "IDEs" are tools
that makes your life much easier, much more professional, have a lot of shortcuts.
Sometimes it might be a bit problematic in the beginning to install it, but eventually, you can install it.
We are going to discuss two popular choices,
"CodeBlocks" and "Eclipse". "CodeBlocks" is much simpler and easier to set up.
"Eclipse" has a bit more support, more popular between people, but it might be a bit problematic to
install.
There are more other popular choices like "Visual Studio Code",
"CodeLite", "Sublime Text" and so on.
If you would like to try the "ideone.com" which I suggest for you to do at the beginning, go to "ideone"
which is just a website. Create your own account. Select the language like (C++ 14).
Write
and paste your code, just compile and run to get the results.
When you compile and run, you get a link to your code like this link.
This is how the website looks like. You would select from here C++ 14. You write here your own code.
If you have some input like we will see in next sessions, you click on "stdin" and just write your input.
After that,
you click this button like "Run" or so, then it is going to show you your code again and show you
the output, like "My First Program.
Helllllllo.".
You can edit the code again and you can just edit it, recompile it, you can download it
and so on. For the "IDEs", this is how an "Eclipse IDE" looks like.
if you notice, there are many menus here.
The code is here, projects are here, the console is here, it is a bit white one.
And this is the "CodeBlocks" one, look you can see
it is also like it has a very similar structure,
but the console this time is black. Installing "IDEs", as I said, might be a bit problematic, but
is eventually doable. On online,
If you search the Internet, you will find typically a lot of materials like articles and videos about
how to install a specific "Codeblocks" or "Eclipse" or whatever.
Just Google your "IDE" and the operating system like, let's say, "fedora installing Codeblocks", "Eclipse on
Mac" and so on.
If you just google any of that and here are some links, you can just use them.
On Linux, I guess and Mac, typically installations are easy most of the time. In Windows, it might be a bit
problematic for some "IDEs" like "Eclipse". In the next videos, we will show some also of these installations
to make your life easier.
That is it for today. :)