In this video, we will learn how to install "CodeBlocks" on Linux. Installing "CodeBlocks" is an easy experience
most of the time, however, it might not be the same for everyone.
Sadly, it is very impractical to support all OS versions and they are different like setups.
Check out the approach here.
If it isn't your version or doesn't work,  just google
your version. Sadly from OS to another, and even within the same OS setup, you may face
different errors.
The good news, typically googling for the problem will end up with a solution, especially on "stackoverflow"
website. The way to install on Ubuntu is as simple as you just follow with the following Ubuntu
commands.
I think I tried them on my (Ubuntu 16) and also they should be working on (Ubuntu 18).
And the installation in Fedora is much easier if you are using another version like "CentOS" or whatever, just
try to google for whatever commands to install the "CodeBlocks".
If you are done with the installation, hopefully, no problems,
you just run it from the terminal, write "codeblocks" or in the search box,
you write "codeblocks".
That is it. :)