In this video, we will learn how to install "CodeBlocks" on Windows.
Installing "CodeBlocks" is an easy experience most of the time, however, it is very impractical
for me to support all 'OSs' and their different versions.
Check out the approach here.
If it isn't your version or doesn't work, just google your version.
Sadly, from OS to another, and even within the same OS setup, you may face different
errors.
The good news, typically googling for the problems will end up with a solution, especially on a "StackOverFlow"
website.
The first step is to just google with word "codeblocks", it typically should show you some page, looks
like this one, click on "Downloads",
then you will find "Download the binary release", just click it. In the download binary release,
you should find different Windows versions, the one that you should select is the one with that "mingw.exe",
this one has all that you need. If you are 64bit,
you just select "mingw" here. If you are 32bit, you just select "mingw-32bit" here. Download and just proceed normally.
There are more links here for Linux and Mac, but you don't need to interact with them.
One critical step is we need to add the path of the "MinGW" to the system environment.
So the way to do that, this is a bit standard step.
Just go to your environment here and click "env".
If you are into Windows 10, then there are more links here.
The path that we are interested to add to the environment path is the path of the "MinGW\bin",
so it should be like this path.
But if it isn't, validate where is the path exactly
First. If you click on the edit, you go and search for "env" and then it shows you such a "System
Properties", click "Advanced" then "Environment Variables",
proceed more, you should find a variable named "Path".
Edit this path and keep going.
You should find a lot of paths here.
Just click "New" and add a new one, the one as we said the "MinGW Path" and click "OK" and "Save". If it happens
that you have problems,
first, double check that the path you added is really here.
You didn't do any mistakes like canceling or so, the second is just restart your whole machine.
Probably nothing more is needed for such step.
That is it. :)