In this video, we will learn how to install Eclipse on Linux. Installing Eclipse sometimes isn't
an easy setup.
Meanwhile, it is a very nice IDE to use.
It is very impractical to support all the OS versions and their different setups.
Check out the approach here, first.
If it isn't your version or doesn't work with you, just google your version. Sadly, from OS to
another,
and even within the same OS setup, you may face different errors.
The good news, typically googling for the problem will end up with a solution, especially on
a "StackOverFlow" website.
Here are some versions that you might like
try if the one here didn't work well.
The first step is just to go to google and just write "Download Eclipse" like this way, you should
find a page in google like this one typically.
Notice the whole name "C++ CDT". On the right side of the page here,
you should find a "Download" button, typically adjusted to your operating system.
Once you did that, you should find something called Eclipse Installer in the file.
Just double click on this file.
Some of the older versions have the installer directly to run.
So, there are two cases.
Either you have to install it or it is the executable, ready to run.
If you click, they just start to follow the normal path. It should find some internal files.
Click install and select here C++.
And if it asks for certificate, just mark all and just accept. Otherwise,
that is it. It should open for you. For Fedora,
also, I would like you first to try the installer in the previous system if it worked for you, great!
If it didn't, then you might try the "sudo dnf install -y eclipse-cdt" command, then reboot and probably
it is going to work. Again, for other operating systems,
start with the installer.
Otherwise, just try to google if there is someone who posted the command for that.
If you would like to run, just write in the terminal "eclipse" or in your search box.
It should look like this box. That is it. :)