In this video, we will learn how to install Eclipse on Windows. Installing Eclipse on Windows is
a bit problematic because it involves three steps.
This video is about Windows 10.
It is very impractical to support all "OSs" and their different versions.
Check out the approach here.
If it isn't your version or doesn't work, just google your version.
Sadly, from OS to another,
and even within the same OS setup, you may face different errors.
The good news, typically googling for the problem will end up with a solution, especially on
a "StackOverFlow" website.
The first step is to install the "Java JDK", just google it.
It should be something like that,
but Oracle guys change things from time to time, so it should be something like that.
You go to their website. You will find that at the bottom you have (X86 for a 32bit) and (X64 for a 64bit).
It should be something like that.
Be careful, select the one that has ".exe" in its end.
Okay, then download and install
normally, nothing fancy.
The second step and very critical is installing the "MinGW".
The "MinGW" exists in two places on the web.
Just google "mingw". And one of the best ways is just to go to the "sourceforge" website and just click it,
download, and install normally.
If it asks you to the path, please provide this path.This one, OK.
The
third
critical step is adding the Windows to , the same path to the "System environment".
We mainly need to add 2 paths the "MinGw" path and the "JDK" path.  The "MinGw" path will be like (MinGW\bin).
This is a standard step. For the "JDK" it should be something like that.
There should be some post-fix here based on your version.
This is a standard step to add the System Environment,
so check out here your operating system version
if you are in Windows 10. For Windows 10 you write here "env" in the search box,
it gives you here, "Edit the system environment variables".
You click on the "System Properties", and on "Advanced" then on "Environment Variables",
then you see some variables.
Click with the one that is "Path". Here in the path,
add "New" and write 2 paths, where the "MinGW\bin" path and the "JDK" path.
Click OK and save. If you face problems, please
double check first that you really added the path here,
second, restart your whole machine.
The last step is installing the "Eclipse" itself.
Just google the "download eclipse IDE".
Notice here (C++ CDT) and download
the OS version, download the version that is good with your setup.
Typically, there is auto-generating one that is nice for you.
The second step, just launch the installer and start to follow the steps.
Select C++ here.
If it asks for certificates, mark all and keep going, then just run the Eclipse.
It is going to show you a welcome page like that.
Click the 'X', and that is it.
Thank you. :)