In this video, we will discuss how to create a project using CodeBlocks. When you open
the IDE, you will notice there are many menus here.
You are encouraged in the future, one by one to explore.
There are two important things here.
You can create a new project or open an existing project.
So let's go with creating a new project.
You select here a console application, and then go, then C++,
then you start to give a title and there is here a path to a workspace.
Workspace is something that has a lot of projects and every project has something like that, as
one unit.
The very critical advice here, make sure the path of your workspace and the path of your project and
the path of any file name doesn't include any space.
So let's make a name here like this "test111". We just write a name here and give a path here.
Don't play with these two things.
Notice here the "cbp" extension.
This is the project title name.
When you would like to open an existing project, you go and browse this 'cbp' file.
Let's go with next. Some default option.
Make sure that this is "GCC Compiler" and then finish.
When you open the project, you will have some initial code here in the "main.cpp" file.
And then let's build and run the code. It's very important to keep in mind the following, to get
results of executing a code,
you have to always do two things.
You have to Compile it (to build it), and you have to run it. From this menu here
you see, there is a build option here.
So you build the first.
After that, you start to run from here.
Then it gives you this black screen with the "Hello world!".
If you entered "Enter", this screen will get closed.
Now, there is a nice choice here to build and run at the same time.
And this is what I actually usually do, like let's say "111" here and then click on it,
then it is updated with "111".
Now let's make another update here and just try to run.
You would notice that the "Hello world!" didn't update with this new one.
Why?
Because you forgot to build and run,
Ok. So you always need to build and run, or easily, try to run this one.
So let's try to build and run again.
Oh! they are disabled.
Why?
Because you forgot to close this window.
You have to close it first, then come and build and run.
You can also come to this menu here "Build" and click build and run.
You will notice 'F9' allows you to build & run.
This is actually what you can do usually. Like, 'F9' is going to build and run. this is how
you can write your own code.
Let's try to make an error.
Let's remove this semicolon ';',
and then build and run. You will notice here it says "error: expected ';' before 'return' ".
There is a missing semicolon here.
So now, let's return it and click on build and run.
Perfect! Notice here it says "0 error(s)".
It is important to always verify that this is a zero-errors-program.
What if I wanted to rename this file to something else?
Let's right-click and search for "rename".
You don't find it.
You have, sadly, to close the window first, then come here and say "rename".
Let's make it "main111.cpp"
Now, you can double click and get it again.
Let's get here something new, and then build and run.
So far so good.
What else?
Let's say you would like to create another "CPP" file, maybe here.
Let's right-click on the project here. Sorry, on the sources or the project from the menu "file". "new", "file" and
select "source file".
Go and let's give it here
C++ also. And it asks you about which directory and file name. Browse from here.
Probably, it would be the same project as yours,
and let's say "hello.cpp", enter, now it is updated here.
Click "All" and "Finish".
Now you get this new file which is empty.
Let's
copy & paste this code here, and let's run it.
If you try to run it, it gives an error
"multiple definition of 'main' ".
It means the 'main' is duplicated.
There are two things with this line here,
'main' and 'main'. C++ doesn't accept that in a project. There should be only one 'main'.
Later we will know that the compiler is searching for this one.
If it sees it in two files, it gets confused.
There are two ways to handle this problem.
An easier one; that I do not encourage you to use it.
Change this one from 'main' to 'main(something)'.
It should be also unique, like 'main1' or 'main2' and so on.
Now try to run, It is going to run. But this isn't the standard way to do it.
Let's return this one here.
The way that you should do it, you go to the compiler here.
Let's say you want to cancel this 'main' file, you want only this one that has the 'cpp' file.
come on
the one that you want to discard for now,
right-click,
go to "Options",
remove the "compile file",
right-click,
go to options,
remove the link file.
Now, this guy is now with a 'main' but you can now run
This "hello.cpp" in a normal way.
So here it is just giving you "111". This way during the project, you can create a lot of files. Every
time you are adding a new file, just cancel the old one or return it from here, if you would like,
by marking these two choices.
So far, we learned how to rename, we learned how to review.
If it happens at any moment of time that you corrupted this view, let's say you close this 'X' in a
wrong way,
come here
in the 'View", tell him the "Perspectives", get me for the default one. It is going to return everything as it is,
because this is a bit a common error for the guys.
You can come here on this project and,
right-click
and say...
I guess in this one here, you can tell it to...
"Open Project Folder in File Browser", is going to show you the project here, you can see that this is the
actual project path.
So you can take it and maybe you can go and maybe visualize it here.
Let's go here.
You find some "bin", inside it you find...
This is an executable. For Windows guys
It will have ".exe". Every time you compile your code,
this file is going to be removed and another file would be created.
Here in the "obj" you find something that ending with ".o".
The ".o" file is an intermediate step, that we will know more about it later. If it happens that
anything that is weird in your project, maybe you come back to the project here and
right-click
and tell it to clean or to rebuild, then tell it
"Yes", this is going to clean
if there is something wrong in the project that happened in a way or another. I would like also
to show you some about the settings of this project.
You can right-click
on this project here and tell it "Build Options...". It is going to show you here options to enable warnings.
This is something very useful.
So tell him I like this one
and this guy,
and this guy and also this guy. This one enables warnings that you might create in your
own projects.
In the next video, you will also find that I am talking about enabling the compiler like C++ or like
C++ 14.
You mainly come from the menu here.
You will see this in another video.
I'm just showing you the 'Menu', 'Compiler'
and then you go to the "Toolchain executable"' here, from the compiler.
And then you add here "--std=c++14", you will see this in another video,
but I'm just showing you how to reach it from the menu from here.
What else to consider here? The shortcuts, if you went to the settings here and say,... "Editor"
and then you could find here, there are in the menu here, there is something we call "Shortcuts".
Where is it?
keyboard shortcut.
There are a lot of shortcuts here that you can use in your system.
For example, remember the build and run.
You will notice the 'F9'. You are encouraged to explore all of these guys.
One of the interesting features, but in code is what we call a "Code Formatter". "Code Formatter",
when you write a code but it isn't organized, then using some shortcut, you can reorganize the
code for that if you would like to.
The editor in CodeBlocks doesn't have a formatter by default, so you have to provide it by yourself.
So you mainly go to the "shortcuts" and then you have to go to the "plugins" here, and then
you go to the "Source code formatter" here, and then you start to provide it here.
I wrote here [control-shift-f], so you provide it, give it [control-shift-f] and make sure you add it here.
This way, the code can be reformatted.
Let's see
what does this mean here?
Let's see.
The code is like not organized and this happens a lot from beginners. If you press the [control-
shift-f] is going to be a bit, a bit handled.
The one in CodeBlocks isn't as good as the one in Eclipse. But anyway, it should still be a help. That is All. :)