In this video, we will learn how to create a project in Eclipse. As you see, there are many menus
here.
You are encouraged to explore all of them.
On the left side, you have the Project Explorer.
This is where you have a workspace.
A workspace is just an area with a bunch of projects for you.
You start from this top menu or from here and right-click,
"New" and then say "C++ Project" or "C++ manage a project", give it a project name.
Remember that the workspace's path in Eclipse
should have no spaces at all.
And also the project name should have no spaces at all.
This reduces a lot of problems.
Select here "Hello World C++ Project" and either one of these guys. If you are Windows then you select
also "MinGW".
You click next and make sure the source is empty, and next, and click "Advanced Settings", this is an important
choice here.
You go to "C++ Building", "Behavior" tab and mark "Auto Build". The Auto Build choice is going to make your
life much easier.
Clicking Finish, you have now here your own code and then let's run it.
If you would like to run it, you right-click
here and say "Run As" then "C C++ application".
Then it's going to print "!!!Hello World!!!".
Remember that in any C++ project you have to do two things to run,
you have to compile and you have to run it. As we are making it auto build,
we usually don't have to compile it,
we just have to just run it.
The first way to run it is as we did here to right-click
and "Run as" and just go ahead.
Also, you can just click here in this run test, run this button.
If you have many projects, then you can click on this item and just click one of them.
You can also find it here from the run menu, so all of them have the same thing.
In the future, you can go here and run as "Run Configuration".
You will find your own project here, among other projects, and you will find other tips that are
important to explore in the far future.
Going back to our project, maybe the next thing to do is..., by the way, I think there is also
[ctrl-F11] here as a shortcut.
So if we did [ctrl-F11], it just also going to (Build and Run) for us.
Let's create a problem.
Let's remove this semicolon here.
Then you either use [ctrl-S] to save the file, or there is this "Save" single-button, or there is this "Save All" for
all opened files.
So let's just save whatever way. You would notice that there is, here in the console area,
there is "expected ';' ".
So there is a problem here missing.
Also, if you go to the tab "problems", you start to see it here.
So this is how you know that there is something wrong, mainly through the console part.
what else to try here?
Let's open this test project.
You would find here the "Test.cpp" and the "Binaries',
The "Binaries" is referring to the executable, which is ".exe" on windows.
Let's do something interesting here.
Let's click on the "Debug" folder, get "Properties" and "Resource" here, then let's get this directory
and try to go and print it.
So here we can go to that guy.
You can find here the "Test executable" and the "Test.o". Every time you change your code and
save it and build, these two files are going to be replaced with new files.
If it happened for some reason, for example, that this executable is opened in a way and the program
failed to replace it, you are going to face a problem. It is just cannot replace the
file.
What else might be useful here?
In this menu here,
if you have several programs running, you can see them. Later,
we will run several programs together.
You would notice that there is a red-button here indicating that the program is actually running.
If you run two programs at the same time, you will get an error, as I said, something like,
"permission denied" because it cannot run the program.
shortcuts.
If you press [ctrl-shift-L], it is going to show you the list of shortcuts in Eclipse.
I advise you to be very clever in this shortcut list.
But for now, the shortcut that I have interest to teach you is what we call the "Formatter".
Let's say I'm going to corrupt the shape of this code this way, like here...
Typically, young guys write in a bit unorganized way.
If you started to press [ctrl-shift-F], it is going to return it back in an organized way.
So this is a shortcut that we are using all the time.
Other than that, there is the menu of choices that you have.
One of the..., you can clean the project
if there is something wrong. Refresh it to refer to some file, close it, or close other projects and
so on.
One of the very lovely features here is the "compare and restore" features. If you would like to, if in the future,
you have an updated version and thought, "I would like to come back to a previous version of the code",
you can right-click and "compare as" with "local history" and it is going to show you a bunch
of your old history changes.
And this is very useful in many cases.
The last thing I would like to highlight here is creating a new file. Let's create a new file and
let's call it maybe..., "source file" here,
"HELLO.CPP"
here, and click it here.
Now, it is an empty file.
Let's copy this file to it here,
and let's save. What is going to happen here, we will have a problem. The reason behind having the problem
here is as following,
OK, I used a wrong name file.
It should be "cpp"small.
Got a bug anyway. Let's type ".cpp" file.
OK, so now it is going to tell you, that we have multiple redefinitions of 'main'.
What does this mean?
It means that there are more than a ".cpp" file with the word 'main'. Multiple definitions of 'main'.
There should be only one file that has a 'main' function, only one that has this line,
OK. So we need to get rid of one of these two files.
There are two tricks.
The easiest and I like it more,
you right-click here,
and rename it to anything that isn't ".cpp". Let's say ".txt" here, for example, or
underscore.
Now, the program would be fine because now this file is just a text file, nothing else. The other way,
and I don't like it a lot.
Sometimes the Eclipse isn't consistent.
Right-click
here and tell it "Resource Configurations", "Exclude from Build" and select these two choices, then OK
this choice is telling the compiler to ignore this "cpp" file
That is all for today.
I don't think you need to know more at the moment. Just start to create your own project. start to
explore as much as possible. The "Build" menu here is one of the most important menus.
In a next video,
I will show in a separate video that we go to the settings here and we go to the, you see here "GCC"
and "C++". This one here, the "C++" one in the "Miscellaneous",
you can add here, as we will do in a separate video "--std=14" or 17,
We will know in the next video about that.
There are slides also attached to the video.
Also, check it out.
That is it. :)