Congratulations on running your first "Hello World" program!
The caveat here that I would like to share with you is something about configuring the compiler.
C++ has many recent standards, C++ 11 came with a very, very big jump in the C++ syntax,
14 did a good refining to 11, 17 has like another good jump and so on.
However, the first thing to keep in mind is that different "GCC" compilers support different
versions of C++.
So, if you can stick to the latest "GCC" compiler, this is much better for you, but here is the trick,
even having the latest C++ compiler doesn't mean by default
it will compile your latest code.  and here is one thing that you might face a lot,
You might have a code from my code collection and it compiles on my side,
but it doesn't compile on your side.
When this happens, 99% it doesn't mean something is wrong in the code, just probably something is
wrong in the compiler itself.
So let's go a little more. In C++, to support C++ 11, you need at least a GCC version of (4.8)
to support 14, you need (5.2) at least,
to support 17, you need version (8.0).
Sometimes it isn't easy for everyone to have the latest version, Why?
For example, some guys on some Linux based system might prefer to keep using (5.2) in his system,
because it's very stable for example,
or he's hesitant about moving further.
So, maybe at least something like (5.2) would be a good idea. In case you can not upgrade,
or you're facing some difficulties with the compiler,
Here is some advice.
The website from "ideone.com" supports C++ 14, which should cover a lot of your code.
The C++ compiler in the "onlinegdb.com" website supports also online compilation for C++ 17.
So, if it happens that you suspect that, "Oh, This code might be C++ 17 and I don't have a support for that!",
you might try first these C++ online compilers. If your compiler supports C++ 11,
this should be very good for a lot of examples in this course, because C++ 11 already is a very
big jump in the modern C++ syntax.
Here, there are few steps to follow to configure "Eclipse", you right-click on the project, select 'Properties',
'C++ Build', 'Settings' and go to this keyword “Miscellaneous”, and add one of these guys.
So, here's what you see when you right-click on the project, you go to 'C++ build', 'Settings'. Here in C++ Eclipse
there are always two sections, one of them is for C programming language, and the other one
is for C++ programming language.
Be careful, because in most of the cases guys get confused and configure the C not the C++.
You have to be here in the C++ section.
Here, you would find this keyword “Miscellaneous” .
Click it, now in this text area, you are going to add,
" --std=c++14" for example or (C++ 17) or (C++ 11).
If you don't, you are using the default of your compiler.
For the "CodeBlocks" guys, you should select the project, then from the top menu find the 'Settings', 'Compiler',
then select the  'Toolchain Executable'.
And again, add one of these three choices.
Here, when you click the compiler, you will find the global compiler setting, click it, go to this tab
the 'Toolchain Executable' and here in the C++ compiler section add " --std=c++14"
or 17 or more.
This way you have already configured your compiler. In case you are using another IDE,
just google how to add the C++ version to your code.
One concern here, some of the IDEs like "CodeLite" provide different checkboxes,
like one checkbox for 11, another for 14, another for 17.
Please select only one of them.
For example, the latest. OK, here is an important verification step.
I would like you to run this code, this code will tell you what your current configured compiler is.
OK, so if you run,  it is going to print either "pre-standard C++",
98, 11, 14, 17. If your compiler is printing 11
It should be good for most of the cases.
If it can print 14, this is great!
If it can print 17, this is good!
If it is printing 98 or pre-standard, this is bad.
Try to figure out what's wrong about your compiler and change it.
The code is attached to the lecture content.
Please run it and double check it.
That's it! :)