Hi Everyone, in this lecture we're going to talk about the pigeonhole principle but again, it's a very
simple principle but sometimes it's very useful in solving competitive programming questions.
So let's talk about pigeonhole principle.
So it is based upon a very simple idea.
And let's start with an example.
Suppose we are given five pigeons and there are four pigeonholes. OK?
And you start putting pigeons one by one into each pigeon hole.
So what is going to happen. if you have five pigeons and you only have four holes
And if you put this pigeon here.
If you put this pigeon here.
If you put this pigeon here, if you put this pigeon here then if you want to put this pigeon then
this might
one of the whole will contain at least two pigeons.
OK?
This is what is going to happen and you can see it is as obvious as it is.
Then you will have one pigeon left and you can put it into any one of the pigeon holes.
That means
to conclude, when the number of pigeons is greater than the number of pigeonholes then there will
be at least one pigeon hole with at least two pigeons. OK?
That's that's the whole idea of a pigeonhole principle.
And now you may ask, why do we need this?
This is something that is very obvious.
But yes, we will be using this simple concept to solve some interesting questions.
Let me give you another example. Hair counting example.
Let's say the amount of hair is expressed in terms of number of hair strands.
The average human hair does about one lac fifty thousand strands of hair. assuming no human has
more than one million strands of it.
That is 10 lac. given the population of a city is let's say 30 million.
OK, then definitely
we can conclude that there would be many people who would have exactly the same number of hair on their
head.
OK, so very simple. we are saying OK. one million so anyone can have a hair in the range zero
to one million on their head. OK?
But if the number of people who are there in a city, they are in the range, let's say that 30 million
ok so there are 30 million people.
So each of these 30 million people needs to be clubbed into this bucket.
So this is basically buckets. OK?
We can say definitely a lot of people are going to have overlap and there will be many people who would
have the same number of hair on their head.
This is another way of, you can say
it's just what way pigeonhole principal.
ok So we are putting people into buckets where each bucket denotes the amount of hair on
their head.
OK?
And that's all for this small introduction. and in the next lecture will start solving problems on pigeonhole
principle.