Hi everyone, in this lecture we're going to solve a problem. the name of the problem is divisible
subset and we are given a multi set of N integer, so multi set is nothing but a set which
can contain repeating elements as well.
OK.
And we need to find a non empty subset of it such that sum of the subject element is divisible by
N. so this N is nothing but the size of the subset.
So given set we need to find a subset who's sum of element is divisible by the size of the set.
OK.
So N is size of the actual set.
OK, so we are not given a different number but it is same as
the size of the original set.
And if such a subset does not exist we will print minus one.
But if it exists, what we are going to do? we are going to output two lines.
One is the size of the subset on the first line. OK?
We need to tell what is the size of that particular subset and second is we need to output the list
of indices
That form the required subset. OK?
And you can see N is very large.
So actually this question is from the platform codechef.
I will just show it to you. so you can do this is from codechef.
The problem is divSubs and again we have already gone through the problem statement.
But if you look at the constraints here.
So.
We are given each element of the multiset is a positive integer not exceeding 10 power nine. ok which is
fine.
And now we are given three different values for constraint.
so if you solve this problem four N up to 15. OK. you get 37 points.
If you solve it up to N equal one thousand, you get thirty seven plus twenty four points.
And if you also solve for a larger of the value of N that ten power five, you get thirty
nine more points. ok.
That means we there must be multiple approaches to solve this particular question.
OK. now let me also give you an example.
So if you look at the input. so input, the first line of the input contains an integer T denoting the
number of test cases. OK. then followed by the N and followed by N integer.
Alright. so we have one test case.
Which contains three integers and the integers are four six ten. So these are the values in the set.
And now we need to output ok, anyone set. Output any one set such that sum of the integers in that particular
subset is divisible by three.
So in this case, they're saying. OK. I will just pick the second element that is six and six modulus
three that is equal to zero which is fine.
So that's why you can see the output as what ? the output is
the size of the set is one and the element index is two.
This is what what is the size?
So we can pick as a subset, the sum is 6 and it's divisible by three.
OK.
The only thing is it should be non empty and that means at least the size should be at least one.
Now we need to see
what what can we do?
OK, so if so. what is a brute force way of generating all possible subsets?
So, you know if you're given array of size N which contains some elements A, B, C, D and so on.
So for each element, you have two choices. either including the set or you do not include it. OK?
So if the arrays of the size N then you can generate two raise to the power N subsets. OK?
And if N is large, this is going to be a very huge number and it's obviously going to give you the
time limit exceeded error.
So for N, the value of N up to 15.
You can easily do the work of two raise to the power 15 and you can definitely use the brute force
approach.
This will work fine here.
So generate all the subset and print anyone subset that follows this particular property.
But for N that is equal to one thousand. OK?
That is equal to one thousand.
We might not be able to do the same.
OK.
We cannot.
We cannot do two raise to the power one thousand.
This is going to be a huge number and it's going to give you TLE. OK.
So this exponential complexity will work only till 20 or 30 at MAX.
Because two raise to the power 20, this is of the order 10 power six. two raise to power 30
It is of the order ten power nine.
Even this is not going to work.
OK, so for larger values greater than 20, it's going to be become.
It's going to become very slow.
So now what do we do for an equal to 1000 ? So one thing we need to recall is
there are generally two terms. one is called is subarray. OK and one is called a subset.
And all subarrays are also subsets of.
OK, so subarrays are also subset, so I need to find only one subject.
So if I find, if I can ensure
If there is one subarray then we have also found out the subset.
OK, then we have also found out the subset.
so ensuring a subarray will ensure a subset also exists.
So now let's see if we can.
how many subsidies we can have for the array of size N. so subarray
a continuous part and subarray...
A subset might not be contiguous as well.
OK, so let's see if we have a array like this.
Then a subarray is a continuous part of the array. let's say starting from this index and this index.
let's say this part of the subarray
we have
and somehow, if we are able to prove that OK. there would be this subarray which will have this which
will follow this property that some of elements from a A[i] till A[j].
sorry A[i+1] till A[j]
The mode of this would be divisible by N. then we do not need to look for subsets
Additionally. OK. if we can find a subarray then subset is
subarray is also a subset.
So how many subsets you can have?
So if N is of the order ten power three then you can pick the starting and ending point of a subset
in nC2 ways.
So roughly, we can have N^2 subsets.
OK.
That means for
N that is ten power three, we can have roughly 10 power six subsets.
We can find the sum. OK. by generating accumulative sum array and we can find the sum ok. we know the sum
till this particular point, we need the sum till this particular point.
And we can find the sum in just constant time.
OK.
That means in order of N^2 complexity.
We can check
for all subarrays. OK.
But the question is what if, if we don't find subarray. OK?
But now what I'm going to do is, I'm just going to jump jump to this particular part.
An I'm going to prove, we are going to prove.
For this problem the subarray
that follows this property that follows this property that is mentioned in the question that sum of
elements should be divisible by the size of the original array.
OK. will always exist, will always exist.
So it's a little tricky to think of this but we will try to prove it using the pigeonhole principle.
So now we'll solve for N, that is ten power five.
And that will also cover the case.
We will not need to find all the subarray.
We will just prove that this subarray will always exist and in the output we only need to print one subset
and the subarray is also a subset.
So let's let's go into what we need to do for ten power five in the next video and that will give
us an idea how we can use the pigeonhole principle.