So let us continue our discussion on the problem divSubs and let's try to prove that this problem
can be solved using pigeonhole principle and that to in almost linear time.
OK. so we are going to look at how we can solve this problem
So this test case we have already seen.
And let's take an example.
Let's take a array.
One two three five and let's say seven.
Let's say we have five elements in this array and we need to find a subset or not a subset. Subset
there can be a lot of subset.
So we said we will first try to find a subarray and we will prove the claim was that such a subarray
will always exist.
So we are claiming a subarray will always exist.
OK. will always exist and we are not going to prove our claim.
So what we are going to do?
So if you need to find the sum of elements of a subarray  than what we generally do is, we make array
of accumulative sum.
OK, let's make another array.
And
what we will do? we will say ok.
Let's find out the sum till this particular point.
So this is one. what is the sum up to the index zero one two three four. The sum till this point is three
this is three plus three six.
This is what? this is
11.
And this is what? this is 11 plus 7, 18.
OK.
Sorry this should be
Yeah, so this this sum should be what? this sum should be
18.
OK, so now what we can do is, we can say
Suppose what we are saying is, we are saying. OK. we will find a subarray, maybe let's say this is
subarray who's sum is divisible by N, let's say the value of N is five.
So we are saying we know the sum till this particular point is let's say this sum B. the sum total before index
one is still up to this particular point
that is A. the sum of a subarray, the subarray sum
can be computed in order one time.
that is nothing but b minus a.
OK, so we are saying b minus a taking mode with N that of subarray sum and this should be equal
to zero.
That means B mode N should be equal to A mode N.
OK.
So effectively what are B and A. So B and A denotes the cumulative sum.
So what we do in this particular array is, we can reduce everything by mode N. OK.
So if you do A mod N here here, what you're going to get? you're going to get these numbers. OK. so
you're going to get one mode five.
That is one.
3 mode 5, 3. 6 mode 5.
Again one. 11 mode 5 again one. 18, mode 5 that is three.
All right.
So we are getting so many numbers.
So now we also know that something mode five, something mode five will always lie in five buckets.
OK?
So something mode five or something mode N will always lie in the buckets
zero, one, two, three and four.
OK.
Right now, what we are getting is, we are getting three numbers which are getting mapped with the bucket
one.
OK. we are getting two numbers which are getting mapped with the bucket three
and we're getting zero number mapped with the bucket two and zero numbers
mapped with getting bucket four and zero numbers mapped with getting
mapped with bucket zero. So right now, this is how their distribution is
but now let me just tell you that there can be two possibilities. OK?
So in the worst case, you might get something mode N as
zero, one, two, three and four.
OK. so we have five numbers and let us assume that these five numbers give these three different modes.
OK, so now what
may happen is.
Let's say if something mode
If I say OK. the cumulative sum till this particular point is let's zero.
Then what it means
you you already got the subarray. you already got the subarray.
OK, if you have something like, if, if, if you get this some B as zero that means instead of five
this number would have been four.
OK. let's take the example of this array. Let
one, two, three, four and seven.
Then you have got sum one, three, six, 10 and 17.
Then if you do mode with N, you would get one three one zero.
and again, this is nothing but two.
So if this sum is zero that means the sum till this particular point, the sum till this particular
point.
This sum is what? this is a subarray who's sum is divisible by N.
So if you get the number zero then it means you are already done.
But suppose instead of instead of getting zero, you get something else. OK. instead of getting zero,
if you get something else as your sum
that number could be one.
That number could be two. that number would be three or that number could be four.
That means it would always lie in the range one to four.
OK.
That means it would always lie in the range
one to four.
Let us say this number is nothing but two.
So maybe what you get is, you get one two two and three four. let's say, two numbers
they lie in the same bucket.
So effectively, what I'm saying is if you get zero, you already find find out.
You already found out one subarray
But if you don't get zero, then what happens? For these numbers
You have five numbers. OK. and you have only four options.
You have only four, four options.
That means four buckets.
That means there would be at least one bucket which is storing two numbers which are same. OK.
In this case, there are multiple such buckets.
There is a bucket of one.
There is a bucket of three.
There are only four options for five numbers.
So according to the pigeonhole principle we can say, we can say.
At least
one bucket or at least one bucket or at least two sums
will always lie in the same bucket. will always lie in the same bucket.
Ok. that means we found out the values of B and A. that means such B and A will always exist because of
the pigeonhole principle.
Why? let us look at this example now.
So we are saying. ok. this one and this one are same. so effectively if you pick the entire subarray
in this range.
That means if you pick these three elements that the elements to three five. they follow this property.
OK?
Or if you pick anything in the range.
So this one and this one also same. OK.
That means if you subtract the sum till this particular point is one. the sum to this particular point
is also one.
That means if you subtract this B minus this A, you again you can again get something like this.
So you can get two, three.
So two plus three.
This is also subarray that satisfies the given property.
So here we are saying the sum till this particular point is three.
The sum till this particular point is three.
So if you subtract three minus three, it is also zero.
That means these three elements
they will also satisfied the property three plus five plus seven
So you can to this is nothing but 15, this is nothing but five.
This is nothing but ten.
So all of them are divisible by zero.
All of them are divisible by zero.
So effectively in the cumulative sum array.
What should happen is, either one of the values would be at least zero or if it is not, if none of
the numbers is zero then we are saying at least two numbers will have the same value and the area
of the array in between these two indices will form your subarray who's sum would be.... who's sum mode N would
be zero. OK. that's..
That's the whole idea.
So I hope you understood how we have applied by pigeonhole principle in this question.
OK. so if it is still not clear, so we are saying pick any  two numbers which are same
So we are saying. OK. we will pick the numbers till this particular point.
Let's say this one
and maybe this one.
OK.
If I subtract these two. OK. if I subtract these two.
So that effectively means I'm taking all the elements of the array till this particular points
summing them up. and i am subtracting all the element till this particular point, I'm subtracting
them up.
So what I'm left with? I'm left with this number five.
This is nothing but five mod five.
This is also zero.
OK.
This is also a subarray. in the question that we have just seen on codechef.
What  you need to do is, you do not need to find the in exponential time
we have already proved such subarray will always exist because of pigeonhole principle because there
can be two cases.
If one of the numbers, if one of the sums turns out to be zero that means starting from the 0th index
till that particular index, you got the subarray.
But if one of the number is not zero then you have five numbers here and you have only four buckets
left.
That number would always lie in the range
one two four.
OK.
I think if you have N numbers here then you will have n minus one buckets here. So at least one number
would repeat and the indices responding to those two repetitions would give you the sub array.
OK.
So that's how we have used the pigeonhole principle to prove this claim and solve this problem.
Now this cumulative sum can be done in linear time and you can maintain a kind of a frequency array
and you can check the place
we are the frequency is at least two that will solve that problem.
OK.
So that's all for this video.
Thank you.