Hi everyone, in this lecture we're going to solve this problem. the problem name is Gray similar Code
and it is again a question from codechef.
So it has given, we are given N 64 bit integers such that two consecutive numbers differ
exactly at one bit.
Okay.
So let's say if the first.... if the Ith numbers is let's say if there is like one one zero zero one,
then A[i+1] will only have one
bit different.
ok. maybe this bit is different. ok. rest
all the bits are the same. so we have to find four integers.
OK.
So this is a small mistake.
We have to find four integers.
Such that their XOR is equal to zero and we have to output yes or no.
If such four integers are possible or not.
Now again, this is a problem from codechef.
So let us look at the exact constraints.
OK.
And the question is same like you're given N non-negative integer and Ai is of the range to 2 power 64
that means the number can be stored in long long.
And you need to check whether there are four numbers such that the following properties is satisfied.
Ok. So it is saying the XOR of the numbers let's say  the four numbers is A,B,C,D.
So So A^B^C^D. this is equal to zero, this is the property that needs to be
satisfied for this particular problem.
And in the output, we just need to print yes or no.
So let us look at the value of N.
So N you can see it is, it is a large number. N is of the order
ten power five and  now what is a brute force approach?
So let's talk about the bruteforce approach of doing this.
So we are also giving a sample input.
So we have five integer and the answer for this is yes.
So there exist four numbers from the set so that the Xor is equal to zero.
Now let us look at one thing.
So let us discuss what are the various approaches to solve this problem.
So the first way is brute force approach in which what you're going to do? we are going to pick four
numbers.
OK.
And how do you pick four numbers out of N numbers? simply by using four loops and you would have nC4
options.
And this would take that O(N^4) time and since N is of the order ten power five.
This solution will give you the time limit Exceeded  error.  OK.
The the brute force solution will not work.
The brute force will work for smaller values of N. OK for smaller values of N, let's say four N
less than equal 100.
The brute force will work because doing N power four  would be of the order
ten power eight.
OK, so now let's see how what optimizations we can add to our solution.
OK.
How do we optimize our solution?
SO the thing is, what we want is we are not exploiting the property.
So there is one information given in the question that
two consecutive numbers, two consecutive
numbers differ only at one bit. differ
only at one bit and another information given is the numbers are 64 bit numbers.
This is also given. till now in the brute force solution
we have not used this information.
Now we need to see what is special thing about this information and how we can use it.
OK, so two consecutive numbers differ at only one bit.
So if I do a XOR of a number along with the next number, some Ith number. OK. since they differ at only one
bit. let's say this is the number and let's say this is the next number.
If I do a XOR of both what I will get? I'll get all zeros except
one at one position. OK. so it will be all zeros but we will get one at
one position. OK. at any any one position where the bits are different, I'll get the bit one.
Now suppose I have a lot of numbers. OK. so I have numbers from A1 A2 upto upto , let's say
A129, A130 up to up to An. OK.
So what I'm saying is, if I have at least 130 numbers. OK, if I have at least
130 numbers, If the value of n is greater than 130.
I can say my answer would be always yes. I will tell you why.
I will tell you why.
But if N is less than or equal to 130, ok if N is greater than or equal to 130 than the answer is always going
to be yes.
Let me just tell you why.
So if you have 130 numbers and if you do a paire wise XOR of all the numbers.
Okay. so if you do as XOR of these, A XOR of next two, A XOR of next two , A XOR of next two. ok.
SO what is going to happen?
You're going to get 65 pairs. OK?
You're going to get 65 pairs and in each pair you will have a number of the form
One one of the positions will be one. OK?
So only one bit would be set. only one bit
would be set. OK. because of the property that we have just seen that if we do a XOR of two consecutive
numbers, we get a number in which only one bit would be set.
Now this one bit
can occupy a position in the range zero to sixty three.
OK.
That can be indexed from zero to index
Sixty three.
OK,. but how many pairs we have?
OK.
So basically we only have 64 positions.
OK, we only have 64 positions.
OK.
And but we have 65 answers. ok so we get 65 pairs and each pair is of this particular form in which
one of the bits is in this range.
OK. that means at least at least two pairs will have same value.
At least two pairs will have same value.
Let us assume the value is this much. that means
one of the pair has a bit at let's say some Kth  position. there must be one more pair which has bit
at the same position.
So at least two pairs will have the same value because all the pairs of the form in which all the
positions contain zero except one position contains one.
OK.
And since there are only 64 positions for one but we have 65 such pair that means two pairs will
have same value.
That means the set bit at same position. the set bit at same position. to know what we can conclude
from here as, we can see if we if we know. OK. there must be at least two pair which are having the
same value.
Let's say the numbers A  and B formed the pair P1. the numbers C and D formed the pair P2 and hence
doing XOR of these two pairs. p1 and P2
they will always produce the XOR zero.
let's say pair is P1. this pair is P2.
P1 xor P2 would be zero.
So this would be always be yes.
if we can get at least 65 pairs
that means if the number of numbers is greater then equal to 130 in the array, the answer would be
always yes.
This solves for the case when N is greater than or equal to 130.
OK, now let's come to the second case. what if N is less than if the value of N is less than 130?
OK, so if an is less than 130 then what we can do? we can say our brute force solution will work for smaller
values
of N. we can still optimize the brute force solution little bit.
Let's see how we can do it.
OK?
So let let me just summarize so if N is greater than equal to 130. we can say the answer is always
yes, because we have proved by using the pigeonhole principle that if we get sixty five pairs and we have
only 64 bit positions which can which are possible then two pairs will have the same value.
And doing XOR of those pair would produce an output of
zero.
OK.
two
pairs will have
same value.
And we can say  that, P1^P2 would be zero.
And let's say  this pair is made up of A and B.
This pair is made up of C and D. and doing a XOR of these would give me an answer
zero.
But if N is less than 130. N is not greater than 130.
then what we need is, we we can actually use a brute force approach.
So we need to find out four numbers A xor B xor C xor D
This is equal to zero or what we can do is, we need to find out a number B.
So we can use three loops to iterate over the values of A, B and C and we can say  A xor B xor C must
be equal to D. OK.
If this xor is equal to zero then if we find out a
If we just use three loops to iterate on all positions of ABC?
We can look for D.
We can look for D in the array.
Now how we can look for D.
So there are two options.
One option is you do the sorting and then you do the binary search.
OK, binary search for D. another option could be if you can do hashing as well.
OK, if you hash, you can simply look for the value of D in just constant time.
So that means this operation can be either reduced to log(n) operation or if you're do binary research
or it can be reduced to order one operation.
If you use a hashing.
OK, so now the brute force solution can be solved in order of N^3  time or order of N^3log(n)
time
And since the value of N is only of the Order 100.
And this would take ten power six operations and hence this will get accepted.
OK, so you basically make if else, if N is greater than equal to 130, output
Yes.
If it is no, then use a brute force technique to check whether these four numbers are possible or
not.
OK.
That's what you're going to do.
So that's all for this lecture.
I hope you understood the solution.
And that's it.