I so in this lecture, we're going to solve this problem it.
It's actually a pretty big problem.
So I have written to somebody.
The actual version is on the platform spot and let us try to go through the problem statement and try
to understand this question.
So it says people have many ways to save money on accommodation when they're on vacation, OK?
One of these ways is to exchange house with other people, OK?
So instead of going to hotel, people want to exchange houses.
So there is a group of people who want to travel around the world.
They live in different cities and they can travel to other people's city.
And use that house.
Now they want to make a plan.
For a destination for each person, there are two rules to which, despite all the people, should go
to one of the other people's cities.
So if there are multiple cities.
OK, that said, this person be one, it will go to some other city.
This person will do it may go to some other city.
This is better than be treatment.
Go to some other city.
This is than before.
It may go to some of the city so that all people are able to exchange those who have them never go to
the same routine because they're not willing to share ours.
OK, so that means in the final output, there would be some kind of permutation among the people they
want to maximize some of people's travel distance.
OK, the total travelling distance should be maximized.
The travel distance is the distance between the city and the city he travels to.
OK, so the entire distance traveled from source to a particular destination.
OK, that is known as the travel distance for a Person B and other entities.
And did it end minus one I was going to give them?
The travelers always choose the shortest, but when traveling, this is something that we need to see.
OK.
So effectively what it is given there are entities, OK and did it and minus highways which are connecting
them.
That basically means if you have three cities, then there are only two highways, OK, that means it
will be in the form of three.
It will not be a growth again.
So that means all that you can take.
It is a graph without a cycle.
OK, it's a graph without a cycle.
And that is also called as a tree.
The structure of the cities is in the form of the restructure.
So maybe the most it is here, here who go.
So you're going to if you have one two three four five six seven seven cities and there are only six
cities.
OK, so any anything that follows this kind of a structure, it is a graph without a cycle.
Look, if you add the edge like this, then it will violate this property that did and minus one is
in this case, you have neighbors, so this edge should not be there.
Now what is the meaning of the shortest possible path to get an ideal condition that is given to us
is they always take the.
Shortest possible, but.
While traveling, and second thing is we have to maximize the total distance we can maximize the total
distance off the road.
That effectively means if this person zero, if it wants to go to the Node two.
It will take the direct route, it will not go go like this one possible way could be it's going to
go like this from zero.
Well, this particular year, this is the shortest.
OK.
It will not do something like this, that it first goes to the Note eight and then it comes back, OK?
This is not how you're going to maximize the but.
You're going to take the shortest route.
But the distance might be maximized if you choose a different note.
Zero traveled from this node to maybe just note in that case, it is possible that it covers more distance
because this is how you need to maximize the total distance.
And I hope you also understood what is the meaning of shortest possible.
But so let us discuss the rest of the statement and they want to maximize the total distance travelled.
The travel distance is a distance between the city and distance traveled to.
All right.
And we have already seen, given the highways information, it is your job to find out the maximum total
travel distance of all people that it would need to find out.
And then what?
We are given the number of best guesses.
OK.
East-West Good contains two integers and the number of it is followed by PN minus one lines, which
denote the city ex the city by.
And the land of diving.
So these are basically nodes and edges.
OK.
And here we are given how many sorties we have in this particular test case, and this is a number of
excuses.
Alright, so let us look at the input example one, so in the input example and what we have, we have
four cities.
Let's call them as 81, 82, 83 and 84.
If you look carefully now from one to two, there is an edge that contains a distance of what.
It contains a distance the.
So this edge is of distance.
Three, then there is also an edge between.
The note to entry this is Outdistance two.
There is alternate between three and four, which is also of distance.
So this is two, this is two, and now we need to see what is the maximum possible distance that all
the travels can travel.
So one way is if we just exchange these two, if I exchange one and two.
OK, the person one goes here, the person to go, is it the person three?
Was it the person forgoes it?
In this case, the total distance traveled would be three blustery or one and less two plus two.
That is how much the entry is X and four.
This is 10 units, OK?
But the answer is 18, because this is not the best way of arranging.
No, this is not the way that will maximize the total travel look.
So let us look at another way.
So, yeah, this is this is three, this is two, and this is to another, if would be, let us exchange
one word for.
And let us exchange two with three, that means this person comes here and this person comes here.
This person comes here and this person goes it.
So what would be the total distance traveled by person?
One, It would be three plus two plus two.
And similar distance traveled by Ford, so we can do twice of it between two and three.
We will travel distance two and three will also travel distance.
So this is for this is how much.
This is 14.
So 14 plus foot is what this is.
18.
So you're going to in this case, the answer is 18.
OK?
Another possible way could we exchange one with three?
OK, one comes to today's location and two it goes to four locations.
In this case, the total distance I will be right off, one goes to three.
So it is three plus two.
It is five.
There it is.
It goes to four, which is like this twice our foot.
This is also fine.
This distance is also 10 plus eight.
So one of so there can be multiple possible combinations which are leading to the same output.
But we are interested in the final output.
Instead of finding out the combination, we need to find out.
The final output.
OK, so now let us see how we can approach this particular problem.
OK, so let's discuss and approach that will help us to solve this particular question, OK?
So one one thing is clear the value of A. Large OK, we cannot find out all possible permutations of
nodes and then try to find out their distance.
OK?
The graph may be complex graph.
OK, we don't know.
OK, so now.
One thing we know is not the total distance, OK, the total distance.
Travel would be nothing, but it would be let's see if the edges are like this, if the edges are.
If the do that, even if the entity E4 and so on.
OK, then the total distance would be nothing but.
Some constraints even and when times even plus and two times you do less and three times E3 and so on.
OK.
So total distance would be nothing, but it would be weighted sum of.
They did some of it is.
This everyone agrees, and what we need to figure out is we already know the Atlantic, we know even
if that as given in the input.
What we don't know is how many times each edge would be used.
OK, we need to find out what are the values of and one and two and three.
And these values should be such that they follow the consensus and they should be able to maximize these
in one and two and three should be equal to the maximum number of people.
That will travel.
Through the adage that will travel through that edge, if we are able to find out what is the maximum
number of people that will travel through that edge, we can easily find evidence.
By taking this, we did so OK.
The question is how do we find out how many people are going to travel through a particular age?
OK?
Now let me try to figure this thing out.
How we're going to do it?
Let us talk about a particular edge to this edges eatery.
I want to find out what should be the value of entry.
That means how many people will actually travel through this edge.
OK, and we want to maximize that.
So this edge breaks over graph or the three into two parts.
So one part is clearly visible.
OK.
The one part of this one?
Let me just Margaret Green.
So this is one part of the graph.
OK.
Let me read this part one and let me read it as part two.
Let me know.
That's part.
Now, if you look carefully, what is going to happen, how many what do you think, how many people
will travel through this particular age?
How many people will travel through this particular age effectively?
We have five percent in this part a b, c d e f.
So we have six percent here, OK?
We have six persons in this graph in this part, and we have three persons in this part.
OK, maybe some JJ.
Now, what is going to happen?
OK, so I want maximum people should travel, so if I want to maximize the use of this edge, I would
be sending maximum people from part one to part two.
And I will be sending maximum people from part to part one.
OK, if I want to maximize the use of every age to now, one thing is very clear that if I try to send
all six people back to work again, I send six people to buy two from part one.
The answer is no, because part two has only three transit is available.
OK, there are only three rooms or transit is available there that can accommodate at most it even.
OK.
So I cannot send six people in part two.
I cannot send four people in part two, but I can send three people in part.
OK, that means.
And similarly, since three people are coming here, I can send three people from here as well.
OK.
So what is the number of people that would be traveling through this particular age?
Some I think that would be nothing but a minimum of.
I sense in part one, OK?
And part two and twice of it drives off it.
It is nothing but the window minimum of this is what this is six.
This is three and this is nothing but two into three.
Effectively, in the best case or in the maximum case, there would be six people who would be using
this edge to travel from one part of the graph to another part.
If you do this thing for all ages, then you will get these coefficients.
And you can easily find out the way it did.
OK.
So if this very dense led to forward, then this edge would be contributing six in 2004, that is 24
in Dover, and we will add 24 to your answer.
OK.
So I hope this part is it and that this this is what where we have used the the general principle.
OK, so effectively on the right, we have three holes, but we have six regions, so only three parents
can travel to these three holes.
OK, and three three three regions from here will travel to these three holds, OK.
So it does not matter where they are traveling to.
The only thing that matters is how many times they would be using this edge, OK, how many times this
edge is being used?
And we will do it for all ages, and this will effectively help us find out the total.
And I will call this approach as a greedy approach.
We are kind of finding the local maxima.
OK.
And so we are finding multiple local maximums and adding the answer for all that is OK.
So if you want me to drive around on the give an example, we can do it.
So let's say this is a this is B, this is C and this is D, OK now, along with this dry run, I would
be discussing the implementation aspect as well, or we can implement it.
OK.
So one way is you break the graph around every page and then you say, OK, I will.
I will do what the DFS on this part.
OK, so if you do all the affairs on this bond and you do whatever's on this, but it's you get the
size of the first part one, the size of the second part is three.
And then you say again, this edge lenders three.
So I will.
A minimum of one entry multiplied with two.
Multiplied with three.
OK, this is the weight of debt.
This is because twice the number of people will travel twice of the minimum and this is the minimum.
OK, so this minimize kind of coming from the general.
So we can do this.
This is going to contribute to how much it's going to contribute one into two into three.
That means six units.
OK, but what is going to happen for the other edge that we also need to figure it out?
So what we are going to do is.
So this we know that this edge will contribute six units.
So let us talk about the complexity of this approach.
So we are doing DFS that takes a lot of time and we are doing doing it for every edge, so multiplied
with it again and the E squared plus, even though it may not pass all the test cases.
So let me discuss a slightly efficient implementation of doing the office.
So what we are going to do, we are going to traverse this graph edge badge.
OK.
So let's say we start from this edge.
This is having a very of three, this is having a bit of two, this is that angry enough to bother you,
but I was this edge in Mexico alone.
And you ask me, OK, give me the size of the subsidy that is below you.
So be Bivol again of us on it.
It will make a call on see, and we will again relative as on its own.
It will run a deficit once we run the affairs on the does not have any neighbors that are not visited,
they will return or get my XYZ is one.
OK.
This had just visited so that one.
Once this, I just visited what we can do, we will start building a transit from this edge.
OK, because we are coming back.
Now what we know is we have a node CE and it has a charity D, so details its parent.
OK.
I have only one person inside this entire sub.
That means.
How many nodes you have in the rest of the tree?
How many nodes you have in the rest of the tree, that is nothing, but if one not, is it?
The rest of the tree will have n minus one.
And what is the minimum of these two?
That is nothing but one.
OK, so a minimum of one.
And or minus one that is three into two into the weight of this edge.
That is how much this this, this adds, is going to contribute four units to the answer.
OK?
All right now from see, we're going to go back and we are saying what you see is also one note the
sea is going to tell its parent that I actually have two nodes here, OK?
And if you have two nodes in this sub, the remaining the three, the remaining sub three is also going
to have.
It just lost a leg on.
So we just lost their diagram, so.
Let us let us recap what we were doing, so we said we will try to break between this edge, so we will
figure out how many people will travel travel through this edge, so it would be a minimum off.
On the left side, there is one person on the right side that are three percent rise of it multiplied
with the weight of it, it would be two into one into three.
That is six.
We said we will try to break it for this edge.
OK.
Then there are two persons in this part.
There are two wasn't in this, but it would be twice into a minimum of two into two multiplied with
the attachment that is two.
So it would be two in two to four into two eight eight units.
And if we try to break this edge, so there is one one one or two and there are three nodes, it it
would be the window minimum of one entry multiplied with what?
So it would be again at 3:40.
So this is 12+ +6, that is 18.
So you can divide still getting the right answer.
18.
But now the question is how you can do the DFS that we were discussing effectively what happened in
the offices?
Let me just pick a different marker.
So what happened is a miracle on me.
OK, we made a call on C, C Miracle on D, and it does not have any better details.
See, OK, I am.
I am a single note, so we get to know one of the values is one, OK?
From this note, we get to know if you're talking about this edge.
Then what happens?
So this child basically returns of illusion because it is returning the size of this entry.
It becomes one, followed by n minus one.
So n minus one is and is what for four, minus one is three.
So we get to know this value and we multiplied with two.
And we also know the advert is two.
So we get to know this answer that is four.
So I'd see this.
Is this a three?
And he says, OK, whatever is the size of the child three, I will add one to it.
I will return to my parent.
So she returns to to the parent.
It becomes to a minimum of two and minus two.
OK, what is the size of this?
So that is an adequate and minus two.
That is two multiplied with the agent.
That is two.
So it becomes too intolerant to do that, is it?
So we effectively get the answer for this rule.
The night three, we get to know the size of the subsidy is what it does to we are one do it.
It becomes doing to a minimum of three comma and minus three.
That is one into three.
This ad is now three.
So it becomes went to 3.6.
So we again get this one and we say, OK, this sum is what this sum is nothing but 18.
So effectively what we are doing is we are doing our depth first search and from every child node,
we are returning the size of the Sabry.
OK.
So both you have a complex tree like this in this case, if you make a call, if you make a call.
Here.
OK, if you make a call here, it will automatically make a call here, head hit and this so will return
as a tree to its spirit.
OK.
And we want to see how many times this edge is being used.
We'll find out the minimum of three and how many nodes are there in the other part of the tree.
That is nothing but n minus three.
OK?
We are not using the first to find out that bad because we know the total nodes.
If Tree are in one part, the other part is going to contain and minus three and we are taking this
minimum because.
We cannot fit a larger number of people into a small, smaller number of cities.
OK, so that's why we are taking minimum and that's nothing but an obligation of business.
OK, so I hope now you understood.
So what we have to do is we have just do the office in a single pass.
And while doing the office, you have to keep track of.
These values and this will take overall complexity of order off.
We see that as linear anything.
OK, so that's all for this lecture and thank you.