So let us discuss the implementation of the Holiday accommodation problem and we will write the code for the
same.
So first of all, we'll write the code for main. So in the problem.,
we have multiple test cases so we have to take input how many task cases we have.
And for each test case we need to input the total number of nodes and the list of edges. OK.
So there is an edge from u to v with the weight w and we need to create a graph.
OK, so for Graph will create a adjacency list and it is a weighted graph
so i will need a pair to
store it.to store each...
So let's tell you what we are doing.
I need Vector and I also need that's it.
OK, I need a vector.
Now what we are doing is, we are taking input an edge.
OK, there is an edge from u to v who's wait is w. we are storing it in the form of a,
So this is nothing but an array of vector.  OK?
It's an array of vector.
So we have
each element of the array which is a vector. ok. So if I say this is node
u. u is one.
So then it is connected with let's say, node v. It is connected with node v2.
It is connected with node v3. that store the neighbors here that v1 has weight w1
v2 has weight w3.
v3 has
weight w3.
That's why I need a vector of pair and this v have as an array of
size 10 power five
because that's the constraint given the problem. ok So if you see here N is of the order 10 power five.
That's why we need to create this vector. OK?
And so what we are going to do? we are going to say. OK/ let's say we are on the first test case.
So while this testcase is less than equal to total test cases. I can say TC equals to TC+1.
So here we are going to do the work for each test case.
So We will take input the number of nodes for that graph.
And for every test case, we need to reset the adjacency list that we are creating so we can say for
int i equal to one, I less than equal to N, I++.
I can say adjacency of I.clear.
So why I am doing from one not from zero because the numbering of the nodes in the problem, this
numbering is one based.
It is not zero based.
OK.
So that's why we're just not using the zeroth vector.
We are starting from the first vector.
So reset the adjacency list before every test case because the graph is different. ok Before every
test case.
All right.
So after that, we need to scan
the graph. We will take input N minus one edges.
So for int I equal to one, I less than equal N minus one.
So we'll scan a edge. we will say  cin U, V and W.
If there is a edge from U to V. we will say ok just scan it.
And in order to construct that edge in the memory, what we need is, we'll say OK.
In the adjacency list of u, we will push back pair of v and w and in the adjacency list of v
We will push back a pair of u comma w. ok that's how we push.
So adjacency list of U dot push back a pair of v common W and adjacency list of v
dot push back
u comma w. So we are done. Now what we need to do? what we need to do dfs to calculate
our answer. so I can say a long long answer that is equal to zero.
Ok. and now we need to write to the this dfs function that will work on this graph and that will compute
the answer for us.
OK.
AnN once the answer is there we can print it. Now
The way we're going to define this DFS function is it's actually not going to return as the answer,
but it is going to give us the size of the tree.
ok so this dfs
will give us the size of the tree from the node where it is called.
It is called. but we will do
two things. we will take the current node Let's say we are at u.
we  will take what is a parent node?
We will soon see why this is needed.
We will need the adjacency list so I can say a vector of pair of int.
OK.
And we need this just adjacency list array with us.
And we need the answer variable and we need the number of nodes. OK.
So here we are passing this array.
So array by default is passed by reference. ok. so we don't need to
Um yeah.
So we're passing this array and this array is passed by reference.
Okay, so what is this answer?
So this is the final answer that we need to compute.
We are accepting an answer by reference and we are going to update this answer.
OK, So maybe I can do hash define  ll as long long.
And here I can do ll answer.
That is also finally.
And this N is the total number of nodes in the tree.
So now what we are going to do? let say we, we we we are going to DFS on a tree ok. Starting
from node one.
And let's say there are so many other nodes.
let's say three four five and may be two six seven and so on.
OK, let's say there are so many nodes.
We start from this node and what we are going to do ?
We are going to say
Okay?
Let's go and traverse the entire tree.
So first, let's say we traverse this edge.
OK, so what
we are going to do? we are going to say OK. let us assume the current size of the tree
the current tree size is nothing but one and then we will iterate over all the neighbors of this
node.
So for every pair that is present in adjacency list of u. what we are going to do?
So if you look at one.
So one would have neighbors as what? it would have six and its weight, it would have three and its weight.
That it. One has only two neighbors in this case.
So what we are going to do? we going to say ok.
The node v is nothing but p dot first and the weight is nothing but p dot second. effectively in their
adjacency list
we are starting two things, W1 and W2 as well.
This is p dot first and this is p dot second.
What we are going to do? we are going to say. OK. we are going to make a call on these child nodes.
So I can say int child tree size is nothing but bfs of that node.
So that node is v, so parent of that node.
that node is nothing but the current node, which is u.
So the parent value would be u. the adjacency
list will remain as it is.
The answer will remain as it is.
The number of nodes will remain as it is. ok.
So we make a DFS call.
Now this node is going to tell ok. it will again do recursively some work and it will return okay my sizes
three.
So this child tree size would be now three.
And what we are going to do? we are we are.
We now know that this child tree size is three. so we will count the contribution of this particular edge in the
final answer.
OK?
The edge contribution
that means what is the contribution of this edge in the final answer.
So that would be nothing but two into minimum off child tree size.
What is the number of nodes in the other part of the tree?
In this part, this is nothing but N minus child three size.
OK.
Into the weight of this edge, that is nothing but Wt.
So what we can do is, we can add this to our answer. So edge answer plus this edge contribution
and another thing we need to do is, since one has already called on this part of the tree, the size
of one would increment by this value.
One plus three. now one would make a call on this part of the tree.
When, when we want to compute the contribution of this edge. OK. because we are iterating inside this
for loop. now we come to this edge
that is one comma three. for that
It will again make a call
It will say ok my age
contribution is three so it will become 1 plus 3 plus 3.
OK, but that will happen in the next iteration.
So I can say also update the tree size by adding child tree size.
So I can say current tree size plus equals child trees.
OK?
So once you have done with all the neighbors what you can return is,
you can return the current tree size.
OK.
return
current tree size. So this one will actually return seven in the main which again is not very useful
for us but what do we need is to know there is one case that that is left that we have not handled
is. now suppose you have again this kind of tree.
OK, let's see one two, three four and you come here, you come here.
And in the neighboring neighbors of two you have three and four.
OK.
In the neighbors of three, you only have one node that is two.
So at two, when you make a call on three, three will make a call on its neighbors.
So three will see  two at two as its neighbor.
OK, so what we are doing is? Since no cycle is present. OK. so we are not maintaining a visited array.
We are not maintaining a visited array.
So either you maintain a visited array to make sure you do not visit a node twice.
But in this case, what is going to happen?
When you come from two to three and you look at the neighbors of three. you say ok I will make a call to two.
So that will actually give you a segmentation fault. OK, because of kind of in infinite recursion. you're
going to three via two and you're going to two via three.
So you will you will be stuck inside a loop.
OK, so what do you need to do is, if the neighbor of a node is the parent. OK. like the neighbor of
three is is the parent two,you
don't do any work in that case. OK?
So for example, one, two three.
So from one you come to two. from two you come to three, from three you go to two. like from two you go
to one.
So u two also have the neighbor one. OK?
One also has a neighbor two. three also has a neighbor two.
and two also has a neighbor three. ok So what you need to do is,
you don't need to make a recursive bfs call on it's parent.
OK, so you can check if the value of V is equal to the parent of current node.
You will skip that node.
You will say continue.
OK.
So this will actually serve the purpose of having a visited array. we don't maintain
a visited array explicitly since the graph does not contain a cycle.
So we use a handle for cyclic case.
kind of OK, or skip the parent node. skip the parent node which is acting as a neighbor
in this case.
ok. So this will avoid the work for us.
And now what we can do is, we can say OK, let's make a DFS call and in this DFS call what we
are going to do?
We are going to pass in the parameters ok. The starting node is
one. the parent of starting node, you can put any value. let's put minus one. the adjacency list, the answer
and the value of N. OK. that's what you need to do and you need to print
the output for every test case. so I say OK. let's see cout the testcase number and the answer.
so we need to give some inputs
to test our code.
So I'll just copy the input from SPOJ.
OK.
And we should get 18 and 62 for this input.
Let's run the code.
OK, so we're getting 18 and 52.
OK.
Did we miss something?
Let us let me see.
Let me see if I missed something.
OK, so what I missed was just this last line of input. if I run my code again.
You see, we are getting the correct answer.
And I just submitted on SPOJ also, I got the correct answer there as well.
OK.
So I hope you really understood this one.
And what we have done is exactly same what we discussed in the algorithm.
ok  so what we are doing for this node.
Let's say we have this tree
one, two, three and four.
We start doing DFS
from this node. we say ok what is the tree size? two tells tells ok this size is three.
But two first make the call on three, three makes a call four
at four what we have? OK. this current tree size is one.
And what is a neighbor of four?
There is only one neighbor of four that is three.
In that case, we continue the for loop
And it does not run for any iteration. so we return current tree size that is one to avoid effectively
return to one.
So then we contribute the contribution of this edge when tree made a call on four.
OK.
So during this iteration only. so when three made the call on four.
What happened is we computed OK, this will be used two into the minimum of size that is one and other
option is four minus one that is three into the edge weight
that is two. it,
It is four.
OK, this contribution is four and three says OK.
My size is one plus my child size
that is also one so three will return two to its parent.
OK. so this contribution would be nothing but two into  minimum of two two that is two into two that
so that is nothing but 8.
So this contribution comes out to be four. So this two returns
one plus child size that is three two one.
So this edge is used how many times. so it says two into  a minimum of three and N minus three.
That is one into the weight of this edge.
That is three.
So it is used for six.
four plus eight plus six
that is the sum that we are in the answer every time and to the main we return an answer four.
But in this answer we have six that we print here.
OK, so that's answer, we are printing here.
So I hope you understood this problem.
And that's all.