Similar to the functions, structures come to help us to organize our data, but in a bit different
way. remember that we already had this very basic employee system, and each employee has a name, age, salary and
gender.
So we define 4 arrays for them.
In practice, this is hard to maintain,
Why? assume we now got a new feature for a person,
You have to add a new array for that,
Right.
So this isn't a way to like to keep incrementing things.
C++ comes with a convenient way to solve this problem.
Like what if we have more and more and more features?
Are we going to keep adding more and more and more arrays?
So the way that C++ is doing that is introducing something called struct, and something relevant
to it is called class. struct is a data type, it is something similar to data type.
Remember, we have things like integer and doubles and float and so on.
We call them primitive data types.
These are data types supported by the system.
Struct is like our new data type.
So we here define it as following,
We say struct employee, you open this brace, close it.
Remember there must be a semicolon here.
Then we started to put string name, integer age, double salary, character gender. Now we are defining here
something called employee arrays.
But the data type is employee. so,
"employee" now is our new data type, but it is a user-defined data type.
So there are primitive data types like Integer and there is our defined data types.
Now notice here, there is only this struct that has our data.
so you can think of struct as a way to collect your member data, okay.
We are calling them member data or just variable anyway.
Now let's say that there is a new feature that you would like to add to the system.
The only thing that you need to come to do is just to come to this struct and add the new feature here.
So this way, we allowed the program to grow up with minimal changes,
OK. so this is the critical usage of a struct.
It helps us to gather together the relevant variables in something and we define it as a data type.
So let's see, how can we create elements, we can say element first, then =
you open braces and you give it in the order of the struct.
You can also remove this equal as a C++ style.
Once you did that, you have a new variable named first, which is of type class employee and it
has the name, age, salary, and blah blah blah.
If I would like to add it to array, we add it in a very normal way.
Just you add it here with equal first and that's it.
OK, what if I would like to print or access things, you can say here "court<<first.name", the dot "." operator
is something that's a bit new for us.
We start to use it, to access the elements of a struct.
So we say here first.name, it is just how we get the object.
What else, if we have something like employee array of added (employee_arr[added]), what is that?
This is array element of type employee.
So again, you can say .name = "hani", .age = 55. So you can initialize it with this way, or you can
later read it or print it or you can access this way.
There is an interesting thing,
In eclipse, if you click the dot, it's going to give you this list.
If it didn't give you, just press "ctrl+space", it is going to give you this list of the available variables
for this object.
Please familiarize yourself with the syntax.
If you would like to read an employee, we can have a function here, say, (read_emplyee) and then
it says the following, cin>>
employee_arr[added].name
So, again, you see this syntex, I would like you all the time to deal with that, as we have data type of type
that we define.
Then (.name) is getting something internal in this struct that we are going to use.
So, again, as simple as (.name) read it, (.age), (.gender), and so on. In a similar way, we can just iterate
on the array and just print it.
So if you would like to print it, you can say "for(int i = 0;
i < added; ++i)" so here employee e = employee_arr[i]
employee_arr[i], we are accessing the array and getting the object and then printing it.
It's important to notice that when you do this syntax, there are now two copies of the employees object.
One is the employee e and one inside the array[i].
Later We will know how to make it one, one only looking to one position in the memory,
It's very same to the reference.
If you put reference here, it's looking now at the same position in the memory.
More on that later.
OK, let's read it in a different way,
Yeah, here is the reference way anyway.
So I'm here defining a method, (read_employee) that is taking an instance of employee, but with reference.
So remember, when we take something with reference, it's looking to the memory.
So now we are reading a.name,
a.age, a.salary, a.gender,
This is updated as in the memory based on the caller.
So now, looking to the memory here.
We are doing what? employees of array of added (employee_arr[added]++)) ++ will be applied later,
So now we are adding an employee position here and then we are giving it to this function, which
is going to read the elements.
If you didn't put this reference, it is going to be by copy,
So this one will read something, but the array will not be updated. in a similar way,
If you would like to print, you print with reference e "&e",
so you are referring to the reference.
But the question here, why putting reference in printing?
We don't care if this object is actually changed, the reason behind that,
It saves time and memory; because when you put reference, you don't copy the object and you should
always favor that.
So we have here a print employees function "print_employees()", iterating on every employee, calling employee function
to be printed.
That's it for now.