Let's learn more about structures, the first very interesting thing that you can know is that there
is an ability to put a function inside the struct itself.
So in the previous video, we know that we can add the member variables so that we can access them and
we group them together for convenient usage.
Now we are also adding function inside the struct.
What is the purpose of that?
You have some functions that are very relevant to this struct, right?
So, for example, you might want to read employee or print employee,
OK.
So there is a need here if this function can be inside the struct itself so that we are grouping together
the variables and the functions.
Think of that as a way to make your life easier.
All of your code that is very relevant is just in one place.
Now there's an interesting property when the function is inside the struct, you see here
the function "read_employee" is reading directly name, age, salary and gender.
So the C++ compiler knows that you are trying to read the name of this object and the gender of this
object and so on.
OK, it's important.
I hope that you manage to figure out so far that there is a difference between the struct
employee, as like say how things would be go compared to the objects.
OK, so we call that struct employee and we call that object employee.
OK, so there is here a difference in the name.
What is a struct and what is object?
We call this is a struct, which is the way we define what is an employee.
But when we create an employee here and keep adding it, every one of them we named it object.
So this is called struct employee and this is called object employee.
And this is how things would be defined.
This is an actual example of it.
So anyway the interesting here that "read", "print", "get", "set" and such things are accessing directly the
variables inside the employee; so you don't need the dot operator when you are inside the function.
Now let's see, how can we use it, now instead of like we pass it as a parameter,
We get now the object that we have, remember, "employees_array" at some position is an object of kind employee.
we say ".read_employee",
So now we see another usage for the dot.
One time the dot was accessing a variable and another time the dot was accessing the function itself.
So this is how we again, in a printing, we just get the object and say dot "." and it's going to print.
We don't care now about the reference and such things.
So let's do some comparison between some objects, here is a "compare_name" I would like this
function to take two objects of type employee and tell me if the first is smaller than the second or not
based on the name.
So we can do that as simple as a.name < b.name.
OK, what about comparing salary?
Compare for me salary,
Such that you return true if the first has a bigger salary than the second.
So we say "compare_salary", a.salary > b.salary. OK, let's make it more complex, compare for me name and
salary.
compare first by name after that compare by salary smaller and smaller.
OK, so notice what I'm doing here, the order is very important.
I'm saying here,
OK, you want to compare first all name,
Let's check out if the name are equal or not.
If a.name != b.name then we know we can compare all names only so we are going to
return a.name <b.name.
Otherwise we are sure that they are equal.
So we go to the next feature to compare with it, a.salary < b.salary, then this function as
an overall returns
true, if the first employee has a smaller name or a smaller salary, it's very important to understand
the logic of this function.
OK, let's go deeper.
Let's say that you have array of 5 numbers and you would like to sort it or order it.
What does it mean to sort it or order it? it means to make it from the smallest to the largest.
So we have here five numbers not sorted.
If we sorted them, they became 1, 2, 3, 4, 5. in STL,
we will study something called the "sort" function, it exists in #include
If you did the following sort(array, array + 5) is going to sort this array.
OK, the syntax here is weird.
I know, you are sending the first parameter array, but in the second parameter you are sending array
+ 5.
This means that go five places in the array maximum.
OK, so five places.
If we are here at zero then the five places is at here.
Please familiarize yourself with this syntax, you say array and array +  some integer to indicate another
position in the array, you don't just fill in the 5, it must be array + 5.
Now if you familiarize yourself with that, I would like to tell you that we can also, if we have an
array of employees that we read here, we can also sort them, so sort "employees_array", "employees array"
+ added.
Let's say we added three employees so it's employee_array, employee_array + 3.
There's a question here, ordering the objects of the array based on what? like here,
if we said sort, we know that numbers can be ordered from small to largest.
But here, what about that one?
So here is you see the comma "," and we give a function name.
Remember that this function takes two objects and tells to us true if the first is more than the
second.
So this function "sort" here is going to order them based on which one is the smaller but smaller in which
order?
This depends on the function name.
So this is a bit new also because you now see a function is sent as a parameter of the function.
So the sort function here is actually taking a function, but it is expecting a function that takes
two objects, return true if the first is smaller than the second.
OK, what if I would like to order them by salary, use a salary function what if I would like to ordered them
by the name then salary you can use this function, please familiarize yourself with the syntax.
There is also another very interesting thing, we can create structures of structures of structures.
What does it mean?
Let's say that "employee" would have a full name, in a simpler way,
You can put here, OK, string first name, string second name, string  last_name and so on.
So the features of the "employee" are very in growing.
But you can think from modularity perspective, creating smaller logic.
You can define struct "full_name" and you put inside it the first, the middle, the last features,
and you can define a read function inside it to read them.
Now this is now a ready to use data type.
I can inside the "employee" say we have a "full_name" of employee name.
This means we have a new variable named Employee name and it is of data-type full_name.
But notice that employee is a struct, full_name is a struct, so we have a struct of a struct, we can have
more of struct of struct of struct.
I want to mean by that,
If you to define a new data-type, you can use it,
OK. so now let's say that we would like to read in the Employee, the first thing you can read the name
here so you can go to this object. and say "employee.name.read" this object so that this function
would be called first.
Then you read your age and salary and so on.
If you would like to print, you can print directly "emp_name.first", "emp_name.middle", "emp_name.last" , and the sallary.
So this is a way to build a better, a better structure.
Think of your program in a smaller way, smaller things, and you are building them up instead of one
very big thing.
The constructor is the last thing to explain today.
The constructor is a way to initialize the object from the beginning.
Let's say that you did.
Here is how the syntax of the constructor, the constructor is a function without a return type.
So we first put it with the same "full_name", like the same of the object name.
OK, and then it's a function.
So it has a braces here, parentheses here.
If it is empty,
We named it empty constructor.
OK, and then we are initializing our variables.
And building here, another constructor.
OK, think of it like function overriding, and I'm setting this constructor has first name, and
last name.
OK, so this is like a function
We initialize the array with it, construct with it, and we give it two parameters.
I'm now seeing here first
= _first, last = _last, a "middle" is an empty string.
OK, this is a constructor that takes two parameters.
But the second is default.
Let's see the code below,
I'm thinking, I'm defining here "full_name my_name" and then I did = full"_name
then I opened braces like a function,
and passed the name Ali, the "full_name" here is taking a parameter,
So it will search for a constructor that has matching to one parameter, which is this guy.
So it would send the first with Ali,
Last  will be nothing.
So first will be Ali, last will be empty and middle will be empty.
So if you print it here, it would print: Ali
In another case, I send it full name, his name "Mustafa" "Ibrahim",
So Mustafa will be sent it to the first and Ibrahim will be sent to the last,
You can print it here. again,
Constructor is a function in the struct, but it is a very special function,
It doesn't have a return to type,
It is called only in the creation of the object.
So here we are creating object and here we are creating object,
So only in the creation.
if you created a full name here, like my name, "full_name my_name",
and you stopped at this moment, then you are actually building an object without no parameter.
That's why its code here.
If you provide something that takes a parameter, as an advice, please always provide the empty one.
Otherwise you might face a syntax error, later in the
OOP will know the details of that.
That's it.