Today, we will learn some more details about the different types of the initializations in C++, and
specifically knowing about the C++11, the uniform initialization.
Let me first introduce the basic idea that, the initialization in C++ is just a nightmare.
There are too many types of initializations in C++ and you have to use different types of initialization
for different cases.
So there is no one unique and global initialization way to use it everywhere, before C++11.
An interesting fact is there is like at least 19 ways to initialize, to try to initialize an integer in
C++, like four or so of them are just compiler error.
You can imagine there are too many ways to initialize an integer in C++. In general,
understanding when an object is uninitialized, isn't trivial in C++, and this typically lead to many
problems.
C++ introduces the "uniform initialization", which made our life a bit simpler.
So I would like you to stop the video for five minutes.
Read slowly
these definitions, we're going to highlight some of them, but it will be useful to read the terms and
like give a thinking about them.
Here is a huge number of ways to try to initialize an integer now in C++, which is a lot.
But anyway.
Yeah.
So the uniform initialization is to use these braces this way.
What is good about uniform initialization or the motivation behind it?
It can be used in all the different contexts, before C++11, you cannot have the same technique
to initialize everything.
You have to do different techniques for different types, the word uniform
here is an indicator that it is the same for every context.
You can use it in different context and it is going to work well.
before
that
This wasn't a solution.
You can use them in a bunch of different locations,
It's going to work well most of the time.
So this makes our life simpler.
As I said before C++11,
There are different styles of initialization that you have used in the different cases.
But now you have only one way that you can apply it everywhere.
So it's going to make your life like simpler, more consistent.
Sometimes it is even a more safer choice, for example, for some very minor cases, and we'll know
about that later,
It is going to handle and do better initialization for you.
It also based on the settings of the compiler can give you warnings or even compiler errors if say, you
try to do a narrowing from a data type to another data type.
Sometimes it is the only way to solve a specific problem, like let's say you are in a template and
you would like to
initialize,
It is going to be a very big problem to be a global one, when it comes to templates we will learn about that.
It's still there are some debates about the uniform initialization.
Should we use it in every possible situation?
Should we be more careful?
What are the potential problems of it?
But overall, the uniform initialization like made our life much simpler anyway.
Let's learn more about the different types of initialization.
It's good time to know about that.
We can see these different styles through the course and it's a good time now to know about them.
And I would like you to learn something,
one philosophy for me in this course isn't just to show you the good way of doing things,
I actually intended to show you different ways to do things, including what might not be proper or
what might be not trendy now.
And the reason behind that, in C++, we can shoot ourselves in the foot.
You need to learn how to protect yourself.
What is a safer code, what is right and what is wrong.
You shouldn't just be learned the optimal or the modern way to do things.
That's why during the course I try to familiarize yourself with the different ways and eventually during
the course you get enough tips about what is really modern and what really you should do. anyway,
Going back to the primitives here, when we use the equal "=", we are doing what we call a "copy initialization".
What does this mean?
It means that this array, characters array is going to be created first, then typically copied to here.
That's why we call "copy initialization".
There is always this equal "=" here, but if there is no equal, then this is what we call "direct initialization",
which means that this guy is going to be constructed directly inside the array.
So with equal, you have a copy initialization,
Without it, you have a direct initialization.
As you can expect, the direct initialization is more efficient than the copy initialization, which isn't a big
deal if you are using primitives.
But it might be a problem if you are using heavy objects.
Now, going more here, we know that integer x0 here will be uninitialized, right?
Why ? we call it the default initialization,
When you don't initialize something, it is a default initialization.
And this is the worst thing to do, because it makes the primitives garbage, unless you have
a good reason, you should always try to initialize your variables.
So again, if you try to use the equal, you are going to make it a copy initialization.
But if you try to use the parenthesis or the braces "{}", it is going to be direct initialization.
OK, so the default initialization you aren't initializing, the copy direct initialization, you are initializing
with something.
And here's one more interesting type,
What if I did just braces empty like that?
This is called "value initialization", which is going to be for the primitives, just putting them with 0
what we call "zero initialization", now I know this is now confusing.
You are hearing now a lot of initialization things which might be very confusing.
So the copy, there is a value and you are using equal. the direct, there is a value but you don't use
an equal. if you don't initialize it,
it's a default initialization. if you try to use parenthesis or braces, but without a value, it's
called a value initialization.
Now, here is one of the old problems with C++,
If you tried here to use the parenthesis, which was working
well here and here, now, this isn't a variable, this is how we define a function, which is why before
C++ 11, there was no consistent way to initialize everything that you need.
Now, this is a function which is a problem like you suddenly get a compilation error and you don't
understand, because you shouldn't try to do value initialization using parenthesis, but you can also do it only
using braces.
Here is one more thing about the uniform initialization, when we say uniform, we refer to using
parentheses.
So this is uniform, this is uniform,
this is a uniform. Here is a "double z" and this is an "int z", if you try to define an integer from a double,
this is a narrowing, which means that you are potentially going to lose information, the window in
your compiler
And its settings compilation,
This might be a warning or be like the official language, going to be a compilation error for you.
So this is one good about the initialization.
If you try to do that with the copy initialization here with the equal, you will not get this copy.
If you didn't use the braces of the uniform initialization.
Let's see more about the objects case, this is a struct with an integer "id" and a string "name".
Notice that there's no initialization here.
So the "id" and the "name" will be default initialization.
The default initialization for primitives is garbage.
The default initialization for an object is you call its constructor and the string is a struct or a
class.
So it's going to call its default constructor, which would put the value
of "".
Now, let's see some slides, here,
are we initializing? no, then this is a default initialization, which will call implicitly the
default constructor that is here.
OK, what about "e2" of parenthesis?
Again, we fall in the same problem,
This is a function,
This isn't an object.
What about "e3" with this way?
This is a value initialization, but as there is no value, it's just zero initialization.
OK, now what if I made Employee as a temporary, temporary means that there is no name and
I use the parenthesis or braces, now it's going to work
well, why?
This is a bit tricky, but now line 19 is very different from line 15.
Line 19 isn't like a function signature.
This guy here was a function signature because this looks like a return type, but here it doesn't.
So you see the parentheses worked in one scenario, but it didn't work in another.
But the braces worked here and worked here, which is very well.
I would like to show you another interesting thing,
If you try to do something like employee e4 with parentheses way, the 10 is going to initialize
to the ID and the "Mostafa" is going to initialize the name.
But this happens only for what we call here Aggregate Class, for example.
I don't want to go into details of Aggregate Classes, there are a lot of terms that you still don't know about them,
but for simplicity for now, this class doesn't have a constructor here, so there is no constructor
at all, which make it qualified to aggregate.
If it is that simple, it is going to be an aggregate.
So this, even parentheses style is going to do this initialization.
You know here a lot of words about the initialization.
I would like to make some simple informal rules just to help you to remember, if you forgot to
initialize, this is default initialization.
If it is primitives, the value will be garbage, which is a big concern.
If it's a struct object, like the employee class, it is going to call the default constructor, which is
doing nothing.
If it is initialized with something like this guy or this guy, then if you use the equal "=", it is a
copy initialization.
If you didn't use the equal, it is a direct initialization, which is more efficient. If you try to initialize
but without some value like this style,
If it is a primitive, it will be zero initialization,
The zero value would be
put. If it is an object, it is going to be the default constructor.
So this is overall what happened here.
The primitives here are garbage.
The primitives here are zeros.
The primitives here will take the corresponding value. The objects are going to be the default constructor.
This is future reading
if you like to read.
Some tips, if you can stick to the uniform initialization, which is using the parentheses, please stick to that, it looks
like a good option. If you would like to use the normal style here with the primitives, this is still
an OK.
Some people might hate it and say, hey, use like uniform initialization everywhere.
Some of them will be OK with primitives' styles, otherwise and specifically for your user-defined types
please stick to uniform initialization.
There is a debate around that, but still good idea. Further tips, if you are using any scalar object
and you didn't initialize it,
My advice for safety, assume it is uninitialized, what happens, some coders
will think: oh, in this scenario
I'm sure that behind the scene it would be initialized, errors happens and a lot of troubles
happens. A similar advice,
If you have some struct, please use a default
member initializer, give it some value.
This is very important so that if you forgot to initialize in some constructor, the default initialization
would give a value.
Later, we will see how, there is a lecture called "defaulted
functions" lecture.
We'll see how the braces is giving us several choices
than the default initialization, and also later in templates will see how the braces come to rescue us
in some situation.
Overall, using the uniform initialization is a good style, stick to it, especially with primitives.
I am mixing in the course.
Sometimes it is a bad habit, sometimes it is for educational purposes.
But after, the course stick to the uniform initialization if you can, at least with the user-defined types
That's it.