Let's practice structures, we are going to define our own queue, it should internally have an array and support
the following operations. the word "class" means "struct".
So these are the operations that are in mind.
We would like to add_end(int value), which means we are adding 'end' to the current
array, and "add_front" of a value will add a value to the front of this array and function
"remove_front" will remove the front value from the array and return this value.
And the function "print" is printing the array.
So you can think of our struct or our class queue, as a way to add more logical relative functionalities
to the array that we would like to do.
So, for example, here is our final usage for the struct that we are calling queue, its named queue because
it's like real life.
You can think of it like the hospital when we have for example, a few people who
are in a queue.
So we are adding one by one in a queue.
We are seeing here add_end(10), add_end (20), add_end(30), and printing.
If we did, we notice the numbers are 10, 20, 30.
So internally there is an array inside the queue that have values 10, 20, 30.
And then we say add_front(1), add_front(4), and then we print it.
Now you notice here add_front(1) added 1 here then add_front(4) added 4 over here.
So it's now 4, 1, 10, 20, 30. then we said remove the front and print it and return it,
So this call to the function will return for us number 4, which here is the top and we remove
it. going in the implementation of the queue itself,
We see here that we implemented a struct queue,
We define inside it an array of 100 integers and we define the length.
We also provided an initial constructor to put this length with 0 to initialize it.
So one way you can think of the constructor always as a way to initialize objects. if we decided to add
at
end, this is as simple as what is the current length of the array length.
By the way, initially 0 means that there are no elements in the queue.
If you try to add a value, it is going to add it in [0] and then going to increment the length "len" now with
1, added another value,
It will be 1, so add it here and go to 2.
length now with 2, add another one,
it will be added in 2, and so on. If you would like to add in the front,
This is a bit tricky because the array already has three numbers for example
now. the nice idea is a shifting idea.
We can take all the elements of the array and shift them one step to the right.
OK, so this is a nice logic that I need you to trace it.
Let's say the array has for now three elements.
We start at position 2 and then we come to position three and put the value in 2 inside it, and then
go to position one and put it in 2, and then we go to position 0 and put it in 1.
So this way we shifted every value to the right.
But notice how carefully we did it.
We did it from the back to the to the beginning.
If you did it from the beginning to the end, you would override values in a wrong way.
So if we have in the array 1, 2, 3, we move the 3 to the right, then 2 to the right,
then 1 to the right.
Now the first cell in the array is empty.
So we put the value here.
If you would like to remove the front, we can use a very similar logic.
We first take the value of the front because we would like to return it here, and then we are going to
shift to left,
It means every value we take it and move to the left.
We now start from one.
OK, notice it is something that opposite to this logic, do some tracing please, you start from 1 and
then you put what in 1 in 0, and what in 2
In 1, and what in
3 in 2, and what in 4 in 3 and so on.
This way you made a shift to the left array and then you decrease the size here,
So it's ready for you. and this is just a printing function.
So, what we define now is a simple queue to handle for us logic very similar to the queue that
already we did in the hospital system already.
Let's now try to rewrite the hospital system, but let's make use of the new way of thinking and this
queue struct.
So here is the idea,
We're going to create some class or a struct,
we will name it hospital
queue, the hospital queue will be very similar to the previous queue, but it will have names,
statuses, length, specialization, and some relevant functionality, we create the hospital system of
5 queues, and also will add methods.
so the class  hospital_queue for us
now is representing for us the queue of patients that we have, and the system has 5 of these queues.
OK, so now you see here how the struct is merging things for us.
So we define here some global variables.
OK, like here the "max_specialization" 20 and the "max_queue" 5.
These are some global variables. and this is our struct hospital
queue, It has the two arrays and two variables, then in a very similar way we have here some initial
constructor to initialize them.
We have another constructor,
That specific specialization, function to add in the end, add in the front, remove from the front.
And they just have the relevant data.
For example, if you would like to add, you need a name and you need some status.
The hospital system will have 5 queues of the type "hospital_
queue" and it will have its own methods to add a patient, print patient and so on.
So you create a system, forget about line 3 now, and you just run it, which is a function that
start the system and it has this menu function. Going to the details, the hospital
queue has here two kinds of constructors, one to initialize to something very empty for now,
And one that takes specific specialization, in both cases, the length is defined to 0. The add function
just adds in the end, as we did before, we put it in the end and increment, going to the remove front,
we double check if there are patients already or not.
If there are no, we return.
Otherwise, we make the shift left track. The printing function
just iterates on the whole specialization and start to print the name and the status if urgent or regular.
the hospital system will have here a run function,
that has while true.
And also we have a function for the menu that we call it inside the hospital system.
Yeah, this is the menu function,
Just gives the user a choice by choice and asks him to make a choice out of the current system.
The adding patient, is again, is now like more logic in the hospital system, it will read the
patient details and then checking
Is this urgent or regular? if it is regular add it in the end, if it is urgent add it in the front.
OK, if we couldn't add it, this is false.
We say that we couldn't add this new patient. After that,
the printing we just iterate on the every queue of the five queues of specialization and say ".print".
the "get_next_patient" just finds the specialization and then accesses the queue of the right order and say
".remove_front".
I hope you saw
now how the hospital system
We took it one step forward with the structures to collect variables and member functions, functions
that are very relevant together, please check out the whole code to make a bigger sense of it.
That's It.