One of the interesting topics is the creation of a ray over a set of pointers, let's say that you have
here three variables, A and B and C. So now here the E with its address, B with its address.
And see with this address, one can create something like Integer Pastrick Array or three.
This is creating an array of lenzer three.
Each type of it is an integral pointer.
Now this is an integral pointer and this goes into your pointer and this goes into the router so we
can put here reference and just use it.
So if you started to put references here, you will then have this first element looking to this guy,
second element of this guy, third element looking to this guy.
So if you try to print out the addresses of ABC and try to iterate on the on the array alignments and
bring to them, you will notice that we have the address of every EBC here.
And also we have the address of the items in the array position itself.
Like this is a pointer.
It has an address here and it also looking to an address.
Let's take it modest steps forward, let's create a two array of characters, if you're trying to create
it, then probably you would have to state the number of rules or you can leave it, but you must provide
definitely the number of columns.
So let's say in our application, we expect that the maximum of the string would be, let's say 15.
Correct.
So you find something like five times 50.
Now, an interesting thing here is, first of all, this, five times 15 characters are all of them,
one consecutive block in the memory, typically Rouverol in a row order hardware's.
The second observation is you noticed all of this Noll's they are a waste of time like waste of memory
because like there are a lot of things that aren't using anything.
So one question is how to get rid of these guys before proceeding.
I would like you to remember that in C++, this goal, everything here is a contest, a character pointer.
So if you try to do something like sort of zero equal this guy.
This will be a compilation error.
The way to do that is to make a copy from here to here, and we have to guarantee that this guy of less
than 50.
Now, let's see what can happen if we have an array of pointers.
But before that, I would like to warn you in C++ and you can write something like Characteristic Is
and write something and it's going to compile.
And the reason is it is historical for backward compatibility and C language, things like that.
But the right way is to write the character pointer because this is going to say and you shouldn't try
it.
So now let's create an array of pointers.
Every pointer is looking to a string bytes so we can do something like the character pointer and then
we have here a bunch of strings.
Now the difference in the memory is as follows.
First of all, we have six different consecutive blocks in the memory.
This guy, as in one array, not just here, this is now one the.
So this is when the array is in the memory and every string of them is a separate consecutive variant.
But it could happen that all of them are consecutive, but there is no guarantee for that.
So practically speaking, we have won the array here and we have five one zero zero.
So in total we have six different when the arrays here, the size of this array is as follows.
We have five alignments, each element of the character.
So the character is like eight bite one, one bite.
So it fits.
So this is an overall like a 40 in size.
You notice here also that we can, uh, we can change the value here.
OK, so we can change the the value here of the sports, for example.
Now let's see another similar thing, if you would like to create here.
This is a normal to the array of of three times the five of of integers here.
Now, if I tried to create something to integrate with the array of three, this is a three pointer
at the moment.
Now you can iterate here and every one of these guys and create something like new enter by yourself
now in the memory.
This guy also represents some three times the five items you can now deal with, agree to exactly as
dealing with the to the array.
Normally nothing, nothing here.
But notice the difference.
This guy is one consecutive block of 15 integers, but this guy represents four different consecutive
blocks.
And if you would like to delete it, you have to delete every single element here because you created
three vectors, you remove three factors.
And this is a stack array.
So you don't have to remove that set.