One of the nice topics to learn about is a pointer to pointer, although we practically don't use it
and we should avoid a little refresh if you have some variable bar and you have a pointer referring
to this.
But we know the following.
The VA has an address and has a value here in the memory.
And we know that this pointer, it's its value is an address pointing to the VA itself and its it itself
has an address here.
So now we have here the reference of this guy, the the pointer with it looking and the valuated looking
here eventually.
Now let's go one more step with that and learn about pointer to pointer.
A pointer to pointer can help us to create a chain of pointers where we are pointer is pointing to not
a normal variable is actually pointing to a pointer to to the value itself.
So it's actually pointing to another pointer.
So now here we have the pointer one and what the new pointer is has a value of another pointer.
So address looking to an address which is looking to an address to a value here.
Let's see more about that here.
If we try to define it as following, this is how you define a pointer to which you say pointer to pointer
or two, and it should now reference a pointer, something that is a three pointer.
So it's now referencing reference pointer one.
If you would like to go Werris Pointer to Pointer to pointer, it should reference something of type
pointer pointer like this.
Let's call it as the symbol here as as the pointer is reference something that should be Astrachan three
pointer.
Now let's see the memory of the guys here.
We have here the original reference of Devar and it's a value which is this guy and the value of ten.
And we have this normal guy also, which has its own address and looking to an address.
And there is a value.
So we have its own address and value and looking to our address here of the bar and the value.
Now let's see the pointer to it has its own new address and it is looking to an address which is looking
to an address which is looking to add value, have a value going to pointer three.
We have its own address, which is looking to pointer, which is looking to Pointer Pointer and another
value.
As you see, we have a chain of pointers in each point that has an address.
It could be an address of eventually a variable here or a pointer to another.
Another pointer blue.
Please make sure you understand how this printing's corresponding to this table.
Let's see how this can help us to create a 2D dynamic array in the memory I have here, a function that's
going to create for us as requested.
In the previous video, we learned how to create an array of pointers.
So the array itself was static.
And every every pointer, every pointer was dynamic.
Now making all of it dynamic.
So first of all, I'm saying that we have a pointer pointer B, which is something that's going to be
2D.
And then it's going to be rogue elements, let's say five, for example, every one of them is intriguer
pointer by itself.
So an point-to-point, they're looking to something that would be eventually five intriguer pointer
itself.
Now, once you define that, it's now more like the array of pointers that you had you iterate through
Birute and defining each one of them to be another array of type.
Entier of, of course.
Now you can deal with it as a normal array.
I would like you to check is this visualization to make it a bit easier.
I know that this isn't easy to to get from the beginning.
We have here the integral pointer pointer B.
And this guy is going to create here in line six and an rate of densify, one, two, three, four,
five, which is itself of type integral pointer.
So every element here will be another pointer.
And then we iterate over every rule of this five and create for every one of them.
That is going to be a new integer of of columns, which here nine.
So we are going to create nine elements.
So now we're looking about I would like you to make sure that you can see how these values are printing.
Here we have address of this integral pointer pointer B, which is referred to be and I am looking to
the first array here.
So it has the address of Pete and every one of them is looking, every cell of them is looking into
another array, which has an extra bepaid here.
If you would like to delete, you have to do to delete to avoid a.
You have to iterate over it, delete every rule from this guy's everyday Remgro, then delete the whole
array.
Take your time.
It's always bustling.
The best way to deal with it is drawing and thinking about drawing.
And yeah, that's it.
In practice, pointer to pointer is very style, so we really need it unless we are dealing, say,
with some CBIS or we are unlucky guys to work with some legacy code legacy mean very old.
Good.
Remember when we started the the best arguments to the program, we see something like character Point-to-point
Aragvi or character pointer and most of them are OK.
So this is where where you have to see Pointer Pointer.
Also when you study some some scenarios and what we call Lincolnesque in a structured course, it might
involve extra gastrique.
It's good to know about it, but we don't use in practice.
And this is some future reading that said.