One of the interesting topics is the white pointer that you should know about, but you should then
use also the white pointer is a pointer that can point to objects of any data type.
So so far, we were declaring something like a pointer to declare a pointer of type integer of type
Embley.
But now we are creating a void pointer void means nothing or nothing to be used so it can go into anything
and we can change what is pointing to in dynamics.
So let's say we have an X and Y and now the pointer can reference X here.
So now the pointer is at this moment is looking to the X itself.
You cannot use the pointer directly if you would like to use it.
Therefore, you need to cast it back to, say, a specific type and use it.
I'm guessing here with the system casting to indicate.
Now, I changed it here to y to reference Y, which is of type double and I to use it again, you have
to cast it back.
I'm using here the C++ static cast aside and you call function and you can use it as you see it is flexible
but also it is a bit dangerous.
Like you need to be very careful about what kind of type it's looking to.
It's very cystine.
You typically don't need it, but it's good to know about its existence.
Typically with the mix of overloading and template, you'd need at all to use a white pointer.
That's it.