One of the interesting topics in C++ is also the function Quinter specifically C, let's say that we
have to function like add year in print and C++.
We can declare and define something that is actually a pointer to function address.
So we define it as following the look to the syntax.
Let's say I would like to find a pointer to this function, which means I will be I would like to have
another function, but with a different name.
I would like to Bassat, for example.
So the syntax is following is a bit ugly syntax.
You would have the return type you'd normally and you would have the two parameters here normally.
But when it comes to the name, you would need to do two parenthesis, then put an asterisk and then
the new name that you would like.
So now here I'm defining a function pointer named it Be at One and it's looking to add you can also
use the reference at both of them are OK and now the bad one.
You can use it exactly as you are using that function.
So I can call B, add one, two, three, which will sum them and return five.
That's it.
Now let's create a pointer function to this guy.
We need the void here to be here, the string to be here of integrated branches.
But the S3 and the function name you can now call it.
So as you see, we managed to get the replacement to the another function here.
And this is a we should now the opportunity to passing a pointer function.
Remember, if we define some function here, comparators Seybold between A and B to compare them by
the greeter comes in first in C++.
We used to do the following.
We used to call the did begin, did it end?
And there is a function and that was interesting that we are we are not just passing integer, we are
actually basing a function which is very interesting, actually.
This is a function.
So what happened is let's do our own version here.
I'm having some function on my suit, which is taking a vector reference.
Look to the parameter here.
It is receiving a function, the function of return a table and to arguments X and Y, and it's the
name is CMB.
Now, this is some good, good selection, so you should study it later in the algorithm.
So that will do to iteration the comparison here using this function and sort which one is based on
that comparison function, the model that is we actually we're basing a function here, so we were using
it.
But as you see, the text is very ugly.
Look, let's make it less ugly with the with the modern C++.
We can do something like that using convertor.
Remember the using we talked about it before.
You can also use typedef using a competitor and we can give it the structure in this way.
Now you are giving it.
We can here drop the name and we give just the parameters in the return.
Now the important part here in the function itself, we can say convertor can be and the code as it
is.
So we just made it less ugly by taking the ugly name here and just here we are using normal name.
Now let's try to remember these things that are very relevant to the function.
The first is A function or B, remember, the function is a subclass or struct that has the function
code operator.
So it's now is defining our own function.
Corroborators.
So now we would never set up as a competitor with the warrantees.
This way you send it here, it's now the same.
Exactly.
So an interesting thing as a difference now between this comparator and the previous convertor.
This guy has a t you can define something here internally as an object or variable and use it so it
isn't just a function, it's actually like a class that can steve a state from a call to another.
Remember also the lambda.
So here is another way to play with the with this with this could.
I am defining here and Alamdar, that ticks two things, and I am missing it, but wait, what is the
receiving barometer?
The receiving barometer is of time bull pointer here.
So it is actually a function pointer, but I'm guessing no.
So here is a rule from C++ that the lambda can be converted to a function pointer, but there is only
one condition.
The computer here must be empty, the computer must be empty.
And this means we can use Lambda to be converted to function pointer interfaces, but we should be limited
to new capital.
So it is good to be more flexible with something old from Kosovo.
But also it is has a restriction.
On the other side, and we also learned about that one more thing to know about this dysfunction, which
is just to revert to anything that can be called so I can hear come again, the code didn't change and
that my competitor now is function that is returning bone and takes it to integrities here.
Now I can send lamda, I even can use here some counter as a local variable or let's say what it would
like to count how many times this function has been good.
So it has been good, 15 different number of times.
So this is very modern C++.
You are using function or you can use the comparator.
The the lambda function would be very nice to capitally for you, something very local.
So it's giving you very, very nice power here.
Overall, as I see, the function pointer is very dynamic, but something like, for example, the function
is very competitive.
The function is that we should avoid it.
There is a concern about the speed performance.
I guess some guys were saying that the functor are much faster.
I remember I told you about a scenario where the function better can reduce the memory more compared
to many other things.
The remember the function pointer has a drawback here is limited with lambda it doesn't like it doesn't
store state like the functor.
One more nice thing to know about this, he has some some function could at exit and you can best for
it to function that it would be registered, its function would be called when the whole program would
be terminated.
So here, if you bastida by message here, which say sex, we're using our program.
And then when your program first Sobrante that way.
Hey, hello.
And what's the program.
And it will, it will just call this function here.
If you try to get in the implementation, you will notice it is a state function.
So it's coming from see and also notice here, its structure is a function pointer.
That's all.