In this video, we will start to move to one more unit of advanced blocks in C++. In the previous unit,
we learned about the selections; the if-statement and if-else.
And we found how it helps us to do more complex logic. here, in the looping
We are more about to learn about how to make more sequential processing in our code.
So the word "loop" means circular, and in our context, it's a command to give the computer to keep doing a specific
task or operation more and more until we stop it.
So let's go more details.
Let's say we are processing this statement.
If 3 is less than 5, you print: "3 < 5, ONE time".
Now, what if I want to do this operation forever?
I want the program to just keep printing it here.
C++ comes with something called While-loop.
So as you see here, we changed the word statement if to the word "while".
So now let's go with the logic here to understand what is happening.
The compiler finds something,
So while condition very similar to the if, if it is true, it gets inside it.
If it isn't true, it doesn't get inside it.
But the question is where it goes next.
In the if case, if the condition is false, it just jumps outside the whole if condition to proceed after
it. in the while-loop, it comes back and keeps returning here again and again.
So here is the logic, you say the compiler while 2 < 6,
Is this true?
Yes, this is true.
So while true, it gets here, after that, it jumps again to line 6.
While true,
Yes,
Get inside, execute the body, finish at line 9, jump again in and line 6.
So what happens here is that in while-loop we start to see jumping back logic, jumping back, jumping back.
We used in C++ so far to move one line after a line, one line after a line.
This is the first time we see the program is just going back in logic.
So while-loop is very similar to the if condition, but once the body is finished it jumps back again
to the while-loop.
If you look here to the program, it says this forever.
If you look to the C++ here, you will find this red button means the program is just still running,
and the only way to stop it is just stopping it with double clicking it.
Now, let's start to use this idea to make more complex logic.
Let's say you would like to print the first five numbers, how I can use the whilee loop to make this
idea.
here is,
Here is how I'm going to do it.
I'm going to use the C++ syntax feature.
So I will start with some X number, which is 1.
And then I would like to keep going increasing 'till 5 and I stop once it is 5.
So here's what I'm going to do.
while x is less than or equal 5, print X, increment X, we call it the incremental step.
Let's trace it.
We are at line 7 while X is less than 5,
Is this true?
Yes, this is true.
1 is less than 5.
Execute this line.
So printing, execute this line,
So it's incrementing.
Now finish, go back to line 7.
Is X less than or equal 5?
Yes,
Because X is 2.
2 is less than 5, go, print, increment,  now X is 3, jump to line 7, is 3 less than 5 or equal?
Yes,
Print, increment, now X is 4, end,  jump back to line 7.
Is 4 less than or equal 5?
Yes,
Print, increment, now X is 5, finish.
Go back to line 7 is 5 is less than or equal to 5?
Yes print it, increment, now X is 6.
Now, finish, jump, is X is less than or equal 5? is 6 less than or equal 5?
No,
Now, the condition fails, now like the if-condition it just breaks it here and goes to line 12.
So the three important tracks here is what we call the "initialization step" in line 5, the condition
step in line 7, the incrementation step in line 10.
And here between these two braces of while-loop, we have whatever body very similar to the if condition.
please make sure that you are comfortable with this three steps.
In a very similar way, we can do some changes for the code and changes for the logic.
here in this program, we would like to sum, not to print, the sum from 1 to 5.
OK, so the first thing as we said, we need some initialization and incremental for the the loop.
So you can think of it as two different parts, the three lines that are for the while-loop to keep going
and your extra logic.
So here in line 5, line 8, and  line 11, the three components of a while-loop, and line 6
and line 10
This is our logic.
So line 5, and 8, and 11 here,
This one is just maintaining the while-loop.
We can say it again here,
Look at the condition.
I didn't write X less than or equal five.
I wrote X is less than 6.
This is, practically speaking, the same condition.
I'm just writing it in a different way, for the logic we need to sum from one to 5.
So we need to maintain some variable for the sum.
And then we keep here with every variable X from 1 to 5.
We just say sum += 1, sum += 2,  sum += 3, 4, 5.
So we end up here with sum 15.
So again, this code has two parts, one part for the three lines, for the while loop.
And the another part is for our logic.
Let's do the reverse.
Let's sum from 5 to 1.
It's going to give the same answer but would like to do it in the reverse. in a very similar way,
If I would like to proceed from up to low.
You can think of it as I would like to start with 5.
I would like to make sure that the number is still not zero.
I would like to decrease the X with one step.
So here X starts with 5, then 4, 3, 2, 1, 0.
The condition is still valid, then it's minus one; so the condition is broken.
And for our body logic, we have initially "sum" with 0.
Then we are adding sum += X.
One interesting property in the while-loops, is what we call breaking.
So, check out here what I'm writing, I'm saying while true now saying that "while (true)" means that this
code actually can go forever.
So forget about what is in line 8 to line 15.
While true here just means keep going forever,
Keep going forever. now I'm making more logic,
So here is my program,
I would like to say this is a program to do division.
And I'm saying here our logic is if the second number is zero, we are going to print: "Bye" and end
the program.
OK, so there is nothing specific to stop
The while-loop here, I would like to keep going forever, as long as the second number isn't zero.
So we will "while (true)" forever, then we read two numbers,
If the second number is zero, we say Y is zero and here we say break.
What does "break" mean?
"break" means end this while loop right now and go after it.
So once we say break here we jump to line 17.
So again, what does a break do?
The break jumps completely outside our current while-loop.
OK, so this is what the break does for us.
So here are two interesting things.
The "while (true)" is an infinite loop, and the break is going out of the statement. Infinite means to
just going forever.
The other case is something called "continue", so the "continue" tells the compiler to jump to
the start of the loop.
So let's say if here in our logic we say if the number turned out to be zero, the Y, then tell
him that this is zero and start again from scratch to ask for input.
So when we see the continue, it jumps to line 7.
So now what is the difference between "continue" and "break"?
Continue, it is just continuing the looping so it jumps to line 7, verifies one more time and gets inside.
break in the while, and go outside it.
So one of them goes to the start of the while, one of them goes after the while.
That's it.
Please make sure that you are comfortable with today's content before the next session.