Let's solve the third homework, the first one is about the find NOs, it isn't a hard one.
All what you need is to figure out that there are eight different ways to make two letters in both cases
lower and upper. For example, it can be
no, No, nO, NO.
But we are considering the four cases for the "no" here and in the other side there is on, oN, On, ON in the
four different cases. They are four, because mathematically you have only two choices and every choice
has two cases.
So overall, like four possible cases. In the future, you will learn much easier ways to that problem.
For example, in the future, you can sort this string input and then make all of it lower then all
what you need to do is just comparing, for example, with one of them only.
But for now, given the current tools, you cannot do that. During the course, you will learn that the
the more programming concepts that you learn, the more different ways that you can do
your tasks in an easier way.
In the second problem, we would like to reverse a number. At this moment, this task should be easy for
you.
We developed several ones in the previous sections.
To do that, we need mainly the %10 and divide by 10 trick.
Remember that %10 gets you the last digit and division by 10 removes for you the last digit.
Now, the only remaining part here, if I have a number like let's say I have numbers like
maybe five, six, seven, how to construct five, six, seven
numbers from them. By doing multiplication and addition of ten, how? let's say we have five, multiply
five by ten.
It is now 50, add the next digit with six, it is now 56.
and multiplied by ten.
It's five hundred and sixty, add the next digit which is seven.
So mathematically all what we need is a series of multiplication times N and addition of a single digit.
That's how we can reverse a number to get a complete new number.
We are reversing it because we are getting it digit by digit from the end of it.
And this is how you construct a number from a group of digits.
And this is finally the number, a number of three, the purpose of number of three is to make sure that
you actually did it right.
Yeah, let's stop here.