To solve the multiplication table, you should get a sense of nested loops here, you have for every item
in this column one, then for every item in column two, whenever you have this is for every and for
every, then you are dealing mainly with something that is nested. To do that,
Here, we are going to make something that iterate over every row then something
that iterate over every column.
So we have here count_n and we have count_m, the count_n start here with one and for every count_n
we start a count_m with one and we keep doing the two numbers then for every loop, we print it.
So the moral of that is to get the sense of when we should use nested loops
like that.
In the last one here, the special sum, which is an example of three nested loops, we need one nested
loop to do the number of the cases and then another nested loop to read the n integers.
But in every case, you need to loop also to do this kind of repetition.
Yeah.
Let's see how to implement that.
Three nested loops,
Test case, reading numbers, and the repetition to K times.
Here we iterate over the number of the cases, then we start to iterate over the number of n to read
the n values.
And we have here a sum variable to sum all of the itemsfor us.
And it's very important here.
This is the third loop.
Now, in every step, we iterate K times.
So the current depth first would be one, then two and three and four.
If, for example, it is four, then we will loop four times and keep repeating multiplying the value
four times, which is computing the power of the number, once we are done with the result of the current
step, we just add it to the total sum and so on.
So this is, again, another example of how to get the sense of multiple loops.