In the previous videos, we learned about the while-loops and how they make us make more iterations.
the for loops is the same concept
Exactly, just using a different syntax.
So we are mainly learning how to make the same task using a more convenient syntax.
The for-loop goes as following,
But remember, first, the while loop,
We had something to do, the initialization,
We have a condition, we have a body code, and then we have an incrementing step. in the for-loop,
We are going to rearrange them using the word "for" here.
You open parenthesis, close it.
there are two semicolons here.
The initialization line goes here, the condition line goes here, the step line goes
here,
Then the code. as you see, it is more of an elegant way to organize the code.
So, instead of having initialization, condition, and step, separated in this way on three lines,
we now make all of them on the same line of code.
Then here we put your whole body code.
That's why typically guys are using for loops because it has a better organization for the code.
It's important to notice that the step here is in the last column, but it has a specific order in being
applied. let's see, a while-loop here.
This is how we write a while loop to sum the numbers from 1 to 5.
This is the corresponding one to write the code in the for-loop.
So, here we have line 5 for initialization, integer x = 1.
We here initialize integer x = 1.
We have the condition here in line number 8.
We have the condition here
number 7, we have the increment here ++ X, we have it here, and then we have the body.
If you look to it, it is more shorter and more convenient.
So we put the initialization, condition, step in the line code.
It is important to notice that the tracing is the same as while-loop.
It could be a bit tricky when you look at it.
So here is how the the code goes.
The for loop finds here the initialization, then goes to the condition, then directly goes to the body.
This is the trick.
It isn't like you go to initialization, body, step.
No, it's the same logic as the while-loop.
So it is initialization,
then condition, then body, then step, and then go to condition, body, step, condition, body, step,
condition, body, step.
The same flow as the while-loop
Exactly.
So don't make it like any condition, step.
No,
it is condition, body, step.
Notice this style.
What if we would like to do nested loops
Using for loops? it is the same exact logic.
Let's say that we are reading T test cases, for every
test case, we are printing the sum from 1 to N. So now we need one for-loop to iterate
over 1 to N for the test cases, and another for-loop for the submission.
This is how you can do it.
You are here reading the number of test cases, then you are iterating from t = 0, till t < T.
So the logic goes this way for the number of test cases. inside
the test case,
You are reading a number, then you are making a for loop to iterate from number one to number N
doing this body logic, and doing this
step. this way, you transfer from while-loops to the for-loops. please make sure that you are comfortable
with that before proceeding more.
We can have some body, empty parts in the for-loops, for example.
If you removed the initialization part, and you remove the increment part, it's actually
now become exactly the while-loop.
So the for is just "while" here without initialization and without any step.
So it's just very empty.
Another funny case, if you removed all the three items, this is now the same as while
true.
So as you see, we can easily switch the for loops to make it more look like a while-loop.
There are some common mistakes when it comes to the for-loops.
The first, if you are doing something like "for (Int i = 0; i < 10)".
This loop is iterating 10 times with index from 0 to 9.
The second common mistake, and it's a killer one, if you put a semicolon here by mistake, then the
body of the for-loop is just this semicolon.
And then you are assuming that this line is going to be printed ten times, but it's just
printed one time.
What's wrong?
The wrong Is this semicolon. The third
common mistake is we have here our ++i step, for some reason the guy did i++ inside it.
One very common mistake
you forget about that
You have it here or something like that.
So make sure that you don't play with your step or do it in a careful way.
That's it.