Let's practice on for-loops, the practice on for-loops isn't different in any way from practicing
on while-loops.
It's more of a different structures.
The special sum Program is a program from the latest homework on the while-loops.
So let's see how this homework can be written in terms of a for-loop.
We need one for-loop,
We need to iterate on three things here.
We need to iterate on the number of test cases.
So I'm here doing it for convenient as while-loop.
So I'm reading here the T and saying "while(T--)", so the body here is just anyway we are going
to read T, so while (T--) would be enough to do the condition and to do the subtraction, and this is
one of the nice cases for the postfix
Operator, if you look to it, you see here, let's say that T is 5.
So you say while T--, we know the value of the T, is going to be evaluated first,
then later the --.
So while 5, is 5 true?
Yes, five true
and then 5, 4, 3, 2, 1, when T is 0,
The while-loop is going to be broken and T here will end up with -1.
So this is the first while-loop, you can think of it here a while
(T--)
This is a shortcut for while (T-- Not equal 0).
And if this is hard code for you, you could just say "while" and put here T--.
But just for convenient we do it this way.
The second loop that we need is a loop that is going to read the N values.
So we are going here to read N, and then we are going to do a for-Loop to read N number values,
OK. so this is a classical way to do the for loop, i = 0;
i < N; ++i, then we read the value.
The third nested loop is that we need to iterate up to i times to multiply the value.
So let's say i is 0 then we need to iterate for one step.
that's way we have here the + 1.
If i is 5, we need to iterate here 5 + 1,
OK. if you put here less than and equal "<=" you can just remove the + 1.
So this inner loop is just iterating for us
(i + 1) times here and then, then we have the sum.
So this way we ended the code.
As you notice here, these two for-loops made the code look much more elegant than we were
doing using while-loops.
Let's go more, we are to read 3 numbers, N and M and sum, we would like to find all the pair of numbers
such that A + B == to the sum value, A is a number ranging between 1 to N and B is a
number ranging between 1 to M. So we would like to find all the pairs of numbers
That satisfy this condition. try to stop the video, write it, challenge yourself, and try also the following
inputs and think about how many number of steps can your code do.
This is the program, if you would like to find all the pairs of them, then we need one loop to iterate
on N and one loop to iterate on M.
And given that we are targeting 1 to N,
So I made here the condition to start from 1 end to N, start from 1 end to M. and then I'm
telling here,
If i + j == sum, then we satisfied the condition, let's count it, this loop, this way we are
actually iterating on every pair of number.
So if I told you to find all pairs, we are expected to do 2 for-loops nested.
If I told you to find all triples, you are expected to do three loops, before proceeding more,
It's very important to understand this code.
Let's now, make this code a bit faster.
This is a very simple math trick, that we can actually remove the whole second loop.
If you noticed, the previous code was very very very slow
code.
If you enter something like one million, it's going to do one million times one million operations.
And this way we're going to do simple math to remove the second loop.
The observation was as following: the previous loop, the nested loop, was actually activated only once
in the whole loop, only once.
So it's actually like we are iterating M times for only one value to be right.
So we just get it by math here.
So now we know if we are reading i, and the condition was that i + j == sum, this means that
j = sum - i
So we are here to compute
The "j = sum - i" and then we are verifying that j is really between the 1 to M range.
If this is true, then we count (cnt++), this is how we switch the code to one loop only.
What's very important here is that if you thought about this code, it just likes one million step times
some simple fact like say here, three million steps.
But if you compare the other code, it's actually 3 * 10¹² steps.
And now this takes you to a very new thing that we call it efficiency, and efficient
code is something that's much faster than a slow code.
The difference between a good programmer and a weak programmer is that a good programmer can write much
faster code and can figure out what is wrong with the code.
So here with a simple math trick,
We managed to make the code much, much faster.
Let's move to another case.
I'm telling you that we would like to find all triples with the following conditions of N, M, and W.
So an A is between 1 and M, B is between A and M, notice here, C between 1 and W, and we would
like to find all triples such that it is A + B <= C, again writing that is
just need triple loops, so one loop iterating from 1 to N, the second loop iterating from i to M.
The third loop is iterating from 1 to W, and then we are making our condition,
If i + j is <= K then this is a valid condition. in a very similar way,
If you understood this code, you can remove the nested loop here, the third loop here to make it a
bit faster
code.
I would like you to give a good trial to think how to remove this code in a very similar way to the
previous one.
The trick is as following,
If we would like to remove the inner loop, we just have a problem, it isn't like the
last time when we say i + j == k, it's this time i + j <= K.
But we are again using some very simple math.
We can do this a very similar trick, we know that in i+ j == k,
The condition was satisfied one time, but i + j <= k
The condition would be satisfied starting
The condition would be satisfied starting from 1 up to..., the K here would be valid,
This is the last code,
The K would be valid as long as the K itself is greater than i + j,
OK. so look from the other perspective.
So thinking about that, this means if the K was 4 and the W was 7, this means that all the
Ks from 4 to 7 are valid for us,
OK. so now this is more like a valid range.
So here it goes like a valid number,
here is a valid range, the range starting from K = 4 to K = 7.
So how many numbers in this range?
W - k + 1, please,
verify it, try to think about it relative to these numbers.
So the way that we are going to solve it, we're going to compute K, which is the first valid number.
If this number is valid, we just are adding here W - K + 1, that's it.
So this way we remove a complete loop.
Fibonacci, Fibonacci is a very, very math popular sequence.
The word sequence means that sum of numbers. in this sequence, every number is the sum of the last two
numbers.
So here is the sequence, 0, 1, 1, 2, 3, 5, 8,
and so on. look at 13, for example.
13 is just the summation of 5 and 8, look on 34, it is the sum of 30 and
21.
So every number is the sum of the previous two numbers.
Write
a code
That can generate for us the Fibonacci sequence.
Let's see, we can do it as following, we can start with a = 0 and b = 1 and then print
them.
Now here, what I'm doing here,  the three lines of code here are doing the logic to keep going
forward.
We take the c to be equal to a + b and then we move the b in a and we put the summation b in
c. for twice in this course,
You saw already these three lines of code doing the Fibonacci printing, but you weren't aware exactly
what is happening. here,
Here, we are doing an iterating to print the first n Fibonacci numbers.
We printed the first two already and in these two we are generating the remaining of them, please take
a paper and pen and start to simulate that to double-check that you are generating really this sequence.
the moral of it is c is the answer of the last two numbers and then you are making a single
shift step.
Here is another way for coding it.
It's a bit more ugly.
But the point is I'm teaching you something about the initialization. in for-loop here,
If you looked, this is the initialization part, look how big it, initializing a to 0, b to 1, C
to - 1, count "cnt" = 0.
So I did four initializations. In the increment step,
I also did several steps,
I incremented the count, I put c with a + b, a = b, b = c, OK, and remember the comma operator
is just left-to-right evaluation.
So here we are just iterating it.
The point of this way is just I'm telling you that you can initialize a lot here and you can increment a lot
here.
Your turn,
I would like you first to try to get all or most of the homework using the while-loop and rewrite it using the
for-loops.
This would make it more comfortable for you.
That's it.