Let's do more homework on looping also because it's a very critical topic. the first homework is you
are to print an X as following.
So you are reading an N, which would be always odd, and you are to print something like that,
And then another thing like that. find a special pair, you are
to count how many numbers X and Y such that X in the following range and Y, also in the given
range.
And you are to make sure that X < Y and X + Y is divisible by 7.
More harder, you are to count all quadruples, the word quadruples refers to something that is 4.
So you would like to count all 4 numbers with the following conditions,
All of them are < 200,
And a + b == c + d.
You can easily code
It with 4 loops, but try to code it using 3 loops and in the future, you will learn something in data
structures,
called hash tables.
You can do it with two loops only in the far future.
Is Prime, you are to read an integer N, which is < 500 and Print YES; if it's a prime
number, otherwise no.
So remember, a prime number is a number that is greater than 1 and can't be formed by multiplying
2 smaller numbers.
For example, it cannot be divisible with something that is smaller than it, except 1.
So the first few numbers are 2, 3, 5, 7, 11, and so on
So if I give you 13, this is yes, a prime number.
If I give you 12,
This isn't a prime number because 12 is divisible by 2 and divisible by 6, which are like less
than it.
Print primes is a similar one,
You're just going now to print the primes, so if I give you 18 year to print all the prime numbers
that are < 18, when you are printing,  make sure please that there is no comma printed after the last
number, you are to print them comma separated,
No comma after the last number.
Digits sum in range, you are going to read 3 numbers N, A, and B, you are to print the summation
of the numbers between 1 and N,
Whose sum of digits is between A and B. Let's give an example,
Let's say that you read 20 and the sum of digits that we are targeting should be between 2 and
5.
So now here, the numbers whose sum of digits are between 2 and 5 and this from 1 to
20 would be 2, 3, 4, 5, 11 and so on.
For example, let's say that you took number like 13.
The sum of digits is just 4, which is between 2 and 5.
20, the sum of digits is just 2, which is between 2 and 5, and so on.
So you are actually iterating from 1 to N verifying that the sum of digits is just between the A and
B.
That's it.