Let's solve the for loops homework. In the first one, we need to print the X mark here and this
this assignment has, like, a memory with me because I thought about leaving programming and computer
science because some bunch of exercises.
This one was one of them, like, I failed when I was very young to recognize the relationship.
That would help me to figure out this X line.
I'm saying that because I hope if, like, during solving more and more, you don't get disappointed.
When we were that young, we also faced
a lot of difficulties to get things done.
Anyway, I think you should be able to figure out this one easily.
And also, it's good to think about the problem in terms of simplification.
Let's say you don't know how to print an X line.
You can think first.
OK, let's print this left diagonal first.
If you are done with that, you think about the right diagonal.
So try to simplify things for you.
If you're thinking about the left diagonal here, observe that it's always, like, at position i and j
there is a start.
Otherwise, there is no star.
So if i == j, then we are at the diagonal, otherwise we aren't at the diagonal.
So this is at least one thing we need to do.
Iterate over N * N here like a matrix printing or so.
And then if i == J, we are sure that this should be a star, otherwise it should be a speace.
Now, this should be an easy part.
That might be for some of you
tricky, what about the the other one?
One approach to think about it is just to try to list the answer like let's say for
for n equal five.
Then start to say at row number one.
What is the answer?
Where does its start? At row number two, where is the star? At row number three, where does its start?
and so on. By looking at the numbers, you should be able to figure out the pattern, whenever  (n - i -1 == j)
(n - i -1 == j)
we have a star for the right, the right
diagonal, so overall, we have two cases.
Either we are at (i == j) for the left diagonal or the other one for the right diagonal.
If these are the two cases we print the "*", otherwise we just need to print a space.
In the second problem, we would like to write a code that will actually get this fixed answer, there
are no different answers here, just this answer, all what you are requested to do is to find it.
So we are given that X should be in this range and Y in this range.
And then this condition and this condition.
It should be straightforward.
This is two nested loops. To implement that
we mainly need to start iterating over the X in the given range and Y in the given range and then
make the two checks.
One of them is the less than and the second one is the mod seven condition.
So far so good.
Be careful, all what you are doing is just translating the problem from the
given to the code.
Sometimes you can think a little more in improve things.
So one way to think about, what is a problem here?
There is no problem from correctness, from optimization perspective.
Let's say X is 100, then all iterations from Y = 70 to Y equals 99 are all of them are failing, why? because
this condition isn't satisfied.
How can we adjust the code so that this is always satisfied.
The idea is simple.
We have a start if start is less than (x + 1),
then we know that start can be directly assigned to the value.
So Y is 70 if X is less than it.
But if X is greater than 70, then we can start directly from after it.
So let's say that X now is 20, then I can start the start with seventy.
Let's say that X is now 50.
I can start the Y with fifty-one.
This way we did two things.
First of all, we are starting directly from the right location, which is more efficient.
Second, there is no need anymore to handle the X less than Y condition.
We are already maintaining it in our computation, which makes our code much simpler, not simpliler but
a more smarter code.