In the third problem here, we would like to try all of the integers A, B, C, D, E, and we would like to find
how many
Ones satisfy the following condition, all of them, ABCD, are between one to 200.
And then we have this nice condition, A + B equal C + D.
It's very clear that we don't need to try every number in the world.
We just need to try ABCD in
these ranges from one to 200.
So this is a good indicator for a for loop, then with every for loop we can just double-check the condition.
So here are four loops, satisfying the target, and then we count every condition that satisfy the
target from us.
So far so good.
But we learned that probably we can get rid of one of the four loops because this is very slow, to do
that.
We just get rid of this loop and we estimate from the equation that D = A + B - C, the
remaining thing for us is some of the D would be invalid.
So let's verify here that D is within the range.
This is how to do it with actually three loops. In the future,
You can learn using something called metal middle and dictionaries or maps.
You can learn how to do it with just two loops in a very efficient way.
But this is out of a scope for now.
In the fourth problem, we would like to print if a number is a prime number or not and a prime number
is a number that is greater than one and cannot be divided by any number less than it.
For example, if you are thinking about numbers like 13, 13 is a prime number because starting from
two to 12, there is no number that 13 is divisible by it.
So what you have to do is to take a number and decide if it's a prime number or not.
The code is very straightforward, all what you have to do is just, first of all, handle the number
in a
handle the number, handle the one as a special case.
I would like here to go one more step and make it less than or equal one.
This way you are handling it even for the negative number.
If someone entered a negative number, any negative number isn't an odd number.
So let's make it even more, more, more wider in the scope.
OK, let's keep going.
In the second case, we like now to iterate starting from n to the number, but lesst than it, not less
than or equal.
We will keep going for all the numbers that is less than the number.
And check, if we found it is divisible by any number, then this isn't a prime number.
Otherwise, the is_OK will be true through the whole iteration.
Then we just print it. That's all.