In this one, we would like to print all the prime numbers that are less than or equal N, for example,
for 18, you would like to print all of them.
This is just a more extension for the one that we took using is_prime, so just one extra loops to handle
it. Observed here,
I would like you to separate them by comma, but don't put a comma after the last number. To implement
that we need
We now need this target number here and start to iterate over all of the numbers and for every given
number, we would like to make sure that this number is prime by checking every number less than it.
Once we are done with it, we are just going to, if it's OK, if it's a prime number, we will print the
number here. To handle properly the comma.
There are several ways.
Let's make it simple for now.
I'm handling here.
If this is the first printed number or not, it isn't the first printed number, then we can like print
always a comma.
If it's a first number, we just print it.
Otherwise, with every next number, we put a comma here.
This guarantee that between every two numbers there is a comma, but there is no comma after the last
number.
In the last homework here, number six, we would like to compute the sum of the numbers between
one and N whose sum of the digits is between A and B.
If you understood the problem, then it should be fair enough to be implemented.
We need to iterate over the numbers.
We need to compute the digits sum.
We need to make a check against the loop and so on.
So let's read the N, A, B, iterate over all of the numbers from one to N.
And then let's take a copy here from the i.
You should know why and then for every number i, we will compute its digits sum.
And if its digit sum is between the range that we will have, the A and B, all that we need to do is just adding
it for us here.
The reason that we took a copy from i, as this copy would end up as
zero as we learned before and we would like to add it here if we didn't, if we corrupted the i
we are corrupting two things, we are corrupting the for loop here and we are corrupting the result here.
So we better take a copy here.
So it was just more of an exercise over two loops and being able to understand the logic. That's all.