It's a practice on the while-loops. the first program is reading an integer X, find all numbers
divisible by 3 from 1 to X. Remember, the divisibility is more about the multiples.
So the multiples of 3, are 3, 6, 9, 12, and so on.
So here to do this program, we need looping from 1 to X. This is our looping and we need the logic
to make sure that something is divisible by 3, which is just
mod "%" 3 == 0.
So to loop, we just have here the start = 1,
We have (start <= end), which is the input number, and we have the (start += 1).
So this is what guarantees that we have a loop from 1 to end.
And our logic is, if the current number is (%3) == 0, then we just print the number,
OK. by the way, thinking about the operator precedence, then the mode operator has higher
precedence than the == operator.
That's why this one is applied first, then compared with the 0.
In the second program, we need to do something popular in programming named as the power function, what
is power ? if you have something like 2 to the power of 5 "2âµ", it means to multiply the 2 by itself
5 times.
You are to read 2 integers, X and Y and to compute the X to the power of Y.
This is how we write this notation, the power.
But anyway it just means multiply X by itself Y times.
So thinking about the looping, we again need something to iterate Y number of times.
So we read here num and power, "pow" here is like the Y and we need to iterate
(pow) number of times; so we say "while (pow >= 1)", we do "pow--".
This is interesting, now I'm actually doing it from top to bottom.
So for example if Y is 5,
I'm doing 5, 4, 3, 2, 1 and stopping, notice also I'm stopping here at the 1.
So it's more of iterating from 5 to 1 not to 0. for our code logic,
We need to keep multiplying ourself.
So we have some result here.
And every time we are multiplying the results by our self, the result by ourself, let's make a minor tracing, if we enter
2 and 5, 2 and 5.
So as we said, 5?
Yes, greater than one.
4? yes.
3, 2, 1.
And the result had been multiplied by 5, 4, 3, 2, sorry, is multiplied by (num)
5 times.
In the next program, we would like to read an integer and count the number of digits of it.
For example, if we entered 123, this consists of 3 digits.
Think for a while how to do that.
We will show several tricks in this
code. the way to count the number of digits of
a number is as simple as keep removing a digit and verify if the number is 0 or not,
OK. so for example, if we have 123, remove the 3, incremental your counters, we now
have 1 digit.
Remove the 2,
Now we have 2 digits.
Remove the 1,
Now we have 3 digits.
So here the logic is as following, we read the number, which is 123.
We say "while (num > 0)", as long as this number isn't 0, we say here, num =
num / 10,
So we are removing the last digit.
And with every step, our logic is incrementing the digits with one step.
I would like you to trace this code to make sure that you are comfortable with it, after you are done
with that,
There are at least two bugs in this code.
I would like you to think about two different test cases that make this code not complete.
We need to find more improvements in it.
Let's proceed, the first bug here in this code, it doesn't handle the input 0, for example,
if the input was 0, the program will say "while(num > 0),
It will never get inside the loop and say the digits were zero.
So actually, this wasn't the case, and we also couldn't just put equal in the loop.
Otherwise, it keeps going for infinity.
So the best way to do that is to make a special handling for the 0.
So we say here, "if(num == 0), then we have 1 digit,
Otherwise, we do the previous code of counting the digits one by one.
So now what is the other bug in this code?
This code will fail if the number is negative.
OK, because it says here, "while(num > 0)", what if the number is less than
or equal?
What if the number is a negative number?
This loop, again, will not work.
So while we have here a special handling for the 0, we need also special handling if the number is
negative.
An easy way for that is just multiply the number with some negative value.
For example, let's say the input is -123, then multiply it by -1, is now
123 and then you do your normal processing.
So far, so good.
There is still one very, very tricky trick here.
And I would like you to think about it.
Here is a hint, think about the overflow.
Give a trail.
OK, let's proceed more.
What is the minimum value in C++?
It is minus this number.
What is the maximum value?
it is very similar to this number, but with -1 here.
Now, what happens if you multiply this number with -1? it is going to be the same value as
positive value, but this is greater than the C++ limit,
So this causes the program to overflow.
We need a special handling for this test case.
So we say here, if num is 0, it's just single digit.
If num is this negative value, we know it is ten digits.
Otherwise we do the same logic.
So if I wanted to share a message with you from this simple program, it is as following; It's actually
very tricky to write a very complete code.
It takes really time. during the course,
I will not necessarily be doing the same way with every single logic because in many cases I'm just
trying to reveal a specific message.
But I just wanted to share with you what it takes to make really a very strong program.
Yeah, there was a request here that we would like to print something like, cout<<"number of
digits of " << num << " is " << digits;
For example, you cout number of digits of 123 is 3 digits.
But this message will not be correct.
I would like you to read it and think why it would not be correct.
The reason is that the (num) is already we kept dividing by it.
So eventually here num is 0.
So it would be num = 0, it would be 0 is 3 digits, for example.
The right way is you take a copy of num because you are actually going to play with your num variable
now.
Nested loops.
Let's say that we would like to make a program that reads T integers for T test cases, then read T numbers
for each number, print them from 1 to N.
Remember, we before had (if-conditions) and we also say that we can had nested if-conditions in a nested-if
conditions. in a very similar way,
Nothing prevent you from having while-loop inside it another loop, inside it another loop and so on.
In this program we would like to read test cases and for each  test case you'd like to print something.
For example, let's say the user entered 3.
It means the user is going to test us on three different test cases,
OK. and for every test case,  we would like to print the sum from 1 to N. for example, if the
user entered 3, then the sum from 1 to 3 is 6.
4, the sum is from 1 to 4 is 10.
5, The sum from 1 to 5 is 15.
So now, it seems I need two things that help us to iterate.
The first one is the while-loop on the test cases, and the second one is while-loop to sum from 1 to N,
OK. so now here we are reading T for test cases and I'm saying here "while t > 0",
Here you see  --T.
So for the first while-loop we are reading its value, we have a condition that we are still not zero
and we are decreasing it,
So test cases are actually going less. inside the loop
we start to read the number and then we prepare another while-loop with the start from 1,
As long as the start is less than num, and we do start to ++, and we have here our own logic.
sum += start, and sum is something that's defined locally here.
Then we just keep summing it and we print it. this is what we call nested loop or nested while-loop.
We did one loop to iterate on test cases and another loop to iterate from 1 to N.
Please make sure that you understand this one.
That's it.