Homework set number one for while loops, the first problem is a very direct one, you are to print
a range you will read two numbers X and Y, two integers, and then you are just to print to all of the integers,
four, five, six, seven between these two numbers, every one of them on a separate line.
That's simple.
In the second problem, you will read an integer and a character, a single character you are to print
this single character according to the number of N  given year, for example, if five and Y then
repeat Y five times, three
And, uh, I forget the symbol,
the symbol name
Let's call it hash, like in programming three and hash then you repeat hash three times.
And so, in this one, you will print a left-angled triangle,
same as here, a five,
then you print to five rows like a left angled triangle here.
And in this one, you are to print it also, but this time it will be facing down.
So for an input like six, you are printing six rows this way.
And in this one, you will print a special average as following you will read an integer N followed by reading N numbers
by reading N the numbers and you have to print 2 values,
The first one is the average of the numbers in odd positions and the second one is the average of the
numbers in even positions.
odd positions are like the first, third, the fifth and so on.
For example, for this input here, six numbers,
these are the six numbers,
We can see that in the odd position we have 10 and 20 and 30,
So the average of them is 20 hear and the average of  100 , 20 and 200 and 600, which are the even positions
the average is three hundred, make sure to choose a good data type for an averaging operation, that's
all.