Let's solve the homework, the first one is straightforward, according to what we learned. Here
we just read the start, read the end and start while loop from this start to this end and every
time we just print the start.
and keep going, very matching to what we learned already. In the second program
We would like to do the repetition, but depending more on the given input.
So to do that, we mainly need to
We need to iterate over the given numbers and start to work over it.
For example, here you read the number and you read the character.
And after that, you start iterating over this number tell it be -1, you can remove this
greater than zero because once it approaches zero, it will be done.
But this is a bit better for readability.
So this is OK, too.
This is mainly the second one, which is also an easy one. In the third problem.
And the fourth one would like to print this triangle, observing here that in the i's row you need
to print like i elements.
Right?
So in the first row, you print once, in the second-row you print twice.
So the relationship here is very straightforward.
That's why we need only two to consider that.
Here we will iterate from row one tell N.
And every time we will have some counter to go up to the row.
So if the row is one will print one star, if the row is two, we print two stars, if the row is three
We print three stars and so on.
The flipped one has a very similar logic.
We need just to flip the order itself.
So here, first of all, we start from the counter row, which is now starting from N now in the first
step, we are actually having N with 5, for example.
Then we print 5 stars, in the second step it will be 4, then we print 4 stars and so on.
So the logic mainly was switching the rows from 1 to N to N to 1.
This mainly be fourth one here. In the final one
We would like to print this special average.
We did this problem in the past, but it was fixed for six numbers.
Now we have variable number of items.
So all we need is to keep in mind which position is even and which position is odd, to do that
We can mainly just consider the position that we are using to iterate.
For example, we are reading here the number of Ns. we have the even sum and their count, we have
odd sum and their count.
And then we keep iterating starting from 1, and with every step we need to figure out is it even
position, if so added to the even part and counter the even, is it odd number added to the odd part and
increment the odd counter.
Once we are done, we have the odd sum, odd count, even sum and even count, that's all.