Homework set number two, in the first problem you will print this time a diamond, this way.
So given five, you are to print five rows this way than five rows.
This way, probably you need to focus first on the above-part and then the next part is very similar
to the above-part.
You need to think about the relationship between the number of spaces and the number of stars per a
line and so on.
In the second program, you read an integer N: print, all numbers or integers that satisfy the following
property, each number is divisible by eight or divisible by both four and three.
For example, if I entered input hundred, then we have to find all numbers that were equal to 100
that satisfies due to properties, for example,
You can observe here that eight.
satisfy the first guy and 12 is divisible by both three and four, And so on.
In this one, we will read an integer N and print the first N integers that are multiple of 3
but not multiple of 4.
Observe here you are targeting the number of the first N numbers.
So this is different.
Here you are reading from one to end, for example.
But here you would like to get the first N numbers.
So this is output for input like 11 observe something like 12, 12 is divisible by both 3 and
4.
That's why it is excluded.
We need the number that is divisible by 3, but not multiple of 4.
So how can we do that in a smart way?
The minimum of values, you would read an integer T for a number of test cases, and for each test case
you read integer N followed by reading N integers and for each test case.
Print the minimum of them, for example, reading here two, two is for T, the number of test cases.
So we have to test cases.
This is the first test case and this is the second test case, each test case start with,
the number of integers here, 6.
So we read 6 numbers.
And then we print the minimum among them, the minimum among all of these numbers is 4.
And in the second case, we need 3 integers.
Here are the three integers and the minimum is 5.
So the output is 4 for the first test case and the second one is 5.
That's all.