Let's solve the second homework set in the first problem we need to print the diamond one and to
be able to solve this problem, you need to focus on the relationship between the number of spaces and
the number of stars per line.
So let's first of all, start with recording some data.
If you try to think about, say, N=4 in rule number one, we have three spaces then one
star, then two spaces, three stars, then one space, five stars, then zero spaces, seven stars.
So this is the overall statistics that we can find per row.
Now, I would like to think about what kind of relationship
we have so far? What kind of formula that we have?
It seems the spaces are typically (N -  rows).
For example, if you are in row one, observe here both of them always seem to be 4, one plus
three is four.
2+2=4, 3+1=4, and  0+4=4.
So N - the current row is enough to get this one.
And this is a straightforward one.
The second one, if you are good in math, it should be easy also to get. Observe
the equation is two times row - one, that's all.
For example, if the row is three, 3 * 2 = 6, 6 - 1 = 5,Here 4 * 2 = 8
8 - 1 = 7
So based on these two equations, we can easily for every row, print according to that number of spaces
and then according to that number of stars, so here we start our for loop and then according to that,
we iterate once (N -  row) to print the spaces and then (2 * row - 1) to print the stars.
Now to do the opposite triangle.
All that we need is just mainly to switch, iterating from 1 to N to N to 1.
That's all.
Nothing else.
For the second problem, we would like to print the special multiples here, so let's see how can
we do that?
It's very straightforward to do it.
Let's see here in the first program here we are iterating.
I think there are two solutions.
... , let's start with that one.
... , here we would like to figure out all the numbers that are divisible by
8 or divisible by both 4 and the 3 to solve this problem, we are just iterating here from
8.
And then all of what we need is to do the condition.
Is it divisible by 8?
Yes.
Or is it divisible by both 3 and 4?
Then we are done.
So if these two conditions are achieved.
We are done with that.
This is mainly all what we need in this simple problem.