Let's solve the third problem, there are two ways to do it at least, in the first one, we're
going to just follow what we are asking to do it similar to the previous time we will iterate from one
to N. Sorry, we are going to iterate up to our counter, achieve the N, because we need to print
the first N item.
So this is like the first thing to consider.
We have a current number.
We keep increasing it with every match.
We increment the  ++ and we keep going till we get all of the N numbers. to make a check.
We first of all, check if the current number mod 3 == 0 or not.
This is a first condition.
And the second one we check, if mod 4 != 0 or not.
This is mainly the code and the logic assemble.
We can optimize this one little bit as following, Let's from the beginning
Iterate on all the numbers that are divisible by three.
How to do that? start by three and keep incrementing by three.
Then every number that you are iterating over it from the beginning is divisible by three then.
Now there is only one condition that you need to handle that if it is divisible by four or not.
So here we check.
If it not divisible, then we can print it and increment, that is all. Let's observe here
I didn't use the counter here.
I depended on it.
Like, we don't need to consider another variable, just use N here and keep decreasing it,
that's all.
This should be enough so we don't need one extra variable.
So this overall good is using less variable and also shorter because you are already iterating on divisible
by 3 variables and only checking for mod 4, this solution was suggested by this guy.
The fourth problem is about the minimum of a bunch of numbers, we already know how to get the minimum
if the numbers are a bit few, but now we are expanding it to be more generic.
To do that.
We mainly need here to, we have different test cases.
So let's iterate on the test cases, for every test case, will iterate and read the N numbers
if it's the first number considered the first the value for us otherwise minimizing on the new value and
keep going.
Once you are done, the result will be ready for you to be the target number.
Yeah, this is mainly the solution for this problem, which is just how to make it more iterative,
per test case.
So this while loop here is reading N numbers and getting the minimum among them.
That's all.