The third homework set, the first problem is a bit an easy one, you would like to read an integer
N followed by reading N strings, and you have to print only the strings that consist of the
following conditions.
First, they have to be only two letters.
Second, this letter can be either N  or O, but you should ignore the lower case and upper
case of numbers.
You don't care about that.
So it could be n small, N the capital, o small, O capital and you don't care about the order it could
be N and O, O and N
and so on, it is eventually have to be the word N O.
And according to that, something like N O
Is rejected ON is rejected.
no
Is rejected.
Oh sorry.
I reverse it, no on no are the right ones.
Something like YEs is incorrect.
Something like Nooo is incorrect because it consists of many, many letters.
So overall just a word of N and O and both of them have to be there, for example, something like
NN is invalid, OO is invalid and so on.
Yeah, so this is a list here of things you OO is ignored, we don't print it.
In the second problem, you are to reverse an integers N, read that integer n and reverse it, print it
the reversed one, and the reversed one multiply by times three, for example, for input, one, two,
three, the output is reverse,  three, two, one.
And if you multiply this number by three, it will be this number.
Here you will print the multiplication table read N and M for the multiplication table and then print it
as following, for example, three and four, then we would like to try every number from one to three
was every number from one to four and print it as I am printing it here.
in special sum one, which might be a little harder than previous ones, you will read an integer T
for the number of test cases for each test case, you will read N then N integers, ABC and you have
to print the following summation for every test case.
it's as follows,  let's say the numbers are ABCDE and so on.
A, then B*B the submission of A plus B plus BB plus CCC plus DDDD plus EEEEE and so on.
Observe in every step we are duplicating or repeating the number for K times here K is one,
so we used A for once, B at the K for two.
We repeating B twice.
This is the third term we repeated C three times.
This is a fourth term we repeated D four times.
This is the fifth term, we repeated E five times and so on.
As an example, here is the input, two testcases
The first testcase is five seven two.
So we will print  as follow.
We need five and the seven twice and two three times.
In this testcase,
we need one, two, twice, three, three times, four, four times.
And so and you need to develop this summation, that's all.