In this video, you will know about some of the algorithms that are in the library.
The first one is the equal method.
The equal method can take an iterator begin and some in the position for one sequence and then some
starting point from another sequence.
And then for every item from the beginning to the end is going to check with the corresponding one here.
If it if it is equal or not, if all of the matching positions are equal, then it returns.
True.
So, for example, if you if you have a vector, for example, and you bust the begin and for example,
the beginning plus say seven or so is going to iterate on this given range, compare it with the corresponding
range from here to check if this Kurama and its application to that might be, let's say we would like
to write is Ballenden function.
If you would like to check a function is Bolinder.
We would like to know if it is from that, from the Left-to-right, it can be read as the same as right
or left.
So one nice idea here is to just use the equal method.
You give it the string begin and end and you would like to start from the end also to start to compare.
So here we start from the beginning, which is the last element in the array, and then is going to
element by element from this range compared with this range.
If it turns out that all of them are equal, then we have an equal result, if you like, a more efficient
way.
We need to compare a palindrome, all of it.
You just need to compare half of its size.
The second set of algorithms here are all of any of none of let's say you have a victory here and you
have some function f the check if the element is even or not.
So it isn't the function.
The function of is going to take a range start and end and the function F is it will check if every
element satisfy this predicate or this function here.
So if every element is even, it will be even.
So this isn't the case here.
The function, any of what a check, if any of them is even and this is happening.
We have you two and six.
So, yes, this will be true.
The function, none of will make sure that none of them satisfy the condition that mean that all of
them are even all of them are old, which isn't the case here.
So,
yeah, this is mainly some some boolean function that you can apply.
There is also a function name, the Kobe underscore in the Kobe underscore and just take from you some
starting position and accounted for the number of elements to make a copy.
And then there is something here that you first time to see is good back into the concert to return
a specific type of iterators that can that will start to cool your Bush back, Bush back function.
So this target function here, the vector to return an iterator for its for its back for its it will
return.
And an attribute that you can call Bush pushed back over it.
So this could be in the function will call the bush back over the iterator that's coming mainly from
here.
So now here the source is a string from one to nine and zero here plus one.
Then we are at starting position to end asking to be before enemies.
So it would be two, three, four, five.
So this guy is going to copy four elements starting from two.
And it would insert in the it will call the Bush back in the end of this of this target, which here
is empty.
So the Bush back four times or just the Bush back four letters.
So for simplicity, back and circle is just calling the bush back over whatever is best here.
The last method I would like to say in this video is I to eight, which is a nice function of the function
take from you some some begin and some end and some initial value.
And it's going to incrementally assign the values from here to there.
So, for example, if you give it a and it was five, which are five votes and you give it starting
value, ten is going to incrementally assign 10, 11, 12, 13 and 14.
Here is a more interesting case.
Let's say you constructed a little string of twenty six letters.
All of them are empty.
Then you give it the beginning end and give it later.
Eight then is going to incrementally assign A, B, C, the block, the Z.
So the to A is it takes an initial value, iterate over the range and give incrementing with one.
That's it.