In this video, I would like to give a more treatment form of treatment to the Étretat topic.
So far we've learned about the iterators.
We use them with almost most of the data structures we use to get them from inside the structure, like
using the scope resolution operator.
It would give you a bit later on the data structure itself.
We learned that they are more like appointer.
Zicam plus plus, minus minus.
Do some arithmetic in some cases and so on.
And we use the most probably the member functionality like big an end and the blockbuster separator
or the most we learned at the beginning.
At the beginning.
But the end is after the data structure.
The urban is at the end.
About the other end is before the beginning.
And then that was enough.
So far today.
I would like you to learn a little more about the big picture of the iterators.
First of all, there are four, five, five different Ofwat of iterators and they follow like an inheritance
hierarchy.
So in the very basic case, we have an input iterator and over the three to the input iterator do two
things.
It can only read variables.
So you can do like esoteric it to to to bring to something, but you cannot change it.
The arbitrator on the other side can only write so you can change the value and both of them move forward.
Moving forward means you can only move for the next step.
Think about reading from a stream or writing to a stream or what you are doing is yet you are moving
step by step to the next.
If you are reading from the console, you are just moving to the next thing.
You never go back.
So this is something that limitation thinking in contrast to, for example, at it at a at a vector,
you can go to the next step, you can go to the next step.
This is what we mean.
We move forward and move backward.
So the input iterator output iterator read only move forward right when we move forward.
That is what we call a forward iterator, which, you know, is like a beer.
And for both of them.
So it can read and can write and can move forward.
The next more flexible iterator is the wider and the wider regional can move one step forward and one
step backward.
This is like the iterator of the set, for example.
The most flexible one is the random axis iterator and the word random Xs.
It means you can access anywhere.
And this is like the array.
So you can read and you can write and you can access anywhere.
And this is typically internally entropy.
The.
So yeah, this is mainly the five different types of the iterators in C++.
You notice that this Tacuba realistic, you don't have any return, the input stream, the input stream
iterator is an example of an input iterator for the outer stream.
We have something like those three minutes later.
We also saw before the concert Turtur, we have something that can keep adding elements to the back
of some data structure, the bidirectional or the like, the list and sets and maps.
You can move one step forward, one step backward.
The random access ones are like the vector and the curandera.
They are internally just gistaro.
Sometimes the triggered from a data structure is of this example of a set and map.
For example, when you get a better iterator from them, it would be bidirectional.
But also to be honest.
And the logic here is you cannot and you shouldn't try to change the values of the system directly because
the internal data structure is built on something that could balance it.
The researcher three, you should study into the structure.
So the design to build on that, but you can only browse and move.
And then generally speaking, during the data structure course, you should get very strong intuition
why things were designed this way.
In terms of the possibilities, if you notice in something like the random access, like over a vector,
you can do everything you can, you can access with this way you can get equal, you can plus, plus
or minus equal, like you can say plus equals seven.
So they try to jump at seven steps.
You can do all kinds of relational operators, but the other ones you will start to notice they are
much more limited.
For example, in the bidirectional, you can move forward and backward, but only one step you can make
equal, equal and not equal, but you can do the other additional operators if you notice the input
or we can further forward.
You can only move forward.
You cannot go back.
One step if you are using an input is three stream.
You cannot go one backstabs logically and naturally keep moving forward in the iterator.
The last thing to be careful about is the iterator invalidation.
When you are reading an iterator and just just reading it and everything is perfect, but the problems
may start with it starting to change the content itself if it's allowed.
Sometimes the return it validated from a step is invalid and some programmers might not might just use
the return like the current iteration, as everything is good.
But the key is that it isn't.
For example, in the vector you notice that the vector after insertion or after erasure is working very
well.
But this might not be the case for other data structures.
I would say be very careful about iterators when it comes to deleting content, especially if you are
treating the data structure like your treating and rating in the same time.
If it had been that, please come back to such such a table, read the data structure and double check
what is going to happen to the Iterator after the change over overwritten.
That's all.