Mingus's billion is still in the bottom approach where you are explaining what is there or are there
different types of things inside it and then go in details.
But I used to believe that this is just confusing for students.
My approach was more of a bottom up approach where I'm teaching you what is and Victor, what is in
it to what is a set and so on a step by step so that you see all of the components.
And then we eventually go back to the big picture and learn about it.
So today we will finally see the big picture of a state which you are already now very aware of their
computers.
The major three things in in the.
Those are the containers that readers and the algorithms.
And you also now should be aware of the different types of the containers.
We have sequence in containers which are just like sequential, like the array and a vector.
We have the associative containers which which really doesn't care about the order, but care about
associating something with something.
For example, in the lab you are associating key with the value.
We also know about the container adapters, which are adapters rehabbing and interfacing to the kind
of interfaces and the unordered associative containers, which similarly doesn't care about the order
at all, but provide you in return the very first association between, say, some items or some key
and value.
We learned about The Iterator, specifically the beginning and the previous and all of this arithmetic
that we see.
We also saw a huge number of algorithms in sorting and searching operation over the over.
They sell this.
Three components are all about what is a standard in library.
And even when you move to a language like Java language like Suchart, eventually you have to provide
you something close to that.
You need containers or data structures and you need algorithms.
And these are two courses that you should take later after programming to really go in the details and
understand difficult algorithms like searching, for example.
The containers, as you see, they are like mainly four types and we studied at the moment and every
one of them is different.
A number of of containers, for example, in the Associated.
We learned about the sediment, the sediment and multimember.
It is for no duplicates, what it is for duplicates and so on.
And we learned about the this five or four types, data structures that are sort of structures that
the key are ultimately sorted, and this allow us for merely a quick search for the item, the analysis
of the bed or something called hashing.
You should study the structure in the structure cause the containers are merely adapters are interface
to others.
The sequence container are very focused on the first access so you can access an item.
But in return, inserting and removing an item in the middle of the destruction might be very slow every
day.
The structure, as you see, has pros and cons.
The traitor's, as we learned to have like a different five types with different flexibilities between
them.
The design was mainly how to separate the data itself from the operations, and the idea was like the
data should be managed by the containers and the operation itself should be like defined by configurable
algorithms and iterators are the way that we link both of them together.
So you see here The Iterator.
Is hexing containers, the algorithms, the algorithms are applied to and continues, and they are using
it to think about all of the algorithms that we're using.
If I give you an algorithm to check for equality, for example, that the algorithm or what it does,
it just using the iterator to do some comparison.
It doesn't care if it is a container coming from a stacked container container coming from a vector
container coming from maybe less.
It doesn't care.
So this way, the genetic algorithm and the templates also played a role in that.
We have a couple of types of independence's here.
We have the templates which made our algorithms independent from the data type itself, and we have
iterators which made the algorithms independent of the containers themselves.
And this is very smart design, in my opinion.
Finally, this is a nice flowchart from this guy's, a flowchart is something like your could, but
just drawn this diamond is an FSA condition.
So this is an X condition is order bullet.
And you care about the order.
If the answer is yes, then you care only about this, guys, that is dequeue, or is it just first
step?
Is it first our skewed?
Otherwise probably you'd need something like Brittanica.
What if I don't care about the order?
You care about the duplication unit and if yes, then you would have to use multimember multisite.
If not, you would have to use an order.
Order said there is another bigger flaw here for the sequence.
Contain or alter the container.
Feel free to read it.
Just give you a sense about which you is the structure and which is an area which I believe at the moment
you have a very good sense of it from all of the practice and usage that we did during the course.
Another interesting thing is the complexity during algorithm's courses, you should study the time,
complexity and the complexity, all of these different data structures and all of these different algorithms
has different complexities.
I know we read this statement as 01 and we read this guy as well.
And and we read this as Orlock in overorder.
I'm not going to explain that at the moment.
Just a very informal treatment or one means that the algorithm do a few steps to get the operation that
let's say three, four, five steps or so.
Well, it means a do say five times in steps to get the algorithm that, for example, if your vector
is of length and is going to go around five, five thousand iterations to get it done, log in is going
to do around five times look in operation to be done.
For example, if the end is million, log in would be like 10, five times it would be 50.
So it's going to get 50 operation to get it done.
So this is a very informal treatment for it.
So looking to it, for example, the set and we have insertion and erase and defined in only looking.
So if you have around a million elements, they can find the answer in around 50 number of steps already
in contrast to the vector in the general case would need to take like say, if you'd like to search
for something, it's going to take one million or five million a step to find the to find the answer,
which is a lot, unless you are, for example, let's say, inserting in the back, then this can be
done in all or in only.
So this is a flowchart here or a table for how fast every operation over this can do the structures.
And this is important in real life projects.
You should be aware of how fast your your data structures are.
Good software engineer should be aware of that.
Very good.
That's all.