In this video, you would know about some of the other algorithms in still the first one Max element,
which is a very basic function, you give it the beginning and end and it's going to find the maximum
one in this range and return and iterate over it.
If the iterator equal to the end, it doesn't exist, otherwise it exists.
So we have here a vector of employees and we put all of the employees here.
When you think about it, the next element would need some operator to figure out if something is the
maximum or not.
So to know the maximum or all what you need is something like the Lizanne operator.
So this guy must have a list then operator so that they can figure out which one is the maximum.
You can also assemble as right here, Pastrick and then Puducherry.
You know, this is an iterator.
So astrally is an object and the third is the actual object, but is also another function in Estela's
good.
The distance which would tell you how many how many items between the two iterators years it the distance
of the beginning.
And it is going to tell me to because the maximum here is in the position.
Twenty five.
So twenty five from zero is just the position here is to zero as to the distances to
the next function is find and find.
If, let's say you have here some vector from police and you have beginning and you would like to find
the E to.
Now, thinking about it, that the algorithm I need to to do in equal, equal comparison, so this Victor
here, this embley here must support an equal equal function to be able to find this guy because it
need to iterate from here to here and do an equal equal comparison with that.
Again, is returning the net result, which could be the end or not.
The end depends if the item exists or not.
There is another variant of the function name defined def, and this guy is going to iterate on the
algorithm, but it takes some predicate function.
Say here, I'm checking if the salary is odd.
So it is going to find if there is someone with an odd salary or not, which would be the case that
we have a couple of odd employees, that they're the variant here is fine, if not, which again is
taking some function to check if we find that element that doesn't satisfy this condition.
And in a very similar way, you can bet it just as an anonymous function.
The city has a county method, but would like to would like to see first hand account method on the
settlements that we already saw this before.
So I have four here, four employees, and I define the multi set which allow duplicates and we have
one to two.
It will have three items would be to try to bring to the count of two is going to give you three and
the count of four is one.
Now, thinking about the mindset, the mindset would like to figure out the order of the items, so
you must bust this then here.
And one of the things to keep in mind about the set multisite the map and multi map is you cannot change
the value.
Like let's say you get an iterator this way.
You can just say as tricky territory what you want because this guy is returning a constant iterator.
You cannot change it.
If you'd like to change it, you have to find it.
Then you have to remove it and insert something new internally.
The set and multisite are based on some specific types of data structures.
And you can a change in this way and observe also here this function here.
The list then must have a constant constant because remember from the will be when you put it means
that the function can change the member variables.
So this is a constant, constant iterator object.
It must call a constant function.
But there is also another interesting observation, supposedly the county method need to make an equally
equal comparison with objects.
However, we didn't provide an equal operator.
We only use the IS operator.
The data structures like Set and map can use that operator to figure out if they are equal, equal or
not.
Specifically and mathematically.
If you have A and B and you found that it is, then B is false and B this, then E false, then just
just means that A equal equal.
B.
Yeah, now let's start to move to the east.
The count would like now to just call this the recount, would like to give it the start and end and
E two.
So observer here, the county method is more flexible that you can provide a specific start and end.
But notice the following.
You need also here to provide the equal equal operator because the the county method here doesn't know
that this is set or what the system doesn't support this then or just going to check and make sure that
there is an equal degree.
So for one side you have to provide another another operator.
But what's more importantly, and we speak about that before, if if you have a data structure that
supports the function that the county for the set and the Esteve function, the one that you should
use is the one that in the data structure itself, not in the namespace, because this function would
be typically much better, making use of the internal representation of the data structure.
Variables function as you can expect you would like to replace in a given range.
You would like to replace something with something else so we can just give it here.
Notice again, we needed the equal equal operator, which is also a similar one to replace F, which
is taking the condition.
So every time this condition is achieved, you replace it with E one.
The search and the search and the search in is going to search for any items, so, for example, if
you give it begin and end and you give it three, it's going to search for three consecutive items of
value to if it haven't found them to return and iterator to the first item of them.
So if we try to get into the distance between the beginning and that return is going to be one here
because it is in this position.
So we're searching for three consecutive, which is this guy.
We have here a victor, by the way, remember that we can compare vectors with equal, equal and greater
than and so on, and we took this at this begin and we did.
And it is for it.
There is another method, namely search, which you can search for a subject or a subliterate or in
a territory, give it begin and end and you give another beginning.
End is going to search of this iterator range exist in this iterator range.
Again, notice that you need the equally good operators to be able to do the search function.
Another interesting function is the for each method, the for each can take a begin and end to iterate
over the range and another function to apply difficulty as you see.
Probably.
Can you just use the normal for us to iterate on something?
Maybe this is more flexible in the beginning end.
But there is one interesting thing about it.
Given that we can better function, we can also Balbus a function like that, some some class or struct
that overload the function called operator.
Now the interesting part is we can wire this guy is iterating with the class.
We can maintain whatever information we need to do in the class so that you can think of it as a more
statistics and more information.
So for example, here I have an assembly.
I would like to sum all of the salaries.
So I give it the sum function called, which is an an object will be created from the guy.
And every time it takes an object from the whole range, it's going to incrementally sum the for each
is going to return for you in this case, an object of type.
So now you can use it here.
So the model of that is you can have a class that can maintain some information and existence and whatever
about every kind of element.
If you have interest in that, that's it.