Let's introduce more algorithm's the let's say that you have some two vectors here.
One and two.
And you would like to say to them, but from the large to the small, there are several ways that one
can do that.
For example, you can give the beginning and then some function that just come off a greater than a
abuela, actually, is that he has some function that's named the greater, which you can do this comparison
for you.
So the greater function is just returning it through.
If it is greater than than B before the modern C++, we used to say greater it and that's it.
There is a nice advantage here.
When you see greater, you know that the purpose is to sort them from small to large.
There is a good intention communicated, but there is a common bug.
What if someone changed at any point of time?
The enter to longlong, but forget to change.
This one is going to compare or sought in a wrong way.
So in the modern C++ you can amet this year and it would be used automatically.
Now let's move to the next function in the activity.
This is more of some math operation if you would like to accumulate this array here.
So let's say you have one, two, three, four, five.
If you call and accommodate with this initial value, it's just going to sum all of the elements together,
which is if you tried to sum, it would be one, two, three, six, 10, five, 15.
Forget about this.
One hundred is wrong.
So far, this is intuitive, the C++ provides on full functionality that doesn't make sense for the
name, but it can provide different functionality.
We know when we are accumulating are typically adding it together.
So when we add one, two, three, four, five.
They are eventually 15.
But you can also, instead of the plus operation, you can override and provide the multiply operation.
When you say multiplies, it's going to apply a multiplication operation over every one of these guys.
You can think of it like the for each method.
Remember, the for each the four each is going to iterate over every element and take some maybe functor
and apply it.
So what we're building here is a multiplication.
If you multiply one, two, three, four, five, it will be twenty four.
You can also use something good in your product if you if it happens that you study it, then you can
understand this easily.
But if you have here a vector one and let's use it the same vector here, then our product is going
by default to some the product of them like it.
We're going to multiply the first element from that guy with the first element of the guy, plus the
first second element from the guy with the second element.
So we're here by saying we want and we want to add actually multiplying the vector in itself so we can
have zero times of on year plus two of zero times a bit of zero.
I mix it here.
It should be like one times if you want.
Plus it depends like a V to the V one, OK, to be one of zero times a two of zero plus the one of one
time the v two of one of them stick.
This is just the product if you know it from some math.
Again, C++ provide you that you can change the actual meaning of it.
For example, if we use the here the plus by default.
This is Blosser multiplies with some initial value of zero.
So if you if you see here we are actually computing some of products, if you switch on it and you provided
multiply Ramblas and use the initial value of one, this is what is computed.
It's compute one times.
So you see again at times plus times a plus this why we call it product of some.
So this is applied first and then this guy and then is going to sum the first two elements and multiply
them in the sum of the second two elements and multiply them in the sum of the 32 elements and so on.
I'm going to fix to the slide with changing these two equations.
So the values of zeros and ones are the initial values, if you felt confused about the product, then
you just don't know what is in a product.
So just forget about it.
The virtual sum is just doing accumulation, that element by element.
For example, if you have here one, two, three, four, five.
And this accumulated accumulation here means you add the current value to the previous sum so far.
So let's start with one.
One is zero one.
Then the two would be added to the previous element.
Two plus one is three.
The three would be added to the previous element.
But from here three and the three will be six.
Four would be added to previous element.
So it was going to be four and six is ten.
And that's it.
We say here minus one.
And again, we're giving back and sort of resolve to keep pushing back in this vector.
This is called the eventually, but also in a very similar way.
You can change the meaning and instead of just the accumulating with plus you can override with the
minus.
So it will start to subtract.
For example, one is here is initially then two, minus one is minus one, three minus one is minus
four for minus four is minus eight, five minus eight, minus 30 and so on.
There is also what we call a just indifference, and I just find you just give it the vector, begin
and end and another vector, and it's going to do a decent step by step subtraction to the vector itself.
If you want to begin, here is your elbow.
So it's going to go right in your eye with victory itself.
Probably it depends on your need.
Sometimes you would like to change in the actual vector and sometimes you would like to just give it
another vector back and certain another victim so different.
So here, if we have a vector of one, three, two, six, three, that Gissen difference now will will
do.
They will do exactly like the partial sum here with the minus.
So one will be here, three minus one is two to minus three is minus one.
Six minus two is four three minus six is a minus three.
So there is a difference.
The adjacent accumulation is the bending with the accumulated output, not the original, but the function
here as you see is subtracting when the actual vector itself.
So here three minus six will be minus three.
That's why we call it a decent difference supplied on the current vector.
But as I give it here, we want to begin here.
That is going to override in the actual actual vector itself.
Notice that it's not going to push back after the arrest, if the element exists, it will just use
them.
If they don't exist, it adds new elements.
Now, here it is, I'm showing you the two things different.
The first is I'm not providing the film to begin.
I'm actually providing a new iterator here and providing the iterator.
I consulted on a new vector's.
Pushing back and this guy using back inserted, the second thing is switching the default of the difference
to be plus.
So I was going to be like you, but your one three plus one is for two, but three is five three one
two eight six two plus two is eight, three plus six is nine, which is also what we call adjacent to
find, which is searching in the array for two adjacent according to some predicate function.
You.
The function, take your array or your vector and push it one step to the left, for example, if you
have one three to six three three, it will take every element and push it on the left side.
So the three will go here to be three and two will go here, six to go here, three go here.
And this one is going to rotate to the back of the vector.
If, you know, if you studied probabilities and you knew about what a random numbers and what is shuffling,
then you can also understand that one, if you have a vector of numbers, you can shuffle, shuffle.
It would make it like a random random order of the items.
For example, you take it from here and just shuffle it this way.
This is just important in some real life applications.
Before C++ 14, would you use usually using something called random underscore shuffle.
But now this is deprecated.
So please use the new shuffle method, which you Internet use more modern C++.
The lost function is the next permutation.
If you studied the discrete mathematics, then you can understand what is next permutation.
If you started with a sorted vector of items and you listed the next permutation, which is do while
and then you say next permutation will be the one and will end beginning, end the next permutation
is going to return.
True, if there are more permutations of this vector.
So for example here, if we started with one, two, three, it's going to list the six items here of
the different permutation.
If they were four elements of distinct values to return six and so on.
That's all I know that today topic might be a bit weird to some of the people.
It will depend on your background.
Like if you don't know what is inappropriate or what is an permutation or suffering, you probably will
not be able to make use of that, that's all.