There are some algorithms in the e-mail that be utilized that you are giving the containers that are
ordered.
Let's say that you have a big array like that and you would like to do a search for 17, then the normal
search function will step by step to find it.
Let's say there is one million integer then is the function.
WHITECHURCH Up to one million ISTEP to find the number so far.
Now, let's say that the numbers are sorted.
If the number are sorted, there is a very, very fast algorithm named as binary search.
The brain research will take longer number of steps to reach the answer.
The log is a math function.
So, for example, if the array is one million number, the log the million to be to be around ten.
This means that the binary search function can check if the values of in the array in only ten steps.
So the normal search is one million step, but the binary search would be only ten steps, which is
extremely fast.
But remember that this must be applied on all of data structures.
If you applied it on something that isn't sorted, it would give you wrong results.
There are other two interesting function that urban and suburban, which are internally based on a binary
search, also the lower bound to start and end and is going to find the first value, which is greater
than or equal to the provided value.
So for example, you say here 17 and in this array, then the first value greater than or equal to 17
would be 17 if it's right to give it 16.
The first value greater than or equal 16 would be all 17 if you provided the first value greater than
or equal.
Seventeen is fifty.
The upper bound is finding the first element greater than a value.
So if you give it seventeen, the first value greater than it is 50.
If you give it 50, the first, the value greater than 50 is nothing.
So just to be the end.
So this is a little lower than other functions.
There is also a function named as unique.
The function unique can take an array and get all of the sorted array, get all of the unique elements
in the in the in the beginning of the array of the vector and the other ones after it in some order.
So for example, if you give it, this array of sorting is going to return for your arrays following
the first group of numbers are the unique numbers in this vector and then some of the other duplicate
number in the end, in some order or another, we don't care.
The promise is this.
First the baddies will be will be sorted and unique.
They are already sorted.
They will be unique and return and iterator to the end.
So if you try to subtract the iterator from the beginning, it would be seven, four, seven elements.
Now, there's an interesting function here.
If you try to use the vector, the Tresize and you give it this size is going to get rid of this three
items.
The moral of that is if you would like to update this vector to the unique number of elements only given
that it was sorted, you can do that with a single line calling the resize function over the return,
over the list, over the unique results.
So this way, the unique return for you part and the size is going to remove this extra port.
Let's also see the set intersection and set union.
And this is a more of a mathematical definition.
Also, let's say we have two vectors and let's sort them first and let's create a vector result and
we will create a back and forth over this result.
If you give me the beginning end of the first vector and begin an end of the second victim, it will
find all of the intersections between the two vectors.
So thinking here, what are the intersections?
Two is coming between these two guys.
Seven is coming here, 50 is coming.
But for example, ten is here but not here, 17 here, but not here.
So this is the intersection in a similar way.
Let's hear the result and create another answer to it.
If you try to make a union, it's going to get all of the values here, which include giving the public
advice.
There is also the difference which is going to find elements that exist in the first one, but not in
the second one.
So, for example, 17 here, you find 17 in the first, but you don't find it here in the second one.
There is also what we call the the systematic difference, let's for simplicity, get rid of all of
the duplicate value, some resizing on the unique and resizing business on the systematic difference
when found elements that exist in one of them, but not in both of them.
For example, let's see the one sorry, the one existed in the first, but not in the second.
The five exists in the second.
The first, but then the second.
Then we use it.
The forty exists in the second, but not in the first.
All of them would be included.
Anything that is common, like the result of the intersection two seven fifty, it would be just would
be just removed.
You can check the documentation for what happened.
If there are duplicate in the vector, I just get rid of here to make it more simpler for you.
That's it.