One of the new data structures in the standard library is the array of reckless you see here with the
final array and you give it a type and you give it also affects at length value.
Remember the temperatures tied for the parameters here.
You give it also a number.
So internally, this is just wrapping internally, affix its size array.
So the point here is the target of this array to be a replacement to the belt and fix it array from
the sea and it doesn't use any extra memory.
So you are okay here, initializing it with a list of three, four, five, one, two.
And then if you call a redesign is going to give you five, you can now normally change the value array
or that at or specific array position which is handling the exception.
If you try to access out of the world, you can also sort it normally you can assign it to somebody.
So if you are assigned it this way, the last elements will be zeros.
If you try to initialize it was numbers that are the more five, it will give you a comparison error.
If you want to get the internal array which is created, it just you can get the pointer here and plus
seventeen.
If you would like to omit these two things together, then you can just remove them and is going to
recognize all these are double numbers and also just like double and two, which make our life easier.
The purpose of the array is to be a replacement to the fix the system error rate.
So please stick to it if you would like to use a normal rate.
The.