Two of the interesting data structures in the C++ is list and the modern one for the the list and the
list are designed to be very efficient, to insert and remove.
So I hope you get the sense that every data structure have a specific Bouar, for example, the vector
is internally generated so you can randomly access any position very fast.
Now what if you think about the vector, if you try to remove anything in the middle, it's going to
be a lot of work.
The purpose of set list and forward the list is to be very efficient.
If you would like to insert and remove in the method, if you have something, if you have an iterator
position, when you study the data structure closely so that something could link that list, which
is how these things are implemented internally.
So we we started with the list and we give it the values eight to one.
I can also say something like assign four and six, which will assign four values.
Each one of the six, I can assign them again to another, maybe the list of numbers.
Now you can push in the front and in the front and center back.
So if you watched in the front is going to be thirty here.
If you move the front, if you remove the front here, if you push the back, it would be here.
But if you try to x like an array, it will fail.
Now we can insert a list of numbers.
For example, if I here at the beginning and inserted five, six, eight, then it will take five,
six to eight and instead to them here in the beginning for the iterator notice that you cannot say iterator
plus equal to you have to move one step forward or one step backward and you can erase something.
So the moral of that is, as I said, is very efficient in inserting and removing if you have the iterator
that you would like to apply and operational.
But now the forward list is a bit limited then that it doesn't move backward.
It only moved forward this way.
Code for this in a very similar way.
We can push items here.
There is a function that say insert after you give it an iterator and insert something.
So our list now is one, two, three.
And I say insert after the beginning, five, six, eight.
So that's what's happening here is the beginning.
It is the after it with thirty five six.
So notice that it is in the very beginning.
It is in this position.
You can also like, let's say here, the return iterator from here is going to be the last element inserted.
So we inserted five, six to eight.
Here is the eight eight return and iterator to it.
If I am BLIS after and I give it to any is going to insert the twenty of three and return alliterative.
You can Iblis after it again.
Forty.
So it's going to insert the forty here and use it.
Or you can still use the insert after notice that the forward list doesn't go backward.
It must go forward.
You can also go the is after which is going to erase after something if the iterator as a position to
here and you say it is after that just there is the element element after it.
Yes, one moment we insert the the vote is returning this to we are doing it later, which is three,
I guess that this is I guess this is this is an accurate you might double check with some running again.
We can go back.
We can we can give it.
It is after and some some it returned here.
You cannot again, you cannot access with random with random balls, I'm not sure if my final words
here are very accurate or not.
Here we give it we move to the beginning, so we are here at the one with the plus bus, so we are in
the five, we say it is after this.
OK, there is after here is taking two pointers, the starter.
And so it is after it later it returns fired.
What is after five?
It is six.
So after three it is from the sixth to the end.
That's why is going to remove all of these guys.
So one five, the only one that I'm suspecting here is this, this line of code because the forty should
be the forty should be here.
So Étretat plus plus is going to be a two.
This is correct, but it is after eight it should remove.
The three, so I expect that these three should be removed.
That's it.
Thank you.