The array is a container with a very focus on meth operation, sequential, linear, on some data structure,
some people doesn't like it, like the design of it is a bit not the best, but still nice to know about
it.
So let's say that we have here an array of numbers.
You can create a wide array of this array by saying that.
And five, it is the first track noticed.
It isn't like vectors.
You see that and.
And this is a bad thing.
So it is.
It is one and five which is taking five numbers.
So it is the first interesting thing you can call the absolute value over, over, over, over.
The vast array is going to apply absolute value over every element which is going to make every element
you're just supposed to that you can see just the summit, which is going to sum all of the values.
Now, if you try to say something like two times, V1 plus two is going element by element, some them
and multiply over all of them by two and return a new vector.
So this is an element twice abberation rootsier V two is just a street value.
So we want to be two is going to do what is going to
plus one and one is two and two minus two is zero.
Three plus three is six times to be six.
Four minus four is going to be zero, five is going to be zero.
Now you have here a new vector element.
Twice you can say something like we want equal equal V two.
So the result would be one zero one zero zero.
Uh.
If we say the year one and one plus one.
I doubt that this is one zero one zero zero.
Oh, sorry, this is about the three, so what do you want to be able to say?
It is correct.
So if we try to compare V1 and V2 with equality, one is one to minus two equal to Foldes three, three,
two, minus three, minus four by four is false.
Minus five and five is false.
So you see, you get a very low rate here of every element.
Now you can say the men and max, which is going to give you the minimum, is zero and the maximum will
be one.
Let's define a new Valory of four.
That is this way.
Zero one, two, three, four.
You can do something like two times V five plus one, which is going to multiply every single element
with two and then add one for them to two times.
The plus one is one two times one plus one is three times two plus one is five times the three plus
one is seven as you see is more of a very math operation, like a whole sequence of numbers.
Let's see some nice functions about the lower function.
You can do something like about two and five and then even you can call the good sum.
So it is what's going to happen the way that every element in V five would be to talk about it.
So V five is zero.
One, two, three.
It would be two to the zero to the one to the two to the three and all of that, some 250.
Now you can reverse it V five and two.
So now every element of the five will be squared zero to the to one or two to the war, two, three
to the two and so on.
You can also do something like on the fly two times to be five and six.
Again, the same logic, but it is a catch.
You cannot here have something temporary like that.
You can have it for the first argument, but you can't have it to the second enemy.
You need to take this in a battery first and then apply it.
As you see, it is very math operation for the guys who are doing some math application.
That's it.