We studied some data structures for containers that are known as container adapters, and it's time
to make them more formal about them.
Remember, we once had an interesting homework.
I asked you to reimplement a stack, but only because you did a structure.
The point here is many that the structures can be implemented actually by utilizing others as an example
of that, one can implement a set data structure using just the vector, the structure, how to do that
with every call for the insertion function.
You just sort of the whole vector, this where you are maintaining the vector as a sorted, sorted data
structure.
But this is very slow.
This isn't wise to do it in a very similar way.
You can implement a barrier to Q using just set.
And this is by the way, it would be very efficient.
However, there is another, more suitable little structure that is named as Hib, which is internally
just an array.
So actually Vertica eventually is implemented based on a vector internally.
So the point here is we can implement the same data structures in terms of others.
And this stick us to the idea of the adaptor.
We use the word adapter and the wardrobing before in the Obbie, you are merely providing an interface
of something that is using something behind the scene, something like the composition.
So you're actually probably are limiting some functionality from the internal data structures and you
are providing some new functionality in C++.
Still, there are some data structures that are directly ahead of some other structure and you even
have the chance to tell it, to tell him what kind of the underlying data structure that we can use.
Think about the stack.
We can definitely define a stack based on a vector and use the push back and Bulbeck methods.
But Bethwaite, what is the point if we do that, are specific logic for us that that the structure,
then we can just read the structure of the stack, say based on the dequeue or within the vector and
provide the suitable methods.
I hope this isn't confusing for you.
So here is some good.
This is a model of what I'm saying.
We used to use the stack of integrase one internally.
The stack is by default will depend on a dequeue to be implemented.
You can't actually specify other types of internal data structures.
You can specify a state based on a vector state based on a Q stack based on a list.
I'm not sure if there is a practical reason that you can decide that O list is more efficient for my
usage or not.
I would like probably the default one is very good, but it's nice to know that this actually interface
and internally there is something else that is used to implement the request in a similar way.
The queue is internally at Q and you can use a Q over vector or a Q over list.
Now he did an interesting thing.
If you tried to use a Q over a stack or Q overset, this will compile, but once you start to use it,
it will tell you, hey, I don't find the pushback method.
Remember this oral templates seps are going to generate code and in both cases is going to search in
the given data structure over a Bush back method.
So if you can provide your own data structure with a Bush back method, you can even replace the Internet
of these guys with other ones.
There is nothing more than that.
There is no practical implications.
Most of the time.
I just wanted you to know that something like Stack and Q and Rearticulate are internally using other
data structures and you can even specify some of the details of this data structures that's said.