Ruled the time using the setout, which are eventually a stream, and as you know, they keep keep moving
forward typically in the in their in their processing, their obituary.
We can create the streams.
We can create like some some streams over this iterators, some streams over some iterators, over streams
in a nice way.
So let's say that we have here some vector V, I can create some output stream iterator and it's going
to receive some integers and stream object that would use this out and is going to separate them space
by space.
So now I'm going to call and still function in this Cobbe and giving it vector one and vector victor
begin and end.
And this iterator, the copy function would have started to take element by element here and copy it
to whatever iterator you can give it back, insert or whatever.
But now I'm giving here and Iterator is going to cool the stream straight over this item.
So the Charlotte will be equal to the current iteration and then with the next element, Espace would
be printed after it.
So if you try to print that is going to print for you.
A string is going to print on the console.
One, two, one, three, two, six, three.
I know the syntax of that is a bit weird compared to many things, but after time you will be familiar
with that.
It is a different way.
Let's say I don't want to write over the console.
I would like to write over a specific string so you can create the string extreme like that.
And then on the fly here, instead of taking it in a traitor, I'm creating 033 iterator.
It's going to receive integers and this is the object to write it and then again use the spaces as operator.
If you try to run this copy function here is going to give you a string of one three six two six of
the.
Here is another one.
Let's read.
I'm creating a string is three overstand.
OK, you can also read from from from from just here but we have a string and I'm creating, I string
a stream over it.
I'm going to call the partial sum function which remember it just doing an accumulation and I'm going
to give it the iterator string stream iterator over this, over this ETR stream and I'm giving here
an elbow to stream over it and.
So this guy is going to read from this source and write to this destination is going to bring the following
zero point one, which is the first guy, the sum some of the second one, 0.01, which will be there
with three comma separated zero going to three, Blasdel going to three is zero point six zero point
zero six is what notice this is an extra comma here.
Why with everything out here is going to be printed at something and also bring to the coma as a delimiter
or separator here in a very similar way.
You can run the program to read from this end and do partial sums to the CIA.
But this will keep reading based on what you provide to the notice here.
I did those three metadata to be of type integer, but the input was double's.
So this means whatever final value would be costly to integrate this all about stream iterator at the
syntax looks will.
I know that.
But I wanted to know that we can iterate the SNC and to read, write and send it from source to some
destination in a in a nice way.
That's it.