In the next project, we will implement an online book reader over all this is a simple project.
So from functionality perspective, it's limited.
Specifically, let me tell you first the big picture we have something in software engineering that
we call functional requirements and we have what we call non-functional requirements.
The functional requirements is actually what we initially as a as a Z, students focus on it, which
are the functionalities provided by the system.
In reality, there are a lot of concerns that are actually non-functional.
For example, the usability to what degree the system is understandable, usable compatible with something
like customer experience, for example, to a degree, the system is secure, reliable to a degree,
the system is fast to what degree we can like maintain the functionalities and scale the system from
like 10000 users to one million users.
Nothing here like a function that these are expecting.
They are non-functional requirements.
Please take time to learn more about the non-functional requirements.
You should meet this again in the software engineering, of course, but pretty good to have some background.
So now going back to our focus, the focus is functional requirements in this project.
The user has mainly two users who could log in or sign up the admin user and the customer user.
In fact, in this system, the admin user doesn't sign up is just logging.
The customer is one that can log in and sign up now.
Mainly the main role for the admin is to just add books here in the system.
The user himself can read one book at a time, and we will have history.
If his session sections of books, as we will see during the session, the user can browse the books
and navigate between them.
For simplicity, you don't use files in this one.
You don't use any better decisions.
You focused mainly on the design of the system.
So let's see.
There are more constraints for simplicity.
The admin users are already added to the memory, which is like your database here, so there is no
sign up actually for the admin, you don't need to sign up for the admins.
The second thing is that you can also add in the system initial books a bit, which will make it easier
for you to just test the system.
But the admin can add books.
And the second thing is, you can also add initially some customers, but the user can sign up in the
system, so this is to be the user can sign up and the inputs make everything symbolic.
For example, to use all of the strings without spaces, assume the user is behaving verbally.
Don't waste a lot of coding in these directions.
So let's see some usage here.
The system is start by menu that has log in and sign up, and I'm having some users in the system,
but in a way I selected to sign up.
So I'm adding user name Billard one to three, my user, my name and email.
Now we started the system, we see the use that has four items.
The first one is his profile and the last one is the logo.
So what is the first one?
The profile, if you connected to provide it, just will list your current information.
This is fair enough.
Number three and number two are important here.
Number three can list for us the current, the books that are available in the library.
So we have here three books, as you see now.
The user can select one of these books, let's say selected C++ book later.
The user can request the number two, which will show his reading history.
So we know that here the C++ C++ book has five widgets.
The first we are in the current image, which is the first page, and it has content to plus plus plus.
This is just dummy content.
No, the user can navigate in the screen.
He can go to the next page or go to their previous speech or even stop reading.
So let's see.
The user here decided to navigate to the next.
So now he is in two over five.
This is dummy content.
Again, next.
So now he is in three over five C++.
He then click the next, you know, in four five and this is dummy text.
Now we decided to go two, which is previous, which this is now three over five.
Now these are decided to stop reading here.
Remember, we were in a C++ book and with the last image was three page number three.
Now the user see again the choices here.
If the user selected two, he will notice that he has one entry here which a C++ how to program Beja
three were five.
And this is the last time and that you were in this session.
So now which session to Auburn, you have your only one a choice, so you selected it Auburn again,
that you are in big three over five with C and C++.
So this is what I call by session here.
And I mean here by session, a reading decision for the user what he can navigate.
For simplicity, these are can have multiple sessions of the same book.
Don't get confused by this request.
I'm just meaning that if you go back here, let's say these user decided to go back to this.
This he can see C++ again.
Then he can select C++ again, which will be added.
Don't try to make extra logic.
If you are confused about this is that means just ignore it.
Now one thing here this program would be random chance, but during the running, everything is maintained
in the memory.
For example, if the user logged the out, then look the end.
He can still see this session again in the system.
Now let's move to the admin the admin logged in.
My code has like hardcoded user Mustafa and 1-1-1.
So this is the admin that Mindy can add a book, which is number two.
Then we started to add the information of the book.
The book has four pages and I started to add the content of the pages done right in hospice's here.
Keep things to be simple, design wise.
This has limited features, but meanwhile, if you tried to make a good design, it's going to be like
a bunch of lines of codes here.
Not not sure to program.
Try to make things as simple as possible and focus on the design itself.
There is no there are no better decisions.
Just run the program only one one run to improve your design skills.
Please draw your best to design early before any coding.
Then could the system then re update your design and ask yourself this mandatory and fundamental question
Why did I miss this voice?
You will notice that there is always a gap between our initial design and our final design.
Why?
Because some some areas in the coding would be shadow.
A lot of uncertainties.
So when you are done with the coding, everything would be clear.
What matters here is you try to compare and think, how can I the next time spot this kind of missing
things?
Finally, try to read my work, compare and learn about it.
Look what if you are done with the project and you would like to go more and more?
I suggest for you, you might stop at this point.
I would like you to keep going in the in the in the in the in the in the course.
Maybe you can come back later.
But anyway, here are some thoughts.
Sometimes in some systems, the admin must activate the sign up for the user first.
So you see you signed up in the system, but you are allowed to just just use it.
The admin must activate it first.
How can we implement that?
What if the admin would like to edit, delete and search the books?
What if the customer would like to clear all of his session?
Probably this is an easy, easy case.
What if we would like to read from file allow better decisions?
What if we would like to look information in the system?
We can have multiple admins which admin approved, which user like.
We need to know this information, which admin added this book and so on.
I'm not going to implement for you something like that.
I'm not going to provide implementation.
I'm not going to provide support for you in this in this features, but just more for you if you would
like to keep going.
That's all.