Let me take you in a very short tour in the queue.
They were led diving in the could itself up to you.
Please read the could criticize it.
I might not be the optimal one.
I probably write the code very fast.
The Good has a built in admin user, which has user name Mustafa and Best with the three ones and customer
name as Matt was 2-2-2 as a password.
So you can use this ones to try my good.
There are here some nice functions to be helpful.
There's a function that will return for us the payment date.
Now, when we start to look to the big picture of the code, we noticed we have book and book reading
session user and user manager's books, the manager.
We have a user view, we have an admin view and a line reader system so that the functionality of the
system looks like small functionalities.
We ended up with something like 700 lines of code or so.
So let's see what's happening here.
The book, as you expect, which I expect you to guess, it mainly has some information as we see while
the admin is inserting them, and we have here the badges.
Then we have a function that allow us to read the book and bunch of sitters and and getters here.
OK.
In the second one, we have what we call the book reading session.
It's very important to separate the book and book reading session.
Don't mix things with each other.
As we mentioned, there is what we call the cabling.
The concept don't cover things in an unnecessary way.
Now we have here a book reading session, which admittedly has a book and has a current debate and has
lost access date.
And this is a way to represent the current image and some bunch of information the user can request
to move next page.
Or we move to the next page or to the bereaved speech.
And every time we can reset the lost access, we update this.
This is doing here.
So this is merely another utility complementary to the book information.
The user is also a class that I expect to to have it with the user name, password and all of the all
of the information.
Here is a flag if this is an admin or not in a different scenario.
You can actually, like, have something more complex, like inheritance or so.
This is a representation of the user.
This is reading for the user and just a bunch of some some information.
This is something that returning to the reading session of the user.
So the user here has what we call its reading decisions.
So the reading session is list of all of the books that he is orbiting at the moment in another design.
Maybe you're going to have this list here.
May in another thing that's OK.
The third one is the users manager, which would be managing mentally what is who are in the system
as admins or as customer users.
It doesn't make sense that this class be loaded multiple times.
It should be once in the system.
So this kind of lines of code here will be will cancel the ability to copy or delete a copy this copy
or assign this class here.
The database here has a condition I like just for simplicity.
Um, I'm just assuming if we looked at the database once, then don't load it again.
If you have multiple sessions, you don't.
You shouldn't do that.
You actually need to make sure that you are loading things in every step.
This are the two, the music that I have in the system and I have here a map that mapped from the string
like user name to the actual user in the system.
Here is the accent of the system, it says that you do not need to log and you need to sign up, and
then we have the menu here for the and the menu here for sale.
Sign up the sign up.
Make sure the first that this username doesn't exist so that we guarantee some uniqueness in the system.
It allow us to add some reading session here.
Getting current user, which I'm quoting here, current user.
So as as we are a single person who is running the system, just a single user, he is all what we need.
And the next step, we have the books manager, which should again have some mapping from the book idea
to the book when I'm shooting here, some also some of the dummy data in the class.
The next things are about viewing, we have a user view and we have an admin view, so let's separate
them these two things.
It is the user view.
It would have the user menu with the different choices.
We we just give the choice and we just apply it here and so on.
And in a very similar way, we have also the admin view, which again will have it's it's the stuff
you need to like, follow up the design and see what I'm using and strategic to will be different for
the me.
You can even be better than me.
This is totally OK.
Uh, yeah, this is merely the overall of the system.
This is a major menu here.
Uh, to just, uh yeah, like to to proceed with the system.
And this is around the system.
So this is a very high level overview.
I will like diving in the system itself up to for you and feel free to raise up questions in the queue.
Thank you.