In this project, we will create a project very similar to "askfm" website and if you know the askfm website, it's
a question where people can ask questions and then you can read the answers.
You can ask more questions and questions and so on.
We target this project to be files based system.
And this means that there are files that maintain who are the users and the questions and the answers
and so on.
You are also expected.
But if this is hard for you, don't try this at the moment, we would like the system to be able to run
in parallel.
What does this mean?
You can login with different users who are asking and seeing the responses on the fly.
So if I ask a question and I see the answer, then the other user if refresh, then he can see the answer in the
same time.
As with any basic system, the system should have full functionality to log in sign up, and sign out in the
system we care with these basic features.
For now, there is also a flexibility about the questions.
The questions can allow to be anonymous.
What does this mean when I'm configuring my system, my settings, I say, do I allow
people to ask me in an anonymous way or not?
If it's allowed to be anonymous, then I don't know who is asking.
But if it is, then the username of the target user must appear.
The user can do operations like printing the questions either from him.
A question for you, questions from you question to you or the overall feed question.
In a system the user can ask and answer these questions.
And there are threads in this question side that we'll see after a little.
You can also delete a question which can be a normal question or a thread.
I'm trying to give you some thoughts about how I was designing this system.
First of all, the systems generate IDs for every user, for example, and for every question.
And as I said before, in reality, we always have IDs attached to objects.
This is how we save things in the databases.
A third question is, is something like in Facebook and there are the questions.
You ask a question, did someone make an answer?
Then someone asks another question, then another question, and another answer.
and so on you notice in Facebook there are threads.
Someone is posting something, you reply another person reply when the reply and the reply and so on.
here in this system, the threads are like one level.
What does this mean is just a single question and bunch of answers on the same level over the same question
correctness.
You should make sure that your system is correct.
For example, the user cannot remove a question, asked it to someone else.
You can only see.
Edit your own questions.
and so on.
So anyway, let's visualize the screen to get a sense of the system.
The menu initially asked the user to log in or sign up.
I'm here.
I have hard-coded some names in the codebase to help me.
So I said login with Mostafa and three ones.
When you get login you see all of these eight operations one and two are printing question to me or from
me.
Three is answering a question four is deleting it.
Five is asking a question.
Six would be to list all system users.
Seven to list the feed of all the questions and eight to logout.
I'm here having choice from one to eight.
If I try to enter an invalid number, it say this is invalid.
Let's try again.
Let's go more with the system.
If I entered one, which is printing a question to me, I'm also having here in my database initially
some files.
These questions are actually loaded from a file.
So there is a file in my system that have information.
So here is the questions to me.
I have a question.
ID one or one.
I have another question.
ID three or one.
If you notice under this question, there are also here a thread question, thread question, thread
question.
So there are three questions under this question.
This question is coming from user ID one one notice here.
I know they use it in practice.
We usually see a name, but I'm just like for simplicity making it from user ID.
So we have this question ID from this user ID, the question was should I learn C++ first or Java.
And the answer to this question was as following there were more questions here, like user ID eleven
also asking why do you think so?
And here there was an answer from me and there was another question from forty-five user saying, what
about Python?
But notice there's no answer at the moment.
So this question isn't answered so far.
And here it is one more question.
Is it okay to learn Java for oop?
there is here
An answer from me.
Notice that this question here doesn't have a user, so it means that this user was allowed to send
in an anonymous way.
And here is another totally different question.
So I have two parent questions.
And this question is thread.
It has thread, two, three, four.
There are four thread questions under this question.
On the other side, if I enter two, I see the questions that I made them by myself, for example,
I ask the user ID 11, it was nice to chat with you.
And he also replied and say for my pleasure, Dr. Mostafa.
There is also another question from me, and it is the user ID.
Forty-five, I say, please search archive before asking.
But this guy didn't answer so far.
OK, you see here something say not AQ.
not AQ, it is just an abbreviation for not an anonymous question.
This means that my user id appeared to the user so I can know if my user ID appeared or not.
Now let's move to answering or deleting a question.
If I here entered three, which is a question to answer, then I entered a question ID.
one or one (101).
If you remember 101 is here, this question that was should I learn C++ first or Java? notice that
i already had an answer before that?
So the system here is sending me warning.
Already answered answer would be updated.
So if I say C++ is a really good choice as a new answer, this is now would be overwritten.
Answer if I say four, four is a question ID to remove.
Delete then I entered  the question id three hundred looking here to three hundred then we remove this
thread.
That question.
If we try to remove the question, one or one (101), it should remove it and all of the thread questions here.
OK, let's print one.
As you see the question.
Three hundred now is removed.
Option six give you a list of user IDs and names.
You use it to mainly make asking other questions.
So here, asking a question, let's ask a question that isn't a thread.
So here I'm asking the question say is who to ask?
Give me user ID.
I say 11.
It said note.
Anonymous question.
aren't allowed for this user.
The configuration of user ID 11 doesn't allow you to ask a question that is without clarifying the user
sent from there is a question here, do you need a thread question or not.
if it is a thread, you should give the parent question ID otherwise you should give minus
one.
So I gave it here minus one.
This means that it would be a new question.
So I asked here the question, Noha how old are you? going back to the feed seven.
Seven is going to list all the questions that have answered so far.
So there is a question ID 101 from this user to this user.
And this is a question and this is the answer, another question from.
But it is a thread question.
Question ID 101 question, ID 202.
So 101 here is the parent question.
ID two or zero (203) is the current question.
ID from this user to this user.
And this is a question, this is the answer.
And here is one more question to this user ID, notice here the from is invisible.
So this was an anonymous question that the feed is just listing questions that have answered so far
in the whole system.
If you would like to ask a question in a thread style, so you say five and then who which user
and then you give here two one one (211), which is a parent question.
OK, so this was my question for her.
This this is an ID of a thread, that question.
OK, let's login by another user, like let's log out and login now we enter one for Noha to
see the questions to this girl you see here.
She has this question.
It was nice to chat with you and she really answer it.
She has a new question.
please don't forget emailing the slides, it is an answer.
She has another question here.
How old are you?
It is an answer notice here.
This is a thread question two one one is a parent question that we just use to answer this question.
If you enter two to get the questions from Noha,  you noticed that she sent these four questions,
this is answered.
These two are not answered also in these three questions here.
One, two, four.
The user ID wasn't visible, please during reading these slides back again, verify the numbers and
the IDs and make sure it's consistent.
It would help you when you are doing your own project back then to the sign up operation, it just you
will be giving different like names and so on.
You can use one keyword for the name without spaces.
And here if you entered one, then you see all of your list of questions.
That's it for now.
I'm going to make in the next video a demo mainly for the parallel sessions.
It is like one advantage features when you can see more than a session running in the same time.
That's it.