In this video, I would like to give a very short demo of a specific feature in the ASKme project, specifically
opening parallel sessions.
Let me tell you what I mean by that.
Let's say here I am going to run my personal code, is asking me to log in.
I'm going to log in with Mostafa and password one one one, now it's giving me a list of choices.
If I give one, it's going to list to my choice by my questions.
Questions to me.
Remember, this is look like a thread question.
These all are questions and rate.
This question, for example, is an answer.
This is another question.
And so now we can run the same project several times.
For example, I can here run again and say I'm going to run with say Noha 222 it's going again
giving me a list.
Let me print the question that came from Noha itself like two here.
OK, so Noha is asking a lot of questions like yeah, a lot of them depends probably on the
first guy here, in Eclipse, you can switch between the two views easily and code blocks are going
to generate like one black screen for every one of them.
Now, by being parallel, I mean something like a real situation.
If you are on a website like ask me and you are asking a question, the other guy can see the question
in Facebook.
If someone commenting the other guy is seeing the comment, this means there is somewhere the programs
are like handling this kind of information together in a way or another specifically here, you will
depend on files.
You need some files.
You need to keep these files very updated with the new things such that the other code can all the
time refresh and load the updated status, note.
If this is hard for you, just skip it in the beginning and just go ahead and implement like
a one system per one user this is totally OK.
I would like to show you here something.
This is a user Mostafa so Mostafa
would like to, let's say, answer a question.
So here we get the three.
Now, let's answer this question, which has ID three zero two.
OK, so the question is, why so late?
OK, let's say very sorry for that now if we try to print to the questions again of my side, we should
find it here updated.
This is the easy part.
But I would like to make sure that the other guy here.
Noha can see the update, so Noha at the moment has no answer for this question if now she clicked
two again is going to find the answer here.
notice that both of them are working on files and both of them are being updated in the same
time.
So let's go back here.
Let's say that I would like to delete a question.
So let's delete question number four and I'm going to delete one or one, which is the third question
with a lot of questions.
So I'm going to give the ID here of one or one here.
Now, let's separate the questions.
I have. notes here
Most of them are done.
This is the easy part.
Now, let's go to the other user here and let's print their questions from me to notice that all of them
are removed.
Why?
Because all of them were the thread questions, for word two Mostafa.
So the moral of that is we have two sessions that now communicate to the Single-file, reading it
and writing it together.
It could be one file two files three files, it is up to you, please
When you are trying to solve a big problem, try to make it simpler for yourself.
First, if the project is big, try to think in a very simple set up and very simple features and start with
them.
Don't make it very hard for you.
That's it.