We will start explaining some points about the ask.me project, the project in size is like double
the size of the last project, so it might be like a big jump.
Make sure to not try a new project unless you are good with the previous projects.
Otherwise, it would be frustrating for you.
You should know that it takes time to learn how to write a good code.
It takes time to learn how to divide a problem to sub-problems.
It takes time.
And in many of the courses' projects, maybe the best project is like 100 or 200 lines
of code.
But in my opinion, we should go further than that so that students realize that the path is much
longer than what they think.
Expect that you will have difficulties.
Take it easy, don't get frustrated.
You will learn by struggling and suffering.
There is no way to skip that.
And also it will take time.
And more importantly, it will be like an iterative style
So try not to get disappointed, like having this spirit of a fighter who try to get things done.
The other advice is when you try to approach a hard project, try to think in the most
easy and simple features of the system and start implementing them. The more building blocks that you
do in the system, the more capabilities to make it bigger and bigger.
Whenever you try a project that you think it is too much for you to get, too much for you to start,
simplify the project, call it like a project version number one, which is a very simplified view of
the system.
For example, you might discard the thread's idea or whatever and so on. Anyway let's start
and it's very challenging to be able to explain something that big. In industry,
when you get a new team,
no one comes and explains for you everything.
Just we we explain for guys the big picture and we let them deep dive in the code by themselves.
So anyway, that's a start and try to give a trial.
I have here a bunch of utilities.
It's very good whenever you realize some utility to develop it in a separate function or a separate
class; this makes your life easy to code, easy to debug.
I have here some function to read the lines of code, some function to write the lines of code.
If I would like to append or start from scratch, a function to take a string s and split it and there
is a default delimiter here: comma ',' .
So for example, if I give it here like this string, it is going to split it to this word.
There is a comma here.
This number, this number, this number, this string.
This is string.
This is what the function is doing.
There is also a function that convert a string to integer. A function that reads integer
but it must be between low and high. And a function that displays a menu and return a choice.
So there are the utilities.
Considering the big picture of the system, we can all easily notice that the system has questions.
So I have here a class question.
The answers in this system are very simple.
The answer is just a text.
That's why we don't need a specific class for it.
In reality, the answer can be a text, an audio or a video. In such a system,
you will also expect a struct for the answer itself.
So we have here a class for question and another class for a user.
The question is a class representing a single question.
But what if I would like to have something that manage for me a bunch of questions? Here is the idea
of the manager.
So the questions manager is another class that is representing my struct that handle a lot of different
questions. In a similar way,
the user representing a single user, but the users manager is representing the something that can
handle the overall of the system.
Starting the system we would create an object from this front end surface of the ask.me system, which is a
front end and I'm telling it to run so it would keep running forever.
And the preparing bunch of choices here for the user.
And then we have a while loop that keep taking a choice.
And then you have here a function for every choice.
So something closer to what we did already before in the previous projects.
Important here to notice that the front end system needs to contact the back end system, which
are here like our user manager, our questions manager. The word "front end" refers to what the user is interfacing
with, which is here
the menu options. The word "back end" refers to what is behind the scene doing the logic,
doing the processing, reading from file, adding data to database and so on.
So these two in fact are more of like back end, but that guy is more of a front end. You don't study the
word of front end and the back end in C++, you typically start to see them when you start to learn web
development and mobile development.
But I like to like make it easier for you to get a sense of what does this mean?
Let's try to inspect a high level of the functionalities here.
The question class: every question should have an ID.
The idea of an ID is very important here in software engineering.
We typically need IDs for questions.
In reality, if, for example, you have a database, the ID is typically coming from the database because
the database will be generating unique IDs for like every question, every ID and so on.
For now, we are maintaining here an ID by ourselves.
There is one issue that we want to support threads and there is a nice idea here, what we call
the parent
question ID. The parent question ID is either another ID in the system or minus one.
If it is minus one, it means the first question in the thread.
For example, let's say we created the first question, then its parent ID would be -1.
Let's say that the ID is 77.
Now we created a thread
question over this question.
So let's say the new ID is
99, but the parent ID would be the 77 of the parent ID and so on.
In reality, if you would like to do something that has a like a reply on a reply on a reply on a reply, then you can make
like every parent ID is referring to a parent.
But here in our case, it's just one level relationship
to make your life easier.
Every question should be from a specific user to a specific user.
Again, we depend on the IDs.
By the way, one of the reasons we depend on IDs for now is also that we don't use pointers.
If you try to make like, say, a user_from & user_to, they would be typically by copy unless you are
careful enough.
So one of the things that make our life easier is just depending on IDs itself.
We have a variable for the is_anonymous or not, string for the question and a string for the answer.
We have here a constructor.
One of them is empty doing nothing and another one that read the line from a file.
Take a line from a file, convert it to a question.
So we have questions.
I can take this line, pass it to this constructor to split it item by item, convert it back to a question.
And we have some functionality, a function to convert the question to print it to, to print it
from; just a bunch of printing functionalities.
As you see, the more functionalities related to the question should be pushed in the question class not outside
the class.
In the second struct, we have here the struct user, which again has a user ID.
Then we have some of the popular attributes of all the new users and we have vector
and map. The first victor for the IDs for the questions coming for me, like let's say you asked
the question here and here and here.
So all of the questions that you asked are in this list.
Now, we would like to have a question ID to the list of questions on this question, like thread here.
So I have here a map from a question ID to the list of the IDs, these are the list of IDs representing
this current thread.
So this is how the user has its own from questions and the two questions.
But observe that the two questions need to be more like a thread style.
At least this is what I selected here.
By the way, feel free to have your own data structure for map.
So for me, I am mapping my ID a question ID to the list of the questions under this ID.
So for example, if you have a question and three questions in this thread, then for this
ID would have a vector of three question IDs.  In a similar way,
we can take a line from the users line and convert it to a single user class here.
This is mainly the two things here, the question and the user.
Now what if I would like to manage a set of questions?
The question manager has this role. We have here map: the first map is questionID_ questionID_thread_
to_map, which is a map from the question ID to the questions IDs.
This is the same as the previous one, but it is now for all the users.
So the one that was here, as you notice, they are very similar.
This one is for this specific user, but this one is for all of the users.
All of the questions and all of the IDs. We have here another map which is map for us an ID to the
corresponding question.
The reason for
mapping, as I said, and actually the dependence on integer IDs here is I'm avoiding to have multiple
objects.
I'm trying to make sure every single question is just in this map so that we avoid duplicates, all
of them to be in one place later.
Later when we learn about pointers, this problem would be much easier to be handled.
The question manager here have a lot of functionality.
One of them is loading database, which is going to read the data from the questions.text and just pass it.
And then other functionalities here like fill and fill, read, answer a question, delete a question and
so on.
The second class is the users manager. In the users manager,
we again loading the users and we have a trial to access the system by log in
to sign up.
And here we have the couple of functionalities and we have more functionalities related to that.
I hope in this video you got a good big picture of the system and its nature.