Let's get into more details.
Let's focus on the user manager, the user manager here has a constructor which is has a last ID
initialized to zero.
As we learned, we have to provide every user just an ID.
And we have here a map from the current user name to the actual user object.
And I'm defining here a user object to use with every new user.
The system starts with loading the database, which simply starts with clearing the data.
The reason behind clearing the data is I will be calling now the method LoadDatabase several times so
in every time I'm clearing all the data and I start to go to this read file lines function with the user
text to read the file for me with every line in the file, I create a user object and then add a map from
user name to the actual user.
And also I keep maximizing between the current last ID and the user ID from the guy, which is just
incrementing it.
So that's how we simply load the data from the database.
And as we learned, access is just giving a choice between login and sign up. in the Login function,
we load the database again.
Why I do that?
Because I want to if there are multiple sessions, I would like the system to be like feeling with
the changes.
That's why if someone added a user, I will probably feel it here.
In reality, things are handled in a different way.
But this is a good trial for now in terms of a console program, the program keeps
reading a username and password from the user and we double check if the user have this username or
not.
So to do that, I take the user name to the map and count the number of people with this username.
If the answer is zero, I say that this is an invalid user name and then we continue to try again.
if It isn't.
we keep going.
Now, let's get the user existing at the moment, which is, by the way, copy here and then the
user_exist would be compared with the current password if it doesn't match.
We again say that the user name or the password is wrong, otherwise, we continue.
If these are is done with both cases, we take the current_user to match the user_exist.
So every session, once the user logged in, will have the current_user as the object available.
in the UsersManager. observe that, this map is focusing on all of the available users.
But this object is available about the current_user.
By the way, when you always access a website with a username or password that are invalid we don't tell
user, most of the time it's a problem if the user name or the password for more security.
We just say that either one of these two guys is invalid and someone might say that the username is
invalid and here the password is invalid.
But we like to make it back for some security reasons.
In the case of sign-up, we have similar logic here, we started to read the username for Simplicity.
I'm avoiding spaces, we read the user name and the user_name shouldn't be on the map.
So every time the user is trying to give a user name that already exists, we tell him that this is
already used to try some other username after that we read the password, name
the email and so on.
In practice, we do a lot of verification about this data, but let's keep things simple.
Once you are done with that, we give a new ID for the current user by using
++last_ID.
And then we add in the map, this new user here, and after that, we update the database to add this
new user to the file again.
This one is helping us to make our code more parallel.
I would like to show you something here that this linking generates .
a bug, let's say we have two users are signing up at the same time.
Let's say that the number of users are ten.
So why the first one signed?
The second one signed.
Exactly.
And both of them accessed this line of code at exactly the same moment.
So both of them will have last_ID
10. this guy will be 11 and the other parallel session will be 11.
And then both of them will update the database with the same ID.
If you didn't get this, this is totally OK.
I'm just teaching you what happens in parallel session when you study parallel programming and threading,
you will be more familiar with this issue.
This is a sign-up method.
And what else is the update?
database here is just we can convert every user object to a string which will follow the structure of the
commas.
You should have this user constructor and this ToString function.
Both of them should be like very relevant.
Like this reading is parsing based on this writing.
So they are very relevant here.
So here the code for updating the database, you just convert the user to an ID and then you go and push
it to the file.
I'm creating a vector of one string and then writing all of it to the file.
There is also some read user ID here.
Yeah.
Overall, I think this is the important part that I needed to do.
This is just the printing all of
The current IDs in the system, this function is reading a user ID, so in practice, we will never
have such a function because users will not have a user ID. But just for simplicity, this guy is reading
a user id and verify that it exists in the map.
That's all about the users manager.