Let's highlight some information about the Questions Manager.
I know the project overall isn't easy, so let's highlight something that might be helpful.
We talked before about these two data structures.
One of them is like a question ID to the list of questions that we have and another one just map
the ID itself to the question object itself, we are trying to make sure that the objects
are just in one place, not distributed here and here to avoid copies.
The first function here is the Load Database.
The Load database has two maps and has a last ID. again
Given that I am doing a lot of load base to make sure that two programs are synced together.
If there are multiple sessions, I start  by clearing everything, get the  content of the
file, iterate on the file line by line, read the question that we have using the current line and
updating the current maximum.
Now we have year two things.
We have the question that we read and we have the question IDs that we would like to update the map
with it.
So we start to put this ID matches this question.
So far, so easy for the parent ID.
If the parent ID is minus one, we know that this is the head of a question.
So we come back here and create a map from this ID and we put myself on the list.
However, if the question belonged to another parent question, then we go to the parent directory,
the parent object and book myself.
So I'm going to put myself either with myself if I am actually a thread or in the map of the parent
itself.
This how we load the database.
I have your utility function, which fills the user question you provided with the user object and
you extract the questions matching this user.
For example, you start with clearing the two things.
Iterate over all of your questions like a vector of question, actually vector of integer, and then
iterate here to over the question itself and get the current question.
But observe here, I'm taking it with reference to avoid a copy.
If the question from is matching this user ID, then we add it to the from.
also if it's matching user ID, then also if the to user ID matches with me
take it, but be careful.
Is it a parent question or not based on that, put in the correct map?
I have here a function that also prints the user to questions, we have the to questions of the user,
so we iterate on the map of this specific user and start to print his questions.
And also, we have the from questions, so this is a list of my from questions, again, be careful,
avoid copies and print them.
There is also a read question utilities here two cases, the target is to read the question that
is valid and we check that this question ID exists really in the map, otherwise this is invalid.
1- if the read question failed,
I'm calling myself in a recursive way.
This isn't the best coding style, but I wanted to teach you that.
And otherwise, we can get the question and make one more verification that this question is really your
question.
So you aren't playing with me.
And this one is a similar one, it just for whatever user, so it's more flexible.
We have here a function that's answering questions, so it starts by taking what is a question ID
get the question, get the answer updated.
We are reading a couple of getline to avoid the last enter.
Deleting that question we have here, we get the question ID, yeah, this function is a bit tricky
in practice when you have more than a data structure and all of them contain the data,
this is what we call a multi view.
Multi view means that the same data exists in more than a data structure.
And now we would like to update or remove something.
You have to code it in a careful way to make sure you are removing from all of them or updating in all
of them.
So that's why I would have here this list of IDs to remove and I'm marking what to remove exactly.
And then going here to remove it from the other list.
Also observed that there are two cases.
Either we are removing a single question that is like, for example, a no thread or a threaded question.
If you are removing a question that is a thread, then you need to remove it and remove all of the questions
around this question too.
And so on, yeah, very similar concept here we are updating the data set here, list feed is just iterating
and printing, asking the question here.
I will take the data from the user, verify that is in order or not, and so on.
And the new ID and put it in the list based on is it thread or not?
So this is mainly the ask question one here.
The final thing that I will leave it for you is the mean.
Here we are a choice by choice.
Would we started to call our own functionalities, observe here with every run I call the LoadDatabase here to
keep reloading.
This helped me to make two sessions are working in parallel as much as possible.
That's all.
I hope you enjoyed the project.
I know it's challenging.
It takes time.
I know many students complain that doing a project is hard and there is no way.
There's no other shortcuts you have.
Like there is some part of struggling and suffering.
No way.
And I think that you did enough short exercises, it's time to challenge yourself with more such
big level of projects.