Hi, everyone, in this section, we're going to talk about data structures, a quick recap and C++ STL,
the C++.
C++ STL stands for the standard template library.
It is a library that provides us common algorithms like searching and sorting.
So there are functions that are there in the algorithm header file.
It provides us with data structures like the containers for stack, queue, array, vectors, unordered maps and so on.
map.
So on and all the containers I have built using templated classes.
OK, so that means you can fit any datatype into that container.
So that's more like a generic container, OK?
You can create an object for any particular type as well.
This framework is same as similar to the collection framework in Java.
If you're coming from java background, you might have heard about the collections framework.
The same similar kind of a thing in C++ is known as the standard template library or STL in short
So we are going to give you a quick recap of what is a container.
So a container is an object that stores a collection of other objects.
OK, so these objects are also elements, these objects could be as simple as integers
Lets say an array of integers, we can say that the integers are stored in an array containers
Or maybe I might have a class that.
I might have some kind object.
And I'm storing lots of cat objects inside a container.
OK, so I can say, an array of cats, that is also fine,  so the object can be as simple as the integer,
or it could be something complex like a cat, which may have certain attributes like color, height, size, ok, weight
OK,maybe some method as well containers can store objects as well, so
container manages the storage space for its elements and provides member functions to access them.
So mostly through iterators.
So iterators is again a very important concept.
Now if you have this array you can simply iterate it, using a variable,
lets say starting
I is at zero, I is at 1
But suppose if your container is complex, OK, maybe you.
Your container is implemented using a tree like data structure.
In that case, you cannot say I can Iterate simply using an index.
So what you will need is you will need an iterator, ok, to iterate over the different nodes of this
particular tree.
If you have a hash map, if you have a container, which is implemented using a linked list.
Then also, you will need a iterator to iterator over the different nodes in that particular linked list because
iterators will allow you to.
iterate over the different nodes that are there inside the container, OK?
So they're also objects.
They're also objects, which which became like pointers.
OK, so they know how to move forward, OK?
And they're defined for each of the containers that we have.
OK, so an example of a container is a stack or a map or a vector & so on.
So the containers in STL are divided into four broad categories.
The first set of category is known as the sequence containers in which the data is stored linearly in
a sequence like array is a sequence container you store all the elements linearly inside array
vector is like a dynamic array that can grow in size.
But again, the data is stored linearly inside vector as well.
OK, so Array has fixed size, but the vector can grow.
OK.
That is something which is known as Deque, which is known as the doubly ended queue.
It is also a linear container.
And the thing with this container is it can expand both from the front and both from the back.
And it can also contract both from the front and both from the back.
So it is known as doubly ended queue.
So you can see you can do the operations like insertion deletion at both ends of the queue.
And what are the most common operations that you would be doing in all of the containers?
So one is you are adding some data so that is known as insertion or adding, then you might be doing
searching looking for data.
Where does this data have stored?
Is it present or not?
And third is removing that is also known as deletion.
All of these containers will provide these operations in different time complexities that you should
be knowing.
OK.
and there is something which is known as forward list, so forward list is nothing but a singly linked list.
Again, the data is stored linearly, but the memory is not continuous.
OK, and then there is something which is known as list.
So list nothing but it is a doubling linked list.
You can expand.
Both at the front and both at the back. In forward list and list.
The memory allocation is not continuous, but in array and vector, it is continuous and Deque has a slightly
different implementation.
It's a complex implementation, so it combines various linear chunks of memory and it can take them
OK.
So it has a little complex implementation.
Then there is associative containers.
This is the second type of containers.
OK.
So in the associative containers, what you have is you have something that is known as a set.
So what is a set?
Let us talk about set.
So set, basically stores the collection of elements let;s say, you have one two three four five.
And let's say you have multiple force, the set is going to store only the unique element that means it is
not going to store the duplicates.
OK.
But if you stored if you store them using something known as multiset, it is going to store the duplicates
as well.
OK, so the multiset can have duplicate values secondly the set is going to store the values in ordered
fashion.
OK.
The values will be ordered.
That means they will be sorted.
OK.
And how is this set made?
So internally, it might be using a tree like structure, a balance tree like structure to implement as it?
So next thing we want to talk about is a map.
So what is a map?
The map is a container that is used to store a collection of key value pairs looking, for example,
you are in a restaurant and you.
You have to order certain items lets say.
You want to order a pizza that costs Rs 500.
OK.
And maybe you want to order a drink that costs Rs100
Maybe you want to order something like noodles that costs rupees 200.
OK?
What we can see is we have something which is known as key, something which is known as a value.
So basically that inserting these pairs inside the container.
And what this map will do, this will keep data.
Sorted by key, ok so the data will be sorted by keys.
And again, it uses a balanced BST(Binary Search Tree) like data structure
to store this data so that it might be stored like this.
You might have.
OK.
And then you might have noodles, you might have pizza, something like that, OK?
So it is going to use a tree like structure to store the items, OK?
So and that will give us sorted, for example, a b and c.
You can see this is a.
Balanced BST, OK, because the items are sorted by there key.
And if you do inorder reversal of the tree, you will get a list of all items.
Sorted by the key.
And you can even perform searching by going through this data structure.
So multiset, we have already discussed it as kind of a set.
It can contain duplicate keys and multimap is like a map which can contain duplicate keys OK.
So one key can have multiple values.
OK, mango can be mapped with 10 and Mango can also be mapped with 15.
But this might.
This is not possible with map.
This is possible with multimap.
So the thing to remember about associative containers is they use tree like structures to store the information
and the data is ordered.
The data is sorted.
And if you don't want to store sorted data, you want to store data in any random fashion.
OK, so we can use the unordered associative containers.
OK, so we have an unordered  set.
So maybe we want to store a set of numbers one three, four eight and may be 2.
So they must be stored in a random order inside this data structure.
And now you want to look up this number two is present or not.
OK, then this unordered set is very fast.
It will give you the results in almost order one time (O(1)), OK?
Similarly, we have something which is known as unordered.
Map.
It is like the hash table.
OK, it's like the hashtable.
And in hashtable again, you can do insertion, you can do look up.
OK, that is basically search.
And you can do deletion.
So all of these operations are done in order one time on average.
OK.
The Average Time Complexity, is  O(1), and that means it is very fast.
But it is going to tell you what is my mapped with the given key?
OK, so.
Anytime when you see, OK, map or unordered map, the data stored in the form of key value pairs, for
example, again, Pizza has a value 500.
If you look, look for what is the price of pizza and a list of items that you have inserted inside
this table.
But it is going to tell you in almost order one time that these pizza costs 500 and almost
overnight.
OK?
And maybe you want to insert noodles in the hash map, so it is going to take almost order one time,
Then there is unordered multiset, which again.
It is like an unordered set, but it can contain multiple keys of the same type , so there can be repeating
numbers in this state as well.
OK.
So it is going to store all of them and there is unoredered multimap.
That means you can have duplicate keys and those will be stored in the multimap as well.
So these are unordered associative containers.
There is one fourth category which is known as container adapters, so they provide a different kind
of interface to the further containers.
ok so one of them is stack.
OK, so the stack can be easily implemented using array or  vector or a linked list.
But what stack provides is it provides different methods to access the data, OK?
It also restricts the functionality.
You cannot have a look at all the elements, OK?
You can only look at that topmost element if you're using a stack.
You cannot remove from the middle or you can only remove from the top or you can see what is at the top.
Because that hides that stuff, the elements under the interface, OK?
Then there is Queue, so you again can be implemented using an array or a vector.
So but queue support the following operations.
so why we are using these data structures because it is easier to think in terms of queue or a stack
when we're solving a problem in which this kind of a data structure can be used.
We don't need to worry about what happens with the middle element because we are only doing insertion
at the back and we are going to remove elements from the front.
OK?
queue allows us to remove elements from the front and push elements from the back.
OK, so pushing is known as enqueue.
Removing elements from the front is known dequeue we are moving something push or inserting or
whatever you want to call it as.
then there is something we do, which we call it as priority queue.
So again, although it seems it's like, queue but internally we know it's a heap data structure.
That's OK.
So heap allows us to get the maximum element.
Or the minimum element out of a collection of elements, and we can remove the minimum or maximum element.
OK.
And we can insert any element so heap allow us these three operations insert new data get max and
remove maximum or the minimum elements, OK?
So again, these operations are supported in almost log(n) time.
And this is what a priority queue is.
OK.
So I hope you got a quick overview of the different type of containers that we have in STL.
And that's all for this video.