Hi, everyone, in this section, we will be looking at them of various STL containers starting
from Array.
So let us begin from Array.
So in order to use an array, there are two ways one as a classical approach that a lot of people use
to create, an array, a classical way of creating an array.
and one is STL based way of creating an array.
So array is also a class that was introduced in C++.
11.
OK.
And it offers some advantages over the classic arrays.
So let's have a quick recap of how to use classical array and how to use the STL based array
So if I want to create a simple array in cpp so I will write some basic code.
So let's see this code.
So first of all, what I would be doing, I would be creating an array of integers.
Let's say I create an array of fixed size.
So I hope you remember what is an array.
So array is a very simple data structure that stores all the elements in a fixed size sequence.
It is a container in which the elements are stored linearly.
And it is of fixed size, let's say the size is 6.
So it stores that are 10, 20, 30, 40, 50, 60, OK, and the starting index is zero.
The last index is n-1.
So the indexing will be from zero to five.
So this is the array of 100 elements.
You can create an array like this.
Or you might say, No, I don't want an array of 100 elements.
I want array of five elements that you can do, and you can also initialize what are the elements in
the array.
So this is this you can do or you can take input, the elements of the array, that is also fine.
So you can say ok for int i =0.
I less than n, where n would be what it is size of the array, divided by size of each integer.
So this array is going to occupy how many bytes let's say each.
integer occupies 20 bytes, sorry 4 bytes.
So the size of that array would be five into four divided by four.
That would be the value of N that is equal to five.
So we can say ok the number of elements is five in this particular array and giving this is giving
this sizes is optional if you're giving the elements, if you're giving the initialization list.
OK, so this is known as initialization list.
If you give the initialization list, you don't actually need to define the size that is completely
optional, if I want to print the element of array.
I can do it very easily.
I can say cout array of i.
OK.
And let's see.
Let's try to see this code.
So we have array classical dot slash, array classical.
So we get one five four three two, which are the elements of the array.
We can put some space as well, and we can do the same work as well.
One five four three two.
So now one thing we have to notice, then how do we pass arrays to function.
OK.
Let's talk about passing.
arrays to functions.
Let's say you have a function like update array.
OK?
Suppose I want to update a particular element of the array.
Let's say I will update the zeroth element or a particular ith index what I get I will get the array
and I will also get the index of the array.
So I would say array of I, this is equal to or the new value that I want to put so I can say array of i.
This is equal to value.
This is going to update the array, for example, I want to say update the array and take the index, take this
array and take the index one and make this number as 13.
OK.
And if you now print this array, if you now print this array, you will see the first index
is becoming 13.
That means when you are passing this array, no actual copy is created.
Okay, so the array, you can see it is passed by a reference.
Now we need to understand why it is passed by reference.
OK, so what happens?
Is this array name
OK, this array name.
It it actually stores the base address of the array.
OK, let's say this array is one five four three two.
So when you're passing this array let's say.
This address is  two zero two two.
So what will happen is when you're calling this update array function, this is also like a pointer
it is you can also write it as int star arr, because they are same, writing this or writing this is same
in the function call.
So effectively, you're creating a copy of this variable.
OK, you're creating a copy of this variable.
And this this address is to 2022 The stored here, so this address is also to 2022 so effectively this is
also pointing to this location.
OK.
So when you try to update array of i
So how does this breakdown by the compiler to the compiler says this is array + I.
OK, so that means it will take a jump of one if I want, it will come to this address, which is to
2026.
OK.
So effectively, if you say I will take a jump of one, it will take, it will go to the next box.
If you jump of 2, it will go to the two boxes ahead.
So in the memory, it is going to this address to a 2026 and it tries to dereference this and it puts
the value that is equal to, let's say, 13.
So what is going to happen?
You're going to come to this location and you're going to make this value as 13.
So that is why you can see the actual array is updated.
OK, in this case, the actual array is updated.
OK, now why I'm teaching you this stuff because when you're going to work with STL Array.
All of this is not going to happen.
Everything is going to be a copy of the original object, and you have to pass the object explicitly
by reference.
OK, we will see it very shortly in the next video.
But in this case, the actual array is updated.
OK.
Actual array is updated.
So this is one thing that you should be knowing that array are passed by reference because they're passed
by making a copy of the address.
And this array variable also points to the original array.
OK.
And you can also have a function to print the array.
So in order to print the array, you always need two things.
One is the base address of the array.
And second is the value of n.
OK.
So what you can do?
You can say for int i = 0,  I less than an n, i++
I will iterate over each and every box and I will print the value of array of i
OK, so now, instead of writing this for Loop It What I can say call the print method.
So in order to give the print method, I will give the array and the value of n, so lets build the code
And let's try to run it.
And you can see we are getting the same output.
So one thing to note is when you have to work on all the elements of the array, you also need to pass
the size of the array as a parameter because this array.
Does not know how big is the array?
This is just the base address of the array.
It does not know how big is this array because if you simply do cout, print the base address, OK,
so the base address is nothing but cout arr and I can say endl
So let let me show you the base address so you can see this is the base address.
OK, so addresses are printed in a hexadecimal format.
OK.
So whatever is this number, it is converted into hexadecimal number before printing, while printing
and hexadecimal numbers start from 0x.
OK, so all addresses will follow this form.
If you are coding in C++, so all addresses are hexadecimal addresses, this is nothing but the base address
of the array.
OK.
Another thing I want to tell you is.
Why you can't do size of the array if you do size of the array in main
And if you do the size of the array inside the function, there is a difference.
So let's see that different as well.
void
Let's say array size.
So suppose if i pass the array to this function and I say ok cout array size in function.
And here, let's say you do size of arr, OK?
And if you do size of array here, cout array size in main and let's say, size of arr.
OK.
And cout endl cout endl.
This is an important thing, and you should be understanding, so we are getting a warning here, sizeof
function parameters, so there is one warning.
So the warning says array function parameter will return the size of int star instead of int array, so this is actually
same as writing as they're discussed.
Either you write this or you write int star arr both are same, OK, both are same.
But in main, this is an actual object.
But in a function, this is only an address.
So let me tell you, let me show you the code output.
So array size in Main is 20, and
We have not called this method.
array size, so let's call this method array size, and we pass it the array as well.
And now let's run the code.
so you can see array size in main is 20 and array size in function is 8.
now how this is happening, OK?
So inside main, when you do size of array, you actually get the size of the array.
OK?
That that contains five elements.
so 5*4 is what?,  it is 20 bytes.
But inside the function call when you're saying, OK, I'm going to pass this, array, you're actually
copying the address let's say 2022.
That is a base address inside a pointer variable.
OK.
This is nothing but a pointer variable.
This is not the actual array object.
It is.
It only stored the value 2022, which means it is pointing to this one only.
So inside main you're getting the size of the array is 20 bytes.
Inside the function, you're getting the size of this array, which is eight bytes.
OK, because pointer variable is taking 8 bytes to store this particular address.
OK.
And that is why you cannot execute this statement inside a particular function like array size or inside
print
So that is why I have explicitly pass the value of n OK this value you won't be able to generate inside
the function, so you have to pass it explicitly.
This is how we work with classical arrays, so we try to cover through some common pitfalls, that people
might be doing so.
If you have this knowledge, you can easily work with arrays and in the next few videos, I will show you
how to work with the array object that you can create using STL based class.
And that's all for this video.