Hi Everyone.
So let us talk about Arrays that are present in C++ STL so for that.
you need to include the header file called # include array the way to create this object is you
have the Array class, which is part of this header file and you have to define what kind of object this
array will hold, maybe area of a dog or maybe an array of a integer.
And second thing is you have to give the size of the array, OK, so let's say the size is 6 and you
create this array.
OK, now what you can do?
Either you can take input and stored it in this array, or you can simply give it initialization list.
Just for a simple example, I've created an array of six elements and I have initialized what all elements
are in this particular array.
Now let's see how we can work with this array.
Suppose I want to update a particular element so I can say ok the array of zero.
This is equal to 10, so it will work in a similar manner.
And suppose I want to print the number of element so I can say for int i=0 i less than n
now.
And how do we get the value of n?
This is an object.
OK, so this is an object of the Array class and array class has a method called size.
So array.size will give us how many elements are there in this particular array.
So I can say, OK, cout the value of Array of i
OK, let's try to build this code, and let's also try to run this one.
So I can say dot  slash array
I get all the values of this array.
Array of 0 is updated as 10
And we are getting 10 two three six seven eight 10 two three six seven.
Yes.
Now one thing is how this object is passed to a function.
For example, I want to create a function to update an array so I can say void  update array and I will
pass in this object.
So this object
Is of this type and i can say array off.
Let me take an index and let me take the updated value.
So I can say Array of i this should be equal to value.
So what I'm going to do instead of doing this operation here, I'm calling the method.
Update array, and I'm saying, take this array take this index and take the value.
The I should be zero and let's say the value is now 100.
If I run this code, what I can say is the array is not updated, the array is not updated.
Why it is happening is, in this case, this array is an object.
OK?
This array is also an object.
And this object is nothing, it is STL container.
And one thing we should remember is all STL containers, all STL containers.
They are passed by value.
are passed by value.
So what is happening in these case is you have created around me and you are saying, look, I'm passing
an array to the updated function, which is a copy of this array.
So you're actually creating a copy of the original array.
So it is like to one two three four five one two three four five.
So this is the array in main.
And this is the array object inside.
Update.
Now, if you make a change inside this updated array this value becomes 100 and the actual array in the main it
does not changed, the actual array is not changed.
So what you need to do if you want to make the changes in the actual array, you have to use pass by reference.
Okay, you have to pass by reference.
So how the container that pass by reference.
Let us see.
So in order to pass any STL container by the reference, you have to create a reference variable here.
OK, so now what happens is we have one array, which is like this and we have an array object in main
and this array is a reference variable for this object because you're saying array int and arr, this
is equal to arr, OK?
And you can give it any name.
You can give it a name like some x array.
OK?
And even this x array, it would be same.
So if you run this code, you can see the actual array is changed to get the actual array is changed
so both x array  and this array are pointing to the same object in memory.
OK, so there they refer to the same object in memory.
So there is an object in the memory, which now has two names.
One name is arr.
Then then this function is called.
It gets a new name that is x arr.
OK.
So this object can be accessed using two names.
We call this as an alias.
That means you have a nickname.
You also have a nickname.
Now this x array and this arr they are the same object.
And once this function call is over, this name is gone because the scope is only,present inside this function
this function.
This name will not exist, and hence when you're coming back in the main, you're printing the array, and
that is how it is working.
Now there is one more thing.
Let's say you want to create a print method.
So in the classical array, we saw that we have to pass the value of n as well.
But in this case, since we are passing the entire object, we are not passing the base address we
are passing there and that object.
So in that case, if you want to write a print function for this kind of array, what you can do is you
you can say
I will pass this array to this function and I will take it for int  I=  zero I less than n.
And what is now n and is nothing but a array dot size
So this thing and you can say cout array of i and now you can call this function print array so you can say print
going to print array and that makes the work easy for you.
And let me show you the code again, you get the same output, and maybe we should, print some space
as well.
So this is printed by the print function.
Know how you're passing this array again, you're passing it by.
that means you're creating a copy of the array So if you don't want to create and copy, you're
say ok i will pass it by reference
And if you want to make sure your object is not changed, you can make it as a const also.
Also, you can make it as a const also.
Now what this const is going to do, it is going to make sure that this is print function.
This should be a read-only function.
That means it should not be modifying the values of the array.
So if you say area of zero and you make it as 100, then you're going to get an error because this is
a constant parameter.
OK.
This is a consent parameter.
It should be used in a read only mode.
It should not be modified.
So if you want to adopt good coding practices, then use in const with Read-Only data members is what
you should be doing.
So this is this is how it should be passed.
But yeah, so this is the correct way of writing the code, OK?
So we want to use this in a read only mode.
So that's why we're using this as a constant parameter.
It does not change inside the function, OK, but you can change it here.
You can change it in main.
OK.
So you can to array of zero, this is equal to 100, and this will now work fine.
The only for that function, the arrays read only OK, but in main you can change it.
But if you put the const here, then again, a similar thing will happen.
You will get the same error.
OK?
So that is what we generally use const.
And this is how the array objects are passed.
Now we can also talk about some more methods to work with this array.
So maybe I can say I want to sort the array.
OK.
So in STL containers, we also have one more concept that is a concept of a iterator.
So what we can do is we can sort this array.
I want to sort this array starting from this point till the last   give me this address.
So this is this would be given by a array dot beginning.
The address, which is after the last element.
OK.
The location, which is just after the last element, it will be given by a array dot end.
If you want to sort the entire array, let's say array of zero is 100, this is 16.
This is eight and this is lets say 17.
So if you want to sort this array, you will just sort it out.
array dot begin till array dot end.
So now we will have to import another file that is known known as algorithm.
This file contains some common functions like sorting, searching.
OK, so it is a inbuilt sort function.
And now if you print the array, this array should appear in a sorted manner so you can see we are able
to get a sorted array, so  the same thing if you have to do it with the classical array.
So this is our classical array.
So again, you have to import.
#include algorithm.
And what do you have to do is you have to define the starting and ending point of the array.
So you have to say OK in order to sort it, you have to say sort, array.begin.
So Begin will not work with the classical.
So we have to give the starting address that is array plus zero or even write it as array.
And you have to give the address of the last location, which is after the last element that is arr+n
and the last element is at n minus one.
So the next location would be to array+n.
And this is how you can do the sorting with the with the classical array as well.
OK.
So maybe there's a dot slash array classical.
You can see this is this is the sorted array
Yes, we made five as 13 and.
Then we did sorting so we get 1
One, two, three, four and 13.
So this is what the classical array.
So I hope you have understood some basic methods and these are the some of the commonly used things
that I have and only do.
And there is one more thing.
There is one more common operations.
In some cases, you might be required to initialize an area with all zeros or you might be doing array
with all once.
So in that case, we can use a method called fill.
So let me create the array of zeros.
Let me call as array of five so I can see array of integers with 10 elements.
And let me call it as fives.
So again, to fives that fill every value as five.
OK, I want to fill every value in this array is five, so I can say OK.
for int i equal to zero I less than five dot size.
I want to print each element so I can say cout fives of i.
So let me show you.
So this array will contain.
All fives.
dot slash array, so you have all fives in that, you have 10 number of fives in the array and let cout endl
let me just commend this thing out.
There is one more method that we can use for each loop.
OK, so we can use this look also to easily iterate over any array.
So maybe I can for some auto or some numbered.
int x that there inside your original array or in the fives array.
you can say cout X.
So let me show you how this will loop will work.
This is this is done using the normal for loop.
And this we have printed using a for each loop, OK, this we have done using a for each look.
So let's see how this loop works.
Let's say instead of iterating over the fives array, lets iterate over the original array.
So now what we're getting, we're getting the elements of the original array, so let's see how this
works.
You have elements like two, three, eight, 16, 17 and they say, OK, X is going to assume each and
every value in this array, in each iteration.
So we have X, which is initially to be printed.
Then we get X, which is three x gets the value, three we printed then x gets the value 8 ,16 and so on
so on.
So what we have seen for int x which is there inside the original.
OK, so here we are not iterating over the indices, but we are iterating over the values inside there.
This kind of a loop is known as a for each loop.
We have similar loop in java.
We have a similar loop in Python as well.
So this is called an colon ok, this is what this is a an colon operator.
So it simplifies the syntax of iterating over the array so you can use this for each loop with the array
container as well.
So I hope you are now clear with the how to use array containers, and we have discussed the commonly
used functions with arrays containers.
OK.
So that's all for this video.
Thank you.