Hi Everyone so we have talking about the containers, and we have already seen, how do you work with Array.
based container
OK.
On the next container that we will talk about is a vector.
So what is the vector?
Vector is a dynamic array.
OK, so what is the meaning of a dynamic array?
So it is an array that can grow in size.
So we look at how this works.
So we have already discussed about Array Class and we have also discussed how they are different from
the classical Arrays.
And there are a lot of methods associated with each and every container that you do not need to remember.
OK, so I'm doing do not need to remember, but because you can always look up at the documentation
and if you want to look for a specific method, but there are some common operations that you must be
knowing, that.
How do you access the Ith element or how do you get the size of the array?
And there are two more methods which we have not discussed.
There is a method called Front that gives you the element at the front of the Array, and there is a
method back, which gives you the last element, OK?
So ideally, you can do it using it of zero or array of n minus one as well.
So this is the element at the back.
So there are a lot of other methods as well, which you do not need to remember, but you can always look
at the documentation.
But one thing you should be remembering is in an array in order to access any ith element like this,
or you can use the add function.
All of these operations are order(1) operation ok.
That means you can you have the random access to any element in constant time.
And now what we arre going to do, we are going to talk about vectors which are very similar to arrays, but they
have a special power as well.
So that special power is they had the ability to resize themself, when an element is inserted in the
array.
OK, for example, you have a vector which is currently off size.
Let's say 4 and.
You want to insert one more element in this vector, let's say the vector is of size 5
You want to insert one more element to the element is 20.
So you inserted it.
Now you say, OK, I want to insert one more element in this particular vector.
And but the vector is full, the vector is full.
So what what it is going to do, it is going to resize itself when an element is inserted.
OK, now how that resize happens.
I will give you a quick recap to the vector doubles itself.
OK, so if the original size is five, it is going to create a new array in a.
And this array is allocated dynamically on run time.
OK.
And it is going to copy all the elements of the previous array, so it is going to copy one, two, three
4 20.
And now you can see this.
This had a capacity of five.
And this vector has a capacity of 10.
That means it has doubled its capacity.
And you want to insert a new element.
Let's say you want to insert 21 so that 21 would be presented.
OK.
So this vector has a concept of relocation happens when the underlying array is full.
And second thing is, these locations are continuous.
OK, that means if this addresses 100.
The next would be 104 the next would be 108
Next would be one 112.
These are continuous addresses.
Now why?
This is a difference of 4 because each in the box takes four bytes, OK?
So the original array would be deleted.
The original array would be deleted, and you would have a new array at a new memory location.
Okay, so it's it uses dynamic memory allocation.
To create these underlying arrays, OK, so dynamic memory allocation.
So again, it is a sequence container, so, this all this thing, all the code that is responsible for
reallocating the memory.
It is already written by the people who made STL.
You just only need to call some of the functions to work with the vector.
OK, so you have the square brackets as an overloaded operator, then you have square brackets, either
overloaded operator and you you have this clear method as well.
If you want to remove everything from the vector, you have a method called popback.
If you want to remove the last element, you have a vector method called push back.
If you want to push something from the back now, it is very important to think, why don't we have
a method like push front that push back or push front in the vector?
OK?
Because you're working with array, so anything.
All the empty locations are on the back of vector.
If you want to push now 50, so you will call ok push back 50 and that will insert 50 inside the vector,
OK, that is going to insert 50.
And we want to say popback.
It is going to remove 50 from the vector.
OK, and this can be done in order one time.
This can be done in order one time.
There again, a lot of methods.
So I'm just highlighting the important ones like reserve you should be doing.
The reserve is used when you're sure that I need at least this much space to work with the vector.
In that case, your memory would be reserved for that many number of units, for that many number of
units.
So.
That's that's how you're going to use the reserve method at, for example, you're sure I will need
at least 1000 elements that will make sure in the beginning your array is of size 1000.
And then you if it exceeds 1000, then it will double itself.
It will make itself as two thousand, okay.
So we have pushback that inserts at the back.
We have pop, but that removes something from the back.
We don't have push front because there is no additional space to push something on the front of this
vector.
You cannot have anything at index minus one.
You cannot push directly at the front without doing any shifting so that that's where we don't have
push front or pop front methods.
OK, so no pushfront, no popfront inside the vector, and there is a method called clear that is
going to remove all the elements.
It is going to make the size of the vector zero.
The capacity may not change.
OK, the capacity may not change.
So let us look at a demo.
Let's look at a demo.
Of how do we work with Victor?
If you want to create an empty container, you just OK vector, followed by the datatype in angular brackets
followed by the name of the vector, OK.
And if you want to create a vector using a fill constructor, OK, that means you want to create a vector
in which every number is 20.
So for that, we can use something known as a fill constructor.
So we say OK, four boxes each of value 20.
So this is your vector and once it is full.
You want to insert something more.
It will double itself.
It will make itself as eight.
And there is also a range constructor that you can also construct a vector from an array, so this is nothing
but an array.
And you're saying, ok, I'm defining the range starting from this point till this point.
Put all these values inside of vector.
So this is how you use the range constructor.
There's also something which is called a copy constructor that will take in a director as object and
it will create a copy.
OK, it will create a copy.
So that means if you have a vector of any 20, 30, 40, this is third, then you will create another
vector that is copy of this one.
OK.
So for that, we can use the copy constructor to create an object, and most of these ways are common
for many STL containers.
OK.
And you do not need to remember each and every one.
You can also construct a vector using an initialization list.
OK, you can say ok
These are the numbers I want to use to create create this particular vector.
OK?
So let's talk about one more way, so you can also say, OK, I will take inputs and I will push back
those inputs in my vector where if you know that you already have a vector, which is of, say, 100,
then you can also say, OK,v[0]
This is one v of I.
This is equal to 20.
You can access the ith index, provided I is less than the capacity of the vector.
OK, so the capacity means how much storage has been allocated for that particular vector.
You cannot say I is this location, make it 100, so you will get a memory error.
If you if your i goes out of bounds of the capacity of director, OK?
So some of the common functions like you want to access the Ith element, you can either use at
or you can use square brackets.
You can get the current size by using the size function.
You can get the underlying capacity.
That means how much memory has been allocated using arr.capacity, and you can also get the maximum
size.
That means how much memory is available due to available RAM.
And for that, you can use a arr dot max underscore size.
OK.
So this is an example of using the pushback method if you want to push something in this vector,
arr dot push back 20, so this will add 20 to the vector
And if the capacity is full, then it will double itself OK.
And.
If you want to remove something from the back, you want to remove something, then you can call the
back method, and this is also an order one method, OK?
So array dot clear like you want to remove all the elements from the vector, so it reduces the size to zero.
The size is not the same as capacity, not same as capacity.
That means currently we have a empty vector.
And if the original capacity is C, the capacity is going to remain same but the elements are not going
to be there in the vector.
So when you start pushing back in the element again, they're going to push from zeroth index maybe
13, 14, 15.
They will get stored after clearing the original vectors, and there are some more methods like it
erase or insert.
So now we will look at a quick demo of how to work with vector.
So let us look at a demo of working with the vector, so first we need to include the header file.
OK.
And that's lets say vector.
And what I'm going to do, I'm going to simply create a vector.
Now there are multiple ways.
There is a fill contract that we can use or there is a range of iterations that we can do on an array
and then we can make a vector.
So let's create a very simple vector.
And I will take input a value of n and and I will begin with that and I will push an element in the vector
so for int i =0 i less than n i++, i can say ok, lets read those input
So int, some number will cin that number and we will say  be OK if we don't push back that particular
number.
Now, if I show you the code, we also have to let us also print the size of the vector after each insertion.
Or so what?
Maybe lets print the capacity.
And that is we dot capacity.
OK.
And let's also print the size after each insertion.
So that is v dot size.
So, no, let's see.
Let's I want to insert 10 integers in my vector.
So I can say, OK, that is 10 and followed by one.
So in the beginning, I inserted one number, so it created a vector of size one and that stores one.
Then maybe I store 10.
So the capacities to the vector itself and it is storing the number 10.
OK, maybe then I store 20.
The capacity becomes four.
And it is storing the number 20 here.
Then I again insert 30, the capacity remains four and we have 30 here, OK?
And now if I again insert something, let's say 40, the capacity will double itself.
It will become it.
The capacity will become eight and the size would be five.
Because we are storing five numbers.
OK, then let's say 50.
Same 60.
Same 70, same 80.
And now that's OK.
Now it is full because 50, 60 70.
And now it is full.
Now the size would become how much 8*2 16, the actual size would be now 16.
And this would be storing 10 numbers.
10 numbers lets say 90 and you're going to see what happens now.
OK.
So we size is 10, then the capacity is 16 and the vector is doing actually 10 numbers, OK, we're doing
10 numbers inside of it.
So what you're observing is there is a repeated doubling operation that is happening and this is an
expensive operation every time, every time the doubling of the memory happens.
OK.
You're spending linear time to double the array.
OK, you're spending linear time to double that particular.
And that makes your push back operation in some cases as a linear operation instead of a constant operation.
OK.
So on an average, it is constant.
But when the doubling happens, it becomes a expensive operation because in order to avoid that, what
you can do you can to get v dot reserve.
I know there would be at least 100 element in the vector, and why I should start from 10.
so now you can see, if I push one, let me build the code and let me stop this
OK, let me push one.
So the capacity is 100 from the beginning, let me push 2, the capacity is 100.
So there is no doubling.
That is happening until you have reached 100 element, OK, until you reach 100 elements or this is one
where you would have done another would have been yours.
OK, I want to create a vector of 1000 elements, each initialized with the value zero.
This is also going to make the capacity of the vector as one thousand.
In the beginning, it's a 10 element.
And store 100.
Sorry
So.
OK, so in this case, what happened is when you're using this fill constructor, you have already said,
OK, we have already filled 1000 element in the vector.
OK?
And now you start pushing from one thousand oneth position that is going to double this vector.
OK.
So you have to observe that there is a difference.
There is a difference between using a fill constructor and calling v dot reserve.
OK.
So you have to make sure that you do not confuse these two.
So right now, I would be just saying vector of int.
And let me call it as v then, I say, OK, reserve these  many elements inside the vector similar
to push back.
We have pop back.
We have we can also print the vector so we can look for every element and go to the vector and you say,
OK, but every element that is there inside your vector?
You go and it.
So you see out.
Uh, X.
OK.
So let me take input n element I will push them into the vector  and I will print those elements.
So let me say I want to give five elements and let elements are one two three 15 and four.
So now you can see it is reading all those elements.
The capacity does not change because we have used the method reserve and the size is increasing as we
are inserting those elements.
So this is the output and this is how you get all those elements.
You can also do sorting on the vectors like sort.
You can say v.begin till v.end.
OK, and that will give you the sorted output.
Right now, I'm just going to comment this thing out.
I don't want to see the capacity again and again, so I can say ok five elements five four one three two.
So you get one, two, three, four and five.
So this is how you work with a vector, and that's all for this video.