Hi Everyone in this lecture will talk about the doubly ended queue, which is also known as deque.
So that is a very simple container.
It is a sequence container and with dynamic size that can expand and contract on both ends.
So this is a very special property that you should remember about Deque.
So as the name suggests, it's a doubly ended queue.
So it can expand and it can contract on both sides.
Okay.
So basically, you have a container like this.
And what are you going to do?
You can push data from the front, which is known as push front.
You can pop data from the front, which is known as pop Front.
You can push data from the back push back.
You can pop data on the back pop back.
OK?
So when you have something like a problem in which maybe you want to implement some sliding window kind
of an algorithm in which you are maybe adding data from here and you would be removing data from it?
Or maybe you are also adding data from here and you might really moving from here as well.
OK, so maybe a window which can expand and contract on both sides.
In that case, you might be using this kind of a data structure, which we call it as Deque.
So now let's also learn a few more points about Deque.
So one thing is that internally, the implementation of the container is quite complex, and it is not
guaranteed that you will be storing everything in a continuous memory location.
Okay, so the two addresses may be different as well.
OK, and elements of the Deque can be scattered across different chunks in the memory.
Also, because it is not guaranteed internally, it would be linear, but for you, it would behave like
all the elements are stored sequentially.
So let us talk about a few important methods of Deque so you can access any element you can.
OK.
So could you give me the ith element of the Deque using the Square Brackets, which is an overloaded operator?
Or you can use the at function both that same.
And if you want to see what does the last element, you can call the back method.
If you want to remove all the elements, you can call the clear method.
If you want to get the front element, you can call the front method again.
So these are four important operations that you should be knowing, push back ,pop back , push front, pop front
front OK, and there is size.
method also tells you how many elements are currently there in the Deque.
So let us look at a few ways to initialize this Deque so you can create a Deque like this, or you can
use a fill constructor like you can say, OK, I have empty Deque.
I have four integers with the value of hundreds, so this is going to create a Deque in which we have
4 numbers and everything is initialized as undertook it
Or we can use.
We can iterate over another Deque and we can create up a third Deque as well.
Or we can also use the copy constructor like we did in vector as well.
So these are a few ways in which you can create a Deque.
You can also use an array and you can iterate over the elements of the Deque, and you can give those
elements in the Deque of the device.
You can use the operations like push back to insert some integer into the Deque.
OK, or if you want a remove pop back, put something at the front was trying to remove something from
the front pop front.
OK, so you do not need to remember each and every method.
You can always look up at the documentation, but these are few things that make Deque special that
insertion and deletion at both ends.
You can do very easily and that do in constant time.
OK.
So let us also look at a quick demo in the code.
So let me create a Deque of size, Enzo.
I can see a deque of integers.
Create it stores 10 elements.
Now what I can do, I can say ok int i =0, i less than 10 i plus plus now the memory
is already created.
What I can do, I can say ok, deque of i
This should be storing the number I * i.
That is i square
I'm storing i square in the deque and let us try to print it for Auto X that is there in deque I can
see out X. So let's see what output does it produce?
So we have built the code and now we can run the code as well.
So I can say, OK, let's run deque.
So we are getting the numbers from zero to 81.
That means we are getting the squares of these numbers.
Now what we can do is we can also say instead of using a loop like this, maybe you might be doing four
for int i=0,i less than 10
10 I plus plus.
So you can also see out deque of i.
And this is also allowed.
Or you can say cout deque of at of i.
at of i
at method is supported in all the containers.
Most of the containers which have like the sequential interface, so we can say, OK, so this also
works this is also fine.
you can access all the element, either using at or using square brackets.
So let me show you an example of let's first print the capacity of deque so I can just say cout
deque dot capacity
OK.
And let's also print the size of the deque.
So deque does not have the function capacity, OK?
It is only with the vector so will not print capacity we will only print the size.
So let's build the code and let's try to run it and...
OK, so the capacity is 10.
And if I do push back, if I say, OK, size is 10, then if I push something into deque, let's say
deque dot push back 123, that number would be there at the back.
So now you can see the number 123 is there inserted at the back of the deque, OK?
And if you do the push front, then this would be at the beginning of the deque.
So let me show it to you.
And you can tell at the beginning of the deque, so there are methods that allow you to insert something
in the middle of the deque, something remove from the middle of the deque
Those are also done a bit, but they take linear times and ideally for most of the use case, we would
be dealing with these methods insertion and deletion from both ends.
OK?
So I hope you got a quick idea about deque.
And that's all for this video and thanks a lot.