Hi Everyone,   today I'm going to tell you about the C++ standard template library for the stack that
is available for use for everyone.
And you can use STL while solving online coding challenges.
OK.
You can also use it during your interview rounds.
And what this library offers is it offers you implementation of most common data structures that we're
learning in this course.
Learning data structures is important because you understand the core concepts of data structures, and when we are
going through the implementation.
Once you understand the core concept for every problem, you don't need to repeat the same date structure
,,
You don't need to write the code for that data structure again and again
OK, so we want to reuse our code.
And for most of the data structure, the code are available and hence the library for the stack is hash
include stack.
So this is not written by me.
It's written by the people who built the C++ standard template library framework and that provides the
direct implementation of stack.
Let's see how we can use this stack.
So firstly, you define the class that is stack, then maybe you type the data type, maybe a stack
of strings.
And maybe let me call it as books ,Books, dot push, I can say C++ and sorry, then I can
say.
Some more books I can push, maybe a Java, or maybe a python, or maybe an operating system book.
Now here you can see it is very similar to what we have done, and we actually try to replicate the
same functionality that is provided by the STL stack.
So what I can do is I can while this stack is not empty, which supports the empty method.
It supports what is there at the top.
It supports the pop method.
And it also supports the push method.
OK, so let's build the code.
OK, it says undefined.
Identifier.
wait..
This should be books.
The name of the stack is actually books.
So I was using this.
Now you can see the code is getting built very fine and it is using the inbuilt stack that is provided to
us.
So yes, it has an empty method.
Top method, pop method, push method?
You can also read about more details in the C++ reference are C++ dot com.
And let us run this code and see.
So dot slash stack STL
We are getting os, python, java and C++.
That means the stack is working as expected.
Yes.
Working perfectly fine.
So that's all for this lecture.
Thank you.