Hi Everyone in this lecture, I'm going to tell you about the queue STL, the queue standard template library,
so that is present, the queue class is present in the file hash include queue.
So you have to include this and once you include this.
You can easily make a queue of any datatype.
Let's say queue of integers, and we will just try to insert some numbers in the queue so
queue dot push lets say one.
And.
Maybe two.
Then three, then four, then five and then six.
So what we will do will try to print the entire element of the queue and we will remove everything from
the front so while the queue is not empty, so we will do cout queue dot front.
So the STL also provides this method and we can do queue dot pop
But OK, that's it.
And this is how we can use the inbuilt C++ standard template library, queue.
And now we can actually try to run over code as well.
So.
Let me show you.
We are getting the output in the same order that means it is a fifo kind of a queue.
All right.
So that's all for this lecture.
Thank you.