Hi in this lecture, I will tell you how you can use the inbuilt priority queue class in C++, as heap data structure
OK, so firstly, you need to include the header file that is queue, and after that you need
to make a class priority queue.
So this class is already defined, so we will create an object and each node will contain an integer
it.
So let's call it as a heap.
And now this is a variable, OK?
This is and this is the data structure that we're using.
What we can do, we can iterate over all the elements in array and let us try to insert all those
elements in this particular priority queue so,
As the name suggests, each element will come out of the queue with a certain priority.
In this case, the priority is element with the higher value has a higher priority.
OK?
So let us see if I can say, heap dot Push X and let us build the code and it is working fine.
Not all the elements are added inside the heap and internally it looks maybe something like this.
You will have 90 at the root node.
then it would have maybe 20 or maybe it would have 10 OK.
So I don't know.
Internally, the structure would look something like this.
What we can do, we can keep on removing all the nodes one by one from this heap and see what is the
output we get.
So we can say while this heap is not empty.
While not empty it, us try to remove one element that is at the top of the heap so I can to say cout,
if dot, I think the function is called to stop it.
And then I can call the heap dot pop function.
The top function displays what is at the top and pop function removes that topmost element.
OK, so and now we're we can run this code.
We can see dot slash.
The file name is sorting using a heap, if I now show you, you can see we are getting the elements
in our descending order.
That means you're able to do sorting using the heap.
But now you may ask what if I want to sort these elements in reverse order, OK?
So by default, it makes a max heap.
You can see it as a max heap by default if you want the min  heap.
Then what we can do, we can.
We have to provide two more parameters.
One is called vector and there is another comparator.
So you're going to build comparator that will reverse the comparison, OK?
This will convert this max heap into a min heap.
And if I now run the code and you're can see we are getting these elements in a reverse order.
So this is inbuilt comparator, OK?
It does.
It has reversed the comparison that he was using internally to compare two elements of greater element
was going to the top.
Now the smaller element is going to the top.
If you don't want to use this kind of a comparator or maybe for a complex object, you can also write
your own custom comparator.
OK.
Let me also show you how we can write those own custom comparator for this particular class.
I will maybe make a copy of this code.
And I call it as custom compare dot.
And here we are going to define class compare.
And inside this class, we have to define method so we can say bool operator.
And.
Now, if you look, we are doing operator overloading here.
We have we are going to get to numbers int a and int b and we are going to compare them.
This compare function we will not call directly.
The heap class will call it internally whenever it is comparing two elements OK, so we say return
let's say a greater than b.
So this function is public because it would be called from outside the compare class, and then we have
this operator, that means we are overloading the round brackets
And then whenever we are doing a comparison, we get 2 numbers which are as argument and based upon
the logic it will return true or false if it is greater than it will return.
True if I instead of doing this, if I simply send the compare class.
So if I do, starting using heaps, I get this output.
But let's say if I change this comparison here and build my code and I get.
I should get a ok this is the output, and if I do it like this, I will build the code.
And.
OK, so it is my mistake, I'm running the wrong file.
It's not sorting using heap the file name is custom compared.
So dot slash custom compare.
And you can see we are getting the elements in a sorted order.
But if I change this now to like this one, we get the reverse order, OK?
So this is one thing you can do in some of the problems, and we will see more such application in coming
lectures.